<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11723A0101-MLI-15151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Electoral cycle support in Mali</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Electoral cycle support in Mali</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of the intervention, it is expected to ensure national ownership in terms of organization and the management of the electoral process.
This will be done through a strong coordination of support to the electoral cycle from partners for 1) The organization of free, inclusive, transparent and peaceful elections in line with international standards and regional instruments governing electoral processes and integrating gender equity and respect for human rights and 2) Institutional capacity building for the management of the electoral cycle in the light of strengthening democratic governance.
The achievement of the two dimensions mentioned above is a long-term process because the conduct of an election involves a sequence of events and the engagement of several actors. The entities of the EMB are the main beneficiaries of the support. They will receive specific trainings to improve the election result management system including the process of counting, tabulating, aggregating and announcing the results of the election.
In addition to the EMB, direct beneficiaries will include civil society organizations, political parties and the media. Adequately-funded civil society and media organizations will play a wider role in the area of civic and voter education. Youth, women, refugees and internally displaced people also stand to benefit, and support to a more inclusive process is intended bring them into the electoral process. Finally, support to conflict management and dispute resolution aims to reduce election-related violence which often affects some of the poorest and most marginalized groups.
The Embassy assesses that the project is supposed to promote social equality, political inclusion and minimize electoral conflicts and build trust among the various actors targeted. In addition, the project will contribute to the stabilization and the consolidation of the peace process as elections are an important part of it. Holding the presidential polls on time is vital to avoid a political crisis with unforeseeable consequences in Mali.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">F&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja anordnandet av president- och parlamentval i Mali 2018 har UNDP ans&#xF6;kt hos Sida om ett finansiellt st&#xF6;d  f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra det s&#xE5; kallade projektet &quot;St&#xF6;d till valsprocessen i Mali under perioden 2018-2019&quot;. Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r programmet &#xE4;r ber&#xE4;knad till 4 941 000 USD (41 809 100 SEK).

Insatsen syftar till att fr&#xE4;mja demokratisk styrning och m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra konsolidering av fredsprocessen genom att h&#xE5;lla trov&#xE4;rdiga, transparenta, fredliga, inkluderande val med brett deltagande i enlighet med internationella standarder. UNDP kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen p&#xE5; uppdrag av Malis regering och givarna som bidrar till finansieringen i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med FN: s fredsbevarande styrka i Mali (MINUSMA) och andra FN-organisationer och organ som st&#xF6;der valprocessen. Genom insatsen kommer kapaciteten hos de enheter som utg&#xF6;r det nationella valf&#xF6;rvaltningsorganet  EMB att st&#xE4;rkas i rollen att utf&#xF6;ra sina uppdrag. F&#xF6;r en mer inkluderande valprocess kommer insatsen ocks&#xE5; omfatta st&#xF6;d till det civila samh&#xE4;llet f&#xF6;r undervisningsinsatser betr&#xE4;ffande om val och medborgerliga r&#xE4;ttigheter.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to support the organization of the 2018 elections (Presidential and legislative) in Mali, UNDP has proposed to the International Community for funding a proposal of 4 941 000 USD (41 809 100 SEK) to carry out the project &quot;Support to the Electoral Cycle in Mali during the period 2018-2019&quot;. 

The intervention aims at promoting democratic governance and enabling the consolidation of the peace process through the holding of credible, transparent, peaceful, inclusive and participatory elections in accordance with international standards. UNDP will implement the intervention on behalf of the Government of Mali and the donors contributing to the funding in close collaboration with the UN peacekeeping mission in Mali (MINUSMA) and other UN system agencies providing support to the electoral process. Through the intervention, the capacity of the entities constituting the EMB will be strengthened in order to carry out their mission. In addition, support will be provided to CSOs for civic, voter education activities for a more inclusive electoral process. 

The financial contribution of Sweden is estimated to 15 MSEK (1 785 880 USD) corresponding to 33% of the total budget. In addition to the Swedish financing, other donors committed to make a financial contribution include Norway with 1 000 000 USD and UNDP with 500 000 SEK. At the moment a financial gap of around 40% remains.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elections</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879313</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-959956.4589508887</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-02">1726042.529687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">-959956.4144326091</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP has implemented many activities including communication and public awareness-raising for more inclusive elections, support to the Ministry of territorial administration and decentralization and mobilizing civil society organizations for greater participation. The following results have been achieved:
&#x2022; UNDP has mobilized donors&#x2019; funds and coordinated them to support transparent, free and fair electoral processes &#x2022; The technical and operational capacities of the main electoral management bodies have been strengthened and they have organized the 2018 Presidential elections in a professional way according to international standards.&#x2022; electoral advisors have been deployed and stationed in the 11 regional government offices and supported local commissions in charge of centralizing electoral operations&#x2022; Populations have been widely sensitized on the necessity of the NINA card (national identification number), how to vote and why to vote through various means of communication&#x2022; civil society organizations have been selected and awarded funds to implement communication and public awareness raising activities about elections at regional and local levels&#x2022; journalists have been trained on how to make an impartial and nonviolent media covering of elections&#x2022; Despite the political and security context that were tense, the election turnout rate reached 42% thanks to the massive awareness raising campaigns organized in collaboration with the civil society&#x2022; UN system&#x2019;s support to elections have been evaluated to capitalize and learn lessons from the 2018 presidential elections and prepare for the 2020 legislative elections.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11723" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1180000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Mali 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Mali 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
