<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11003A0102-MLI-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Studio Tamani - news and information for dialogue, peace and equality in Mali</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Studio Tamani - nyheter och information f&#xF6;r dialog, fred och j&#xE4;mlikhet i Mali</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Hirondelle, a non-profit organization based in Switzerland working to strengthen independent media in especially conflict-affected countries, has submitted an application to Sida for support to the project Studio Tamani  - news and information for dialogue, peace and equality in Mali, for the period 2018-2022. Sida has previously contributed to Studio Tamami during the period 2015-2017. Studio Tamani is a media platform for professional and impartial news and information. Through a network of 70 local partner radios,  covering 85% of Mali&apos;s population, daily news and debate programs are broadcasted in five languages. In addition, thematic programmes on children&apos;s and women&apos;s rights, shortly also on environmental and climate issues, are broadcasted every week. Moreover, social media are increasingly being used to reach especially the younger part of the population.

The overall objective of the intervention is to contribute to peace and development in Mali through information and dialogue between all peoples and all regions of the country and the two specific objectives are that the Malian population is better informed and more engaged in supporting the peace process, democracy, gender equality and a fairer society thanks to its access to independent, professional information and debate programs, and that Studio Tamani becomes a sustainable project run by a Malian legal entity and fully gender mainstreamed.

The total budget of the intervention is 87.2 MSEK, of which Sweden contributes with 51.6 MSEK. In addition to this amount, Sida provides 500 000 SEK to be disposed by Sida to support strengthening of Fondation Hirondelle&apos;s capacity for results based management. The other main donors are currently the EU and Denmark.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fondation Hirondelle, en ideell organisation baserad i Schweiz som arbetar med att st&#xE4;rka oberoende media i framf&#xF6;rallt konfliktdrabbade l&#xE4;nder, har till Sida inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan om st&#xF6;d till projektet Studio Tamani  - nyheter och information f&#xF6;r dialog, fred och j&#xE4;mlikhet i Mali, under perioden 2018-2022. Sida har tidigare bidragit med st&#xF6;d till Studio Tamani under perioden 2015-2017. Studio Tamani &#xE4;r en mediaplattform f&#xF6;r produktion av professionella och opartiska nyheter och information. Genom ett n&#xE4;tverk av 70 lokala partnerradiostationer som t&#xE4;cker 85% av Malis befolkning s&#xE4;nds dagliga nyhets- och debattprogram p&#xE5; fem olika spr&#xE5;k. Varje vecka s&#xE4;nds dessutom tematiska program om barns- och kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter och inom kort &#xE4;ven om milj&#xF6;- och klimatfr&#xE5;gor. Sociala medier anv&#xE4;nds ocks&#xE5; i allt h&#xF6;gre utstr&#xE4;ckning f&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; s&#xE4;rskilt den yngre delen av befolkningen.

Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att bidra till fred och utveckling i Mali genom information och dialog mellan alla m&#xE4;nniskor och regioner i landet. Det tv&#xE5; specifika m&#xE5;len &#xE4;r att befolkningen &#xE4;r b&#xE4;ttre informerad och mer engagerad i att st&#xF6;dja fredsprocessen, demokrati, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och ett r&#xE4;ttvisare samh&#xE4;lle tack vare tillg&#xE5;ngen till oberoende och professionella informations- och debattprogram, samt att Studio Tamani uppn&#xE5;r h&#xE5;llbarhet, drivs av en malisk juridisk person och &#xE4;r fullt j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsintegrerad. 

Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 87,2 MSEK varav Sida bidrar med 51,6 MSEK. Ut&#xF6;ver detta belopp tillhandah&#xE5;ller Sida 500 000 SEK som ska disponeras av Sida f&#xF6;r att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka avtalsparten Fondation Hirondelles kapacitet f&#xF6;r resultatbaserad styrning. De andra huvudsakliga givarna &#xE4;r i dagsl&#xE4;get EU och Danmark.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention is to contribute to peace and development in Mali through information and dialogue between all peoples and all regions of the country.
The two main expected results are that the Malian population is better informed and more engaged in supporting the peace process, democracy, gender-equality and the development of a fairer society thanks to its access to independent, professional information and debate programmes and that&#xA0;Studio Tamani at the end of the project period has become a sustainable project that is fully gender mainstreamed and run by a Malian entity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Hirondelle</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Hirondelle</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mali</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.3 - F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra utbildningen, medvetenheten och den m&#xE4;nskliga och institutionella kapaciteten vad g&#xE4;ller begr&#xE4;nsning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarna, klimatanpassning, begr&#xE4;nsning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarnas konsekvenser samt tidig varning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.3 - Improve education, awareness-raising and human and institutional capacity on climate change mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.b - Enhance the use of enabling technology, in particular information and communications technology, to promote the empowerment of women.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.b - &#xD6;ka anv&#xE4;ndningen av gynnsam teknik, i synnerhet informations- och kommunikationsteknik, f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja kvinnors egenmakt</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">14146.6174557684</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">39765.7904166259</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">14146.6174557684</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">39765.7904166259</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-31">57534.750989</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">14146.6481244514</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/mali/11003_AgreementStudioTamani.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement on contribution to Studio Tamani</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/mali/amendment-to-the-framework-agreeement---28062019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision 28062019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/mali/studio-tamani---nyheter-och-information-for-dialog---fred-och-jamlikhet-i-mali---29052018.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision 29052018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/mali/11003_DecisiononcontributiontoStudioTamani.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on contribution to Studio Tamani</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During 2020, Studio Tamani continued its mission of informing and promoting dialog between all regions and citizens. Several activities were carried out in order to achieve the defined objectives.
Covering and treating news&#xA0;
The legislative elections, postponed many times since 2018, have been announced for the end of March 2020. Studio Tamani accompanied the electoral process with precise and strict editorial provisions. 4 training workshops of 3 days each in Bamako (3) and S&#xE9;gou (1) brought together journalists from all regions of Mali. These trainings were an opportunity to review the fundamentals of journalism (accuracy, clarity, balance and neutrality, independence and honesty) and to train participants on the specificities of journalism during an election period. Activities linked to legislative elections were covered according to an electoral with three different but interlinked periods: before elections, the elections day and post-elections.&#xA0; Young people were particularly targeted through the Youth Program broadcast on Saturdays and Sundays, in order to encourage them to take an interest in the current electoral process, to register themselves and to vote.
Onset of the COVID 19
The editorial staff of the Fondation Hirondelle, including Studio Tamani, from the beginning of March put in place measures to best protect their staff. Fondation Hirondelle set-up a contingency plan in March, which was adapted by each of the editorial staff. With regard to Studio Tamani, the contingency plan provided for the following measures:
. Adaptations to the organization of editorial staff and the production of programs.
. The reduction of outdoor reporting. &#x201C;Stopping travel outside the capital&quot;.&#xA0;
. A preference for studio recordings and telephone interventions.
At the same time, adaptations have been made to productions, consisting in particular of the rebroadcasting of certain programs, dual-flow operation and reduction of teams, or even the limitation of outings and travel. At the editorial level, new sections were created in March:
. a 3-minute daily magazine devoted to COVID and its repercussions and a 15-minute weekly cultural magazine dedicated to COVID and broadcast on Saturdays and Sundays within of the youth program.
Prevention spots in 7 languages, therefore in two additional languages (Sonink&#xE9; and Torosso), were produced and broadcast in order to reach as many people as possible.
Studio Tamani launched its radio education program on June 2020. This program is a response to the multidimensional crisis that affects the country&apos;s education system. In addition to the pre-existing structural problems (lack of teachers, precarious infrastructure, insufficient equipment, difficulties of access, etc.) there is added growing insecurity in many localities, the teachers&apos; strike which lasted almost a year between 2019 and 2020, and finally the COVID19 crisis. The issues of both quality and accessibility of the education sector are aggravated, and it is expected that the number of children out of school in the long term will increase. Thus, with the launch of the radio education program, Studio Tamani has joined the efforts of the Ministry of Education and its partners to maintain educational continuity as much as possible.&#xA0;
As part of the radio education program, Studio Tamani works in partnership with the Ministry of Education, the National Directorate of Basic Education, the Norwegian Refugee Council and UNICEF. In doing so, we offer one hour of program per day on the basics of reading / writing and arithmetic. Our program covers levels 1 to 6 of basic education, with the target audience for out-of-school children between the ages of 7 and 12.&#xA0;
Studio Tamani also provided information to Malian citizens in real time via social networks, the website, and news papers during the coup d&apos;&#xE9;tat in August 2020. It provided live coverage of the two days of validation of the terms of reference for the transition and the three days of national consultations which took place on September 5 and 6 and from September 11 to 13.&#xA0;
Our assessment of the rate of achievement
The greatest attention to local languages, the reports produced in the regions partly explain the achievement of the results mentioned above.&#xA0;In addition, collecting information related to the situation of women&#xA0;In addition, the fact of collecting information related to the situation of women and a greater involvement of women in the animation of radio programs (Grand D&#xE9;bat) have improved the quality of programs. The consideration of environmental issues has also made it possible to broaden the range of programs to be disseminated and to raise awareness among the populations on environmental risks.&#xA0;Studio Tamani also collaborates with media organizations, NGOs or companies, national and international partners. At the same time, Studio Tamani very regularly uses the expertise of NGOs to feed or intervene in its productions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11003" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1180000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Mali 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Mali 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
