<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10006</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF Kabojja</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)    Project NameUganda - Kabojja Junior School    RegionSub-Saharan Africa   Sector   Project No10006   Projected Board DateJune 14, 2000   Company NameKabojja Junior School   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The major shareholders are: Mr. Ahmed Nsubuga (50%) a qualified teacher and Mr Nasser Lubega (50%) a member of the Chartered Institute of Accountants (UK) and a retired banker. The sponsors own Kabojja Secondary School, a boarding co-educational school with an enrollment of 796 students. Ms Susan Cardis, aged 50 and a British national, has been recruited as the headmistress for the project. She has 28 years educational experience in primary schools and she was the head of two British schools and one school in Pakistan prior to coming to Uganda.       Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    The project cost is estimated at US$1.26 million. The proposed IFC investment is a loan of US$0.35 million.    Location of Project and Description of Site    	The project is located on a 0.45ha site at adjacent plots 17 Acacia Avenue and 28 Windsor crescent, Kololo Kampala District. It is about 3 kilometers from the city center, which provides an easy proximity to parents to transport children and proceed to work. The site is adequately supplied with electricity, water and telephone. Water supply and sewage are connected to the city water and sewer system. A standby diesel generator will be purchased. The school will consist of four main buildings  which are sufficient to accommodate an office block, library, music room, bursars office, classrooms and other amenities. The location and topography of the site are suitable for the project.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project is to establish a high-quality, co-educational private primary school in Kampala, targeting middle income Ugandans. The school will cater for approximately 660 students, day scholars, and will offer a comprehensive quality curriculum leading to the Uganda Primary Leaving Certificate of Education. The school will establish a pre-primary (nursery) education and also create a scholarship fund for under-privileged children from rural areas as a contribution to poverty alleviation.     	Development Impact: The project will (a) provide quality school education for approximately 660 students each year at affordable costs, (b) create 59 jobs for teachers and administrative staff, with attendant training and improvement in environmental health and safety standards.(c) The project increases the involvement of the private sector in the provision of social services and reduces overcrowding in public schools.       Environmental Category and Issues    	This is an environmental review Category B project.  Key environmental  occupational health and safety issues include: sewage disposal and treatment, disposal of solid and liquid wastes, water and power supply, CFC-free cold storage, hygiene and general house keeping, and fire safety and emergency response preparedness. Details on how the environment matters are addressed  are summarised in the Environmental Review Summary (ERS).    Host country location of environmental documentsKampala City Council, Local Council V, Chairmans office, City Hall, Kampala     Date SPI sent to InfoShop May 10, 2000   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kabojja Junior School</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10006" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-10-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-02-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="UG-Uganda">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.2500000000 32.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Elementary and Secondary Schools</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.35 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-10-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-10-03">350000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-10-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-10-03">350000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kabojja Junior School</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10006/aef-kabojja">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
