<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MJR2014 Legal Booklets</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Microjustice Legal Booklets for Start-up Entrepreneurs in Rwanda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) 1 Legal needs assessment report
2) 2 Microjustice prototype product manuals and forms
3) 500 doing business and how to deal with legal issues booklets</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Microjustice Rwanada (MJR) is a locally registered non-goverment organization that provides basic legal services to the Rwandan population. Its main work has focused on giving assistance to small-scale traders at the Gatuna/Katuna border to increase understanding of their rights and oligations under the EAC Treaty and Protocols, access trade-related documents (such as the simplified certificate of origin) and thereby strenghten the free movement of persons and goods across the Rwandan/Ugandan border. Microjustice Rwanda is a part of the Microjustice international network that is coordinated by Microjustice4All.
In order to assure the quality of the legal services, Microjustice4All provides all Microjustic country organizations with tehnical assistance, including on the implementation of the Microjustice method and the development of legal products. in the past, Microjustice4All has assisted MJ country organizations with similar consultancies where the country organizations made informative booklets, developed legal products as well as traiings and training manuals for the distribustion and use of the legal products and manuals.
Spark Rwanda requested MJ Rwanda to draft a proposla for the development of legal services and information for start-up entrepreneurs to complement the business services already provided to them. For the development of these services, MJ Rwanda will conduct a legal needs assessment, research the relevant Rwandan laws, develop legal products, and prepare and test a booklet for entrepreneurs, that contains the information they need to know how to start and manage enterprise.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The prime target group consists of start-up entrepreneurs. These are often young people that start their business. They may choose to do so on their own, with business partners or cooperatives. The booklet will be developed so that they can use it to make an informed choice about the legal form that best suit their business plans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-28" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-28" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Microjustice Rwanda</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beata Mukeshimana</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Microjustice Rwanda
Niza Plaza 008
KIGALI
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">26500</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
