<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MOBINC2014-2015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projet de D&#xE9;veloppement des Fili&#xE8;res de transformation agro-alimentaire</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">More than 90% of Burundi population lives in rural area. For centuries foof agriculture and livestock have been the major sources of means of life. High demographic growth on small land leaves population unemployed. Families has no longer enough land to produce food; land is scarce. Poor education system and lack of skills have left the majority of rural young people  unemployed. This situation builds up poverty and social unrest. One of the ways to achieve this is by stimulating entrepreneurship in rural area in order to engage itself on a new path to development.  Entrepreneurship will create new opportunities address the land issue help skills acquisition create youth employment and lead the country to prosperity. The sorghum value chain offers high potential for this form of development since there is a demand for sorghum not in the last because of the presence of Brarundi /Heineken as a purchasers. The demand is for sufficient quantities of better quality sorghum to be used in beer production. If local production can be sufficiently improved imports of sorghum can be reduced. There is therefore a good business opportunity and need to assist farmers associations and champions to structurally enhance their sorghum production processing and marketing skills. As Burundi does not have organizations that are capable to provide these services to starting entrepreneurs in the rural areas , MOBINC as a mobile incubation organization is need to provide assistance under SPARK ABC program,

Entrepreneurship could be a sustainable solution for Burundi rural environment. It could create new opportunities, address the land issue, help skills acquisition, create youth employment and lead the country to prosperity.
Mobile business incubator (MOBINC) adapts itself to rural context by deploying its advisory services and training modules in entrepreneurship, its mobile equipments for technical training, information and communication services, and its coaching teams to young entrepreneurs. Its competitive advantage is that it invests more in human capacity building instead of investing in incubators own infrastructure. Furthermore, it goes towards incubates and thus reaches more beneficiaries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will directly target sorghum producers associations and selected champions from Bubanza Bujumbura rural and Cibitoke provinces</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To make available local Business Development services for entrepreneurs in the rural areas of Bubanza, Citbitoke and Bujumbura rural provinces
To establish 40 viable businesses that will create jobs in the sorghum value chain
To stimulate productions in the first growing season by providing loans to selected farmers/SMEs
Results  FOR 2nd SEMESTER 2014

8 cooperatives set up: 4 in Cibitoke and 4 others in Bubanza
2 federations of cooperatives set up at provincial level, one in Bubanza and one Cibitoke
120 producers (15 members x 8 coop) trained on entrepreneurship and cooperative management tools
Study tour organized for 20 producers on cooperative management in Rwanda</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobile Business Incubator</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seleus NEZERWE</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobile Business Incubator
P.O. Box
BUJUMBURA
Burundi</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burundi</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">35225</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
