<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-STIKK2015 ICTValue Chain</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICT Value Chain</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.5 Participation at B2B Matchmaking with Dutch Companies 2014
# number of companies participated - 5
# of business leads generated - 5
# of contracts signed - 1

3.1 Implementation of IT promotion programme for increasing the awareness of ICT to policymakers and relevant stakeholders
# workshops organized - 2
# certified persons - 20
# females certified - 5

3.2 IT Industry Barometer introduced
# interviews conducted - 25
# questionnaires produced - 1
# businesses participating in barometer - 25
# report produced - 1
# of presentations held - 1

3.3.1 Regional &#x201C;KosICT&#x201D; conference organized
# of international speakers -10
# of participants - 250
# of companies participating in B2B - 20
# of matchmakings between businesses - 10
# of female speakers - 3
% of female entrepreneurs participating in B2B meetings - 20

3.3.2 Brand ambassadors of the ICT industry (continuous lobbying) appointed
# of ambassadors appointed - 5
# of countries covered - 5
# of meetings with ambassadors held - 10

3.4 Interest group that will lobby for &#x201C;enabling startup ecosystem&#x201D; created
# of participants (private sector, government, academia) - 10
# of presentations held - 2
# of workshops organized - 2

3.5 Set-up the quality forum for Policymakers, Academia and Businesses
# of platform created - 1
# of participants involved (private sector, government, academia) - 20

3.6. STIKK established as an IT Cluster of Excellence for lobbying purposes
# of clusters formed - 1
# of lobbying themes identified - 3
# of meetings held - 5</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICT in Kosovo is one of the fastest growing sectors and is currently quite competitive with other countries in the region. The ICT infrastructure has marked significant improvement in the last decade and most of the major towns and cities in Kosovo are linked to the Internet via Optic Fiber Cables. This is well documented on STIKKs last Internet Penetration report, where it is identified that 76.6% of whole Kosovo territory is covered with Internet. The sector of ICT has got the most potential and contains some of the most engaged companies from the whole sectors of economic development in Kosovo. The workforce tends to be young and in trends with the latest global developments in technology. Additionally the sector has been supported throughout by one of the most engaged business associations STIKK (Kosovo ICT Association). However, even though the sector is one of the most promising to bring socio-economic improvement in Kosovo, it still faces difficulties to unleash its full potential.

It should be noted that the ICT market in Kosovo is quite fragmented and comprised of small-to-medium companies with up to 20 employees, with larger companies make for exceptions in this sector. Currently, the ICT companies are determined to grow and prosper within the Kosovo market, while more and more companies are seeking expansion (outsourcing) in markets outside of Kosovo, where better opportunities for growth and profits exist. Together with the growth and expansion, there is also a need for supporting actions and the policy framework to be regulated and proactively developed in a national level in order to achieve better results as a sector in the country and region.

Even though the local ICT sector is proactively represented by STIKK on policymaking events such as working groups, public discussions, committee review meetings etc., there are still obstacles that need to be tackled. Currently, some of the biggest challenges that ICT companies face relate to IT promotion policy, disadvantaged tax regulations, lack of governmental incentives in supporting the growth of the sector, lack of promotion of the export/outsourcing opportunities, access to finance, educational policies that boost ICT education, as well as specialized technical/professional trainings and certifications.

Chronologically, most of the sectoral policies and legislation for ICT date before the independence of Kosovo. The main chunk of laws was passed from 2003 to 2006 during UNMIK legislation. The two central pieces of legislation concerning the ICT sector are the Law on Information Society Services (promulgated in 2005) and the Law on Telecommunication (promulgated in 2003). The latter created the grounds for the establishment of the Telecommunication Regulatory Authority (ART), which became operational in January 2004. Other legislation relevant to the ICT sector includes the Law on Copyright and Related Rights (2004), the Law on Trademarks (2006), the Law on Standardization (2004) and The Law on Prevention and Fight of Cybercrime (2010). Finally in 2013, after years of lobbying by STIKK, some of the ICT products were exempt from custom taxes, nonetheless, the list of products that have been officially exempt is vague and does not satisfy the platform for a proper development of the sector.

This year, STIKK in cooperation with Ministry of Economic Development, and the support of GIZ and Norwegian Ministry of Foreign Affairs has drafted a complete National IT Strategy. The national ICT strategy compromises of 9 pillars that need to be addressed in order for Kosovo to reach a better tech infrastructure and socio-economic development. The 9 pillars are the following.
IT Promotion Policy
Company Excellence &amp; Quality
Export Promotion
Domestic Market Development
IT Education
IT Clusters &amp; Collaboration
Entrepreneurship
Innovation &amp; Applied R&amp;D
Investment Promotion

For the national ICT strategy, the workshop groups were formed out of actors that come from the entire triple helix of Kosovo (Government-Academia-Industry), with representatives involved from stakeholders such as: Ministry of Trade &amp; Industry, Ministry of Economic Development, Ministry of Education, Science and Technology, Ministry of Finances, private universities, public universities, donor community, relevant organizations and more than 30 ICT businesses. This way STIKK has formed groups of interest that are enthusiastic for developing the sector and the countrys economy. This document is awaiting to be submitted at the Ministry of Economic Development, which will send it to the parliament for approval.

When analyzing the obstacles to growth of the ICT sector in Kosovo, it is important to focus on very apparent issues that directly hinder the growth and development of the ICT market in a sustainable manner. In Kosovo, one of the key challenges when dealing with policymakers from the government is that they are not aware of the current existing problems and do not have the necessary know-how on how to approach and tackle the problems through innovative policies. Therefore in 2015, STIKK wants to address that challenge by concentrating on advocacy &amp; lobbying issues identified by the members and reflected on the National IT Strategy that are related to the increase of awareness (promotion) of the ICT throughout the Kosovo economy and direct advocacy &amp; lobbying activities that will lead to alternatives in policymaking, and will advocate for a better business-environment in Kosovo. Moreover, STIKK wants to follow-up with the recommendations of the latest position papers conducted through SPARKs.

The reason why we need to increase the awarness before actually starting to implement advocacy &amp; lobbying issues is that we strongly believe that policymakers should at first be shown of the importance of ICT for the general well-being of the Kosovar public and the impact it provides on the socio-economic development. Moreover, this would enable the policymakers to later take charge and start influencing policies on their work, and become supportive stakeholders of the initiatives.

It could be argued that by promoting the ICT sector as the most dynamic sector of the country, increase the awareness of policymakers around proactive policies, by effectively lobbying for more favorable conditions for growth, and by lobbying for specific changes that lead to growth, there will be a more promising environment for business enabling for ICT companies and other sectors in general, as ICT is wide-spread in a multi-sectoral line.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since this project is more ambitious than the previous years and aims to increase awareness of ICT and to directly advocate and lobby for a better business environment, then the entire business community in Kosovo as a whole is considered as a indirect beneficiary. Moreover, the project aims to promote the engagement of policymakers for advancing the sector. Additionally, the SMEs in the ICT sector are beneficiaries, as they will benefit from the promotion activities and direct engagements in advocacy &amp; lobbying for the sector. Moreover, the project aims to satisfy start-ups in the ICT sector from the recommendations that STIKK has got from the &#x201C;enabling start-up ecosystem&#x201D; position paper</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STIKK (Kosovo Association of Information and Communication Technology</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vjollca Cavolli</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>vcavolli@stikk-ks.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STIKK (Kosovo Association of Information and Communication Technology
Pashko Vasa Str 22
10000  PRISTINA
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">49994</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
