<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-BAC MN2015ConferencBC</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conference of Business Sector of North and South Mitrovica</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Mapped potential participants for the conference - 100 of companies interviewed, 20 of companies participated the conference
2. Roundtables organized - 1 of roundtable organized		
3. Recognized problems which impacts on cooperation  -  1 of survey conducted
4. Conclusions from the conference which will be presented in media and delivered on all important addresses which are dealing with economic development - 1 of advocacy strategies formulated</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Short description of the aims of the activity

BACMN with support from SPARK would organize Conference of Businessman from North and South Mitrovica where would be discuss about establishing better cooperation between companies from North with companies from Southern Mitrovica and also to recognize problems that companies are faced in regular business operations. Conference will also serve to establish links between companies and to expand markets for selling products. Conference will also bring various donors who will present their programs on which companies can apply.


Detailed description of the project
Reasons and considerations that have led to the project-proposal
Following positive changes in Kosovo and expanding opportunities for better cooperation all communities in Kosovo. It is visible need to encourage tendency better cooperation of business sector. Organizing conference this type would contribute that problems exist in daily business operation of companies are presented in one place and where foundations for solving this problems will be made. Particularly is important that these problems will be discussed donors which will recognizing problems and put those problems as priority for their work. Also engagement in overcoming these problems will take local authorities. 

Needs that the project addresses/problems that it is going to solve
After long period of difficult conditions for cooperation, within positive changes that happened in Mitrovica encouraged with the results from the first conference conditions are acquired for overcoming this problems. One of the most important segments of improving quality of life is stable economic system. Stability of economic system is sustainable if there is good cooperation between businesses of both part of the Mitrovica. To encourage this type of cooperation it is needed for companies to meet and to discuss not only about problems that exists here but also to expand their cooperation in sense of supplementing in doing business which will create possibilities to reduce unemployment rate.  

Designated goals and chosen strategy
Main goal of the project is to bring 20 businesses from North and South Mitrovica, where representatives of business discuss about problems with presence of representatives of local authorities of both parts of the city and as well of donors who will present their programs as encouragement for this type of cooperation. This conference represents continuation of the cooperation and initiatives and results participants of the first conference who supported these types of events. PSCMS engaged that mutual initiative is successful which would result with mutual study visit in country and region which in future would result creating fair of entrepreneurs in Mitrovica Region.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start-up business, companies, SME, donors</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Advisory Center Mitrovica North</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dragan Spasojevic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>pscms@ymail.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Advisory Center Mitrovica North
Cika Jovina bb
38220  MITROVICA NORTH
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">3980</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
