<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-SUTCO2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YOUTHNOW</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">-To build capacity of 40 youth in leadership, decision making and how to participate effectively, rationally and actively on youth issues.


-Follow up of two Action Groups in Nyakuron, AtlabaraandHai-AmaratofYouthNow trained by THA in 2013:To find out to what steps have been taken up by the 2 Actions in advocating for; socio-economic activities; youth unemployment; and political participation.



-Follow up of Media training done in Nairobi with youth in Juba;
To find out how many trained youth have practiced and produced media content for broadcasting, if not, why?
To assess challenges faced by media practitioners according to their topics from Nairobi.
To find out if the construction of a youth centre in Aweil, Northern Bhar el Ghazal has been done. If not done, what are the challenges? (This was a suggestion from the media training in Nairobi)
To find out if youth trainees from Nairobi have been couched and mentored


Trainer of Trainees (ToTs) Practicing of Facilitation Skills organised by SUTCO.
To enhance the facilitation skills and knowledge of ToTs so that they become very competent.

-Follow up on fellowship/internship program for youth. Development of a concept paper for fellowship &amp; internship for 2015.
Identify 10 organisations for placements of fellows/interns.
Identify 5 organisations for sponsorship of fellowship/internship program for 2015:To train, couch, and mentor youth on job-specific skills.
NB: SUTCO will for 2014 work only on the issue of internship for 6 youth requested by National Constitutional Review Commission of South Sudan.


-Advocacy plan: Follow up on Policy Writing on job creation for youth; and Constitutional Review Process for youth to understand the process and prepare them for inclusion of their issues in the final draft constitution: To support the establishment of a legal framework for jobs creation for the youth that will be of high impact.


-To equip Ating Benson with specific skills on website maintenance and management.


-To make the website up to date with new contents and connecting it with other social networks for regular visiting and access to information.


-Editing of 12 radio episodes to be broadcasted on Miraya Radio:To remove contentious/sensitive issues from the episodes and make them ready for public broadcasting.


-Up-loading of edited radio episodes on YouthNow (YN) website:To inform youth through the YN website and participate by giving their views after listening to radio episodes.


-Reaching out to IDPs through radio programs (radio debates):To raise voices of IDPs to decision makers in the peace negotiations.


-Meeting with political party leagues:To groom them to become active so as they can push youth issues through their political parties.

-Constitutional review:To enhance youths understanding of constitutional review process and inclusion of their issues in the final draft constitution.


-Multi stakeholder dialogue;To link and connect youth, establish partnership with business communities on issues of; sponsorship, access to finance (loans), job opportunities, and capacity strengthening of youth on social economic activities.


Campaign to keep Juba clean (Welcoming the up-coming peace deal):Encourage youths unity and diversity as regardless of where they come from, to receive the upcoming peace,   and enhance general cleanliness, safe and healthy environment, for health and sound minds of the youths and all in Juba and elsewhere in South Sudan.


-Advocacy training for political leagues and ToTs (50 persons):To enhance youth leaders skills and knowledge in advocacy work.


-Follow up of 6 youth placed for internship with National Constitutional Review Commission (NCRC):To identify challenges met and skills learnt during internship to inform adjustments in planning for 2015.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Partner shares the vision of the Programme: the consortium partners are united in the overall objective of the Programme: to reduce instability in three fragile state environments through strengthening the institutional capacity of relevant political and civil society stakeholders to improve the social-economic position of young men and women.The Programme makes the strategic choice to focus on the socio-economic position of young women and men[[1] Young men and women refers to the age group of 18-35 years old1], and aims to create an enabling environment for youth entrepreneurship and youth participation in the public sector and in civil society. The Youth Engagement Programme and its partners work towards this objective efficiently and effectively;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young men and women refers to the age group of 18-35 years old</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUTCO</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tom Ogwal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUTCO
HaiThoura, University of Juba road
University of Juba road
JUBA
Zuid-Soedan</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">41803</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
