<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-BCZ 2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SME North Kosovo Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Center Zvecan and its employees and trainers through building capacity of the organization  as main support entity for entrepreneurs of Northern Kosovo.
Entrepreneurs and SME established in the previous phase of the project, Start-ups and existing businesses, entrepreneurs from North Kosovo municipalities: Zvecan, Mitrovica, Leposavic and Zubin Potok.
Young entrepreneurs, as promoters of new development initiatives.
Farmers from North Kosovo.
Community of the North Kosovo.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the previous phase of the project the awareness was raised on the importance of enhancing entrepreneurship and its potential role in overall economic development. Apart from awareness rising, steps were undertaken to build the capacity of the people supporting entrepreneurship (like Business Center Zvecan), or potential entrepreneurs themselves or local stakeholders who can successfully support and influence creation of Business supportive environment. Considerable efforts were put to achieve above results, however it was proved that such activities need continuation in order to provide further-reaching effects.
Kosovos unemployment rate is estimated at 45.4% Kosovos Agency of Statistics (KAS) unemployment rate in 2009 (KAS, 2009). and is the highest in Europe. According to the KA Group research (2010), in the Mitrovica region it has reached 70% of the active population. Within Northern Kosovo, the environment for economic development was far from being conducive, due to continuing political dispute over the status of North Kosovo. Until 2010, the access to business education and consulting services was difficult due to the underdeveloped business development infrastructure. The existing registered SMEs were experiencing difficulties in accessing financial services due to the reduced number of financial service providers that operated in Northern Kosovo, restrictive credit extension policies in terms of credit history and collateral requirements, as well as the high cost of credit (15  25% interest rate declining  per annum). Since June 2011, the two main financial services providers, ProCredit Bank and Raiffeissen Bank,  have refrained  from extending credits to the individuals and business in the Northern Kosovo  (Mitrovica  North, Zve&#x10D;an,  Zubin Potok and Leposavi&#x107;), limiting the range of financial services to transfer of funds, payment of salaries, utilities, and establishment of saving accounts. In 2011 BCZ in cooperation with UNDP and SPARK, through NLB bank, started a micro crediting scheme, and more than 20 entrepreneurs were credited, to develop or start up a business. Even though situation for crediting start ups has not improved in 2013, there was surprisingly large number of candidates who were interested to learning how to make business plans and to gain other skills necessary to start up a business. Because of earlier mentioned BCZ decided in this year, to show and to teach our clients how not to rely on banks only but, to find other sources of funding and financing through Fundraising trainings as well as through matchmaking activities. Also BCZ became leading centre for entrepreneurial trainings, having trained more that 300 beneficiaries in years 2012 and 2013.



Output(s)	Indicator (s):	Target(s):

1.1 Capacity of BCZ staff increased in the area of fund raising and lobbying.	Number of staff member certified	9/3 woman
1.2 Capacity of BCZ staff increased in the area of business entrepreneurship support  	Number of new activities that BCZ will introduce 	1
1.4 Through successful meetings cooperation obtained	Number of new projects	2
2.1Through successfully held trainings on topics of business and entrepreneurship trained and certified potential and existing entrepreneurs	Number of potential and existing entrepreneurs certified	100/ 40 woman
2.2 Through successfully held trainings, and delivered grants new farms started 	Number of new family business started 	10
2.3  Through delivered grants to entrepreneurs new jobs created 	Number of jobs created 	40
2.4  New BCZ Clients from municipalities: Zubin Potok, Leposavic and Mitrovica 	Number of new BCZ clients registered in BCZ database 	80/25 woman

2.5 Business plans approved and ready for finance.	Approved business plans
	50/25 woman

2.6 Best Business ideas approved 	Number of BBI forms approved	15/5 woman
2.7 Stimulation for business start up 	Number of awards given 	12/3 women
2.8. Through successfully held B2B event matchmaking between entrepreneurs was realized	Matches accomplished 	10/3 woman
2.9 Through an educational study visit successful matchmaking between entrepreneurs was realized 	Matches accomplished 	10/3 woman
2.10 Successfully held consultancy sessions and meetings for support, growth or start-up of SMEs	Number of SMEs owners/ potential entrepreneurs supported by consultancy	40/12 woman
3.1 Joint activity of all MFS II members in order to solve Problems and remove barriers 	Number of research conducted 	1</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output(s)	Indicator (s):	Target(s):

1.1 Capacity of BCZ staff increased in the area of fund raising and lobbying.	Number of staff member certified	9/3 woman
1.2 Capacity of BCZ staff increased in the area of business entrepreneurship support  	Number of new activities that BCZ will introduce 	1
1.4 Through successful meetings cooperation obtained	Number of new projects	2
2.1Through successfully held trainings on topics of business and entrepreneurship trained and certified potential and existing entrepreneurs	Number of potential and existing entrepreneurs certified	100/ 40 woman
2.2 Through successfully held trainings, and delivered grants new farms started 	Number of new family business started 	10
2.3  Through delivered grants to entrepreneurs new jobs created 	Number of jobs created 	40
2.4  New BCZ Clients from municipalities: Zubin Potok, Leposavic and Mitrovica 	Number of new BCZ clients registered in BCZ database 	80/25 woman

2.5 Business plans approved and ready for finance.	Approved business plans
	50/25 woman

2.6 Best Business ideas approved 	Number of BBI forms approved	15/5 woman
2.7 Stimulation for business start up 	Number of awards given 	12/3 women
2.8. Through successfully held B2B event matchmaking between entrepreneurs was realized	Matches accomplished 	10/3 woman
2.9 Through an educational study visit successful matchmaking between entrepreneurs was realized 	Matches accomplished 	10/3 woman
2.10 Successfully held consultancy sessions and meetings for support, growth or start-up of SMEs	Number of SMEs owners/ potential entrepreneurs supported by consultancy	40/12 woman
3.1 Joint activity of all MFS II members in order to solve Problems and remove barriers 	Number of research conducted 	1</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC Zvecan</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srdjan Zivkovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>dynamic@beotel.net</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC Zvecan
Kosovskih junaka 4
ZVECAN
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">149840</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.poslovnicentarzvecan.com">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
