<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFSII.KOS.UM 2012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for training and development Kosovska Mitrovica II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project objective(s):
The aim of our project is to: is to establishment of the new / enhancing and diversifying the activities of the existing enterprises in Northern Kosovo and actively contribute to the activities of companies, thus intensifying job creation and economic development in North Kosovo. Providing skills and practical knowledge important for the labour market, expanding professional experience.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outputs:
These activities will result in:
1.1 One CTD Project manager engaged in project development, project sustainability, financial operations and coordination of the activities of the participating stakeholders; at least 2 Capacity Building training attended by CTD staff; 2 student/client satisfaction surveys conducted (period January-June and July-December)

2.1 Information on business plan trainings and competition disseminated on 10 UPKM faculties and 3 Vocational schools and one College; 2500 flyers and 200 posters distributed, 4 promotion events organised;  2 Business Plan Competitions organized by BCZ

3.1 Group of 3 professors (Economics, Law and Technical sciences) responsible to develop module &#x201C;Development of Entrepreneurial Competences&#x201D;. 40 UM students entered module&#x201C;Development of Entrepreneurial Competences &#x201D;. The module is organised in two cycles per year and consists of  3 sub-modules (Entrepreneurship, Logistic Management, Legal Training) each module consist from 4 day intensive training.  30 students successfully pass the module and received certificate.

3.2 After competition of the above mentioned module 30 students that received certificates, plus 10 additional UM students, will be trained by BC Zvecan (Business Plan Writing training) for Business Plan competition (5 modules x 2 cycles; 10 days per cycle). 40 students will attend; 30 will successfully pass the training and receive certificates;  25 BP will be submitted to a jury  15 find eligible, Bank will approve 10 BPs

4.1 45 students and/or BC Zvecan trainees entered the Basic Business English 3  cycles x 1 module (27 two-lesson /2x45min/ intensive English training); and 13 (2x45min) preparation for classes, 4 classes of examination preparation and evaluation, 6 classes of the  additional counselling (help with home work)

4.2 15 students and/or BC Zvecan trainees entered the Advanced Business English 3  cycles x 1 module 27 two-lesson /2x45min/ intensive English training); and 13 (2x45min) preparation for classes, 4 classes of examination preparation and evaluation, 6 classes of the  additional counselling (help with home work)

5.1 24 students and/or BC Zvecan trainees entered the Basic IT 3 cycles  x 1 module (26 two-lesson /2x45min/ basic IT training); 13 (2x45min) preparation for classes and  1 classes of examination preparation and evaluation.

5.2 24 students and/or BC Zvecan trainees entered Business IT 3 cycles x 1 module (26 two-lesson /2x45min/ Business IT training); 13 (2x45min) preparation for classes and  1 classes of examination preparation and evaluation.

6.1 Study visit to Maastricht School of Management or Nijenrode University organised for 3 University staff (one professor of Economics, Law and Technical sciences, they will be engage in study visit and writing of curriculum) and 1 CTD staff.  Group of 3 professors (Economics, Law and Technical sciences) responsible to develop module &#x201C;Development of Entrepreneurial Competences&#x201D; will be engaged in curriculum writing for the period of 6 months each. Those Professors are: Associated Professor Jelena Djokic (Faculty of Technical Sciences and IBCM; Assistant Professor Jelena Delovic (Faculty of Law); Professor for Entrepreneurship  negotiation in progress). Group of 3 teachers/trainers will be responsible to adapt English, IT and Business plan writing modules conducted during 2011. in the period of 2 months each. Curriculum revised by 1 MSM/UNS expert (in the period of 3 days). New course called Comprehensive Entrepreneurship Course consisting on revised module &#x201C;Development of Entrepreneurial Competences&#x201D;, Business English, Business IT and Business plan writing modules will start in January  2013 .

7.1 50 UM students will be trained by BCZ through Entrepreneurial training program;
          40 students  will successfully pass the training and receive certificates; 30 BP
          applications will be submitted out of which Jury approved 20; Bank approved 10.

Project outcomes:
These outputs will lead to:

Engagement of all stakeholders. Delivering the planned outputs in 12 months. 1 CTD staff member trained by MDF and Triodos Facet in 2012. 2 client/student satisfaction surveys conducted  10% improvement in second comparing to the first.
2 BP Competitions held
 5 new enterprises established / existing grow; 10 new jobs created
40 trainees successfully passed A2/B1 CEFR level exam until the 31st September 2012 which will lead to increased employability of trainees
	- 4 students employed owing to newly acquired knowledge
30 trainees successfully passed IT exams the 31st September 2012 which will lead to increased employability of trainees
	- 3 students employed owing to newly acquired knowledge
Curriculum developed, new module Comprehensive Entrepreneurship Course developed, ready to be introduced since January 2013.
7 new businesses started/ grow; 14 new jobs created.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Students, graduates, employed and unemployed people, entrepreneurs, minorities, IDPs...</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University Mitrovica (International Relations Office)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleksandar Jovanovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University Mitrovica (International Relations Office)
Filipa Visnjica
38220  MITROVICA
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">67645</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
