<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-PSF2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Initiative for competitiveness of Enterprises (PSICE) project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although much of the interventions have been directed to capacity building initiatives, there is a need to strengthen the ongoing efforts in building the competiveness of enterprises in Rwanda. The following reasons justify why PSF needs SPARK support in financing the project;

Increase of the target group: Businesses have increased by 90% in the past five years. The business census of 2011, enumerated 123,256 businesses compared to the PSFs business operators census in the year 2008 which enumerated a total of 72,994 (Source: establishment census: August 2011).

RPSF restructuring: With the new orientation of RPSF, there is a need to emphasis on decentralisation of services through associations and regional representation (districts). Each business operator will feel represented by PSF and be proud of the organization. (Source: RPSF Strategic Operating Plan 2012/2013  2015/2016)

Building Competitiveness for the special business groups: The final report carried out on targeted needs assessment for women and youth entrepreneurs (2009), revealed that this special groups are facing challenges and difficulties that influence on the performance of these businesses. These issues are mainly: access to finance, market access, poor infrastructure, skills gaps, bureaucracy and taxation

Regional Competitiveness of local enterprises: Rwanda needs to be competitive in the regional market. Due to shortage of skills labour, Rwanda has lagged behind comparably to the EAC region members, especially in tourism, construction, general services. For Rwanda to be competitive, there is a need to fill the gap of this skills by supporting local entrepreneurs accessing regional market , regional networking and more importantly access to cheaper raw materials  (Source: Assessment of Non Tariff Barriers(NTBs) along the Northern and central corridors-EAC, PSF-  2008).

Given the aforementioned background highlighted earlier, the RPSF and its members have decided to embark on a project that has the following main pillars:

PSF Regional Structures strengthening to realize the full potential of the federation at the grass root is critical. The federation lacks in human resources both in numbers and quality but also needs to modernize its equipment and facilities to deliver on their mandate as the single united voice of the private sector in public private sector dialogue right from the sector level, district and provincial level.
Enhancing the effectiveness and efficiency in Service delivery by reducing the burden from the PSF Umbrella organization which is distanced from the point where needs are felt and services delivered. For example writing business plans to access finance, training, Arbitration of local business issues etc
Foster capacity&amp; entrepreneurship promotion through empowering the SMEs at the grass root in increasing their competitiveness and access to markets both regionally and internationally.
Regional integration by creating awareness on business opportunities in East Africa community and part-taking in creation of rules and regulations favourable to business environment.

This project is well timed considering that all policy makers as well as the development partners are focused on private sector development with the private sector seen as the real engine of economic growth.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outputs	Indicator	Targets

PSF membership collectors trained 	# trained membership collectors	60

Membership collecting strategies developed	# developed strategic plans for  revenue collection	4 (one for each zone/province)

BDS coaches trained in coaching and mentoring techniques	# trained coaches	30
PSF staff completed successively the accreditation program	# of graduated staff	6
Entrepreneurs from existing SME from previous BPC coached	# of coached entrepreneurs	83</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main beneficiaries of this project are the private sector actors and the economy of Rwanda in general, and MSMEs benefiting from RPSF services. The public sector also benefits from the project through an enhanced public-private sector interface.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier ref="PSF2014" type="A9">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Federation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-22" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-22" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Federation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Roger Munyapenda</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>rogerm@psf.org.rw</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Federation
PO BOX 319
KIGALI
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">59943</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.psf.org.rw">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
