<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-Pyalara2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MANARAT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1 Empowered and well-trained Pyalaras staff, young Palestinians, representatives of political parties and students unions.

1Number of training of trainers workshops conducted-10 training workshops conducted.	

2Number of participants awarded completion certificates26 young Palestinian participants awarded completion certificates. 	

3 Number of networks of young leaders initiated or supported 2 networks formed	

4Number of training manuals developed  One training manual on leadership and debating developed. 	


2.1.1. Young Palestinians are more  acknowledged and aware of the importance of their role in the decision making process. 	

1Number of exchange visits between young Palestinians and decision makers. 16 exchange visits between young Palestinians and decision makers tool place. 	

2 Number of youth in the network 60 young Palestinians are involved in the network. 

3Number of beneficiaries reached through networks. 1000 young Palestinians both males and females

4Number of participation development participants awarded completion certificates50 young Palestinians. 	

5Number of media outlets produced as part of the project.3TYT issues will be produced.
4 TV episodes will be prepared and broadcasted. 	

6Number of young Palestinians reached by media productions and other projects activitiesAround half a million young Palestinians. 

7 Number of reports on the two advocated for themes prepared by PYALARA,2 reports prepared

8Number of young Palestinians reached through the different interventions related to socio-economic initiatives and interventions. 500 young Palestinians  both males and females reached through the different interventions


3.1.1. Decision makers and political parties more aware of the socio-economic position of young Palestinians.	
1. Number of events held (like round tables etc) 8 events took place.	

2.Number of guidance and coaching trajectories implemented. 10 guidance and coaching trajectories implemented.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Partner shares the vision of the Programme: the consortium partners are united in the overall objective of the Programme: to reduce instability in three fragile state environments through strengthening the institutional capacity of relevant political and civil society stakeholders to improve the social-economic position of young men and women. The Programme makes the strategic choice to focus on the socio-economic position of young women and men[[1] Young men and women refers to the age group of 18-35 years old1], and aims to create an enabling environment for youth entrepreneurship and youth participation in the public sector and in civil society. The Youth Engagement Programmeme and its partners work towards this objective efficiently and effectively;


Enhancing PYALARAs capacity to advance its socio-economic interventions along with 
 enhancing capacity of duty bearers including representatives of political parties and other interest groups to advocate for the advancement of socio economic position of young Palestinian..


Enhancing young Palestinian representation in the decision making bodies through leadership training.  


Influencing political agendas of political parties through multi stakeholders dialogue. 

. Improved PYALARAs,  young Palestinians and stakeholders capacities to advance young Palestinians socio-economic position

Enhanced young Palestinians  representation in the decision making process.

Stake-holders and political parties pay more attention to young Palestinians and their socio-economic position.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is considered a milestone in the road leading to empowering young Palestinians to become advocates and agents of change vis-&#xE0;-vis socio-economic and political rights, Therefore in order to achieve its objective the project targets key persons and decision makers in the government, political parties, university professors, the private sector, trade-unions and other stakeholders like the World Labor Organizations representation in Palestinians
In addition to the specific number of direct beneficiaries listed below, the multi-sector approach which further involves media and journalist, ring more allies on board 
The list of direct beneficiaries include 
26 young  Palestinians( 16 new you Palestinians and 10 young Palestinians who are already part of Manarat Project) between the ages 18-25 who are involved in debates with Palestinians officials and decision makers  the total of 8 debates will be carried out 2 in southern WBH, another in northern WB ,2 in central West Bank and 2 in the Jordan valley 
500 people involved in the 4 community projects with a project in southern WB, another in northen WB a third in central West bank and 4th in the Jordan valley 
Representatives of at least 5 private businesses 
20 representatives of political parties and student unions 
10 representatives of youth department inside a number of governance bodies including municipalities , local authorities ,etc</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier ref="Pyalara2014" type="A9">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Palestinian Youth Association for Leadership and Rights Activation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Palestinian Youth Association for Leadership and Rights Activation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hania Bitar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Palestinian Youth Association for Leadership and Rights Activation
P.O. Box
RAMALLAH
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">72096</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.pyalara.org/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
