<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFS II BWF 2011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building of BWF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BWF wants to be able to provide tailor made capacity building to women entrepreneurs to start or grow their business. These services will consist of implementing business plan competition training upon their needs, consultation and coaching, and to build a pipe line of beneficiaries In order to continue to solidify its leadership in the community, its membership, and build momentum for its future services and advocacy work BWF will conduct a total of six one-day workshops. The workshops target women entrepreneurs to start or growing businesses, aiming to reach 180 women in 3 communities (Hebron Bethlehem and Nablus).
In conducting awareness workshops, the BWF will start by introducing the opportunities of entrepreneurship for women and the main services BWF can provide, including the business plan competition. The targeted audience in will be encourage to submit requests simple application forms. In Addition, in these introductory workshops, BWF will promote for the Business plan competition.
Raising awareness about the role of a woman as breadwinners, businesswomen and leaders outside their homes.will help increase BWFs members by a minimum of new 5 women run business, in order to strengthen BWFs basis, which will give it a stronger voice to be heard and eventually have some influence over policy makers and decision makers.
Build and expand the current national and international network of BWF and its members in the MENA region to increase access to new markets in other regions for their products and services and introduce them to potential investors. BWF had this experience through introducing some of the Business Development Center beneficiaries products to investors through participation in local exhibitions (Ramallah, Bethlehem, Jerusalem) and International exhibitions like Arab Emirates. In addition, BWF displays samples of the beneficiaries products while it participates in any training conducted to BWF executive director internationally.
BWF annual conference in June 30 invites Corporate Ambassadors to share their expertise, provide space for B2B and conduct field visits were these ambassadors can meet local entrepreneurs. In addition, 4 panels focusing on specific themes will provide BWF with valuable recommendations. This years panels will allow local entrepreneurs to engage with experts on topics like strategies to grow business, mentorship and advocacy role. These recommendations will be integrated in the plans for 2012.

2. Strengthen women entrepreneurs capacity to build and grow their own businesses.
Training of a minimum 90 women in how to develop their Business Plan in 3 areas.
Income earning opportunities for 15 selected women entrepreneurs are increased.
15 entrepreneurs will develop their business plan and 1 winner will have the seed money based on a selection criteria.
15 SMEs will be assisted to start and grow.
15 will receive mentorship and coaching program where mentors will pass the experience to young SMEs and creative entrepreneurs which will equip them with the needed skills needed by the market to compete.
Each new SMEs creates at least one new job

3. Lobby and Advocacy
Awareness about Gender equality issues for at least 200 women. This activity will be conducted through the conference in a specialized session entitled Advocating for Entrepreneurship, and success strategies to grow your business, the indicator will be through a short customized questionnaire, this questionnaire will test in specific preset indicators in the contest of lobbying and advocacy.
Having an advocacy strategy to improve womens role in running business.
BWF will increase the capacity of one staff to provide services in advocacy.

4. Strengthen BWFs internal capacity
BWF will have increased the capacity to provide services in mentoring, evaluation and coaching.
In 2011 BWF staff will be trained on Business plan development, marketing, facilitate B2B consultation.
2 BWF staff trained in project management, planning and monitoring.
Develop operational manual to standardize operations and services and collect existing institutional memory. BWF is the first organization to work on this field, and its essential to build the manual of procedures especially for the technical services done by the BDC.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific Objectives:

To outreach to business women and potential women entrepreneurs by raising awareness and do networking. The outcome of this project will help increase BWFs members by reaching out to new members and networking through them. The more the members, the stronger the representations which will give BWF a stronger voice to be heard and eventually have some influence over policy makers and decision makers.
To strengthen Palestinian businesswomen and women entrepreneurs capacity to build and grow their own businesses.
To advocate for an improved position of business women in the national economy.
Strengthening BWF Internal Capacity to to be able to provide quality services in partnership building, outreach tools, and advocacy techniques</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main target groups of this project are going to be women entrepreneurs who started small Business, and transitioning to a formal business. In Addition, business women who have newly joined BWF mainly in South and North (Bethlehem Hebron and Nablus). Since we want to pay more attention to the needs of groups lay in less fortunate areas.
For the Business Plan Competition: Female graduates, from low income families, from all West Bank, mainly South, will be targeted, and have the desire to start their own small businesses due to the lack of job opportunities and the increased rate of unemployment and have creative ideas.
On the other hand, BWF will target entrepreneurs targeted from the general workshops and trainings from different areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-18" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-18" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-02-29" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Woman Forum</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doa Wadi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>info@bwf.ps</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Woman Forum
Al Fare Building, 2nd floor, Al Balou
RAMALLAH
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-07-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-02-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">85740</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.bwf.ps">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
