<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFSII.RWA.PSF 2012/2013</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Private Sector development (EPSD)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Existing BPC winners, BDS staff and Members</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project objective(s) 

To strengthen  Private Sector Federations organizational capacity 
To provide technical support  to SMEs and tourism chamber 
To enhance the public private interface for effective advocacy and lobby

This project is a continuation and complementary of existing project entitled &#x201C;Business Plan Competition-BPC&#x201D; proposed and presented by Rwanda Private Sector Federation to SPARK for funding. The project seeks to implement its efforts to harness knowledge building to existing business plan winners. It will seek to address issues related to businesses management by stepping up the training and business coaching activities for business plan competition winners. The project will further aim at contributing to economic growth, job creation and poverty reduction. 
The SMEs will be provided with technical assistance to better implement their business in sustainable manner. Chamber members and PSF representative will also benefit from this project. There are various activities planned for this project that are all in line with the core programme areas of the organization. The project describes the proposed and planned approach of both technical and financial aid for implementation. 

It is expected that within 12 months, the project should have benefited SMEs of BPC winners, Chamber members as well as PSF representatives in all five provinces in the county. This will be through; business health checks, different type of trainings and coaching, All these technical assistances will be delivered through a training of PSF existing Business Development Services staff who will then be required to assist the SMEs in their region.

As the core mandate of Private Sector Federation, PSF and other stakeholders will strive to lobby and advocate for favourable business environment especially for the youth in rural areas. 

Throughout the 12 months period, certain benchmarks will be verifiable as true indicators of the benefits that the project is aimed to realize for the target group.

The project thus lays out a clear strategy for implementation of this approach that will be closely monitored, reported and replicated for the purpose of continuity and sustainability of the whole programme.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outputs


Output 1: Private Sector Federations capacity is strengthened 

Output 2: Business performance of SMEs that received PSFs services improved. Overall performance of members of Tourism Chamber improved 

Output 3: Strengthened Private Public Partnership for effective advocacy and lobbying



Targets 

Output 1: Private Sector Federations capacity is strengthened
At least 20 leaders (2 per chamber) speak fluently English language and trained in leadership skills
60 BDS consultants acquired business development skills and proficiency in ICT utilization 
An efficient monitoring and evaluation system is operational with PSF

Output 2: Business performance of SMEs that received PSFs services improved. Overall 	                 performance of members of Tourism Chamber improved
108 SMEs acquired necessary  skills on basic management to successfully implement 
and sustain their businesses 
At least  8% of the total members of tourism chamber trained in customer care and services delivery 

Output 3: Strengthened Private Public Partnership
5 consultative meetings  held at provincial level with 20 participants - representatives of various stakeholders
At least 3 official proposals on improvement of business environment and reduction of barriers for business growth submitted to policy makers</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2013Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Federation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Roger Munyapenda</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>rogerm@psf.org.rw</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Federation 
PO BOX 319
KIGALI
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">70000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.psf.org.rw">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
