<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-UP2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">, Promoting Entrepreneurship through Capacity Building and Coaching (PECBC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Current students: 
With a student population of over 4.000 spread across five faculties, UP is one of the fastest growing Higher Learning Institutions in Rwanda. The demographic background of the students is that a majority of them come from low income earning families that can hardly cater for their needs at campus. The students have very limited job opportunities while at campus. Besides, five of the faculties are non business, offering non entrepreneurial, non commercial and non business subjects. The starting of this project was therefore a blessing to fill the missing gap among students.  

Alumni
 UP has to-date graduated over 600, whilst the economy of Rwanda is growing, the growth is not fast enough to match the population growth. There are limited job opportunities available to the graduates of tertiary institutions, though they are equipped with both practical and theory capabilities to handle several jobs. UP- Spark project retrains the students with practical entrepreneurship skills to enable students to start their own businesses. The revolving fund has proven vital to assist as startup capital to students especially in times when they lack mortgage to get loans from financial institutions. 
Youths
Currently, Youths count for more than 145,000 of the population in Nyagatare District.  They are also among the vulnerable groups, especially the school dropouts and most of them are jobless and a few are employed as casual laborers. This group lacks basic entrepreneurial skills to enable them start meaningful businesses and cannot access loans due to the fact that they lack mortgage. UP- Spark project will undoubtedly bridge this gap.    
Indirect beneficiaries: 
Residents of Nyagatare District
With a population of over 265.000 among which more than 145,00 are youth in Nyagatare District is one of the fastest</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Outputs: 

15 staff from UR-Nyagatare Campus trained in coaching techniques    
2 UP staff completed successively the accreditation program 
At least 150 Applicants from UP students, alumni and local community applied for the business idea competition
120 applicants trained on entrepreneurship and generating and presenting a business idea 
Of 120, 30 high potential entrepreneurs selected for comprehensive 6-week training on business ideas
At least 20 high quality business ideas received of which at least 10 should be bankable to receive coaching. 
30 pre-entrepreneurs taken through a business venture model (learning by doing)
1 documentary developed 
1 Business Incubation Center developed
1 Business show room jointly with Nyagatare PSF set  
18 entrepreneurs from previous business plan competitions will be sported to develop and improve their businesses. 
25 businesses/ cooperatives from the local community will receive training in business growth and sported to grow their businesses. 

Project outcomes: 

By 2014, At least 10 staff from UR-Nyagatare Campus will equipped with coaching skills 
By 2014, 2 staff will be accredited as business advisors by Rwanda Development Board (RDB)
By 2014, 4 enterprise development related services will introduced within UP Incubation Center
By 2014, 15 new SMEs will be started
By 2014, 43 existing SMEs will be grow at least by 20% (of their current income)
By 2014, 58 direct and indirect jobs will be created in started and grown SMEs
By 2014, entrepreneurship culture will be promoted among UR Nyagatare students and the local</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Umutara Polytechnic (UP) is a tertiary learning institution established by the Rwandan Eastern Province community in 2006 to address its developmental problems and avail learning facilities for thousands of post-secondary school young people in the region and the country at large. It offers training at degree level in agriculture, veterinary medicine, engineering, ICT, and business studies in addition to offering advisory services to the community of Eastern Province.

UP however faces several capacity problems. There is very few (less than 5%) local academic staff members qualified to teach at degree level in the sciences field. This poses a serious risk to sustainability of the Polytechnics programs including a heavy financial burden owing to relatively high expatriate staff salaries. There is therefore an urgent need to address this situation by availing more training opportunities to local staff for postgraduate training coupled with coaching by senior expatriate staff.

Few job opportunities are available to the graduates of tertiary institutions. Whilst the economy of Rwanda is growing, the growth is not fast enough to match the population growth rate. Taking cues from this scenario, Umutara Polytechnic introduced a business management course in the sciences program. However this was not streamlined in the whole curriculum and most of the staff members do not have skills in entrepreneurship necessary to teach, motivate and cultivate an entrepreneurship culture within the institution. UP therefore seeks to review its curriculum with assistance from an expert so as to streamline entrepreneurship as well as build capacity among staff in entrepreneurship training and coaching, strategic planning, performance management, ICT and in lobbying and advocacy.

Start-up capital is difficult to secure for graduates without collateral. Grants are therefore necessary to initiate entrepreneurs. Grants will avail examples of viable business for others to see and hence motivate them to start their own businesses once they see a working example.

Rwanda generally has few professionals in many scientific disciplines and it will be difficult for people venturing into value addition projects in these fields to obtain quality advice. A coaching and nurturing program using oversees volunteers and senior staff at the polytechnic will be necessary to initiate the entrepreneurs. 

The intervention discussed above will go a long way in alleviating poverty and creating employment if implemented. Otherwise social unrests like those of Egypt and Tunisia may result if young people have no economic activity to do. The quality of life is also threatened as a population increased much faster than the economic growth rate.


We undertake the above problems with aim of developing our beneficiaries to meet their needs   and sustainable development of the individuals and UP as a whole. 
Contribute  to the Government priority objective as articulated in VISION 2020 for  poverty eradication ion and employment creation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Rwanda, Nyagatare Campus</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Gashumba-GASHUMBA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>James.gashumba@gmail.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Rwanda, Nyagatare Campus 
Nyagatare 57
Nyagatare Campu  NYAGATARE
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">64712</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.umutarapolytechnic.ac.rw">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
