<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFS II UMUTARA 2011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Entrepreneurship through capacity building and coaching</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff development results:

60 staff members acquire strategic planning skills necessary to participate in the strategic planning process by end of 1st quarter (Q) of year (yr) 1
Staff share same vision and are knowledgeable about UPs core business, customers and internal and external environment by 2nd Q of yr 1.
60 staff members acquire skills in Business management and entrepreneurship (20 by end of Q3 of yr 1; 80 by end of Q3 yr 2; Communication (20 by end of Q3 yr 2 and the rest by end of Q1 yr 3); ICT (20 by end of Q1 yr 2 and the rest by end of Q4 yr 2) and lobbying and advocacy (20 by end of Q1 year 2 &amp; the rest by end of Q1 year 2) necessary for them to train and coach entrepreneurs, use ICT effectively, improve organizational communication and lobby and advocate for entrepreneurship.
20 staff members acquire skills to participate in a performance management scheme and to evaluate performance of their subordinates using the reviewed UPs performance management system and 20 staff members improved communications skills by the end of year 1.
4 young Rwandese academic staff members acquire postgraduate skills in entrepreneurship (1), agrigulture, (1) engineering, (1) veterinary medicine and necessary for them to effectively teach undergraduates by end of year 3 (for 2 members) and by end of year 4 (2 members)

Curriculum and Support Results:

At least 10% of UP curriculum directly supports entrepreneurship by end of year 1 and is implemented by Q1 of year 2.
A 10% yearly improvement in entrepreneurship and business course grades is realized starting from year 2.

Entrepreneurship Promotion Results:

At least 50% of students who go through the pre-incubation centre start businesses that survive the first 3 years.
At least 30% UP students and graduates participate in business ideas competitions in year one and thereafter participation increases by 10% each year.
Entrepreneurs acquire necessary skills to develop bankable business plans, and technical skills to successfully implements their projects.

Generation of information on entrepreneurship and networking Results:

Barriers to business development, opportunities, and sources of funding and policy constraints are established by end of year 2.
Stakeholders are made aware of constraining policies to business development by end of year 2.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to contribute to economic growth, job creation and poverty reduction. Final year students in agriculture, engineering and veterinary medicine will be encouraged to participate in entrepreneurship competitions whereby they will develop business plans with assistance from Umutara Polytechnic (UP) staff and other project stakeholders. Plans will then be reviewed by a panel of experts. Students with promising plans will implement their plans under a nurturing program managed by UP with funds for implementation coming from the SPARK and the BID network.

The project will cultivate a culture of entrepreneurship across UPs programs. The students entrepreneurship club will be strengthened while UP staff members will be empowered through training in entrepreneurship and coaching, strategic management, performance management, ICT, communication and advocacy and lobbying. A comprehensive plan will be produced for the Polytechnic. UPs curriculum will be reviewed to streamline entrepreneurship training. UP and other stakeholders will also lobby and advocate for favourable policies for graduates to start businesses. All the trainings will be delivered through a training of trainers approach which will empower some staff members to train others. For sustainability, the programs will be incorporated into the UP learning programs for all new staff.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UP final year students, graduates and staff.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-04-05" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-04-05" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UMUTARA Polytechnic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philip Brierly</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>philip@brierley.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UMUTARA Polytechnic
PO BOX 57
NYAGATARE
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-04-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">70000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.mutarapoly.ac.rw">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
