<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFS2 GEM 2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GEM</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enabling environment for SME and Entrepreneurship whit aim for faster economic growth and thereby contributes to poverty alleviation, thought removal business barriers

Global Entrepreneurship Monitor (GEM) survey attempt to create an international benchmark for the monitoring of enterprise culture focused on the business startup process. The GEM Survey is conducted in over fifty countries and is based on a combination of national opinion poll surveys and expert opinions. Indeed GEM survey, recognizes that culture is a pattern of beliefs, norms and values that are widely shared throughout society. Inan overview of entrepreneurship, the OECD (1999) describes culture as a key pillar of the entrepreneurial economy alongside the macro economy and regulatory environment, with education playing an important role.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output(s)	

Kosovo becomes full member of GEM	
GEM Staff Training	
Adult Population Survey Completed across Kosovo	
National Expert Surveyed 	
National Conference for Promotion of GEM Report /Dissemination of Report	
Design and Printing of Kosovo GEM Report</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target group
The main target group aiming to remove business barriers are Public Institutions and Business Association.

In terms of Public Institutions, the main responsible body for addressing barriers to business with specific emphasizes to start up barriers are Ministry of Trade and Industry (Kosovo Investment and Promotion Support Agency) and local municipalities (Departments for Economic Developments) Other relevant public institution consist of Ministry of Labor and Social Welfare, Ministry of Culture Youth and Sports.
Business Associations, mainly Kosovo Chamber of Commerce, Business Alliance of Kosovo, American Chamber of Commerce. Through this association we will have a larger impact in the lobbying in the Government of Kosovo in the context of business barriers removed.
Additional relevant institution/bodies
Business Service Providers such as Kosovo Business Support Center, Innovation Center Kosovo, Center for Entrepreneurship and Business Development, Encouraging Young Entrepreneurs, etc.
Donor community involved in the financing and supporting of Entrepreneurship development in Kosovo
Universities, Research Institutes, PhD students, MA students
Entrepreneurs</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universum College</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alejtin Berisha-Berisha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>alejtin@universum-ks.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universum College
P.O. Box
PRISTINA
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="410"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.universum-ks.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
