<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-RTUC2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RTUC Entrepreneurship Centre</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Limited technical and business skills
Many SMEs suffer from lack of technical and business skills. SMEs themselves identify a variety of skills gaps in areas including ICT, technical and industrial knowledge, finance, accounting and management. Many SMEs have rudimentary production facilities, low quality products and underutilize appropriate technologies. There is also limited innovation and competitiveness in the SME sector caused by a lack of technical and managerial skill.

Limited Business Development Services (BDS)
SMEs face a lack of good quality business development services tailored to their needs. PSF&apos;s efforts thus far have been forced to scale back due to resource and capacity constraints, meaning many businesses have not received the skills they need to succeed. Studies indicate that while many institutions exist to provide BDS services, the quality of these services varies greatly, making SMEs wary of taking advantage of them. Furthermore, the previous lack of private sector involvement means that the private sector does not need to commit to these services and interventions may be inappropriate to the needs of SMEs.

Lack of access to finance
SMEs lack access to financial services. As evidenced by the OTF/PSF survey, financial institutions perceive SMEs as high risk and are therefore inflexible in terms of collateral and repayment terms. This is compounded by the fact that most small borrowers lack experience and understanding of financial organizations and do not have the necessary technical skills to make successful applications.
In addition, most financial products from commercial banks are not suitable to the agricultural sector, where most SMEs currently operate, and existing regulations limit the total funds available for lending.

Difficulty accessing market information and markets
SMEs face difficulties accessing and utilizing information regarding local, regional and international pricing, a major constraint to business planning as well as about the regulatory environment in Rwanda and regionally. Among SMEs there is poor participation in the policymaking process, meaning they have little knowledge of interventions designed to assist them. SMEs have inadequate access to market information that could benefit their businesses as well as inadequate knowledge about marketing their products both nationally and internationally.

To address these challenges, RTUC through REC project, seeks to reinforce an entrepreneurship and business development module in all the courses provided including sciences program. This will significantly address the issue of skills scarcity and create awareness among young students towards business set up. Another area of intervention will consist of providing mentorship and on job technical capacity building of REC beneficiaries combining the BPC participants for the year 1 and new group that will join this second year.

This project will be carried out with the main purpose of bringing the people with bright ideas and entrepreneurial spirit on board to fulfill the national vision of turning Rwanda in to an Entrepreneurial and Innovative Economy. It subscribes to the idea that the &#x201C;entrepreneurship development&#x201D; is a key to the growth of the economy.  RTUC Entrepreneurship Centre (REC) will continue to provide Entrepreneurship education, training and advisory services to the prospective and established entrepreneurs are the major components of this project.  This project also addresses the capacity building needs of the associated academic staff and the related business incubation.

The total budget is 96,299 Euros and the partner contribution is 27,119 Euros



The project will be managed with 5 members:
The Patron: RTUC Rector to pull the REC vision and support the team members to achieve this.
The deputy patron: In charge of daily management of the REC, the monitoring, control and evaluation of all activities related, and take a lead of inception activities, collaboration with management, staff and students, partners and regular reporting to the management of the daily management of the REC.
Champion Management: Champion for daily management of inception activities, will be responsible to make sure that all planned inception activities are conducted timely, with good quality, cost effectively and in an efficient manner.
Champion Entrepreneurship: Champion for entrepreneurship curriculum development and mainstreaming, he will be focusing on content and quality of dissemination of the module and mainstreaming activities within the University.
Champion Partnerships :  for partnerships management, documentation and communication and public relations</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Outputs:

15 RTUC Staff trained in proposal writing and fundraising
2 RTUC staff completed successively the accreditation program
2 Staff undertook the tour visit
30 best business plans (20 from last year BPC and 10 from this year BPC) selected, awarded and linked to potential partners for needed services (information, technical advisory, finance etc)
210 entrepreneurs trained/awarded certificates
600 entrepreneurship magazines designed and disseminate.
1 Network session for key players in SME development and high institution learning is organized

Project outcomes:

By 2014, 2 project proposal will be developed, by RTUC staff, and funded
By 2014, 2 staff will be accredited as coaches by Rwanda Development Board (RDB)
By 2014, 4 new learnt enterprise development related services will be introduced within RTUC Incubation Center
By 2014, 20 new SMEs will be started
By 2014, 50 existing SMEs will be grow at least by 20% (of their current income)
By 2014, 130 jobs (50 direct jobs and 80 indirect jobs) will be created in started and grown SMEs
By 2014, entrepreneurship is promoted among high institution learning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RTUC students and alumni will be the direct project direct beneficiaries where will be provided with entrepreneurship education, training, guidance and counseling on how generate business idea, how to write a winning business plan and then facilitated to started their own enterprises through career guidance and linking them with micro finance institutions. Moreover, some of them will be taken through a business venture learning by doing approach).

The project also targets the RTUC staff whereby some of them will be supported to improve their organizational and managerial skills through trainings and tour visit.

Last but not least, the local community surrounding RTUC, those involved in hospitality services especially youth and female will be supported to develop business plan and assisted to access business skills and information from the REC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier ref="RTUC2014" type="A9">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda Tourism University College</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda Tourism University College</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mbarushimana Nelson-Nelson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>marketing@rtuc.ac.rw</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda Tourism University College
Kigali City, Kicukiro district, Niboye sect 350
KIGALI
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">69180</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.rtuc.ac.rw">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
