<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-CTD2015 MFS 2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFS II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Kosovo do not show any sign of sustainable economic rise for more than decade despite the (considering the state of regional economy and current circumstances) excessive financial help delivered: therefore, Northern Kosovo remains totally dependent on financial remittances coming outside the region while the capacities for the economic development remain minimal.
The lack of private initiative is considerable: most of the young expect to &#x201C;be provided&#x201D; job in public (state) companies, which are, however mostly at the brink of collapse and exist only due to financial help coming from the region, or in public administration. Both public administration and public companies have low employment capacities. With the process of economic transition the number of companies that could afford to offer kind of well-paid jobs with minimal work decreased abruptly. The salaries remain the dominant interest of employees, while the opportunities, careers development and working conditions are out of their focus.
Furthermore, the fact that must be taken into the consideration is that the current job-creation and employment capacities in the region rely more on kinships and nepotism, personal connections, monopolistic behavior etc..Than on quality and capabilities. Business education by itself is far from being enough to overcome these issues.
Our intention is to stimulate the examples of good practice based on fine ideas and plans of operation, quality and capability and cooperation rather than dubious business and management. Our aims consider stimulating creativity among the future entrepreneurs, so they could move on with the new ideas/businesses/companies/services that are lacking in the region. 
CTD plans to start business incubation center in Mitrovica at the beginning of 2014. Along with that we plan to help and stimulate young entrepreneurs by mentoring process done by our professors and experts. The process can be managed centrally by CTD who could provide expert help and with donors.
The entrepreneurship curriculum, already developed, structured and piloted within MFS2 Program is going to be adopted by two more faculties during the 2014. In 2013, 4 UM faculties accepted curriculum (Faculty of Medicine, Faculty of Law, Faculty of Technical Science and Faculty of Agriculture).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reaching awareness about entrepreneurship on University and high school students&#xA0;	% of all UM students involved in the project activities till end of 2014&#xA0;	12%	
2.1-2.2    Business English Courses I &amp; II (basic, advanced- 5 cycles) organized in&#xA0;Mitrovica&#xA0;	# of beneficiaries attended trainings
# of beneficiaries certified&#xA0;	75, 60/30 women	

2.3   Norwegian language course (2 cycles)	# of beneficiaries attended trainings
# of beneficiaries certified&#xA0;	20,16/8 women	

2.4 Business IT Courses organized (1 cycles per semester)&#xA0;in Mitrovica and Zubin Potok  	# of beneficiaries attended trainings
# of beneficiaries certified&#xA0;	24,16/ 8 women	

2.5   Business Skills Trainings organized&#xA0;
# of beneficiaries attended trainings
# of beneficiaries certified&#xA0;	40,32/16 women	

2.6   Students took part into Business Plan Writing training	# of beneficiaries took part in this training
# of Business Plans submitted
# of business plans approved by jury
#of Business Plans selected for additional mentoring/coaching through consultancy hours	12,8, 6/2 women,5	

2.7   Students took part into 2 cycles of Project Proposal Writing Training 	# of beneficiaries attended training
# of beneficiaries certified
# of projects created
#of projects submitted to donors	16, 12/6 women, 5, 2	

2.8    Creation&#xA0;of short term/seasonal jobs for students supported through small allowances for equipment or material&#xA0;&#xA0;	# of students got an allowances for job creation
# of &#x201C;short-term&#x201D; business further developed
(Business plans/ Projects proposals written)	10, 2	

2.9    Awarding ceremony organized	# of events organized
# of beneficiaries attended events	2, 150	

2.10  Contribute to establishing of network of companies	# of events organized
# of companies presented	1, 20	

2.11    Promo events organized	# of events organized
# of posters distributed
# of fliers distributed
# of students/ stakeholders/ UM faculties management representatives/ donors organizations representatives informed about CTD activities and results 2, 100, 1800, 200</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Students
 High school students
 Teachers (UM academics and high school teachers)
 Youth (graduated students and unemployed under 35)</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CTD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleksandar Jovanovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CTD
P.O. Box
MITROVICA
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">25000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
