<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-Starter Rwanda 2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Starter Rwanda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the study PROMOTING ENTREPRENEURSHIP ON TV AND IN OTHER AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA by EUROPEAN COMMISSION, Stated that, the available evidence clearly suggests that TV is one factor influencing occupational choices, although interests and perceived skills, the family and school  play a more important role. Not surprisingly, the strength and direction of the influence that TV might have is different for different age groups. Around the age of six to eight years children develop gender roles, which also influence their interest in certain occupations they see as typically male of female. TV can play an indirect role in children&apos;s job aspirations in the way it presents or does not present job-related gender stereotypes. Entrepreneurial activities on TV are often undertaken by men, and so young girls could be less attracted to such occupations. An experiment has, however, shown that girls&apos; interest in typically male jobs increased after they had seen women in such jobs on TV.
Over the years there has been a phenomenal growth particularly in the SME market and this has formed the backbone of African economic growth. There are many entrepreneurship education efforts going on in the world but Ebuco eventually Inspires Africa to realized the need of an innovative and more efficient way to teach Business and entrepreneurship with upcoming digital revolution in the niche market of technology
The media has a great advantage of reaching a broad audience. The programmes in these channels can quickly and potentially convey in a direct and vivid way what being an entrepreneur could be like, presenting the local role models in an inspirational and entertaining way especially attracting the young ones to become entrepreneurs.

The proposed project here is called &apos;Starter&apos; is to gather young, dynamic  and African entrepreneurs who are passionate about solving the continent&apos;s challenges and create opportunities for them to realize their visions through the project.  Starter Rwanda follows how an ambitious, fresh generation of  Rwandese entrepreneurs achieve their biggest dream by transforming innovative ideas into succesful businesses.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Output:

One shed&apos;/an incubation is set up
150 candidates will be registered and followed up closely during a full calendar year with coaching and mentoring etc..
Six weeks of filming  5 days a week
TV audience : to be define regarding used tools by local Rwandan TV channels
80 press articles
website /facebook page : 20.000 people
6-10 local successful entrepreneurs will be recruited as mentors and coaches
6 new enterprises will see life throughout the course of the project.
1 Winners receive seed capital however this will not come from SPARK contribution budget

Project Outcomes:

In a period of three years 30 new sustainable jobs will be created.
6 new SMEs will be created in 1 year, this will be with assistance of the Kicukiro Hub which is SPARK Partner by fellowing up with the 5 candidates who will not win the seed capital
Aim to be an enabling force and a part of the positive and gradual transformation through use of media.

The total project budget is 410.130,00 Euros and the partner contribution is 380.130,00 Euros.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SMEs, Unemployed dynamic youth with a drive to become entrepreneurs, women and the general public.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ebuco</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Janssen Patrick-Patrick</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>pjanssen@ebuco.eu</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ebuco
78 avenue Victor Jacobs  1040 Bruxelles (Belgium)
78 avenue Victor Jacobs &#x2013; 1040 Bruxelles (B 78
BRUSSEL
Belgi&#xEB;</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.ebuco.eu">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
