<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-LEAD Enala</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEAD Enala</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Create sustainable youth employment in growth sectors with special attention to young women, through existing and new entrepreneurs:
Indicator (s):
Business and market opportunities identified -2
Business plans and ideas received by young men (60%) - 6
Business plans and ideas by young women (40%) - 4
Incubators and entrepreneurship centres strengthened - 1
New male entrepreneurs trained and coached - 6
New female entrepreneurs trained and coached	- 4

Objective 2: Promote entrepreneurship among young people by integrating entrepreneurship education into secondary and higher (vocational) education
Indicator (s):
Global Entrepreneurship Week events organised - 1
Young men participate in Global Entrepreneurship Week - 200
Young women participate in Global Entrepreneurship Week - 50</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The problem of Libyan youth that there is a high rate of unemployment reached 50% according to The central bank for the Middle East and North Africa research, and those who are employed, the majority of which are employed by the public sector around 80% according to Ministry of Labour . The is little support from the government to invest in the private sector, while youth are discouraged to turn to this sector as a source of employment or job creation because of little development or encouragement.  As a result, the majority of youth who are unemployed often end up being recruited into militia and armed groups as a source of income generation. These groups are prone to radicalization and migration to seek better opportunities and quality of life. While those entrepreneurs who have businesses are not being supported and often find themselves lost or at despair for support in developing and growing.

Libya has a high potential of job growth in sectors such as Renewable energy, services related to the oil industry, fisheries. In addition to this, it has been identified by experts in the field, that other sectors such as construction; banking; I.T and catering are also emerging sectors with potential of job creation.

With the support from SPARK,  ENALA aims to increase &amp; strengthen the role of the private sector for SMEs and also link youth to the private sector through a number of activities. The objective is to support and coach existing businesses in the value chain and raise awareness and inspire entrepreneurs to become business owners.

In this context, we can identify multiple opportunities that could lead to profitable and suitable projects for future and existing entrepreneurs. The main impact would be to reduce: the unemployment rate and create jobs,  and boost  entrepreneurial intention in Tripoli and the surrounding regions</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target group is young people aged 15  35, with strong emphasis on category age 15  24 years old, and women account for minimum 40% of all beneficiaries. The project will target young men prone to irregular economic migration, and young women that will increase family income and help reduce migration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enala</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diaa Abdelhafid Naas-Abdelhafid Naas</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enala
Dhahra, Tripoli
TRIPOLI
Libi&#xEB;</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Libya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">96806</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
