<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-DGSolution 2015 LEDII</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Economic Development LEDII</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minority vulnerable groups, women and youth  in rural areas;
Women and youth from Mitrovica south and north
Existing and potential/start-up SMEs;
Entire  population of targeted region</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mitrovica municipality problem analysis
Municipalities of Mitrovic&#x450;/a North &amp; South are no exclusion to the general economic situation in Kosovo*. Due to such political, social and economic disadvantages, it has very high levels of unemployment, pollution, rural under-development, a small and inexperienced private sector, a young and relatively unskilled population, a severely inadequate infrastructure and a complicated, divided structure of administration. Women in Mitrovic&#x450;/a are particularly disadvantaged in the labour market. The territory where the action will focus are municipalities covering population of 130,000 people, of which 17,000 are Kosovo Serbs (according to OSCE Municipal profiles, September, 2009). In North Mitrovica there are few hundred small businesses which provide goods and services. One of the most industrially developed towns before the war, today even after 14 years is far away from economic position Mitrovica had in Kosovo. As divided city Mitrovica was developed separately and unequal. During this period of 14 years very little attention has been paid on economic development of Mitrovica and north Kosovo in general. Women as a marginalized group were left aside. To try to overcome gender labour inequalities, Kosovo women have attempted to set up their own small enterprises, Unfortunately there are no data of women businesses in North Mitrovica, because no data exists. On the other hand, all of these small businesses operate in the informal economy which makes them invisible on the market.Lack of business skills for production capacity, quality, efficiency and competitiveness, understanding market opportunities establishing strong business links with clients and grow their business,  resulted in generating very limited income per year from women businesses which can hardly cover for the raw materials.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outputs: 

2.1. Promotional campaign on program details launched in four municipalities
2.2. Organized two rounds of business plan preparation workshops per year
2.3. Organized two rounds of Business Plan Competition per year and providing financial support to beneficiaries from 
Spark Loan Guaranty Fund, EU EEVG, USAID AKT and UNDP Grant Scheme
2.4. Organized training on record keeping, basic accounting and finance issues for local youth, potential and existing 
entrepreneurs in four municipalities
2.5. Organized training on marketing for local youth, potential and existing entrepreneurs in four municipalities 
2.6. Organized specialized training on agricultural production improvement for local potential and existing 
entrepreneurs in three municipalities
2.7. Organized specialized training on SME management for local youth, potential and existing entrepreneurs in three 
municipalities
2.8. Organized specialized training on introduction in entrepreneurship for local potential and existing entrepreneurs in 
three municipalities 
2.9. Organized specialized consulting services for most promising business and mentors consulting services for woman

Output indicators: 

2.1. 200 potential beneficiaries from targeted municipalities informed on program details 
2.2. 80 (out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs from seven municipalities certified 
2.3. 55 (out of which 7 woman) business plan approved by jury
       36 (out of which 6 woman) matchmaking accomplished 
2.4. 75 (out of which 20 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form seven municipalities certified
2.5. 75(out of which 20 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form seven municipalities certified
2.6. 75(out of which 20 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form six municipalities certified 
2.7. 75(out of which 20 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs from six municipalities certified 
2.8. 75(out of which 20 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form six municipalities certified
2.9. 22 beneficiaries supported
 	       15 women start-up received consulting and mentoring services</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">62510</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
