<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-BCZ2015 TANK</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tourism potential development of North Kosovo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1. Organized monthly meetings of TANK with topics identified in NKTDS 
# of meetings held - 9
# of topics pointed - 9

2.2. Joint meeting between TANK and TAK 
# of meetings held - 5

2.3. Round tables between Serbian and Albanian business form tourism sector;
# of round tables held - 2

2.4. Multi-ethnic conference for tourism business and association;
# of business participated - 20
# of authorities representatives participated - 5
# of topics for future developing process identified - 5

2.5. Joint tourism fair participation;
# of business participated - 15</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cultural tourism alongside agriculture are seen as main sectors that have potential for economic development and employment generation in the Northern part of Kosovo. 
Fortress Zvecan one of the oldest Balkan fortresses, lake Gazivode in Zubin Potok, monastery and spa Banjska in Zvecan municipality, Spring health centre  Vuca, Roman-Gallic-City, are only some interesting destinations located in the northern part of Kosovo, which are worth seeing. In this region there is a huge potential for traditional tourism programs such as mountain tourism, historic sites, hiking, hunting and fishing activities which can be considered as key potential areas for sustainable local economic development. To support this potential, we are planning to increase economic development and employment in North Kosovo by improving touristic services through the upgrade of municipal infrastructure, by improving skills and perspectives of youth and women, by promoting Nonrth Kosovo as a tourist destination. This will improve living conditions of the population in the areas targeted by the project and will contribute to the reduction of development disparities among Kosovo municipalities and regions. 
This region offers more possibilities for rural tourism development than any other in Kosovo. This fact is based on a territory surface which is covered by forests varying from 400 to 2,000 meters above the sea level. These forests offer possibilities for development of many summer recreational activities, but are also suitable for winter tourism. An example for all is the locality of Belo Brdo, on the southeast side of Kopaonik Mountain. 
Besides many possibilities for development of winter sports, the area is also rich in thermo mineral water springs, which offer many possibilities for the development of rehabilitation and health tourism. Areas which are subject to spatial planning and special protection are Belo Brdo tourist centre, and Vuca Spa spring and Banjska complex. Village tourism is unfortunately not very developed in this area even if there is a great potential for its development, due to its unpolluted environment, its far distance from city centres, appropriate sea-level height, homemade food, natural water, and more. The road network (macadam and asphalt) in the main localities for tourism development already exists, as well as the power supply network, which allow for further development and improvement of tourism. Projects for development of winter, summer and health tourism have been drafted, but so far nothing has been invested.

Illustrative ideas regarding summer tourism that could be discussed in the Regional Tourism Working Group are: Ibar River Rafting with full-equipped boats that could be organised in cooperation with highly experienced kayakers, riding schools, walking and mountain-bike tours, paragliding schools, sports camps, alpinism courses, building of artificial rocks for climbing, Roman Settlements and Monasteries tours etc. 

The challenge of the project (and other initiatives that promote tourism in North Kosovo) is to connect this potential with the local and regional population as well as international population living and working in Kosovo who seek to explore attractions within Kosovo. The project can address certain issues (better offers, better services and better promotion), while other aspects are beyond the reach of the project team.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Members of Touristic association of North Kosovo and existing potential providers of tourist service.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC Zvecan</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Srdjan Zivkovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>dynamic@beotel.net</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC Zvecan
Kosovskih junaka 4
ZVECAN
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">23020</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
