<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-COE2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowering Future  Technology Entrepreneurs &#x2013; Year 4</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Capacity building of your organisation


Management efficiency of partner universities has increased.	The number of partner universities trained on using best practices in management increased.  	6

Improving the administration of services offered to our students.  	Increase of satisfaction of students by services offered at the university administration. 	100 students will evaluate the services as &#x201C;very good&#x201D; or above.



(2) Direct poverty alleviation through SME development by your organisation, and


Reduce unemployment among young people through self employment and opening new job opportunities. 	Increased number of students participating in training.
22


Increased number of SMEs owned by young people. 70%

Increased number of new jobs created by beneficiaries of the program. 22
Increased number of students who got permanent jobs.600









 (3) Advocacy and policy influencing for SME development by your organisation

Local university partners formulating activities that lead to improve the social-economic position of students.	Number of public discussions 4

Number of proposals submitted to government officials in charge of youth
	1

Improved business condition in the society for business development
Number of proposals submitted to ministry of inline indicating barriers and conditions of youth involvement in business	1</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Existing ICT SMEs with potential growth. To reduce business concentration in Ramallah and to disseminate business opportunities, priority will be given to SMEs outside Ramallah, especially North&amp; South of West Bank and Jerusalem.

IT Center of Excellence staff members, university-partners project staff members, project officers and potential project consultants of all participating partners.

Young entrepreneurs, females and males from all over the West Bank whose business ideas related to ICT. We will target University students through the consortium of Centers of Excellence and community professionals.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Large youth unemployment: recent figures report unemployment rates as large as 20%, with the largest demographic of jobless Palestinians in the West Bank being those aged between 20 and 24.   The labor participation rate continues to be low in the West Bank and Gaza.  In the second quarter of 2010, it remained about 37% in Gaza, and in the West Bank, it held generally steady at around 43% (World Bank, Sep. 2010).

Lack of entrepreneurship education: Palestinian institutions of higher education are focused on creating skilled employees and not creative entrepreneurs.  The policy framework for entrepreneurial learning is low (Report on the Euro-Mediteranean Charter for Enterprise, 2008 enterprise policy assessment).
 As a matter of fact, less than 5% of students have taken courses in starting a business as part of  official schooling; less than 10% outside of their formal education.  (Source: Understanding Entrepreneurship in MENA: Where to go next., ICSB Global Entrepreneurship Summit George Washington University April 29, 2010 by Lois Stevenson)

Shortage in specialized engineers and ICT expertise: information technology is the fastest growing sector in the Palestinian economy  with a growing demand for innovative information technology products and services.

An increasing drop of innovation potential as a result of lack of interest in science and engineering-related disciplines.  Education systems produce more graduates in humanities than in science (UNICEF &amp; MENA Development report: The Road not Travelled, Education Reform in the Middle East and Africa, 2008).

Mobility restrictions imposed by Israel:  the fragmentation of the Palestinian territories has eroded the economic viability of many industry sectors in the West Bank and has hindered the development many of the Palestinian markets.
The inability of people without Jerusalem residence permits to enter East Jerusalem makes it hard for firms located in the rest of the West Bank to provide services such as IT support, repairs, or consulting services.  This has greatly affected the service sector since many lucrative clients, especially among international organizations, are located in East Jerusalem (World Bank, 2010).
The impact of the separation barrier on markets is indicated by the fact that 61%  (of 1,115 surveyed Palestinian households) of respondents said that the Barrier has affected their shopping patterns, with the vast majority having shifted from shopping in the suburbs on the other side of the barrier to East Jerusalem (World Bank, 2010).

Brain drain: university graduates are increasingly seeking to leave Palestine in pursuit of high-paying work opportunities as a result of dim career prospects in the West Bank. (Doing business in the Arab World 2010 (IFC))

As a result, there is an urgent need for innovation-fueled economic prosperity and growth and that is why the IT Center of Excellence at Birzeit University utilizes technology entrepreneurship to help solve the economic development puzzle.

Points of strength for the IT Center of Excellence to engage this area of economic development:

Birzeit University strongly believes that sustained economic growth can be catalyzed through innovation and that innovation can be fostered through the education process.  Innovation-based economic growth thus starts with education.

To leverage university-fueled innovation, the IT Center of Excellence was created at the heart of Birzeit University campus. The Center works to bridge the academia/industry gap by capturing and promoting a pipeline of creative ideas emerging from Palestines youth population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center of Excellence, Birzeit University</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khalil Hindi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>president@birzeit.edu</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center of Excellence, Birzeit University
PO BOX 14
BIRZEIT
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">149920</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.birzeit.edu">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
