<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-URN2015 PECBC</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Entrepreneurship through Capacity Building and Coaching (PECBC)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Existing Entrepreneurs 
For the last 3 years University of Rwanda Nyagatare Campus (URN), offered enterprise development services such as trainings, business plan competitions, providing seed capital among others.
Te above listed services helped URN beneficiaries, students, alumni and the community, venture into business. However, to overcome business challenges they face in their daily business activities technical support is highly needed.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outputs: 

60 entrepreneurs trained
6 sessions (2 networking sessions and 4 matchmaking sessions) organized
120 entrepreneurs attended the sessions
50 business products selected for the show room
Monthly field visit/follow session with entrepreneurs who got loan organized 
3 starter kits developed 

Project outcomes: 

5 SMEs got loan 
10 new SMEs started
60 existing SMEs grown
At least 100 new jobs created
95% of entrepreneurs who got loan paid back well the loan</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Rwanda (URN) former Umutara Polytechnic (UP) is a tertiary learning institution established by the Rwandan Eastern Province community in 2006 to address its developmental problems and avail learning facilities for thousands of post-secondary school young people in the region and the country at large. It offers training at degree level in agriculture, veterinary medicine, engineering, ICT, and business studies in addition to offering advisory services to the community of Eastern Province.

URN however faces several capacity problems in terms of sustaining the existing businesses, revolving fund mechanism. There are very few resources if any that is in place to support some of young promising entrepreneurs in the district. This poses a serious risk to sustainability of the URN Spark projects including a heavy financial burden owing to relatively high expatriate to come and develop or establish a new system. There is therefore an urgent need to address this situation by availing more strategies and approaches to our staff  and beneficiaries on revolving funds and sustainability through coaching and mentorship.

Few job opportunities are available to the graduates of tertiary institutions and community. Whilst the economy of Rwanda is growing, the growth is not fast enough to match the population growth rate. Taking cues from this scenario, URN introduced a business management course to all faculties. However we found out very crucial to have business Incubation Center (BIC) for more confidence and hands onto to those with no skills in entrepreneurship necessary to, motivate and cultivate an entrepreneurship culture within the institution. URN therefore seeks to establish BIC and advocacy.

Start-up capital is difficult to secure for graduates and community without collateral. More support on sustainability, Revolving funds, Coaching and mentoring, BIC, Show Room and business kits are therefore necessary to our entrepreneurs. More financial support and business model will avail examples of viable business for others to see and hence motivate them to start their own businesses once they see a working example.

The intervention discussed above will go a long way in alleviating poverty and creating employment if implemented. 

We undertake the above problems with aim of developing our beneficiaries to meet their needs   and sustainable development of the individuals and URN  as a whole. 
Contribute  to the Government priority objective as articulated in VISION 2020 for  poverty eradication and employment creation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Rwanda, Nyagatare Campus</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Gashumba-GASHUMBA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>James.gashumba@gmail.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Rwanda, Nyagatare Campus 
Nyagatare 57
Nyagatare Campu  NYAGATARE
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">41468</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
