<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFSII.KOS.FRACTAL.2012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minority Entrepreneurship Development (MED)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Existing and potential / start-ups SMEs south of the Ibar River</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project objective(s): 

The aim of our project is to:

Support entrepreneurship and SME development in isolated regions and among marginalized group (youth and women) through trainings

Extend support to starting entrepreneurs as well as existing SMEs through Loan scheme of UEC partners BSCK and BC Zvecan  direct impact to poverty reduction.
             The idea of Loan scheme is to provide good Loan conditions (low installment rate) to 		SMEs. As one of the criteria for using Loan scheme we can request from SMEs to employ 	new staff or/and various contributions to local community (e.g. purchase of raw material in 	local area if project require that activity). Also loans could be used only for start-up of 		business, expand of production or market

Identifying existing barriers to doing business for the entrepreneurs and SMEs, towards enabling environment for stimulating of private sector development. Identified barriers will be provided to trainer for analyzing. During the training, trainer will give special focus on this, and provide the best advice for solution of the problem.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outcomes:

These outputs will lead to:

Fractal staff will be able to efficiently and effectively serve beneficiaries in targeted locations. Better overall project management and reporting performance based on developed NGO Fractal manual with instructions and procedures.
Up to 30 potential beneficiaries continue to participate in the trainings.
20 potential beneficiaries in total from 4 locations selected to continue with consultancy training.
10 BP expected to be approved by Jury members. 
13 beneficiaries awarded by additional in-depth training (marketing, branding) in form of consultancy.
Up to 13 beneficiaries will receive advanced education (as an award) in their fields of work and receive appropriate certificate.
Visibility of the project and successful information dissemination about the Business Plan competition; increase of interest in entrepreneurial activity by 10 % in targeted areas.
Identified business barriers in 4 locations will be presented to a trainer who will give it a special focus during the training in order to find the best possible recommendation for solution.
Forming of 2 cooperatives or/and supporting and reorganizing of existing ones, as well as joint advocacy (as one group) towards national and international level.
Evidence based advocacy based on the research and policy paper about the Challenges of entry of minority businesses to Kosovo market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fractal</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Filip Pavlovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>filip.pavlovic@ngofractal.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fractal
27 Marta 4/8
11000  BELGRADE
Servi&#xEB;</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">33560</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.ngofractal.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
