<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MatMedia2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YOUTH NOW, SS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the YEP programme, MSS seek to help bridge the gap of expectation and the reality of large segment of South Sudans youth sinking into a spiral of hopelessness. MSS will work with South Sudanese youth in identifying challenges and aspirations, and prepare them to present their complaints to the concerned parties and assert and demand their rights as the current/next generation of leaders. Without this intervention, MSS fears that South Sudan is looking at a lost generation forgotten in the transition of the country and left without skills to fend for themselves in tomorrows South Sudan, which promises a different socio-economic reality. Providing these youth with an opportunity to engage and organize their lives in order to become productive citizens rather than a destructive threat to the stability of the new country is what motivates us at MatMedia in our work with the youth.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Update of Youth Participant Network
Investigate and monitor Action Groups
Media trainings
Fellowship Programme
Advocacy on Constitutional Review Process
Advocacy with Business Leaders
Youth Now website, plus online media plan
Radio Broadcasting
Mapping of youth leagues and multi party events
Multi stakeholder and youth dialogues
Business dialogues</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Now SS is working directly with South Sudanese youth especially youth living in Juba, Central Equatoria State.  The direct beneficiaries are youth between 15 to 35 years of age. The project will work closely with the Directorate of Parliamentary Affairs in the national Ministry of Cabinet Affairs to implement a proposed youth internship programme with South Sudan National Legislative Assembly, NLA. The project also target high school graduates and university students to partake in its internship programme. Thirdly, the project is poised to organize tailored events for visible youth leaders since this group can emphatically push forth the youth agenda if engaged properly. Apart from this, Now Youth SS will interact with Ministry of Youth, Culture and Sport (State &amp; National), Ministry of Education (State &amp; National), Ministry of Labour (State and National), Department of Trade, Industry and Commerce (State and National), private sector leaders, Diaspora, political parties and civil society organizations to address challenges facing South Sudanese youth when it comes to active participation and/or leadership representation in politic as well as access to practical employment and business</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-15" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MatMedia Sudan Society, MSS</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ding Lam YUAL</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>ding.yual@gmail.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MatMedia Sudan Society, MSS
 (Across Sedona Hotel),
Juba, South Sudan

Hai Thoura
JUBA
Zuid-Soedan</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">61473</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.youthnowss.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
