<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-BSCM2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Entrepreneurship (SME) Development and Job Creation for Liberians Youths</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAPACITY BUILDING OF YOUR ORGANISATION OR YOUR PARTNERS (provided by SPARK &amp; BiD network)

Output indicators	Outcome indicators

A developed Balanced Score-card (BSC) for your organisation to report progress in the development of your organisation (the BSC can include various intermediate outputs such as efficiency, courses/trainings developed, customer satisfaction, financial sustainability etc)	The number of organisations in your network that started to work with the Balanced Score Card
An  amount of income generated (through service fees, co-financing of activities by local public and private sector) on top of funding provided through your proposed project	An increase in the client satisfaction score of organisations in your network
	The % women, youth and other marginalized clients such as former combatants or refugees participating in training and other activities of organisations in your network



DIRECT POVERTY ALLEVIATION THROUGH SME DEVELOPMENT BY YOUR ORGANISATION

Output indicators	Outcome indicators

The number of business plans, ideas and other business type applications approved	The number of SMEs started or grown
The number of trained potential and existing entrepreneurs (that received a certificate)	The % survival rate of businesses 3 years after launch
The number of success full matchmaking between entrepreneurs and financiers	The number of jobs created through businesses you have supported
The number of SMEs that visited your website for information about your activity	The number of indirect jobs created through businesses supported by organisations in your network
The number of attendees in networking sessions and meetings that you will have organised under the proposed project	Increased employability of those that were trained by your organisation described(qualitative)
The % of approved business plans and other applications and/or % training participants who got certificates and/or %  financed entrepreneurs and/or % of networking attendees are women, youth, refugees and other marginalised groups	The % of owners of SMEs and/or the % jobs created that are related to women, youth, refugees and other marginalised groups




ADVOCACY AND POLICY INFLUENCING FOR SME DEVELOPMENT BY YOUR ORGANISATION

Output indicators	Outcome indicators

The level of engaged policy makers involved in your proposed project described(qualitative)	The number of World Bank Doing Business Indicators improved in your region, thanks to your proposed activity
The number of advocacy strategies (re)formulated through your proposed activity	Proof of business barriers removed in procedures and policies described (qualitative)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct beneficiaries of this program are mostly marginalized and vulnerable youths (rural &amp; urban) men and women with technical/vocational and university skills and knowledge. Focus is on ambitious and innovative youth who have high start-ups and growth potential, all between the ages of 18  35. A second target group are existing businesses that have the potential to grow. These SGBs will, with the right support, grow, generate more revenue and employ people

Also, BSC would target corporate groups such as banks, telecommunications companies, media groups, firms, etc. for income generating purposes as part of the sustainability model.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia over 20 years suffered economic instability due to the incapacity of the Government to prioritize specific sectors of the economy to fully function. There has been little or no attention to the private sector growth, local enterprises/firms still lack the capacity to gain significant market share. The International Finance Corporation (IFC)/World Bank reports using key indicators such as: Paying taxes, enforcing contracts, trading across borders and getting electricity, saw a reduction of 1 in their 2013 ranking. Doing business and getting credit in 2013 had an increase of 3 and 7 as compared to the 2012 rankings.

There are still numerous challenges faced by both local and foreign firms, which have become an impediment to their success. Increasing demands from local enterprises/SMEs to National Government to develop policies that would provide better incentives for them to increase their market shares and earn wealth, for Example: income tax reduction, establishing a credit bureau, establishing fund for SME Development.

Since the inception of the current administration, there has been some focus on the sector in partnership with private organizations to promote Liberian businesses. The Micro Small Medium Enterprise (MSME) Division of the Ministry of Commerce has formed a private sector stakeholders group that would work together and address these concerns. There has been some impact, but largely the problems still exit.

It is very important that these issues/problems will be confronted, as with many developing economies, private sector development is the driving force behind economic growth. These efforts will lead to employment, infrastructure development, human capacity, increase in per capita income, and economic stability. These are a few of the reasons why the BSC proposes to reduce some of these challenges by providing Business Development Services (BDS) to these SMEs: Business skills training, coaching, mentoring, access to finance, access to markets, technical assistance, incubation services, access to opportunities to concessionaires supply chain, and job placement services.



As part of the sustainability model, all the below listed services would be performed to generate income for the BSC. Activities the BSC will perform to generate income:
Provide general Business Development Services (BDS) to entrepreneurs/corporate clients, businesses, etc that includes:
Ready4Finance Training packages
Build Your Business Training packages
Business Edge Training packages
Passport To Success Life Skills Trainings
Coaching &amp; Mentoring
Technical Assistance
Incubation Management
Provide suitable candidates for employment to institutions, organizations, etc. through the BSC Employment Services
General Services (Internet, photocopies, printing, binding, renting of computer lab and conference room facilities, etc.)
Investment Match-making
BSC Advisory Services
Partnerships with organizations that supports Entrepreneurship Development
Co-financing with National Investment Commission &amp; Ministry of Commerce for the National Business Development Advisory Center
Sourcing support/collaboration/Corporate Social Responsibility funds for Entrepreneurship &amp; SME Development</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier ref="BSCM2014" type="A9">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Start-up Centre Monrovia</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Start-up Centre Monrovia</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">William Reide Dennis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>williamdennis@bscmonrovia.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Start-up Centre Monrovia
Graduate School, GD 2-8, University of Libe
MONROVIA
Liberia</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">210958</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.bscmonrovia.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
