<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-HUB/ADC2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Entrepreneurship Hub Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2010, the Government of Rwanda through Rwanda Development Board (RDB) inaugurated the Business Development Centers (BDCs) in each district of Rwanda, total 30 BDCs including the Kicukiro BDC. RDB employed BDC managers who were responsible for provision of business development services to the small and medium enterprises that include cooperatives.
In the first place, all BDCs were set up to provide the following services to help improve entrepreneurship sector in Rwanda the services) include, but not limited to the following;
Entrepreneurial Development Services: These services involve training entrepreneurs to develop essential skills for professional development. This help participant to identify, develop and implement business ideas.
Business Registration: The Centers provide commercial registration for companies so as to encourage formal businesses and to facilitate the process of starting a business by bringing it closer to the business community. This service has already started in 8 Centers and is to be extended to other Centers.
Trainings, Business Advice and Counseling: Trainings, individual business mentoring and counseling form an important part of the BDCs daily activities. Participants can vary from new entrepreneurs with minimum skills needing general assistance to the established and skilled businesses needing specialized knowledge or a specific intervention; Business Plan Elaboration, Accounting, SME (including cooperatives) management, Business Skills Etc. And the business counseling services can relate to tender advice, business plan implementation, loan management, marketing, book keeping and performance management.
Facilitating Access to Finance: Companies or individuals are introduced to financial institutions; particularly those which offer loans to the people turned away by banks and other formal financial institutions such as micro finance institutions and support funds such as SME Support Scheme.
Information Services: This includes provision of trade point services by facilitating the business community to access domestic and international investment and trade information. The Centers serve as sources of information on tourism services in Rwanda, and any other information related services.
IT Services: IT services are offered by facilitating the business community to access and use internet and any other IT related facilities.
Tax Advisory Services: The BDCs also are used as a platform for the Rwanda Revenue Authority to offer tax education services to the potential and existing tax payers.
RDB covered all the costs of the services and the beneficiaries received all services free of charge. After operating the BDCs for two years there was no still a proper working model, quality of services was poor at the BDCs, RDB realized the need to change the model of BDS provision, sign public private partnership (PPP) with private enterprises to provide the services and charge for the services and provide good quality service. It is under this PPP that ADC is providing business development services and managing 7 BDCs in Eastern province and 3 BDCs in Kigali City including the Kicukiro BDC. Under this arrangement RDB compensates 30% of the costs of approved and provided training and business development services to clients and that 70% of these costs are paid by the service users themselves. The change in the approach of delivering BDS and trainings was necessary for the beneficiaries to realize the value of the services and also to ensure good quality services. However, the shift from receiving 100% free services to paying 70% of costs was too drastic, most target beneficiaries of the services are not accessing the services because of the inability to pay the 70% of the costs and as a result BDC facilities are not utilized and ADC is facing difficult to retain and pay salaries of the qualified BDC managers and Business Advisors who can give quality required services. Due to inadequate revenues from the BDC, there is inadequate funds for repair and maintenance of the building and overall environment of the BDC to make the conducive environment for entrepreneurs to work and network.

An additional challenge is the quality of services offered by the BDC, a dynamic inspiring environment for entrepreneurs to learn and network and supportive services to help the businesses grow. An additional challenge in Rwanda is that there are several organisations focusing on entrepreneurship, each with their target audience, but still young people who want to start businesses and existing entrepreneurs who want to grow, find it hard to access services. The Hub aims to address this problem by having all services under one roof.

Kicukiro Entrepreneurships Hub aims to provide practical support to new and existing SMEs, based on ethical
Excellence. This will be done through different initiatives for existence practical business Plan and growth
Competitions, Business Skills Trainings (some of which are very practical models developed for young
entrepreneurs), Entrepreneurship events, Business Coaching/Mentoring and Access to Finance (Debt LGF and
Equity), Information services centre and a hub for all organizations in Rwanda to combine efforts to effectively meet
demand for the Hub members/beneficiaries. The Hub shall help SMEs attain growth and development, thereby creating worthwhile long-term jobs, improved local supply-chains and national economic progress.

With a help of funding and partnership partner SPARK turn the Kicukiro BDC into an improved active Entrepreneurship Hub as a pilot project to be scaled up to other BDCs under ADC and other service providers management.

Moreover, we are looking for a dynamic Entrepreneurship Hub Manager/Trainer to manage and the hub officer to manage all aspects of operational project work to ensure the smooth-running of the Hub activities and act as liaison point between entrepreneurs and partners. These two staff will be transparently recruited with a help of SPARK and they will be separate staff from ADC staff.

ADC is requesting funding and SPARK partnership to turn the Kicukiro BDC into an Entrepreneurship Hub as a pilot project to be scaled up to other BDC under ADC and other service providers management.
This proposal will have a long term impact in terms of contributing to the Rwanda Economic Development and Poverty Reduction Strategy (EDPRS II) targeting to achieve 11.5% average GDP growth per annum and reduce poverty to below 30%.  This proposal will contribute to governments efforts to transform the economy, the private sector and alleviating constraints to growth of investment by developing the appropriate skills and competencies to allow Rwandan particularly the youth and Women to become more productive and competitive.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Owners and managers of Micro, Small and medium enterprises (include Cooperatives); Unemployed youth with a drive to become entrepreneurs (graduates of basic nine years/twelve years of education, Technical vocational colleges, Universities); women.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Output:

2 hub staff recruited and trained
At least 2 staff accredited as qualified business advisers by Rwanda Development Board (RDB)
2 Entrepreneurship awareness campaigns in community
The hub modernized and renovated
230 entrepreneurs trained/awarded certificate
At least 40 business ideas identified trained on business plan writing
18 entrepreneurs matchmaking
24 entrepreneurs taken through a business venture (a learning by doing practice)

Project Outcomes:

230 entrepreneurs enquired adequate skill in entrepreneurship
16 new Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) started
50 existing Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) grown
60 jobs created in started  and grown SMEs
60 attendees at networking events
Pilot Hub model created for other BDCs in the country
100 entrepreneurs referred on to a different programme e.g. DOT, Educat, Grow and others</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-18" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-18" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Consultant Limited</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rebecca A Ruzibuka-Rebecca Ruzibuka</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>rruzibuka@gmail.com</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Consultant Limited
P.O. Box
KIGALI
Rwanda</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="410"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-03-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">75407</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://adcltd.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
