<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-AAO2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agribusiness Creation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.   Overall objective

Support Technical Agriculture Training to Horticulture Farmers and staple food producers for improved productivity for sustainable food security and income generation.

Output 1:
17 Technical staffs from AAO, CAD and CTC trained in Horticulture packages(the methods to be used includes class lecture, practical field learning, group discussion and brainstorming) for improved production.

Output 2:
62 selected champions and Association members (60% are Youths) received Monthly Coaching in Horticulture crop production and management.

Output 3:
12 champions trained in horticulture production and management specific skills where 50 % are female members.

Output 4:
50 Association members Trained in Horticulture production specific Management skills where 50% are expected to be women.

Output 5:
12 champions trained in Use, Installation, maintenance of Drip and Overhead Irrigation in AAO Technology Transfer site demo.

Output 6:
18 apprentices identified, selected and participated in Horticulture production long season for on Job skills development for self employment in AAO demo.

Output 7:
60 Association members trained and adopted good Agronomic practices for increasing production of staple food crop where 50% are female beneficiaries.

Output 8:
60 association members trained and adopted good post harvesting and handling practices for reducing production losses by 30% where 50% are women beneficiaries.


Project outcomes ( Activity plan 2014)

Technical competences improved for better advisory services to the farmers:Skills competences increase by 30%,Adoption of betters practices by farmers by 40%
Increased interest in farming by youths in South Sudan:70% of the Youths develop positive interest on farming for self employment Job,Increasing vegetables production and sales income by 30% will motivate Youths for farming activities
- Adoption of best production and management practices for Horticultures: Increased production by 40%,More income earned by 30% , Improved production sales records

-Change of attitudes and adoption of best horticulture practices and technologies: Increased production by 30%,Production records ,Market supply reports


- Change of attitudes and adoption of best horticulture practices and technologies:Increased production 30%.,Technologies demonstrated Increased income 40%


- Apprentice youth acquired skills for self job creation from the demo site :Youths with self started enterprise ,Success story and testimony of change in life.

-60 Association members trained in Agronomic practices of selected staple food crop production and management:Increase in productivity of selected staple crops,Adoption of best Agronomic practices

- 60 association members trained and adopted good post harvesting and handling practices for reducing production losses by 30% where 40% are women beneficiaries: Reduction in Yield losses by 30%,Quality grains that meets WFP standards produced

.  Project outputs

- 17 Technical staffs from AAO, CAD and CTC trained in Horticulture packages for improved production: Training attendances list, Training manuals developed for the training.

-60 selected champions and Association members received Monthly Coaching in Horticulture crop production and management:Field visit checklist forms, Champion/Association Visitors books ,Pictures of current situation

- 12 champions trained in horticulture production and management specific skills where 50 % are female members: Training attendance list.Training manuals developed.
  	Training reports.
- 60 Association members Trained in Horticulture production specific Management skills where 50% are women: Training attendances list.Training manuals developed.
	Training reports
-18 apprenticeships identified, selected and participated in Horticulture production long season for on Job skills development for self-employment in AAO demo: Training attendances list. Regular demo record book.Monthly reports Picture and story taken.

- 60 Association members trained and adopted good Agronomic practices for increasing production of staple food crop where 50% are female beneficiaries: Training attendances list ,Training manuals developed Training reports submitted.

- 60 association members trained and adopted good post harvesting and handling practices for reducing production losses by 30% where 50% are women beneficiaries: Training attendances list ,Training manuals developed ,Increased production yields by 30%.  Increased income/profits of the farmers by 40%</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Importation of vegetables from neighboring countries have generated a lot of concern among many in the business community, Donors, and development partners since the country has the most fertile land and water resources suitable for production of agricultural products. As a result millions of dollars were injected into the sector by the Donor Community to address the production gap through projects particularly supporting horticultural production in South Sudan and this intervention yielded little results. This is because the approach was focused on emergency programs supporting only producers and other important actors are missing and this continues to yield less impact on increasing horticulture production.  Many of the farming communities in south Sudan still rely on subsistences vegetable /horticulture production. However, some individual progressive farmers do produce for the local market.  At the Governors Forum in 2012, a presidential decree was ordered to stop the importation of horticulture product by 2014 in south Sudan.  This was noted with a lot of doubt since the faming household in South Sudan are not able to meet the consumer demand which is addressed by the imported horticultural products.  This is due to inadequate knowledge and skills, poor horticultural seeds, poor post harvesting practices, lack of packaging materials, inadequate transport facilities, poor infrastructure, pest and disease prevalences among many other challenges, which have been Facing the horticultural sector in South Sudan. The project will therefore address the capacity related challenges to enhance wide production and supply in the market, with a focus on Central Equatoria.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To build on the achievements made, and narrow the existing gaps in developing a functional horticultural production and supply system, the project will target the current progressive horticultural champions in three Counties. A total of 12 champions and one Association with 60 Association members are expected to be directly involved in horticultural production. Efforts will be made in encouraging the target champions/Association members.

While an additional 60 farmers having 60% representation of youth farmers will undergo capacity building on staple food crop production aimed at addressing the existing food gap and taking the WFP (P4P) as market opportunity for famers.

Implementation of the project will be through collaborative networking with RSS Ministry on Agriculture, Forestry, Cooperative and Rural Development  (MoAF), South Sudan Agricultural Research and Organization (SSARO), State Ministry of Agriculture (SmoA) and the implementing Actors including local leaders at county, payam and boma levels.

The Technical capacity building to the association orticulture members and chmapions Is expected to meet the local production challenges at community level as well as increasing opportunity for business development on horticulture production. An expected 90 MT of horticultural products is to be produced by the end of the Year 2014.   This is expected to increase supply of fresh horticultural products to meet the high growing demand for local consumption in South Sudan.

Based on the agro-ecological suitability, the proposed intervention will be implemented in the following production areas (counties) within CES.
Yei County in CES
Morobo County in CES
Juba County in CES.

Horticulture is one of the profitable enterprise based on its use and demand, therefore building the capacity of the champions/association members on entrepreneurship in horticulture will make farming more beneficial for the community compared to subsistence activities.  It was noted that horticulture production is one of the labor intensive farming activities and therefore, there is a great opportunity to increase the amount of available jobs for young South Sudanese Youth.  Improving the production skills and increasing yields and income of the Youths members amongst the horticulture association members and champions would motivate the others youths who are idle in town to become horticulture farmers since majority of them are able groups that are capable of physical labour and once they see the income potential reached by other youth, they will be interested to follow.

Efforts are needed to increase yield per unit areas (vertical expansion) rather than horizontal expansions (more land on production). Its anticipated that use of best Agronomic practices, improving soil fertility through natural means (organic), use of improved seed varieties and reducing post harvesting losses on perishability will increase production without use of external inputs and this will cut down cost of production.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier ref="AAO2014" type="A9">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture Advisory Organization</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture Advisory Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clement Metaloro</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture Advisory Organization
KindiBomain Morobo County
Central Equatoria State 00
MOROBO
Zuid-Soedan</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">36938</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
