<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-Leaders2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creative Steps</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output(s)	Indicator (s):	Target(s):

P1.1 A set of bootcamp training programmes for aspiring entrepreneurs conducted
# of boot camps 1
# of trained potential entrepreneurs 30
# of Business Plans received	10

P1.2  A series of creative economy capacity development seminars conducted
# of seminars 6
# of trained potential entrepreneurs	200

P1.3   Hands on internship programme for
# graduates trained  12 young graduates
# startups supported 4
#website visits to Internship page 1000


P2.1 Leaders Organisation Strategic plan developed	20% increase in income generated by the Organisation to total annual income during the strategy period 2014-2016

P2.2 Capacity development programme for Leaders Staff and consultants on startups and innovation management	# Staff members attending trainings	5

P3.1 Policy environment assessment for startups in the creative economy conducted	The number of advocacy strategies formulated 	1

	#of policy discussion meetups	3</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine, as the majority of the MENA countries, is facing economic difficulties leading to low growth and high unemployment rates, especially among youth. A recent World Bank publication points that the average unemployment rates for youth in the MENA exceeds 25% and countries of the region need to create 40 million jobs over the next decade just to prevent this situation from deteriorating.  World Bank. 2013. Transforming Arab Economies: Travelling the Knowledge and Innovation Road. Washington. The economy of the West Bank clearly fits this description.
While the majority of employment in Palestine comes from SMEs, the business environment is not conducive of the growth of such businesses. Extensive regulatory procedures, high capitalisation thresholds and restrictions on access to finance and investments comprise an extricate web of challenges that face entrepreneurs and SMEs in starting up and growing their businesses.
The majority of credible international reports assessing the business climate in the West Bank have repeatedly come to similar conclusions regarding the business climate in the Palestinian Territories, starting with the World Banks Investment Climate Assessment in 2007, USAIDs BizCLIR study in 2010 and the most recent World Bank/IFC Doing Business report of 2013. In short, the findings and recommendations of these studies and other reports emphasized the importance of improving the investment climate through legal reform and institutional development as a precondition to achieving higher growth rates and encouraging FDI.
The scarcity of resources in the Palestinian Territories necessitate that the Palestinians must approach policy reforms with a view to capitalising on the Territories&apos; highly educated labour force. International and local studies into the dynamics of the Palestinian economy have emphasized this point. USAIDs BizCLIR report, for example, has built on this finding to identify the IT sector as potential key driver of economic development in the Palestinian Territories. It is important, however, to note that while a highly educated workforce must act as the driver of the development process, the accurate deduction of this observation, should not restrict this role solely to the information technology sector but should focus on the more encompassing concept of the creative economy, including such industries as design, engineering, technology and R&amp;D among others as key contributors to this process.
Developing an economic structure conducive of the growth of creative industries requires an organic growth of an ecosystem that supports such structure. Such an ecosystem is a result of the interactions created at three levels: The macro-level, which covers national policies and institution; the meso-level that involves the role played by business associations and support services providers, and; the micro-level, which addresses the role of entrepreneurs and SMEs.
On the macro levels, Palestine operates a highly restrictive business environment that reflects on the ability of businesses to get established and access finance and investments. This is reflected in the World Banks &#x201C;doing business rankings&#x201D; which ranks Palestine at 135th among the countries assessed in the report. This index which incorporate different indicators for ease of starting a business, access to credit, protection of investors, enforcing contracts, paying taxes and international trade, outlines the key deficiencies at the macro level in each of the partner countries.
At the meso-level, Business support institutions, Such as Leaders Organisation, must be able to provide targeted interventions that directly reflect the needs of businesses and startups in the creative economy. This must be reflected in a clear strategy that addresses the various elements in which these organisations operate.
Finally, on the micro-levels, SMEs and entrepreneurs in the creative industries rely mainly on human resources in the development of their products and services. This fact makes it rather difficult for startups to build a strong workforce because they have to compete for highly qualified professional in a very competitive and relatively expensive labour market. On the other hand, fresh graduates constitute a good source of human capital but these lack the experience and exposure required to lead the process of developing quality outputs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main target group of this project are young entrepreneurs and business startups in creative economy sectors. The project will aim to enhance the conditions of success for these startups and entrepreneurs by enhancing their ability to acquire resources, especially human resources, that are required for their growth.
In addition to the main target group, the project will address Leaders Organisations need to develop its strategy for 2014-2016. This will include a general policy assessment as well as a series of workshops designed to identify strategic interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leaders Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shadi Atshan-Atshan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>satshan@leaders.ps</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leaders Organization
2nd Floor, Adel Masri Building, Parliament Square, Ramallah, West Bank, Palestine
Adel Masri Building
RAMALLAH
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">70000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.Leaders.ps">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
