<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-NL-KVK-41213450-LEAD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEAD (Tunesia, Somalia and Libya)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEAD Target Groups are Youth and Women.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEAD is active in three countries, Libya, Somalia and Tunesia. A brief overview of the situation in each country will be provided here.

LEAD Libya run by Enala:
The problem of Libyan youth that there is a high rate of unemployment reached 50% according to The central bank for the Middle East and North Africa research, and those who are employed, the majority of which are employed by the public sector around 80% according to Ministry of Labour . The is little support from the government to invest in the private sector, while youth are discouraged to turn to this sector as a source of employment or job creation because of little development or encouragement. As a result, the majority of youth who are unemployed often end up being recruited into militia and armed groups as a source of income generation. These groups are prone to radicalization and migration to seek better opportunities and quality of life. While those entrepreneurs who have businesses are not being supported and often find themselves lost or at despair for support in developing and growing. Libya has a high potential of job growth in sectors such as Renewable energy, services related to the oil industry, fisheries. In addition to this, it has been identified by experts in the field, that other sectors such as construction; banking; I.T and catering are also emerging sectors with potential of job creation. With the support from SPARK, ENALA aims to increase &amp; strengthen the role of the private sector for SMEs and also link youth to the private sector through a number of activities. The objective is to support and coach existing businesses in the value chain and raise awareness and inspire entrepreneurs to become business owners. In this context, we can identify multiple opportunities that could lead to profitable and suitable projects for future and existing entrepreneurs. The main impact would be to reduce: the unemployment rate and create jobs, and boost entrepreneurial intention in Tripoli and the surrounding regions

LEAD Tunesia is run by two organisations
1) IACE = Institute Arabe des Chefs d&apos; Entreprice: The governorate of Kef is an agricultural region with a great contribution to country. The region has contributed by 13% and 7% of the national production of cereals and red meats respectively, (according to the tunisian office of the northwest development) The agri-food sector has a huge potential in the region by the transformation some strategic products. The governorate of Kef also has archaeological heritage. This could be an asset for cultural, sustainable and ecological tourism The economy of Kairouan is primarily based on agriculture, cultural tourism, industry and handicrafts Tourism has made an impact on Kairouan region since it was declared a world heritage site by the UCESCO in 1988. (according to the tunisian office of the centerwest development) Despite all this, the kef and Kairouan regions are characterized by an unemployment rate relatively High. Young people in these deprived areas are opting for illegal migration and are more tempted by religious radicalization. This is why entrepreneurship is the optimal solution for these young people to limit unemployment and create value in these areas. In this context, we can identify multiple opportunities that could lead to profitable and suitable projects for young people and future entrepreneurs in those two regions. The main impact would be to reduce: the unemployment rate, the low entrepreneurial intention, economic migration and religious radicalization of young people.

2) TAMSS = Tunesian Association for Management &amp; Social Stability: Like the majority of the countries in the Middle East and North Africa , MSMEs (Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises) are increasingly recognized as drivers of economic growth in Tunisia. World bank recent studies have shown that in middle income countries, SMEs contribute up to half of employment and as much as a third of GDP. Nonetheless, the high percentage of unemployment among youth, mainly University graduates, in Tunisia is creating instability led by series of upheavals initiated by a desperate majority of young men and women who are lacking opportunities but also awareness and skills to move from a state of &#x201C;waiting&#x201D; to &#x201C;acting&#x201D;. In addition, the high unemployment rate is the result of not only a heritage of &#x201C;state based&#x201D; and controlled entrepreneurial system but also an educational system that has been for many years completely disconnected from the labor market, more focused on information as opposed to knowledge and skills development. In its 2015 report &#x201C;Investing in Youth Tunisia, Strengthening the Employability of Youth during the transition to a Green Economy&#x201D; OECD describes youth unemployment in Tunisia as &#x201C;a true social tragedy that urgently needs to be addressed,&#x201D; demoralizing and financially starving young generations by depriving them of opportunities to participate in the economy. Unemployment also disproportionately affects women and those living in the certain parts of the country, causing an array social issues arising from gender and regional inequality &#xBB;. Consequently, in order to face the raising number of the unemployed different players in the post revolution period have been focusing on MSMEs launching and job seekers skills development. However, which MSMEs and which skills are needed by the different regions remain the questions that have not been seriously addressed yet. Lack of disaggregated information about the unemployed, priority sectors, recruitment needs, current and future investment plans in a defined region are missing. Thus our program will focus on defining recruitment needs priorities as well as priority sectors in Elkef and Kairouan. On the level of enterprise development for job creation surprisingly, the greatest challenge facing any financial innovator seeking to target the MSMEs market is the generally low level of financial awareness among those running and future small businesses. Often today, it falls to development banks and other public and nonprofit sector institutions to provide the necessary technical assistance and financial education. Although great efforts have been made in few regions in Tunisia to enhance financial literacy among the business community mainly in underserved regions, success to date has been very limited. This could be explained by the fact that financial literacy is only one of the reasons behind the failure of future and current MSMEs in securing existing funds. Thus the project will provide series of training workshops to current and future identified and selected entrepreneurs as needed by a variety of production sectors and services sectors that correspond with each governorate&apos;s specifities and the target women and youth segment on subjects such as entrepreneurship, financial literacy, marketing , loan seeking, customer services, communication, life skills development etc, as well as technical training and assistance based on the assessment results. As for the selected most employable among the job seekers, the project will enhance their employability and raise their recruitment chances by providing education and training for employability based on the mapping, assessment and round tables with future recruiters.

LEAD Somalia is run by YEED (Youth Employment &amp; Entrepreneurship Development):
Somalia has been ravaged by war, political turmoil and humanitarian crisis for decades. While the situation is still relatively unstable, conditions are starting to improve. A significant factor in Somalias future rests with youth and having them engage in economic and development activities. Somalia has a disproportionately large youth population with more than seventy percent of the population aged under thirty years. Traditional formal-sector entry points into the workforce for Somali youth are very limited and jobs leading to careers are scarce. There is a growing need in Somalia to support the entry of youth into informal-sector employment. With fertility levels at 6.2 births per woman between 2010 and 2015, Somali youth will continue to make up a disproportionate percentage of the labour force in the country for the foreseeable future. Youth unemployment is a pervasive issue in Somalia and is especially apparent in some of the most vulnerable groups in society: disadvantaged with limited or no access to formal education, ex-militia, disabled, minorities, IDPs and, most importantly, women. Statistics on unemployment indicate even though they make up two-thirds of the labour force, 70 percent of the youth cohort is unemployed. According to UNDP Somalia Human Development Report 2012 the unemployment rate of youth aged 14 to 29 was 67 percentone of the highest rates in the world. Females experienced higher unemployment rates at 74 percent. Youth unemployment was highest in Somaliland at 84 percent, followed by South-central Somalia and Puntland at 54% and 62% respectively. This is worrisome as some studies have shown a strong positive correlation between having a disproportionately large youth population and social unrest. The conflict in Somalia has disproportionately affected women in Somalia, who are often the bread-winners in most families. Men often had to join the war or migrate to other areas to seek better economic opportunities leaving women-run households in many communities. An overview of the informal economy has shown that many small businesses are run by women, and an estimated 70 to 80 percent of the regions households were dependent on womens earnings for the familys livelihood. Somali women faced with either the loss of a husband or a husband unable to find work found means of earning a living through petty trade and cooperatives established with other women.3 This reality is often in direct contrast to their position in a patriarchal society where cultural norms that mean they often have very limited opportunities for education, skills training and access to financial products that could help sustain and grow these income generating activities. In Somalia, the nexus between unemployment and conflict has assumed great significance due to poor socio-economic conditions and limited economic opportunities, both which make lack of sustainable employment opportunities a catalyst for conflict. As such there is an acute need to mobilize interest, investment, knowledge, resources and action to drive large-scale comprehensive employment and enterprise development programs, particularly for youth. Shaqodoon recognizes that youth employment is a key contributor to healthy and thriving economy. thereby providing technical assistance and related support to entrepreneurs is one of the most effective and flexible strategies in the fight against poverty and, in particular, youth unemployment in Somalia Based on our experience of working in Somalia we see a significant opportunity to stimulate youth job creation through entrepreneurship development by combining the provision of enterprise development training, access to Business Development Services [BDS] and business mentoring , with the emergence of a new breed of responsive financial institutions and linking these both into a structured mechanism which enables Somalia diaspora to invest (financially and with human resources) back into their home communities. In partnership with a number of Somali Financial Institutions (FIs) including but not limited to Micro-Dahab member of Dahabshil group, Kaah Islamic Microfinance Institution Services [KIMS] DaruSalam Bank, IBS Bank, Shaqodoon is in the best position to provide needed support to youth under this project. Whilst access to finance is a critical barrier to starting and/or growing sustainable enterprises it is not the sole support required. Shaqodoon has also developed a range of innovative enterprise support services such as business skills training and market access solutions which have been offered to enterprises to synergistically complement financing. Under this project, we propose bringing our skills and experience in addressing hither to underserved market segments to achieve LEAD program objectives through creation of sustainable employment in Somalias growing sectors [Renewable energy, livestock, agriculture, fisheries, and food processing industries], provision of intensive entrepreneurship training, BDS, and access to SME financing via Financial Intuitions with the aim of creating additional direct and indirect jobs for youth. Shaqodoon will also advocate to promote entrepreneurship education through integration of entrepreneurship education in the education sector i.e. in secondary and higher education by providing in-depth training to teachers, developing and providing comprehensive entrepreneurship learning modules [curriculum] to high school and university teachers. Shaqodoon will build upon promising practices in implemented projects and leverage their own experience, and partnerships to expand the reach of financial and non- financial services to a greater number enterprises both existing and start-ups in Somalia with a particular focus on disadvantaged groups such as low income women and youth (age 15-24).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SPARK LEAD Annual 2016 Narrative Report

Local Employment in Africa for Development (LEAD) commenced on January 2016. &#xA0;The project is a three-year Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs-funded project which aims to create 4000 jobs in Libya, Somalia and Tunisia by supporting young entrepreneurs through access to markets, finance and coaching as well as promoting entrepreneurship in education. The programme focuses on economic sectors with growth potential in regions where youth employment is not only necessary, but also possible to achieve improvements.  In addition, entrepreneurship education is promoted among young people and integrated in higher and vocational education.

The project is implemented in Libya, Somalia and Tunisia, all of which have brought about unique challenges and successes. This narrative report will go through in detail the activities implemented in each country, and describe progress thus far including challenges faced and how these were resolved.

General overview
Although the LEAD programme was awarded in January. The first few months of the project were an inception phase, focusing on the hiring of LEAD programme staff and working with the local partners in identifying which activities will be implemented and how.

By February 2016, the LEAD Programme Manager was recruited whose first task was to identify the staffing needs of the programme for each country and support in the recruitment and on boarding process. This involved the hiring of local programme and finance staff in Somalia and Tunisia respectively. Due to the security conditions in Libya, it was decided that the LEAD Programme Manager will oversee the programme implementation with the support of the local partner hence no local staff was recruited on the ground.
In April 2016, the local partners (TAMSS, IACE and Shaqodoon) convened in Tunis to design their LEAD project activities and receive an orientation on Spark policies and procedures. The orientation included training in M&amp;E, finance and a review of the LEAD proposal to discuss the project indicators, create work plans and agree on a reporting mechanism. The meeting lasted a total of five days whereby on the final day, the partners had completed a draft of their proposed 2016 LEAD project activities. The proposals were reviewed internally by Sparks entrepreneurship specialists and were finalised by May 2016, when grants were awarded to each partner and project activities for Tunisia and Somalia commenced.
There was a delay, however, in awarding the grant in Libya because of a change in the local partner. Originally, it was planned that the local partner for LEAD Libya would be the Benghazi Research Centre (BRC) as indicated in the LEAD proposal agreement. However, due to the fact that the Director of the BRC was appointed as the Vice President of the GNA, and the difficulty in connecting with him and his staff, it was decided to not further delay activities and to identify a new partner.
Since Benghazi was under attack between Haftars forces and other armed groups, and as violence in the city had escalated, SPARK took the decision to postpone implementation in Benghazi and focus initially on Tripoli as a starting point since the security situation was relatively safer, thereby implementation of activities was more likely to happen. With this in mind, the LEAD Programme Manager travelled to Libya in May to meet with potential partners and identify where the LEAD programme could realistically be implemented. Several meetings were conducted with potential local partners and other stakeholders involved in SME development in Libya. A local partner was selected based on its experience on the ground and activities implemented on SME development. After the internal due diligence process was carried out on the local partner, a grant award for local partner Enala was signed in June when programme activities in country commenced.

Challenges and lessons learned in 2016
In 2016, there have been considerable challenges and lessons learned to carry forward in 2017. The main challenges encountered involve implementing in Libya where the situation on the ground is fluid and rapidly changes requiring the need to respond to the change based on the context on the ground. This has been possible through the exchanges between the LEAD Programme Manager and the local partner on the ground who have been able to effectively work together. One of the main challenges we have encountered is ensuring adequate funds are provided to our local partner while the banking sector is on the verge of collapse. Advances to local partner accounts were rejected on numerous occasions which hindered planned activities. To overcome this obstacle, Spark worked with the local partner through small cash advances brought in to the country by the LEAD Programme Manager, or when possible, the local partner travelled to Tunis to receive an advance. Although both these scenarios are not ideal, this was the only method available in order to continue implementing inside Libya. Aside from the monetary situation, increased violence and the general morale of Libyans on the ground has meant that more efforts were required, both from SPARK and local partner to motivate and generate interest in LEAD activities.

The challenges in Somalia have mainly been focused around the drought and the impact this has had on existing businesses. Many of the SMEs supported under LEAD have been affected by the drought. The effects of the drought pose risks to the number of jobs that will be created in Somalia as many businesses struggle to survive let alone grow. As a result of this development, we have agreed with our local partner to diversify the sectors of focus to include the services sector which has not been affected by the drought as much as the agricultural and food processing industries have. Additionally, we adjusted the type of support provided to the SMEs in the sectors affected by the drought in order for them play a vital role in combatting the results of drought. This includes the provision of farming tools, seeds, and coaching for the purposes of restoration and asset recovery.


In Tunisia, whilst SPARK had identified two partners on the ground, there has been difficulties by local partner IACE in retaining its LEAD project staff (a change of 5 programme staff 2016). The staff turnaround has meant that our local partner experienced delays in implementing. Spark has worked closely with the team to ensure that IACE members are familiar with the programme and receive the guidance and support required. In addition to this, as a new international organisation in country, it has meant that time to build relationships and trust which was not originally factored into programming planning has had an effect on delivery. Nonetheless, the LEAD Tunisia Programme Manager and the Regional Programme Manager have played significant roles in building up strategic partnerships and networks. By third quarter in 2016, it was evident that the relationships built have had a positive impact with many organisations contacting Spark to learn more about its programme in Tunisia. The networks built in 2016 has enabled us to build new coalitions and partnerships for activities in 2017.

Cooperation and Synergies with other parties
In 2016, a lot of effort and time was invested in building networks and meeting with stakeholders on the ground in each of the LEAD target countries. Where possible, SPARK has strived to find synergy with other organisations in order to avoid duplication of activities and ensure a wider reach for better impact.

In Tunisia, SPARK has had several meetings with GIZ to identify where the synergy is in both programmes and how the organisations can cooperate effectively to avoid duplication of efforts. It has been tentatively agreed that SPARK and GIZ will join forces to support the training and coaching of existing entrepreneurs in the city of Kairouan. The intervention will focus mainly on post creation and how to ensure that businesses continue to grow and increase their market share. In addition, an MOU was signed in late 2016 by SPARK, Silatech and ATFP to cooperate together on the provision of apprenticeships and internship in Kef and Kairouan.
There has been a significant interest from other organisations in SPARKs activities in Libya. During 2016, SPARK participated in several meetings and conferences related to private sector development and entrepreneurship in efforts to rebuild the country. In particular, SPARK has enjoyed working closely with Expertise France. The two organisations are currently collaborating together in support of activity 1.3: Establishing and/or strengthening entrepreneurship centres by supporting the Libyan Enterprise in improving their service delivery and productivity to Libyan SMEs. The support is focused on targeted capacity building in key areas, notably business planning and feasibility studies. Additionally, SPARK is currently in discussion with UNDP Libya to discuss collaboration in providing support to young entrepreneurs in the South of Libya. UNDP is currently implementing a programme to enhance the stabilization of Libya through economic recovery interventions such as supporting businesses in regions where conflict has happened. Although nothing concrete has been agreed, SPARK is ensuring there is no duplication of efforts and is working closely with UNDP to share information and networks for more enhanced results.
In Somalia, SPARK has convened with other implementers operating in country on SME development. Meetings with organisations such as DAI and USAID have taken place. Currently, SPARK is in discussions with USAID on the feasibility of establishing an incubator centre in Puntland focusing on the fisheries sector. SPARK is also collaborating with BDO for 2017 on the training and coaching of entrepreneurs

Report on Common BZ Indicators
Output 1a: Businesses established by young men in selected sectors
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 1

Output 1b: Businesses established by young women in selected sectors
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 5

Output 3: Incubators and entrepreneurship centres established and strengthened
Somalia: 1
Libya: 2
Tunisia: 1

Summary: SPARK made progress in this activity in 2016. In Somalia, an existing incubator centre called Africa House that provides support to new and existing entrepreneurs in Hargeisa was supported under the LEAD programme. Africa House is the first incubator centre to be set up in Somaliland. With support from Spark in 2016, the centre expanded its operations to a bigger location where it is able to accommodate more aspiring entrepreneurs in its co-work space, while offering separate offices for a small fee to existing SMEs. In addition to providing operational support, SPARK supported Africa House by organising women-only networking events to encourage female entrepreneurs to pursue businesses.

Similarly, in Libya, SPARK, with support from its local partner signed an MOU with the Tripoli Municipality Centre to establish an incubator centre within its premises. The MOU was signed in November allowing for young entrepreneurs to attend the centre and receive support from dedicated experts. The centre was used to deliver targeted trainings to young men and women in support of their business venture. However, after some time, and with the violence in the city increasing, the centre became challenging to use with the Municipality centre officials restricting access to their premises. As a result of this, our local partner requested support from Spark to identify a new location to establish an independent centre in 2017.

In addition to the centre established, SPARK signed an MOU with the Libyan Enterprise Fund to strengthen its existing incubator centres through tailored support based on needs identified. In 2016, Spark collaborated with the Libyan Enterprise Fund to conduct a needs assessment on its centres. Through the assessment, priority areas of intervention included training of entrepreneurship centre managers in feasibility studies. This was considered an immediate priority due to the fact that the Libyan Enterprise Fund is the official mandated body who certifies the feasibility of business plans ready for financing. Without the official approval from the Libyan Enterprise, those wanting to receive financing from banks would be rejected.

In Tunisia, a new centre called Riyada was established in the region Kef. Although this activity was planned in Q2, due to the delay in finding a suitable location and agreeing on logistical matters, the centres opening was delayed until November. The centre received an official opening by the Secretary of State for Entrepreneurship which was attended by various stakeholders involved in the entrepreneurship ecosystem. The centre, which is strategically located in the same building as Centred Affaire aims at providing complimentary services to new start-ups and existing businesses through a dedicated business advisors present in the centre.

Main Output 3a: Direct jobs created for young men
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 2

Main Output 3a: Direct jobs created for young women
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 30

Main Output 3b: Indirect jobs created for young men
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia:0

Main Output 3b: Indirect jobs created for young women
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 0

Output 4: Financial Institutions improved
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 0

Groundwork for this activity commenced in 2016. In July, SPARK conducted a scoping missing in Tripoli to identify the needs and constraints faced by banks in providing finance support to SMEs. The meeting which took place with Libyas main banking institutions such as Aman Bank, Bank of Commerce and Development, Wahda Bank and Jumhouria Bank who convened with SPARK to discuss the current banking situation in Libya and identify the priority needs for intervention. The general consensus was that in the current situation, issuing loans was not possible as there is a lack of liquidity in the banks, and a fear that Libyans would take out loans for purposes other than for business investment. Several banks complained that loans from the Gadaffi era were still unpaid and that providing new loans would be risky given the absence of the rule of law and accountability. However, leading banks including the central bank of Libya an agreement made to provide technical trainings to key banking staff on risk assessment in order to better analyse the feasibility of projects being submitted by entrepreneurs.

Output 5a: Young men willing to start a business
Somalia: 73%
Libya: 44%
Tunisia: 87%

Output 5b: Young women willing to start a business
Somalia: 80%
Libya: 64%
Tunisia: 92%

Output 6: Loan guarantees provided
This activity required prior approval from the Ministry to proceed on. However, in 2016, SPARK began the initial groundwork by identifying suitable partners and conducting studies in each country in regard to access to finance.

The general consensus was that in the current situation, issuing loans was not possible as there is a lack of liquidity in the banks, and a fear that Libyans would take out loans for purposes other than for business investment. Several banks complained that loans from the Gadaffi era were still unpaid and that providing new loans would be risky given the absence of the rule of law and accountability

Output 7: Businesses in value chains of multinationals established and strengthened
Somalia: 0
Libya: 0
Tunisia: 0

Global Entrepreneurship Week

Somalia
905 youth (male/ female) participated in the Global Entrepreneurship events held in Mogadishu and Hargeisa.

Libya
276 attendees (187 male/ 89 female)

Tunisia
525 attendees (377 male/148 female)


Number and % of program beneficiaries who started a business/ self-employment activity and sustained it at least six months after they started


	2016 Achieved		2017 Target		2018 Target

Somalia	0			15			35
Libya 		0			7			28

Tunisia		6 (2.04%)*		30			14

*Note: These businesses commenced operation in Q4 of 2016 and therefore we are unable to confirm sustainability until 2017.

The are few results to report on in 2016 since starting up a business requires time and the first stage of the LEAD programme in 2016 concentrated initially on the inception phase and subsequently providing support &amp; training in the areas where beneficiaries required assistance. Therefore, in 2016, the focus has been on analyzing the demand and needs of the beneficiaries, then providing the targeted assistance for readiness of start-up creation in 2017. This said, we are pleased to report however, that in Tunisia, 6 beneficiaries have created a business through support under LEAD. 2 of the businesses launched are in the Agrofood sector, 3 in the textile industry and 1 in animal breeding. Through support under LEAD, the beneficiaries received coaching from experts within their industry who assisted in the development of business plans that were successful in receiving financing.

Number of companies with a supported plan to invest, trade or provide services


		2016 Achieved		2017 Target		2018 Target

Somalia		0			35			82
Libya 			0			25			57
Tunisia			4			70			43

In 2016, relationships with existing SMEs were forged and the identification of their needs was conducted. In Somalia, the drought and the subsequent livestock ban imposed by Saudi Arabia has had an impact on trade investment and with SMEs diversifying and/or growing in this sector.  The main SMEs we have supported in Somalia thus far have been affected by the ban as well as the drought.  As a result, we re-evaluated in Q3 2016 the type of support to provide to the beneficiaries in this sector to address the drought and tackle the underlying obstacles faced by businesses as a result. The intervention focused on the provision of farming tools and seeds to enable businesses to survive while providing training in topics such as water management to address the water shortage and the affect this is having on crops. Additionally, with our local partner, we agreed to include the services sector as an additional sector to support since this sector is cross-cutting and has potential to create jobs despite the conditions in Somalia.

Similarly, in Libya, the economic instability and the political upheaval has stalled SME growth across the country with businesses struggling to survive and keep people employed. From our discussions with SMEs in country, there are challenges in keeping businesses afloat with a number of companies expressing concern in the hike of US dollar rates and the problems faced with obtaining letters of credit from banks, thus preventing trade.  This has had a negative impact on business growth, which if the situation continues, will be a problem that will be encountered under the LEAD programme. As a result of this, our targets for 2017 for Libya are modest with the hope that the programme will catch up in 2018 based on the notion that a political agreement will be reached within the country and therefore trade and investment will resume. To address the issue of business growth in 2017, SPARK will focus on a few companies whom, despite the crisis in Libya, have demonstrated a continued capacity to grow due to having assets abroad and the ability to continue trading outside of Libya. One of the companies that SPARK will be supporting in 2017 is Mozart; a catering and food business owned by a Libyan female entrepreneur. The support to Mozart will be focused on franchising and the support in production lines as part of Mozarts plan to produce goods in Libya and expand into other countries.


Number and % of trained / supported program beneficiaries who have become employed


		2016 Achieved		2017 Target		2018 Target

Somalia		0			388			722
Libya 			0			150			300
Tunisia			32			665			445

&#xA0;


Report on SPARK Indicators, activities and progress in 2016
The LEAD programme is to provide access to finance and markets to young entrepreneurs and SMEs through two main objectives:
The creation of sustainable employment in growth sectors with special attention to young women, through existing SMEs (70%) and supporting new entrepreneurs (30%) with coaching, training and facilitating access to finance and markets.
To promote entrepreneurship among young people by integrating entrepreneurship education in secondary and higher education.

Objective 1: The creation of sustainable employment in growth sectors with special attention to young women, through existing SMEs (70%) and supporting new entrepreneurs (30%) with coaching, training and facilitating access to finance and markets.

Activity 1.1: Provision of additional market research in identified growth sectors

Somalia
A review conducted by LEAD staff revealed that an abundance of fresh data and research was available on the LEAD target sectors. For this reason, in 2016 SPARK relied on data already available to support entrepreneurs. A new study focusing on a value chain within the fisheries sector will be conducted in 2017.

Libya
Our local partner conducted a mini study to validate the sectors originally identified within the LEAD programme. From the research undertaken, our local partner confirmed the sectors of: Services related to the oil industry, Renewable Energy and Fisheries were not potential growth sectors in the current Libyan context. For this reason, a validation workshop was held with SMEs and entrepreneurs identifying the core growth markets in the current context. The catering, IT and services sectors were validated as growth markets.

Tunisia
A value chain expert was contracted in August to conduct a market study in the cities of Kef and Kairouan. The study conducted identified olive wood and aromatic spices to be two potential products that have the potential of a market share. However, when presenting these sectors to new entrepreneurs, we faced a challenge in having new ideas for business as the sectors were deemed as having government restrictions placed upon them, as well as the need of having significant start-up capital. For this reason, we did not pursue these sectors further. As a result of this, a new approach focusing on validating sectors through a consultative study and focus groups involving new and existing entrepreneurs is designed in 2017.

Activity 1.2: Recruitment of new and existing entrepreneurs

Somalia
Result: 134 business plans received
87 business plans received from young men
47 business plans received from young women

For the first time, the LEAD programme commenced activities in the cities of Bossaso in Puntland and Hargeisa in Somaliland in Q2 of 2016. These cities were chosen because of the high rate of youth unemployment.

An initial needs assessment of existing entrepreneurs and the registration of new SMEs was conducted in order to tailor the support based on the identified needs and challenges of each business in both regions. A large-scale advocacy campaign was launched in the second quarter to notify entrepreneurs and SMEs to register their interest in order to receive support via the LEAD programme.

An advocacy campaign was conducted through a combination of both social media marketing such as Facebook and traditional marketing efforts such as billboards &amp; posters to reach those entrepreneurs and SMEs who have limited access to internet. With the support of our local partner, Shaqodoon, a telephone registration process was made possible. This enabled the beneficiaries located in remote areas, as well as those with no internet access to register by phone through a short code sent to our local partners database that recorded the basic details of the beneficiary, allowing for contact to be made.  To help spread the word, and to support in identifying businesses, the Chambers of Commerce in Puntland and Hargeisa were vital in supporting this activity by mobilizing and bringing together suitable entrepreneurs and providing a list of existing businesses operating in the LEAD target sectors.

From the recruitment process, a total of 805 SMEs were recruited into the LEAD database. A business assessment tool was developed to assist in the selection of the most suitable SMEs and entrepreneurs for training. The tool comprised of a set of entrepreneurial aptitude questions and an interview process to narrow down the selected entrepreneurs. Based on the selection criteria, a total of 489 entrepreneurs (male/female) were shortlisted and subsequently received training on business planning. The training was divided into two categories: new entrepreneurs and existing SMEs. For each group, a specific training was provided tailored to the needs of the group. New entrepreneurs received a dedicated training on how to develop a business plan, learning the basic skills of entrepreneurship and how to build a business (certified by Microsoft). At the end of the training, a business plan competition was arranged allowing for the best business plan to receive an award to help pursue the business idea. With support from our local partner Shaqodoon, a loan of $75,000 was secured from Dahabshil bank to provide funds for the best business plans. 10 participants were shortlisted for funding their business plans which was scheduled in Q1 2017.

For the existing businesses group, the training was more focused toward the gaps and needs of the business and helping to formulate a sound business plan. With the support of experts in the fisheries and agriculture sector, the businesses were coached and mentored to enhance their business plans.

Challenges faced
The main challenge encountered with this activity was the difficulty to obtain business plans. Many of the participants (existing businesses) were reluctant to disclose information about their business while the young entrepreneurs were hesitant to disclose their business idea, mainly because they felt that there was a risk their idea would be stolen. Most participants expressed that until they are guaranteed funding is available for them to pursue their idea, they will not reveal their ideas. It was also evident during this activity, that the majority of the participants lacked the basic skills of crafting a business plan, whilst those who had existing businesses did not even have a business plan for their enterprise. Whilst the reassurance that access to finance was available to the participants at a later stage helped the participants share their business ideas, a lot of effort was put in to make participants understand the importance and need of business plans. One of the reasons for this challenge is because Somalia operates through a mainly informal sector where business transactions are often conducted through tribal affiliation and personal networks. There is very little importance placed on formal business processes and thus the motivation and efforts from participants in engaging in such activities was minimal.

Libya
Result: 10 business plans received
6 business plans received from young men
4 business plans received from young women

Facebook adverts announcing a call for applicants to register for business plan training was posted on several Libyan pages via social media. Although the registration process received significant interest from young men and women, only 10 participants were contacted to attend the business plan training. The reason for this was because it was agreed at the onset of awarding the grant agreement to the local partner, modest targets will be set for 2016 because of the nature of the crisis and the uncertainty that implementation would be possible.

In addition, the difficulty in transferring funds to our local partner because of the collapse of the banking system in Libya meant that very often, activities would be carried out prior to any funds received. This therefore meant that limited numbers were involved in trainings due to the expenses of organizing and hosting workshops. Nonetheless, the business plan training commenced in Q4 of 2016. The 10 participants who were selected based on the prerequisite that they already had an idea that required further development. The business plan training that was delivered was aimed at providing more depth to the ideas the participants presented and prepare them for the next stage of funding.

Challenges faced
The main challenge faced in the training was motivating participants in pursuing their ideas. Most of the participants explained that the situation on the ground in Libya will prevent any real opportunities for businesses to grow, and therefore the motivation and morale was low. This proved a challenge both for the trainer and for our local partner.

Tunisia
Result: 133 business plans received
48 business plans received from young men
85 business plans received from young women

The business plan training took place in Q3 to factor in Ramadan and Eid in Q2. Young men and women in the cities of Kef and Kairouan received training on how to build a business and entrepreneurship by specialized business experts. Similar to Somalia, participants were reluctant to disclose information regarding their business ideas for fear of their ideas being replicated. The majority of the participants expressed hindrance in pursuing their business idea due to lack of funding. However, when asked about whether participants are aware of the main topics a business plan should include, the responses demonstrated that a lack of basic understanding existed. For this reason, the training was tailored to deliver basic business skills training with standardized business plan templates for participants to complete during the training. In addition to receiving support on how to craft a business plan, participants were introduced to the basic concepts of building a business and accounting for business.

Challenges faced
The target sectors LEAD focuses on in Tunisia (agriculture, sustainable tourism, and food processing) has provided limitations in terms of the types of entrepreneurs that can be contacted and supported through LEAD given the high targets set for job creation. In particular, the SMEs and entrepreneurs that operate in the agriculture sector - a dominant sector in Kef and Kairouan- are mainly small microenterprises that work through informal channels. There is a risk that these microenterprises will not grow and create jobs because very often, the jobs created are seasonal and not sustainable. Due to this risk, SPARK requested from the Ministry to broaden its regional scope to other locations in the North west of Tunisia to allow for more choice in the types of SMEs and entrepreneurs available. SPARK is cooperating with its local partner and GIZ to extend activities beyond Kef and Kairouan


Activity 1.3: Expansion of existing and creation of new entrepreneurship centres

Somalia
Result: 1 entrepreneurship centre strengthened

Spark made significant progress in this activity in 2016. In Somalia, an existing incubator centre called Africa House that provides support to new and existing entrepreneurs in Hargeisa was supported under the LEAD programme. Africa House is the first incubator centre to be set up in Somaliland. With support from Spark in 2016, the centre expanded its operations to a bigger location where it is able to accommodate 20 more aspiring entrepreneurs in its co-work space, while offering separate offices for a small fee to existing SMEs. In addition to providing operational support, SPARK supported Africa House by organising women-only networking events to encourage female entrepreneurs to pursue businesses. As a result of the support provided, 7 start ups and 18 existing entrepreneurs were assisted.

Libya
Result: 1 entrepreneurship centre established (Tripoli Municipality Centre)
1 entrepreneurship centre strengthened (Libyan Enterprise)

In Libya, SPARK, with support from its local partner signed an MOU with the Tripoli Municipality Centre to establish an incubator centre within its premises. The MOU was signed in November allowing for young entrepreneurs to attend the centre and receive support from dedicated experts. The centre was used to deliver targeted trainings to young men and women in support of their business venture. However, after some time, and with the violence in the city increasing, the centre became challenging to use with the Municipality centre officials restricting access to their premises. As a result of this, our local partner requested support from SPARK to identify a new location to establish an independent centre in 2017.

In addition to the centre established, SPARK signed an MOU with the Libyan Enterprise Fund to strengthen its existing incubator centres through tailored support based on needs identified. In 2016, SPARK collaborated with the Libyan Enterprise Fund to conduct a needs assessment in its centres. Through the assessment, priority areas of intervention included training of entrepreneurship centre managers in feasibility studies. This was considered an immediate priority due to the fact that the Libyan Enterprise Fund is the official mandated body who certifies the feasibility of business plans ready for financing. Without the official approval from the Libyan Enterprise, those wanting to receive financing from banks would be rejected.

Challenges
Delays in receiving official approval from the authorities in Libya and the fluid security situation impacted the timeline for this activity and consequently, had an effect on the usage and operations of the centre. Towards the end of 2016, it was clear that establishing a centre inside the Tripoli Municipality Centre, despite being a strategic location,  it did not serve the impact we had originally anticipated due to the restrictions placed upon admission to the venue.

Tunisia
Result: 1 entrepreneurship centre established

In Tunisia, a new centre called Riyada was established in the region Kef. Although this activity was planned in Q2, due to the delay in finding a suitable location and agreeing on logistical matters, the centres opening was delayed until November. The centre received an official opening by the Secretary of State for Entrepreneurship which was attended by various stakeholders involved in the entrepreneurship ecosystem. The centre, which is strategically located in the same building as Centred Affaire Centred Affaire is the official Tunisian Government body that deals with entrepreneurship in Tunisia. aims at providing complimentary services to new start-ups and existing businesses through a dedicated business advisors present in the centre. Synergy between the Riyada centre and Centred Affaire is achieved through the type of service and support provided. While CentredAffaire mainly focuses its support to new start-ups, the Riyada centre focuses on post-creation and existing SMEs.

Activity 1.4: Improve local (financial) service institutions and business service providers, and ensure service providers become gender aware.
Somalia
In early 2016, SPARK contracted a local consultant to undertake a study of the banking sector in Somalia to better understand the operating environment, and provide an overview of the financial institutions in the country. The report provided an insight into the nature of the banking sector and the role and importance Islamic banking regulations have in the way financial transactions and lending are carried out in the country.
Following from the report, SPARK organised several meetings with key staff and Directors in order to provide the most effective intervention under this activity. In 2016, SPARK met with staff and directors of three leading banks in Somalia: Dahabshil, Amal Bank and Premier Bank. The meetings were to discuss the report of the banking sector with the banks and understand from operators on the ground where the main gaps and weaknesses are to help improve service delivery. One of the key findings that came out from the meeting was that female investment officers require training on the provision of loans in order to reach women in rural areas and support in their loan applications. Additionally, there was a general consensus from the group that there is a knowledge gap within banks and loan takers regarding the principles of Islamic banking in regard to loans and interest. SPARK has identified 3 MFIs to support in 2017.

Libya
Groundwork for this activity commenced in 2016. In July, SPARK conducted a scoping missing in Tripoli to identify the needs and constraints faced by banks in providing finance support to SMEs. The meeting which took place with Libyas main banking institutions such as Aman Bank, Bank of Commerce and Development, Wahda Bank and Jumhouria Bank focused on the current banking situation in Libya and identify the priority needs for intervention that could be realistically achievable. The general consensus was that in the current situation, issuing loans was not possible as there is a lack of liquidity in the banks, and a fear that Libyans would take out loans for purposes other than for business investment. Several banks complained that loans from the Gadaffi era were still unpaid and that providing new loans would be risky given the absence of the rule of law and accountability. However, leading banks including the central bank of Libya agreed to provide technical trainings to key banking staff on risk assessment in order to better analyse the feasibility of projects being submitted by entrepreneurs. Based on this, risk assessment to key banking staff of Aman and Wahda bank is scheduled to take place in 2017.

Tunisia
A study on the banking sector in Tunisia was conducted by a local consultant in the second quarter of 2016. The study analysed the operating environment of the banking sector and MFIs in Tunisia, and provided an overview of the regulating environment in regard to loans and funding. Following on from the study, SPARK held meetings with Taysir, ENDA, BFPME and BIAT to understand the individual needs of the institutions and identify where our intervention is required. In the last quarter of 2016, Terms of Reference were drafted for a finance expert to undertake a tailored needs assessment with the banks mentioned as part of the intervention planned in Q2 of 2017.
Activity 1.5: Development of entrepreneurship skills of existing and new entrepreneurs through coaching &amp; training

Somalia
Result: 489 male and female entrepreneurs trained and coached
307 young males trained and coached
182 young females trained and coached

In 2016, a total of 489 young male and female new and existing entrepreneurs were coached and trained. The trained businesses came from different sectors such as fisheries, agriculture/agribusiness, food processing and the service and services sector. Were possible, SPARK focused mainly on the core sectors identified in the LEAD proposal. However, as the target for this activity is high, and because business in the other sectors demonstrated a strong potential to create jobs, it was agreed with the local partner to also provide support to businesses in the service sector. This only occurred when the local partners were able to demonstrate a potential to grow and provide jobs.

Experts in the field of fisheries, agriculture and food processing were recruited in the first and second quarter of the programme to provide technical support to entrepreneurs. The coaches organised focus group sessions with the businesses to identify where the main areas for support was required.  In quarter two, training for the businesses commenced. Trainings were given in areas such as water irrigation, fish processing, seed and nursery preparation; pest and disease control. The trainings comprised of a mixture of theory and practical experience to allow for the entrepreneurs to practice on the job. To reinforce the training, SPARK with support of the local partner, developed audio reinforcement messages that were sent to the entrepreneurs mobile phone. These messages contained a summary of the key takeaway points from their training. Additionally, the entrepreneurs were provided with a mentor who provided follow up support and guidance after the training.

Libya
Result: 35 young male and female entrepreneurs trained and coached
20 young males trained and coached
15 young females trained and coached
A focus group was conducted with 30 entrepreneurs in the third quarter of 2016. With the support from the Libyan Enterprise Fund and local partner, Enala, 30 young entrepreneurs and existing businesses attended a business assessment workshop aimed at understanding the current needs and challenges faced in Libya. The one-day workshop brought together a mixture of young men and women from different areas across Tripoli and Western Libya in different sectors. 65% of the attendees were female who ranged between 26-45 years of age. Of the people who were asked about their business related needs, 85% of the group already had an existing business which required support while 15% were potential entrepreneurs who requested guidance to launch their business idea.

Participants had the chance to discuss their needs and the major challenges and obstacles faced in doing business in Libya. The analysed results revealed that 85% of the participants requested business planning training while 80% requested start-up training for entrepreneurs. Financial projection and Marketing was also considered a major area for assistance with 75% of the group stating it as a need.

Based on these finding, training in Business Planning and Marketing took place in the last quarter of 2016. In addition to the participants who attended the focus group, other entrepreneurs who had registered their interest in receiving training in Business planning and marketing were invited to attend. The training was held within the entrepreneurship centre in the Municipalitys premises and was conducted by a female business coach who delivered the business plan training. Participants were asked to complete a short questionnaire prior to the training to gauge their level of knowledge and understanding and help the trainer develop the training materials accordingly. The trainings lasted for 5 days respectively and was followed up by one to one support from the trainers who assisted participants with additional content and mentored them.

Tunisia
Result: 190 young male and female entrepreneurs trained and coached
84 young male entrepreneurs trained and coached
106 young female entrepreneurs trained and coached

In 2016, with support from our local partners, SPARK provided training and coaching to 190 young male and female entrepreneurs in the cities of Kef and Kairouan. The focus of the trainings varied between the groups of participants, but all aimed at strengthening SMEs in areas such as taxation and finance identified as a need by the entrepreneurs and more technical training on marketing and branding.. In addition, tailored legal advice and support for startups who are struggling to launch their business was provided.

Furthermore, as part of its coaching service, SPARK with support from local partner IACE established a hotline platform which aims to provide 24 hour SME services and information to startups and existing entrepreneurs. The hotline is manned by dedicated business experts who are on-call to provide guidance and answer any queries from SMEs.  The hotline directly links SMEs to experienced business experts manning the hotline. When an enquiry needs further response or support, the entrepreneur is requested to provide a suitable time for a callback and if necessary, visits to the business is conducted.
Activity 1.6 Facilitating access to finance for recruited and existing entrepreneurs by guarantee funds

In 2016, a paper was presented to the Dutch MFA in regard to SPARKs approach to Access to Finance in each of the LEAD countries. In December 2016, the Dutch MFA confirmed its approval for SPARK to proceed with this activity which is scheduled in 2017.

Initial groundwork for this activity, however was covered in 2016. This involved meeting with several financial institutions in Somalia and Tunisia to discuss the A2F component, conducting due diligence banks and agreeing in principle on terms and conditions. It was agreed that for Libya, partially funded grants will be awarded to selected LEAD beneficiaries instead of loans given the current conditions in the country. Contracts with banks are set to occur in Q1 of 2017.

Activity 1.7 Strengthening of local SMEs in the value chain of multinational companies and large local businesses

Due to the lack of maturity of the SMEs in the three countries, it was agreed with the local partners to put this activity on hold until 2017 when SMEs are in a stronger position to conduct business with other companies. In Tunisia, with agreement from our local partners, identification of the main SMEs will be identified and supported to create jobs through targeted assistance.  Additionally, a roundtable is planned in 2017 between Dutch companies and businesses from Kef and Kairouan. . The aim of the roundtable would be to facilitate access to new markets for Tunisian businesses and help them to strengthen their position within the international markets.

Similarly, in Somalia, a small networking event was held in December bringing together businesses from the agricultural industry in an attempt to create new networks and relationships. The one-day event was held in Hargeisa and brought together stakeholders in the agricultural sector and government who exchanged information and shared ideas on how to further develop the sector. From the event, 3 businesses had arranged meetings with each other with the aim of doing new business.

In Libya, it was agreed with the local partner that SMEs were not in a position yet to do business internationally particularly as Letters of Credit were not available from banks and restrictions are placed on Libyan companies. It has therefore been decided that the focus will be on growing business within Libya focusing on other cities and developing new products.

Activity 1.8 Promoting successful young entrepreneurs, (especially young women) in popular media

This activity was put on hold in 2016 based on the fact that the entrepreneurs supported under LEAD were not in a position to share a story. This activity is currently underway in 2017.

Objective 2: To promote entrepreneurship among young people by integrating entrepreneurship education in secondary and higher education


Activity 2.1 Introducing or enhancing entrepreneurship courses in the curricula of institutions of higher secondary and vocational education

Somalia
Spark spent time in 2016 developing relationships with stakeholders in the education sector. A number of meetings were held with the Ministries of Education and Higher Education, as well as leading universities in Somaliland to plan for this activity. It was evidently clear from the meetings that the need for entrepreneurship to be introduced to people at a young age was imperative. Based on the discussions held with the Ministry, SPARK agreed to implement this component in collaboration with the Ministry who would be responsible for overseeing the modules and the Teacher training. To this end, a MOU was signed with the Ministry of Education in Somaliland who assigned three technical education experts to support the assignment. In the last quarter of 2016, the initial groundwork of selecting suitable universities and reviewing their curriculum was conducted. The development of the curriculum and teacher trainings was scheduled for Q1 of 2017.

Libya
In 2016, SPARK met with the Head of the National Board for Technical &amp; Vocational Education (NVTBE) to discuss the possibility of introducing entrepreneurship in education. There has been significant delay in implementing this activity due to the fact that the Head of the NBTVE requested that a meeting will be arranged by them gathering all the relevant stakeholders and organisations as part of a government initiative to synergise activities within education. Nonetheless, whilst waiting for the meeting to be held, SPARK has maintained contact with the Higher Institute for Hospitality and Tourism, and Tripoli University and has discussed with them the possibility to cooperate directly. Both institutes agreed in 2016 to cooperate with SPARK. This activity is therefore arranged in 2017.

Tunisia
The progress in 2016 involved building networks and relationships on the ground. Given the fact the SPARK is new to Tunisia, efforts were focused on getting key decision makers within the education sector on board and developing relationships. As a result of these meetings, SPARK agreed in 2016 to support the Kef Agricultural University, and the University of Jendouba. By the last quarter of 2016, a contract was signed with a local entrepreneurship education consultant to work with the two universities in developing an entrepreneurship curriculum by the March 2017.

Activity 2.2 Introduce or improve internship programs in institutions of vocational education
Somalia
In 2016, an assessment was conducted in the cities of Bossaso, Mogadishu and Hargeisa to identify the opportunities and challenges both of obtaining an apprenticeship in the country. Numerous actors were contacted to participate in the research including the Ministry of Higher Education, students, private sector investors, Ministry of Trade and Labour and the Chambers of Commerce. The study aimed at understanding the major bottlenecks young Somalis face in gaining apprenticeships, and identifying how academic institutions can be better placed in facilitating access to work based learning. The research findings revealed that no formal apprenticeship programmes currently exist in Somalia and that there is a lack of government financial support to encourage this. The research also identified that from a private sector perspective, there is a reluctance to provide apprenticeships to students for fear that privacy would be jeopardised. A workshop presenting the findings was held in Hargeisa in which members from the private sector, academic institutions and the government were invited. In efforts to support the apprenticeship programme, the Ministry of Higher Education signed an MOU with our local partner in support of formally introducing apprenticeship programmes in 2017.

Libya
Contact with two academic institutions have been made in Libya. Although the institutions showed great interest, it has been a challenge to move forward on this activity.

Tunisia
Similarly, in Tunisia, meetings have taken place with ATFP, the Tunisian Agency for Vocational Training responsible for overseeing technical trainings in Tunisia. The meetings involved discussing the possibility of introducing improved apprenticeship programmes in Kef and Kairouan and supporting the ATFP in providing better services to students. In 2016, an MOU was signed between SPARK, Silactech and ATFP to introduce apprenticeships in 2017.

Activity 2.3 Organisation of summer entrepreneurship courses at universities and institutions of higher (vocational) education
Somalia
Result: 229 young men and women participate in two-week summer modules on entrepreneurship
126 young men
103 young women

SPARK with the help of its partner signed a MoU with four universities (Hargeisa, Burao, Beder International University and East Africa University) to introduce summer entrepreneurship courses among young people in universities. With support and engagement of the Ministry of Education, and an intensive mobilization process, 229 students (Male 55% and Female 45%) participated in the summer entrepreneurship courses offered by these universities. The courses lasted 10 days covering the basics of entrepreneurship and building a business. At the end of the 10 day course, participants took part in a business plan competition aimed at providing a financial reward for the best business plan. A panel of judges consisting of members from the business community and banks were responsible for judging the best business plan.

Libya and Tunisia
Postponed 2017 due to delays in receiving agreements from participating institutions.

Activity 2.4: Global Entrepreneurship Week

Somalia: 907 participants (519 male/ 388 female)
Libya: 276 attendees (187 male/ 89 female)
Tunisia: 525 attendees (377 male/148 female)

Somalia
GEW was organised by local partner Shaqodoon and centred on the theme of education. Participants enjoyed learning about entrepreneurship in education and the benefits of learning to do business from a young age. Guests included members from the private sector, the Ministries of Commerce and Education. Events were held both in Somalialand and Mogadishu

Libya
In Libya, the GEW was the first to be held since the civil war broke out in 2014. Local partner, ENALA organised a series of events held across Tripoli attracting young men and women. One of the events held by ENALA included a start up expo in collaboration with the Tripoli University Students Union.

Tunisia
In Tunisia, local partner IACE held the GEW in Kef and Kairouan. Entrepreneurship tents were set up in the cities inviting young entrepreneurs to learn more about entrepreneurship and register their interest in attending trainings on building a business. From this event, IACE hopes to include those viable businesses as part of the LEAD beneficiaries in 2017.


LEAD Budget Versus Spend

LEAD - Tunesia:


	Budget on Activity level
	First year: 2016
	Tunisia

Approved budget 2016								Spent in 2016	Budget left as of 31/12/2016
1st main activity	Creating sustainable employment for young people		New (A) or established (B) businesses *	Unit	Unit cost	# units 2016	Direct programme costs 2016	Spent 31/12/2016	Budget left 31/12/2016
Direct programme costs: 1st main activity
	Activity 1.1	Conduct additional (market) research studies in identified growth sectors	A+B	study	6,000	5	30,000	11,689.02	18,310.98
	Activity 1.2	Recruitment of successful existing and new entrepreneurs through existing entrepreneurship initiatives	A	selection	10	150	1,500	3,476.27	-1,976.27
	Activity 1.2.1	Recruitment of successful existing entrepreneurs through existing entrepreneurship initiatives	B		50	500	25,000	0.00	25,000.00
	Activity 1.3	Expand existing and establish new business incubators	A+B	lump sum	100,000	1	80,000	4,246.56	75,753.44
	Activity 1.4	Improve services of local (financial) institutions and business service providers and make these gender sensitive	A+B	business intervention	10,000	2	20,000	16,700.00	3,300.00
	Activity 1.5	Development of entrepreneurial skills of existing and new entrepreneurs through training and coaching	A	business intervention	600	34	20,400	22,859.20	-2,459.20
	Activity 1.5.1	Development of entrepreneurial skills of existing entrepreneurs through training and coaching	B		1,160	100	116,000	0.00	116,000.00
	Activity 1.6	Facilitate the access to finance for exising and new enterpreneurs through guarantee funds	A	loan	3,000	5	15,000	0.00	15,000.00
	Activity 1.6.1	Facilitate the access to finance for existing enterpreneurs through guarantee funds	B		27,250	2	54,500	0.00	54,500.00
	Activity 1.7	Facilitate local SMEs in the value chain of multinational or large local businesses	A+B	business	6,800	5	34,000	10,106.41	23,893.59
	Activity 1.8	Promote successful young entrepreneurs (largely women) in popular media	A+B	entrepreneur	2,500	4	10,000	85.91	9,914.09
		Activity costs of partner applicants	A+B	lump sum	80,000	1	80,000	37,275.05	42,724.95
Total direct programme costs of 1st main activity							486,400	106,438	379,962

Allocated programme costs 1st main activity
		Spark local Project Management Fees		days	400	88	35,200	6,000.00	29,200.00
		Spark local Financial Officer Fees		days	250	68	17,000	9,935.68	7,064.32
		Spark local Project Officer Fees		days	250	96	24,000	9,093.75	14,906.25
		Partner applicant Project Management Fees		days	300	200	60,000	2,016.67	57,983.33
		Spark International Project Management Fees		days	875	52	45,500	46,265.67	-765.67
		Spark International Head of Finance Fees		days	850	8	6,800	5,312.50	1,487.50
		Spark International Controller Fees		days	650	16	10,400	11,821.90	-1,421.90
								0.00
		M&amp;E employee		days	250	32	8,000	2,343.75	5,656.25
		Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Coordinator 		days	650	24	15,600	9,668.76	5,931.24
								0.00
		Travel Costs		month	1,400	12	16,800	6,983.08	9,816.92
Total allocated programme costs 1st main activity							239,300	109,442	129,858
TOTAL 1ST MAIN ACTIVITY							725,700	215,880	509,820

2nd Main Activity	Promoting entrepreneurship among young people			unit	Unit cost	# units 2016	Direct programme costs 2016
Direct programme costs 2nd main activity
	Activity 2.1	Introduce and improve entrepreneurship modules in curricula of higher and vocational education institutions		curricula	40,000	1.2	48,000	35.33	47,964.67
	Activity 2.2	Introduce and improve internship programmes at higher and vocational education institutions		programme	22,500	1	22,500	0.00	22,500.00
	Activity 2.3	Organize summer universities in enterpreneurship at higher and vocational education institutions		summer school	45,000	1	45,000	0.00	45,000.00
	Activity 2.4	Organize Global Entrepreneurship Week events at higher and vocational education institutions		event	5,000	2	10,000	2,977.75	7,022.25
		Activity costs of partner applicants		lump sum	20,000	1	20,000	106.61	19,893.39

Total direct programme costs 2nd main activity							145,500	3,120	142,380

Allocated programme costs 2nd main activity
		Spark local Project Management Fees		days	400	22	8,800	2,100.00	6,700.00
		Spark local Financial Officer Fees		days	250	17	4,250	1,437.50	2,812.50
		Spark local Project Officer Fees		days	250	24	6,000	2,187.50	3,812.50
		Partner applicant Project Management Fees		days	300	50	15,000	0.00	15,000.00
		Spark International Project Management Fees		days	875	13	11,375	15,203.14	-3,828.14
		Spark International Head of Finance Fees		days	850	2	1,700	1,700.00	0.00
		Spark International Controller Fees		days	650	4	2,600	4,509.42	-1,909.42
								0.00
		M&amp;E employee		days	250	8	2,000	732.50	1,267.50
		Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Coordinator 		days	650	6	3,900	3,168.76	731.24
								0.00
		Travel costs		month	350	12	4,200	4,170.90	29.10

Total allocated programme costs 2nd main activity							59,825	35,210	24,615
TOTAL 2ND MAIN ACTIVITY							205,325	38,329	166,996

Total	Directe programme costs						631,900	109,558	522,342
Totaal 	Allocated programme costs						299,125	144,651	154,474
	TOTAL TUNISIA YEAR 1						931,025	254,210	676,815
* New entrepreneurs (A) 30% and existing entrepreneurs (SMEs) (B) 70%.
							check	254,210


LEAD - Somalia:


		Budget on Activity level
		First year: 2016
		Somalia

	Approved budget 2016								Spent in 2016	Budget left as of 31/12/2016
	1st main activity	Creating sustainable employment for young people		New (A) or established (B) businesses *	Unit	Unit cost	# units 2016	Direct programme costs 2016	Spent 31/12/2016	Budget left 31/12/2016
	Direct programme costs: 1st main activity
LEAD 01		Activity 1.1	Conduct additional (market) research studies in identified growth sectors	A+B	study	5,000	5	25,000	2,868.48	22,131.52
LEAD 02		Activity 1.2	Recruitment of successful existing and new entrepreneurs through existing entrepreneurship initiatives	A	selection	10	150	1,500	20,787.07	-19,287.07
LEAD 35		Activity 1.2.1	Recruitment of successful existing entrepreneurs through existing entrepreneurship initiatives	B		50	500	25,000	0.00	25,000.00
LEAD 03		Activity 1.3	Expand existing and establish new business incubators	A+B	lump sum	80,000	1	80,000	40,851.50	39,148.50
LEAD 04		Activity 1.4	Improve services of local (financial) institutions and business service providers and make these gender sensitive	A+B	business intervention	10,500	3	31,500	0.00	31,500.00
LEAD 05		Activity 1.5	Development of entrepreneurial skills of existing and new entrepreneurs through training and coaching	A	business intervention	650	35	22,750	136,480.00	-113,730.00
LEAD 36		Activity 1.5.1	Development of entrepreneurial skills of existing entrepreneurs through training and coaching	B		1,125	100	112,500	0.00	112,500.00
LEAD 06		Activity 1.6	Facilitate the access to finance for exising and new enterpreneurs through guarantee funds	A	loan	2,250	5	11,250	0.00	11,250.00
LEAD 37		Activity 1.6.1	Facilitate the access to finance for existing enterpreneurs through guarantee funds	B		23,600	2	47,200	0.00	47,200.00
LEAD 07		Activity 1.7	Facilitate local SMEs in the value chain of multinational or large local businesses	A+B	business	7,650	5	38,250	0.00	38,250.00
LEAD 08		Activity 1.8	Promote successful young entrepreneurs (largely women) in popular media	A+B	entrepreneur	2,500	4	10,000	0.00	10,000.00
LEAD 09			Activity costs of partner applicants	A+B	lump sum	35,000	1	35,000	93,700.00	-58,700.00
	Total direct programme costs of 1st main activity							439,950	294,687	145,263

	Allocated programme costs 1st main activity
LEAD 10			Spark local Project Management Fees		days	400	98	39,200	8,968.75	30,231.25
LEAD 11			Spark local Financial Officer Fees		days	250	56	14,000	34,062.50	-20,062.50
LEAD 12			Spark local Project Officer Fees		days	250	105	26,250	31,281.25	-5,031.25
LEAD 13			Partner applicant Project Management Fees		days	300	112	33,600	2,016.67	31,583.33
LEAD 14			Spark International Project Management Fees		days	875	45.5	39,813	13,836.00	25,976.50
LEAD 15			Spark International Head of Finance Fees		days	850	10.5	8,925	7,862.50	1,062.50
LEAD 16			Spark International Controller Fees		days	650	14	9,100	11,090.66	-1,990.66
									0.00
LEAD 17			M&amp;E employee		days	250	28	7,000	10,000.00	-3,000.00
LEAD 18			Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Coordinator 		days	650	21	13,650	9,506.26	4,143.74
									0.00
LEAD 19			Travel Costs		month	1,225	12	14,700	15,631.32	-931.32
	Total allocated programme costs 1st main activity							206,238	144,256	61,982
	TOTAL 1ST MAIN ACTIVITY							646,188	438,943	207,245

	2nd Main Activity	Promoting entrepreneurship among young people			unit	Unit cost	# units 2016	Direct programme costs
	Direct programme costs 2nd main activity
LEAD 20		Activity 2.1	Introduce and improve entrepreneurship modules in curricula of higher and vocational education institutions		curricula	50,000	2	100,000	3,588.55	96,411.45
LEAD 21		Activity 2.2	Introduce and improve internship programmes at higher and vocational education institutions		programme	25,000	1	25,000	25,000.00	0.00
LEAD 22		Activity 2.3	Organize summer universities in enterpreneurship at higher and vocational education institutions		summer school	50,000	1	50,000	50,400.00	-400.00
LEAD 23		Activity 2.4	Organize Global Entrepreneurship Week events at higher and vocational education institutions		event	5,000	3	15,000	15,000.00	0.00
LEAD 24			Activity costs of partner applicants		lump sum	15,000	1	15,000	0.00	15,000.00
	Total direct programme costs 2nd main activity							205,000	93,989	111,011

	Allocated programme costs 2nd main activity
LEAD 25			Spark local Project Management Fees		days	400	42	16,800	14,900.00	1,900.00
LEAD 26			Spark local Financial Officer Fees		days	250	24	6,000	14,000.00	-8,000.00
LEAD 27			Spark local Project Officer Fees		days	250	45	11,250	14,906.25	-3,656.25
LEAD 28			Partner applicant Project Management Fees		days	300	48	14,400	0.00	14,400.00
LEAD 29			Spark International Project Management Fees		days	875	19.5	17,063	4,812.51	12,249.99
LEAD 30			Spark International Head of Finance Fees		days	850	4.5	3,825	2,656.25	1,168.75
LEAD 31			Spark International Controller Fees		days	650	6	3,900	4,671.90	-771.90
									0.00	0.00
LEAD 32			M&amp;E employee		days	250	12	3,000	0.00	3,000.00
LEAD 33			Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Coordinator 		days	650	9	5,850	4,062.51	1,787.49
									0.00	0.00
LEAD 34			Travel costs		month	525	12	6,300	4,959.39	1,340.61
	Total allocated programme costs 2nd main activity							88,388	64,969	23,419
	TOTAL 2ND MAIN ACTIVITY							293,388	158,957	134,430

	Total	Directe programme costs						644,950	388,676	256,274
	Totaal 	Allocated programme costs						294,625	209,225	85,400
		TOTAL SOMALIA YEAR 1						939,575	597,900	341,675
	* New entrepreneurs (A) 30% and existing entrepreneurs (SMEs) (B) 70%.
								check	597,900


LEAD - Libya:


		Budget on Activity level
		First year: 2016
		Libia

	Approved budget 2016								Spent in 2016	Budget left as of 31/12/2016
	1st main activity	Creating sustainable employment for young people		New (A) or established (B) businesses *	Unit	Unit cost	# units 2016	Direct programme costs 2016	Spent 31/12/2016	Left Balance 31/12/2016
	Direct programme costs: 1st main activity
LEAD 01		Activity 1.1	Conduct additional (market) research studies in identified growth sectors	A+B	study	5,000	3	15,000	89.50	14,910.50
LEAD 02		Activity 1.2	Recruitment of successful existing and new entrepreneurs through existing entrepreneurship initiatives	A	selection	10	75	750	92.44	657.56
LEAD 35		Activity 1.2.1	Recruitment of successful existing entrepreneurs through existing entrepreneurship initiatives	B		50	175	8,750	0.00	8,750.00
LEAD 03		Activity 1.3	Expand existing and establish new business incubators	A+B	lump sum	77,500	0.4	31,000	5,106.98	25,893.02
LEAD 04		Activity 1.4	Improve services of local (financial) institutions and business service providers and make these gender sensitive	A+B	business intervention	8,500	2	17,000	0.00	17,000.00
LEAD 05		Activity 1.5	Development of entrepreneurial skills of existing and new entrepreneurs through training and coaching	A	business intervention	675	11	7,425	0.00	7,425.00
LEAD 36		Activity 1.5.1	Development of entrepreneurial skills of existing entrepreneurs through training and coaching	B		975	35	34,125	0.00	34,125.00
LEAD 06		Activity 1.6	Facilitate the access to finance for exising and new enterpreneurs through guarantee funds	A	loan	2,100	2	4,200	0.00	4,200.00
LEAD 37		Activity 1.6.1	Facilitate the access to finance for existing enterpreneurs through guarantee funds	B		21,000	1	21,000	0.00	21,000.00
LEAD 07		Activity 1.7	Facilitate local SMEs in the value chain of multinational or large local businesses	A+B	business	7,150	2	14,300	0.00	14,300.00
LEAD 08		Activity 1.8	Promote successful young entrepreneurs (largely women) in popular media	A+B	entrepreneur	2,500	4	10,000	0.00	10,000.00
LEAD 09			Activity costs of partner applicants	A+B	lump sum	13,333	1	13,333	24,395.90	-11,062.57
	Total direct programme costs of 1st main activity							176,883	29,685	147,199

	Allocated programme costs 1st main activity
LEAD 10			Spark local Project Management Fees		days	400	34	13,600	12,300.00	1,300.00
LEAD 11			Spark local Financial Officer Fees		days	250	22	5,500	3,468.75	2,031.25
LEAD 12			Spark local Project Officer Fees		days	250	44	11,000	2,218.75	8,781.25
LEAD 13			Partner applicant Project Management Fees		days	300	48	14,400	2,016.66	12,383.34
LEAD 14			Spark International Project Management Fees		days	875	18	15,750	9,078.16	6,671.84
LEAD 15			Spark International Head of Finance Fees		days	850	3.2	2,720	3,400.00	-680.00
LEAD 16			Spark International Controller Fees		days	650	6.4	4,160	4,468.76	-308.76
									0.00
LEAD 17			M&amp;E employee		days	250	16	4,000	1,531.25	2,468.75
LEAD 18			Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Coordinator 		days	650	12	7,800	8,084.38	-284.38
									0.00
LEAD 19			Travel Costs		month	700	12	8,400	3,543.21	4,856.79
	Total allocated programme costs 1st main activity							87,330	50,110	37,220
	TOTAL 1ST MAIN ACTIVITY							264,213	79,795	184,419

	2nd Main Activity	Promoting entrepreneurship among young people			unit	unit cost	# units 2016	Direct programme costs 2016
	Direct programme costs 2nd main activity
LEAD 20		Activity 2.1	Introduce and improve entrepreneurship modules in curricula of higher and vocational education institutions		curricula	36,000	6	216,000	0.00	216,000.00
LEAD 21		Activity 2.2	Introduce and improve internship programmes at higher and vocational education institutions		programme	20,000	1	20,000	0.00	20,000.00
LEAD 22		Activity 2.3	Organize summer universities in enterpreneurship at higher and vocational education institutions		summer school	37,500	1	37,500	0.00	37,500.00
LEAD 23		Activity 2.4	Organize Global Entrepreneurship Week events at higher and vocational education institutions		event	5,000	5	25,000	5,390.44	19,609.56
LEAD 24			Activity costs of partner applicants		lump sum	20,000	1	20,000	0.00	20,000.00
	Total direct programme costs 2nd main activity							318,500	5,390	313,110

	Allocated programme costs 2nd main activity
LEAD 25			Spark local Project Management Fees		days	400	51	20,400	12,150.00	8,250.00
LEAD 26			Spark local Financial Officer Fees		days	250	33	8,250	4,810.68	3,439.32
LEAD 27			Spark local Project Officer Fees		days	250	66	16,500	8,781.25	7,718.75
LEAD 28			Partner applicant Project Management Fees		days	300	72	21,600	0.00	21,600.00
LEAD 29			Spark International Project Management Fees		days	875	27	23,625	7,929.70	15,695.30
LEAD 30			Spark International Head of Finance Fees		days	850	4.8	4,080	2,125.00	1,955.00
LEAD 31			Spark International Controller Fees		days	650	9.6	6,240	5,281.29	958.71
									0.00
LEAD 32			M&amp;E employee		days	250	24	6,000	2,218.75	3,781.25
LEAD 33			Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning Coordinator 		days	650	18	11,700	2,600.01	9,099.99
									0.00	0.00
LEAD 34			Travel costs		month	1,050	12	12,600	4,363.33	8,236.67
	Total allocated programme costs 2nd main activity							130,995	50,260	80,735
	TOTAL 2ND MAIN ACTIVITY							449,495	55,650	393,845

	Total	Directe programme costs						495,383	35,075	460,308
	Totaal 	Allocated programme costs						218,325	100,370	117,955
		TOTAL LIBIA YEAR 1						713,708	135,445	578,263
	* New entrepreneurs (A) 30% and existing entrepreneurs (SMEs) (B) 70%.
								check	135,445



For the Audit Report please click on the following link:

http://www.spark-online.org/iati/2016_Lead_Financial_Report_checked_by_Auditors.pdf</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anthony Gonzalez</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>a.gonzalez@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adriana Salazar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>a.salazar@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delinah Kalshoven</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>d.kalshoven@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karen Blanken</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>k.blanken@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Michel Richter</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>m.r.richter@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nic van der Jagt</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>n.jagt@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sven Pauka</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>s.pauka@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Todor Panovski</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>t.panovski@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yannick du Pont</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>y.du.pont@spark-online.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beatrice Murekatete</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Blerta Kelmendi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dragan Tomic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mirjana Krsmanovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mirko Topalovic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nebojsa Simic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Richard van Hoolwerf</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tom Luckie Gwagaee</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valentina Qarri</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Verica Koracevic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam
Van Diemenstraat 70
1013 CN  AMSTERDAM</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LY" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Libya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunisia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">7497775</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
