<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFSII.KOS.STIKK 2012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICT Value Chain</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partner local CSOs; Entrepreneurs and SMEs in ICT sector; youth engaged in ICT sector and women</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project objective(s):
The aim of our project is to:
Goal 1. Capacity building of the Association
Sub-goals:
Strengthen manpower/human capacity (management)
Strengthen quality of services &amp; access to information
Marketing of Association &amp; building trust

Goal 2. Support young entrepreneurs in starting up new businesses, thus increasing job creation opportunities  Poverty alleviation
Sub-goals:
Stimulate cooperation among entrepreneurs and other stakeholders (in a value chain)
Finding clients for entrepreneurs/matchmaking for job creation
Identifying niche markets &amp; niche services  focus on comparative advantage
Develop investment schemes &amp; create incentive structures for investment


Goal 3. Support in investment promotion strategy in close cooperation with the Government  Policymaking
Sub-goals:
Support  multi-stakeholder networks, and business to government relations (B to G)
STIKK as one-stop-shop for investors &amp; entrepreneurs (within the Innovation Centre Kosovo)
Support incentives for start-ups
Lobby sector associations by identifying issues &amp; recommendations in different manners (round tables, papers, showing benefits...)
Open attitude towards marginalized communities: there is no difference in business</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outputs:
These activities will result in:

2 training opportunities within the year and if possible provide on the job training on specific topics.
 At least 2 new services to STIKK membership
For the first year, at least 6 start-ups with innovative ideas will receive loans. This is particularly important knowing that Kosovo has limited sources of finance and that the only sources of financing currently include bank loans at very high interest rates. The loans to be provided under the project will be at affordable conditions for businesses. Venture Capital Sources: The project staff will create relationships with a range of equity finance sources (i.e. business angels and venture capital) domestically or internationallywho may have an interest in either receiving financing proposals or playing an active role in coaching and financing high potential projects. The longer term aim would be to develop a formal business angel/venture capital network focusing on innovation.
The Business Tuesday event will be held every first Tuesday of the month. There will be 12 events of this kind organized during the entire year. The event will serve as an arena for incubator companies, investors and international businesses.
Three startup businesses with innovative ideas will have the opportunity to participate in innovation fairs. This will provide the opportunity for startups, students with innovative ideas and companies to share examples of their products, approaches or practices and to disseminate them more widely. The participants cost share will be preparation of their promotion material.
Within the Innovation Centre, coaching and mentoring will be part of the assistance for start ups and small businesses. Using existing STIKK database of consultants, ICK will engage qualified individuals with the purpose of advising and mentoring innovators and entrepreneurs through the business side to developing and commercializing an innovative project. This activity will be supported by Norwegian financial contribution.
Development of at least one policy paper on improvement of business environment. This activity will serve all businesses (including the ones from North Mitrovica, who are registered and are operating in accordance with Kosovo legislation).
At least one regional ICT event

Project outcomes:
These outputs will lead to:

Participation in trainings/and on the job training opportunities. This has been very productive in the past, however given the young age of staff, further professional development opportunities are needed as to enhance capacity building and increase the overall performance.
Members would feel more satisfied with the services provided by the association, thus helping the association maintain its current members, but also gain new members. This would at the same time improve the financial stability of the association and the overall sustainability.
Beneficiaries will be able to expand their businesses by implementing new business ideas, and by introducing new products. At the same time, eventual expansion of the businesses will help create new jobs, but also enable the Kosovo companies to develop their business process outsourcing opportunities.
The aim of the Business Tuesday is to match ideas with the potential investors. Creation of a widespread practice for the businesses to enhance business dialogue. Within the Business Tuesday event we intend to contribute to achieving the following aims:
- The internationalization of the domestic business
- Continuity of attracting investments into innovative businesses
Participation in innovation fairs-This is particularly significant knowing that Kosovo lacks events in which young creative people could present their innovative ideas. Promotion of their ideas would also help them further develop these ideas by finding potential investors or donors who would be ready to support them. Their cost share will cover the promotion material for a fair.
Start ups located in the incubator of the Innovation Centre will benefit from the experience of the assistant team composed from experienced professionals within the ICT sector. They will be receiving coaching and mentoring sessions which is a necessary tool in achieving the best results.
Based on the &#x201C;Kosovo Business Agenda&#x201D;, a survey conducted by American Chamber of Commerce in Kosovo (STIKK was one of the main stakeholders in this survey), most important issues will be identified and a policy paper will be drafted on that particular issue o or group of issues, by making a detailed analysis, rendering conclusions and recommendations. This policy paper will then be addressed to the relevant institutions.
The project will also include at least one regional ICT event, which will enable sharing the experience, best practices and know how between the regional counterparts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STIKK (Kosovo Association of Information and Communication Technology</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vjollca Cavolli</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>vcavolli@stikk-ks.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STIKK (Kosovo Association of Information and Communication Technology
Pashko Vasa Str 22
10000  PRISTINA
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">174558</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.stikk-ks.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
