<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-YED2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Entrepreneurship Development   (YED)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.Increased capacity of BSCs for future self sustainability  through acquired skills on Project on  Proposal Writing	 BSC staff successfully trained	3	
1.2. Increased capacity of BSCs for future self sustainability  through acquired skills on  HR and Business Communication	BSC staff successfully trained	3	
1.3.Increased capacity of BSCs for future self sustainability  through acquired skills on on Business Plan Writing	BSC staff successfully trained	3	
1.4.Increased capacity of BSCs for future self sustainability  through acquired skills on  Public Relations 	BSC staff successfully trained	3
	
1.5. Increased capacity of BSCs for future self-sustainability  through acquired skills on best practices in field of youth entrepreneurship development	BSC staff successfully trained 	3	
2.1. Promotional campaign  on program details launched 	# of potential beneficiaries  from targeted municipalities participated on info session 	150	
2.2.Organized two business plan preparation trainings per year, 3 modules in 3 municipalities, each module lasts  5 days)	# potential and existing entrepreneurs form 3 municipalities certified 	45 (10 women)	
2.3.Organized  training on basic accounting and finance issues for local potential and existing entrepreneurs in 3 municipalities (3 modules, each module lasts two days)	# of potential and existing entrepreneurs form 3 municipalities certified	45 (10 women)	
2.4. Organized  training on marketing for local potential and existing entrepreneurs in 3 municipalities (3 modules, each module lasts two days)	# of potential and existing entrepreneurs form 3 municipalities certified	35 (7 women)	
2.5. Organized specialized  training on hospitality service improvement and rural tourism for local potential and existing entrepreneurs in 3 municipalities (each module lasts 5 days)	# of potential and existing entrepreneurs from 3 municipalities certified 	60 (10 women)	
2.6. Organized specialized  training on agricultural production  for local potential and existing entrepreneurs in 3 municipalities (3 modules, each module lasts 3 days)	# of potential and existing entrepreneurs form 3 municipalities certified 	35 (7 women)	
2.7. Organized specialized  training on Global Gap Standards  (3 modules each module lasts 2 days)	# of potential and existing entrepreneurs form 3 municipalities certified 	30(5 women)	
2.8. Organized specialized  training on SME Management  (6 modules each module lasts 5 days)	# of potential and existing entrepreneurs form 3 municipalities certified	45 (7 women)	
2.9.Organized Youth Leadership and Entrepreneurship Program for unemployed youth people in 3 municipalities (each module lasts 5 days)
 (6 modules each module lasts 2 days) 	# of youth from six municipalities certified	60(10 women)	
2.10. Organized regional business fair  	# of businesses from three municipalities participate
# of visitors 	60 (7 women)

500  	
2.11. Organized participations of BCS beneficiaries on BPC under SPARK loans fund.	# of business plan proved by jury	30 (6 women)	
2.12.  Provided technical support to SME growth in targeted municipalities 	# of SMEs supported through consultancy service 	9 (1 women)	
3.1.Developed questionnaire and conducted in three municipalities to identify business barriers, organized round tables with LED officers in three municipalities and providing technical support in implementation of local SME development strategies	# of roundtable held	6</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BCS staff capacity development increased
	
Increased opportunity for developing new and expanding existing business 	
Thought the supported SMEs open possibility for increasing job position and employing new workers	
Successful matchmakings with investors, not related to SPARK guarantee fund. 	
Business barriers identified and process of lobbying for removing started</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite economic growth of about 3-4% p.a. over recent years and high levels of transfer payments from donors and from Kosovo nationals living abroad, the living conditions of Kosovos population have improved only marginally. With a gross domestic product (GDP) per capita of &#x20AC;2.721 (2012), the country remains one of the poorest in Europe. Kosovo has the weakest employment track record in Europe: the general unemployment rate has reached 48 percent while youth unemployment rate reached 53,3%.  
Sustainable economic development and specific actions to address the high unemployment rates, especially in the rural areas, are a priority in Kosovo. This is especially true for areas populated by minority communities, located in Eastern Kosovo, where statistics indicate even higher levels of unemployment. Adding to the problem is also the lacking of know- how and related skills in rural areas of Kosovo. In fact, Kosovo Statistics Office indicates that 90% of rural population under the age of 30 has not completed high school.Statistical Office of Kosovo.Agriculture Household Survey 2007. Available at: 
http://www.ks-gov.net/ESK/eng/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;task=cat_view&amp;gid=9&amp;Itemid=8 Under such circumstances,  vocational education of rural population and financial support  that would lead to the improved competitiveness of local businesses is essential for achieving sustainable rural development and growth.
The action under this proposal will respond to the needs by increasing of economic potentials of Kosovo East  communities through creating favourable conditions for development and support of businesses. Areas targeted by this Action are Klokot/Kllokot, &#x160;trpce/Sht&#xEB;rpc&#xEB;, and Partesh/Partes municipalities. Total estimated population of these municipalities is close to 40000 people with over 70% being Serbian minority population. For minorities, virtually the only opportunities for employment are in the few socially-owned enterprises (SOEs) that are still operating, in international organisations and NGOs and, to a lesser extent, in small private enterprises. In such an economic environment, the need for assistance in the creation of employment opportunities and sustainable livelihoods is clear from the social aspect. The action under this proposal will encourage self employment trough various skills training  to provide  the opportunity to youth in province to have their leadership, interpersonal and entrepreneurship skills honed through different skills models. Small business in Kosovo currently lack easy access to finance at competitive rates, which acts as an obstacle to starting small firms. This is particularly true for women entrepreneurs and also youth, who often have good business ideas but fail due to lack of funding as potential entrepreneurs are not able to access commercial loans due to a lack of equity. Similarly, micro-finance institutions have not extended a significant amount in loans to minorities and they tend to concentrate on established businesses. As minorities have less access to the job market and less freedom of movement, it is necessary to assist minorities in developing the SME sector in their communities.
The project builds clearly on the activities of the SPARK delivered EURED1 project in that it consolidates further the relationships developed with the Rregional Development Agency, minority communities in Kosovo East Region  and local authorities. It adds further capacity building to the existing business support centres and aims to establish sustainable support to business development. 
This action builds upon lessons learned from the previous BSC Strpce  and BSC Novo Brdo activities delivered under EURED1 and YED project in 2013, it takes some of the best and most successful parts of the past project and expands their delivery into other target regions and target beneficiaries.
The initiative under this action clearly aims to inspire business development through joint efforts of  BSC Strpce and BSC Novo Brdo within minority communities in Kosovo East and Center Region with focused more targeted and better quality business support service, including the provision of reliable information, market research, start-up support, incubation and product development. However, what remains to be done is to develop an entrepreneurial culture and to provide assurance of business growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BSC Strpce</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natalija Janicevic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>n.janicevic@bsc-red.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BSC Strpce
Municipal building ,Firs t floor, office no 73000
Firs t floor, office no.13
KOSOVO
Servi&#xEB;</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">77050</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.bsckosovo.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
