<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-MFS II IUG 2011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building of BTI</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Incubation Staff and services.
Fresh Graduates from Business Administration, Engineering and Information Faculties.
Youth and Female entrepreneurs
Existing SMEs and incubated start-ups
Senior students of the universities.
Stakeholders of business development and entrepreneurship support sector</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Goal:

The major goal of the project is to get a role in reducing poverty and unemployment among female and youth entrepreneurs through encouraging them to start their own sustainable businesses by transforming the innovative ideas of the entrepreneurs in Gaza strip into small businesses and projects through providing integrated packages of business development professional services. This will lead definitely to more developed economy, less unemployment rates, new sustainable jobs creation, new products and services and more strategic linkages between business development programs with the local institutions.

Project Objectives:

The project seeks to achieve the following objectives:

Developing the business development services provided by BTI through building the capacity of the business incubation staff, strengthening the facilities and services of BTI.
Supporting and promoting of potential entrepreneurs who desire to start their own businesses and to remove the business barriers and fresh graduates.
Strengthening the existing and incubated SMEs to have a step forwards growing and sustaining their businesses.
Formulating academic procedure to enhance entrepreneurship among senior university students as a part of the study plan.
Getting a role in promoting the concept of entrepreneurship support among the active stakeholders at Gaza Strip.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Results:

Developed business development services through strengthening the capacity of BTI by new 6 units, increasing knowledge in business incubation principles and services of 3 business incubator staff, forming a board of 4 local industry coaches and mentors, and improving facilities and services provided by the incubator.
High level of knowledge transferring and exchange through strong, informative and interactive website of Business and Technology Incubator.
Increased engagement of marginalized clients in entrepreneurship and innovation activities through allocating 70 % of project activities for women, youth, refugees and other marginalized clients.
A valuable increase of the incubator returns from training programs after the project period so that the incubator will continue offering business and technical training courses.
Increased knowledge and practice of entrepreneurship among the fresh graduates and entrepreneurs through delivering entrepreneurial development training program for about 75 participants of the business plan competition.
Creating more than 20 jobs through approving 6 winners of the business plan competition to start their businesses and 6 existed SMEs in the incubator to grow their companies.
Increased employability of those that were trained or coached the by the incubator through starting about 20 % of the trainees and SMEs their sustainable businesses.
High success rate of the SMEs through providing mentoring and coaching program so that about 70% of the started or grown SMEs are still in operation after the project period.
Great interaction between entrepreneurs and industry leaders through providing a wide area of transferring experiences by implementing the first Entrepreneurship Development Camp.
An increased level of engagement of policy makers and stakeholders in entrepreneurship support though decreasing the legal procedure of registering SMEs, promoting supporting entrepreneurship as a tool for economic development among the government and NGOs.
Formulated procedure for entrepreneurship promotion through developing Entrepreneurship Development curriculum which will be developed at IUG and certified as an elective course.
A well-prepared proposal and study plan of a one-year professional diploma for entrepreneurship which will be offer by the Community Development Institute and Business and Technology Incubator at IUG.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-09-22" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-09-22" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q3</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business and Technology Incubator of the Islamic University of Gaza</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aiman Abu Samra</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>aasamra@iugaza.edu.ps</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business and Technology Incubator of the Islamic University of Gaza
P.O. Box
GAZA
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-09-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">75374</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.bti.ps/en/index.php?page=view&amp;id=62">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
