<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-TAMSS 2016 LEAD Tun</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEAD-TAMSS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Like the majority of the countries in the Middle East and North Africa , MSMEs (Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises) are increasingly recognized as drivers of economic growth in Tunisia. World bank recent studies have shown that in middle income countries, SMEs contribute up to half of employment and as much as a third of GDP.  Nonetheless, the high percentage of unemployment among youth, mainly University graduates, in Tunisia is creating instability led by series of upheavals initiated by a desperate majority of young men and women who are lacking opportunities but also awareness and skills to move from a state of &#x201C;waiting&#x201D; to &#x201C;acting&#x201D;. In addition, the high unemployment rate is the result of not only a heritage of &#x201C;state based&#x201D; and controlled entrepreneurial system but also an educational system that has been for many years completely disconnected from the labor market, more focused on information as opposed to knowledge and skills development.
In its 2015 report &#x201C;Investing in Youth  Tunisia, Strengthening the Employability of Youth during the transition to a Green Economy&#x201D; OECD describes youth unemployment in Tunisia as &#x201C;a true social tragedy that urgently needs to be addressed,&#x201D; demoralizing and financially starving young generations by depriving them of opportunities to participate in the economy. Unemployment also disproportionately affects women and those living in the certain parts of the country, causing an array social issues arising from gender and regional inequality&#xA0;&#xBB;.

Consequently, in order to face the raising number of the unemployed different players in the post revolution period have been focusing on MSMEs launching and job seekers skills development. However, which MSMEs and which skills are needed by the different  regions remain the questions that have not been seriously addressed yet. Lack of disaggregated information about the unemployed, priority sectors, recruitment needs, current and future investment plans in a defined region are missing.
Thus our program will focus on defining recruitment needs priorities as well as priority sectors in Elkef and Kairouan.

On the level of enterprise development for job creation surprisingly, the greatest challenge facing any financial innovator seeking to target the MSMEs market is the generally low level of financial awareness among those running and future small businesses. Often today, it falls to development banks and other public and nonprofit sector institutions to provide the necessary technical assistance and financial education. Although great efforts have been made in few regions in Tunisia to enhance financial literacy among the business community mainly in underserved regions, success to date has been very limited. This could be explained by the fact that financial literacy is only one of the reasons  behind the failure of future and current MSMEs in securing existing funds.

Thus the project will provide series of training workshops to current and future identified and selected  entrepreneurs as needed by a variety of production sectors and services sectors that correspond with each governorate&apos;s specifities and the target women and youth segment on subjects such as entrepreneurship, financial literacy, marketing , loan seeking, customer services, communication, life skills development etc, as well as technical training and assistance based on the assessment results.

As for the selected most employable among the  job seekers, the project will enhance their employability and raise their recruitment chances by providing education and training for employability based on the mapping, assessment and round tables with future recruiters.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1: Obtain business plans and ideas of new young entrepreneurs and existing ones
Indicator: Total business plans created and reviewed
Target: 60

Output 2:Train and coach existing and new entrepreneurs
Indicator:Total start-ups by young women and existing projects reinforcement
Target:100


Output 3: New enterprises are set up
Indicator: Total SMEs created or expanded
Target: 2 created-10 expanded

Output 4: Start and reinforce businesses in the chain of multinationals
Indicator:Total SMEs&apos; partnerships  with multinationals
Target:</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The beneficiaries are already identified by the Lead program. The LEAD-TAMSS portion of the program will be targeting women and youth aged between 18 and 35 years old with at least 70% women. TAMSS had already a good network of partners and a database of future women beneficiaries in both El kef and Kairouan where the activities will take place</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q2</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">70201</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
