<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-CEED2015 Enhan Entrepren</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Entrepreneurship and Business Growth in Kosovo- Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 Delivery of Capacity Building/Practical growth-oriented training tailored for a company&apos;s level of development, focusing on the knowledge and skills required to manage a growing company. Number of Applications for the training program.100 (30 women)
Number of trained existing entrepreneurs (that received a certificate) - 70 (15 women)

2.2 Delivery of Business Planning training   to existing MSMEs  on how to better develop their Business Plans for growing their company
Number of Applications to receive the Business Plan training - 300 (40 women)
Number of trained existing entrepreneurs - 150 (20 women)

2.3 Conducting Needs Assessment to Entrepreneurs part of MFS II project to identify(previous Start-ups) to identify and tailor Business Support Services that would accelerate their business growth.
Total number of entrepreneurs part of  MFS II  project - 30
Number of Entrepreneurs undertaking the Needs Assessment - 22

2.4 Delivery of Business Support Services to existing entrepreneurs part of MFS II and to new entrepreneurs who want to grow the businesses in new local/regional markets. (small market analysis, finding a partner in local and regional markets, while utilizing CEED&apos;s regional network, pre-sales services, etc)
Number of Applications to receive Business Support Services - 80
Number of Entrepreneurs who have received Business Support Services - 60

2.5 Conducting Pitching/Presentation training for entrepreneurs who want to present their Business Plan/idea
Number of participants receiving training for pitching - 70

2.6 Conducting the Business Plan Competition
The number of business plans and other business type applications approved for Business Plan Competition - 60

2.7 Matching of Entrepreneurs with Financial Institutions
Number of entrepreneurs obtained financing - 10

2.8 Local/Regional Business Conferences/ Business to Business (B2B) events organized
Number of B2B Events - 2 local/regional
Number of participants in B2B events - 200

2.9 Promotional Events to promote project activities/outcomes
Number of Events organized - 2
Number of participants - 200



BiD Network

3.0 Collecting business summary profiles (including business plans, financial plans), and promotion and marketing through different media channels
Number of collected business plan and financial plan for exposure to attract investments - 60
Number of SMEs reached to obtain business profile ( Web-site hits, promotional e-mails, workshop briefings, social media, etc) - 3000
Number of website hits on Country Page to view information on investments - 1500

3.1 Training Sessions for entrepreneurs &#x201C;Access to Finance&#x201D; with investors and financial institutions
Number of training session organized - 1
Number of participants in the training session - 25

3.2 Business lunch organized for entrepreneurs with investors and financial institutions
Number of business lunch organized  - 2
Number of participants in the business lunch - 50

3.3 Matching entrepreneurs finance-ready&amp;investors
Number of plans selected for BiD Network matchmaking acceleration program - 12
Number of Finance-ready plans - 8
Number of matching introductions - 10

3.4 International investor conference/forum   exposing and pitching to investors
Number of participants in the investor conference/forum - 65

3.5 (combined with SPARK Activity 2.5): Conducting Pitching/Presentation training for entrepreneurs who want to present their Business Plan/idea
Number of participants receiving training for pitching - 70

3.6 (combined with SPARK Activity 2.2): Delivery of Business Planning training   to existing MSMEs  on how to better develop their Business Plans for growing their company
Number of trained existing entrepreneurs  -150

3.7 (combined with SPARK Activity 2.9): Promotional Event to promote project activities/outcomes Number of Events organized - 2
Number of participants - 200</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Competitiveness constraints/opportunities at the sector level, and prospects for effectively addressing key employment and poverty alleviation priorities will be considered under this project. The focus will be on MSMEs on  the service sector  which accounts for the largest share of employment in Kosovo (70% of which 30% are public jobs),  industry (22% including construction) and agriculture (8%). The focus will be on the largest private subsectors in services (hospitality, healthcare and ICT), industry (energy, textile, wood, metal processing, and construction) as well as agri-business and FMCGs (Fast Moving Consumer Goods).

Kosovo is a poor country in a region of comparative prosperity and faces numerous challenges to economic growth. GDP growth is declining from 4.5% in 2011 to 2.7% in 2012, and all forecasts project low growth going forward.  Infrastructure in roads and utilities is increasingly strained, and the growth of SMEs is being constrained by a &quot;not-yet truly attractive business climate&quot; according to the World Bank Country Manager.  Kosovo businesses must compete with neighbouring markets much more advanced than their own; imports are consistently over 53% of GDP.  Based on the SME Strategy Development of Kosova 2012-2016, due to an unfavourable business environment and in the absence of a creative entrepreneurialculture, Kosovo lacks fast growing innovative firms, which are the main contributors to jobcreation in western developed economies. Above 50% of all SMEs are operating in the trade sector characterized by low and unproductiveinvestments. This pattern, followed by a &#x201C;me&#x2010;too&#x201D; approach to business start&#x2010;ups, limits thecapacity of the SME sector to generate jobs.
For the existing SMES in different sectors, multiple constraints include the inability to scale-up, obtain financing, to link into new markets, to integrate at firm/industry/supply/market levels, to build strong interest/stakeholder groups for collaboration.
In terms of policy development, the SME PolicyIndex 2009 report shows that Kosovo, for a variety of reasons, is still in the phase of completingthe basic institutional, legal and regulatory requirements underpinning SME policy.
As such, Kosovo hasgood prospects for growth. There is a comparative advantage in the labor market and a large pool of available labour with 31% (World Bank) unemployment and another 13% inactive.  With good markets in the region and huge opportunities in import substitution, there is an opportunity to rapidly increase employment within sectors of the Kosovo economy by addressing critical competitiveness issues, and workforce deficiencies.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises (MSMEs) are the direct beneficiaries of the project, with special focus on marginalized groups.  Two types of MSMEs will be targeted: 1. Developed MSMEs who are matured companies, and have high growth prospects. 2. Developing MSMEs who are in the initial growth stages, and are young companies. They will benefit from project activities in strengthening their organizational and management capacities that brings to a more efficient business performance and higher business growth and in return leads to more jobs being created.  Through project activities, the beneficiaries will improve their entrepreneurial, managerial and business skills, and speed access to local and regional markets through Business Support Services (virtual services - small market analysis, finding a partner, pre-sales services etc). These businesses will be provided with loans through the business plan competition and all of the enterprises will have the opportunity to be exposed to investors with the purpose to obtain investments funds. As a result of the business support services, growing programs and the financial support provided, the Micro and SMEs will be able to spur innovation, create jobs and build thriving economies</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEED</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lleshi Lleshi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEED
Street Bajram Kelmendi No. 34, 10000 Prisht 34
PRISTINA
Kosovo (XK)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">50000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
