<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-BSC Strp2015 LEDII</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Economic Development LEDII</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovos economic performance over the past years has been remarkable. However, the steady GDP growth, in the range of two to five per cent per year, has failed to create jobs, tackle inherited structural unemployment, and enrich the stock of human capital. Young labour force, a friendlier business environment, and good quality agricultural land can be key assets and drivers of success in socio-economic development. Yet, Kosovo remains one of the poorest countries in Europe, with particularly unsatisfactory labour market outcomes for multiple groups, including young people, minorities, and women. Relatively high unemploymentrates (estimated between 29% and 35%in 2013)may mask a shocking reality when the low labour force participation rates are taken into consideration: in essence, nearly three quarters of Kosovos working-age population are not currently employedKosovo Human Development Report 2012, Private Sector and Employment,UNDP 2012.. Many of those not participating in the labour force are no longer seeking work as a result of their long-term and seemingly irreversible exclusion from the job market. Therefore, job creation alone is not the answer for them. Certain vulnerable groups require special support to return to active job seeking, particularly where cultural and societal constraints (such as lack of services related childcare and care for the elderly, combined with stereotyped gender-biases) are at play. Women, youth, minorities and rural communities are the most obviously excluded from labour force participation, at rates not found across other European contexts. Insufficiently developed entrepreneurial culture and competences of young people and women in rural minority areas is one of the main causes of youth unemployment, low employability, economic inactivity and, consequently, poverty. 
Regarding target group  potential and existing entrepreneurs, a set of business development skills trainings and workshops, networking opportunities and study visits will be organized throughout the entire targeted area.
The proposed action will contribute to the transition from social assistance to employment and self employment of the most disadvantaged groups in the labor market, with a special emphasis on women and youth, as well as beneficiaries of Social Assistance Scheme in rural areas. 
Youth self-employment rate  in Kosovo is around 5%, comparing to 12% in Europe. Lack of adequate entrepreneurial skills and the lack of opportunities to gain them are perceived as two of the main constraints for further development of entrepreneurship among youth. Opportunities for informal education are very rare and their quality is uncertain, while education systems, including university education, insufficiently foster entrepreneurship competences within curricula.Areas targeted by this Action are Novo Brdo/Novoberde, Klokot/Kllokot, &#x160;trpce/Sht&#xEB;rpc&#xEB;, Ranilug/Ranillug, Gracanica/Gracanice, Gnjilane, Partesh/Partes and Mitrovica municipalities. Total estimated population of these municipalities is more than190.000 people with over 70% being Serbian minority population. The proposed action aims at direct empowerment of entrepreneurial skills and knowledge of vulnerable minority groups, such as women and youth, including opportunity to develop joint business initiatives and associations, which  will on the long term contribute to local socio-economic development, through developing and strengthening of their entrepreneurial skills, productivity improvement opportunities and economic participation of these groups through enhancing regional cooperation. 
For these groups there are very few opportunities for employment such as  socially-owned enterprises that are still operating, in international organizations, in small private enterprises and agriculture. Although farming has been a tradition in rural and semi-rural areas of Kosovo, there has seen a significant decrease during the last decade. High costs and scarce availability of agricultural machines, seeds, and fertilizers, as well as lack of funding opportunities, are few of many impediments to agricultural developmentKOSOVO Mosaic 2012: Overview of perceptions on public services and local authorities, USAID &amp; UNDP, 2012. Sixty-two percent of Kosovos population lives in rural areasKosovo Population and Housing Census 2011: Final Results, ASK 2011, while 47% of them live in poverty. Poverty in rural areas is highly correlated with lack of land, livestock, or agricultural equipment.
Data show that agriculture is one of the sectors with the lowest share of total loans accounting for only approximately 4% of total outstanding loans to enterprises in June 2011Ibid. The low volume of loans issued to this sector is characterized by high interest rates, reflecting the perceived uncertainty of this sector by banks. This  particularly applies to women and  youth, who often have good business ideas but fail due to lack of funding as potential entrepreneurs are not able to access commercial loans because of  lack of equity and inability to provide collateral for the loan.
The proposed action envisages provision of support to these vulnerable groups to generate employment and valorize the territory. Beneficiaries will be provided with access to training opportunities, business advisory and development services, as well as access to credit opportunities from the Loan Guaranty Fund.  Furthermore, provision of up to 45 sub-grants in order to create employment opportunities of the most disadvantaged target groups, beneficiaries of Social Assistance Scheme, women and youth in these areas will be enabled through UNDP grant scheme and establishment of a socially owned enterprise. According to TEP Territorial Employment Pact signed between BSC Strpce and UNDP, &#x201C;grant is activated only after the beneficiary has planted the seedling, with a success rate of over 80% (verifiable by a commission composed of Directorate of Agriculture, UNDP and Business Support Centre staff). It is conditional that beneficiaries formalize and start to regularly pay social contributions for two working-age members per household. UNDP will hire Business Support Centre to prepare all costs in details a standard scheme of raspberries plantation respecting all professional requirements and standards&#x201D; Quotation from TEP. 
LEDII project is a continuation of activities built on lessons learned on previous BSC Strpce  andD&amp;G Solutionscommon activities delivered during 2013 and 2014, it takes some of the most successful parts of the past projects and expands their services into wider target beneficiaries groups.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Minority vulnerable groups, women and youth  in rural areas;
Women and youth from Mitrovica south and north
Existing and potential/start-up SMEs;
Entire  population of targeted region</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outputs: 
2.1. Promotional campaign on program details launched in three municipalities
2.2. Organized two rounds of business plan preparation workshops per year
2.3. Organized two rounds of Business Plan Competition per year and providing financial support to beneficiaries from 
Spark Loan Guaranty Fund, EU EEVG, USAID AKT and UNDP Grant Scheme
2.4. Organized training on record keeping, basic accounting and finance issues for local youth, potential and existing 
entrepreneurs in three municipalities
2.5. Organized training on marketing for local youth, potential and existing entrepreneurs in three municipalities 
2.6. Organized specialized training on agricultural production improvement for local potential and existing 
entrepreneurs in three municipalities
2.7. Organized specialized training on SME management for local youth, potential and existing entrepreneurs in three 
municipalities
2.8. Organized specialized training on introduction in entrepreneurship for local potential and existing entrepreneurs in 
three municipalities 
2.9. Organized specialized consulting services for most promising business and mentors consulting services for woman
2.10. Organizing two rounds of specialized training on rural tourism development for local youth, potential and existing entrepreneurs three municipalities
2.11. Organized Study visit of raspberry producers to Arilje, Serbia
2.12. Organized specialized training on Global Gap and HACCP Standards 
2.13. Organized B2B meeting
2.14. Organized study visit of existing and potential entrepreneurs from 3 municipalities to Brezovica Ski Resort 
2.15. Organized Regional Entrepreneurship Fair  

Output indicators: 
2.1. 200 potential beneficiaries from targeted municipalities informed on program details 
2.2. 60 (out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs from seven municipalities certified 
2.3. 45 (out of which 5 woman) business plan approved by jury
       32 (out of which 7 woman) matchmaking accomplished 
2.4. 55 (out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form seven municipalities certified
2.5. 55(out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form seven municipalities certified
2.6. 55(out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form six municipalities certified 
2.7. 55(out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs from six municipalities certified 
2.8. 55(out of which 15 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form six municipalities certified
2.9. 18 beneficiaries supported
 	       10 women start-up received consulting and mentoring services
2.10. 50(out of which 10 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs from three municipalities certified
2.11. 30(out of which 5 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs from three municipalities increased capacity on 
         production process
2.12. 50(out of which 10 woman) potential and existing entrepreneurs form three municipalities certified 
2.13. 20(out of which 4 woman) existing entrepreneurs form six municipalities increased number of business contacts.
         4 cooperation agreements established 
2.14. 30(out of which 10 woman) existing and potential entrepreneurs from 3 municipalities increased capacity on 
         tourism development
2.15. 60 (out of which 10 woman) exhibitors
         500 visitors</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BSC Strpce</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natalija Janicevic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>n.janicevic@bsc-red.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BSC Strpce
Municipal building ,Firs t floor, office no 73000
Firs t floor, office no.13
KOSOVO
Servi&#xEB;</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Do not use !!! use other Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">59835</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
