<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-BWF2014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building of BWF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Increased fundraising activity and success in bidding for new programs	 Number of programs proposed and approved.  	At least one new program is approved.


-Increase in client satisfaction score in BWF network	Members evaluation of BWF performance.	10% increase


-Increase number of new members joined BWF	Number of new members &amp; beneficiaries joined BWF, 	15 new members and 20 new beneficiaries


-Increased employment rate among young women members of BWF	Increased employability of trained participants 	100

-Participants in BPC 2014 started or/and developed their business 	Number of SMEs started and developed  5 new SMEs 3 SMES grown

-Increased number of direct jobs created.	Number of direct jobs were  created 10


- Creation on new businesses  	Number of new businesses created 	10


-Increased rate of income  	% of increased income 	10 % increase


-Beneficiaries businesses are developed and sales are increased 	30 intensive technical trainings are conducted 	10 businesses are developed


-Improved business environment for women 	Obstacle is identified and removed 	1


-BWF advocacy efforts are promoted  	Number of stakeholders engaged with BWF efforts 	30</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution towards improving of overall socio economic position of women in Palestinian society with high level of gender sensibility and tolerance and equal opportunities.

BWF believes in the significant role of women in economy, especially, in line with the difficult circumstances that the Palestinian people go through, women are in need to do any activity that would contribute to earning extra income for the family in order to improve the standard of living. According to 2008 statistics, 28% of Palestinian women work in agriculture which means that a large group of women participate in the Palestinian national economy.

A BWF research study conducted in 2010 shows that Palestinian business womens current situation in the economy is as follows:
Women in OPT have low levels of labour force participationless than one in five are in the labour force.
Those that do participate are segregated into a few sectors, namely agriculture and services. There are few jobs outside the agricultural sector for women with low levels of education.
Competition among women for jobs in the services sector is intense, and jobs go almost exclusively to those with higher education. Even so, one in three highly educated women is unemployed.
Increasing in formalization of the Palestinian economy since the intifada has disproportionately affected women, as wage work is being supplanted by own-account employment and other less protected forms of labour. It has also led to increased tension at the household level between women and men.
Limited social and economic empowerment: due to traditions, women are undermined especially in marginalized areas, which they face many obstacles and therefore it is not easy for them to build networks. Consequently, women need skills to build self-confidence in networking to enable them to make decisions and depend on their own capabilities.

A major obstacle for entrepreneurs is the registration process as well as lack of knowledge of the revised tax system are main impediments to registering the business. For women this process is even more difficult, due to prejudices.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main target groups of this project are going to be women entrepreneurs who are running and managing  SMEs, mainly graduated from 2011 &amp; 2013 Business &#x201C;Plan competition program&#x201D; and those who are joining the BDC services, and transitioning to formal business. In Addition, women Entrepreneurs who are willing to join the economy through creative ideas all over West Bank with more focus on North and South areas.
For the Business Plan Competition: Female graduates, from low income families, from all West Bank, mainly  North and South, will be targeted, and have the desire to start their own small businesses due to the lack of job opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Women Forum</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jumana S Salous</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Jsalous@bwf.ps</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Women Forum
Palestine, Ramallah, Al Balou, Al Fare Building, 2nd floor
Al Balou 2 Floor Al Fare Buildin
RAMALLAH
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="410"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">115036</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="www.bwf.ps">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
