<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41213450-CCE2015 PROFIT</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41213450" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spark head office Amsterdam</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector Re-engineering: Opportunities For Innovative Tracks</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCE &amp; CoE staff engaged in the provision of business development services to the private sector 
Existing medium-sized enterprises 
Existing micro and small-sized enterprises
Potential students - entrepreneurs from seven Palestinian universities</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2015, CCE &amp; CoE will continue to work on four components: (i) internal capacity-building; (ii) enhancing sustainability of small enterprises; (iii) growing medium-sized enterprises; and (iv) reduction of unemployment among youth through empowering them to establish their own businesses. 
The first component encompasses capacity building of CCE &amp; CoEs specialists working with the private sector through their active participation in different workshops and trainings provided in the frame of the UEC project. This is expected to enable the CCE &amp; CoE to add more BDSs to their existing scope of work, to enhance the quality of the delivered services, and to rely more on the in-house team and their expertise in the service provision. These quality services will be provided in a centralized manner by SPARK and its international partners.    

The second project component will address the problem of vulnerability of local micro &amp; small enterprises. This component will focus on the development of enterprises in remote regions, which are historically neglected by business service providers. Moreover, these remote communities, especially those in rural areas, have been the most negatively affected by the occupation and prolonged socio-economic crisis. They live in a chronic state of marginalization and continue to sink deeper into poverty and deprivation. In such context, many Palestinian micro and small enterprises were established as an employer of last resort: by many unemployed. For them, launching a small own business is viewed as the only chance and opportunity to find a decent living. Daily-wage laborers who cannot work anymore in Israel; women who have to take over the financial responsibilities in their families because their husbands are unemployed or arrested; fresh graduates who cannot find a job because the stagnated and constricted market is unable absorb them  many people from these categories attempt to start their small makeshift enterprises with little understanding of the market sector and with almost no sound business planning . Not surprisingly, the majority of such endeavors fail, leading to worsening the families economic situation because of a heavy burden of loans taken for establishing the business. Hence, by working on enhancing the sustainability of small enterprises, CCE &amp; CoE will contribute to assisting the vulnerable micro &amp; small businesses to thrive and to maintaining the direct and indirect job places created by these small businesses.
Key reasons, for which the small businesses fail, mainly fall under two categories: 
business owners do not have a profound understanding of the market, in which they operate, and do not know how to gauge the market so that to respond to the market needs and trends; and 
in an attempt to cut costs, owners of small companies usually assume all key roles in their companies (e.g., marketing, sales, financial management, operations management, HR management, etc) without having proper education and necessary knowledge in these fields.    
Therefore, this component will aim at (i) increasing competitiveness of small businesses by assisting them to become market-driven; and (ii) enhancing efficiency and streamlining of business operations. 

This component will work through the provision of mentoring services to the micro &amp; small enterprises along the following steps: 
Diagnosis of the current business performance based on face-to-face interviews with the owners and key personnel, in addition to observation of the production, packaging, and warehousing processes. The current business performance will be assessed in all key business fields to include product development and design, marketing, financial management, HR management, inputs supply, and outputs production. The business owner(s) will be responsible for gathering any information regarding target markets, customers, suppliers, distributors, etc, however, the mentors will provide him/her with all needed forms and advices on how to collect the market data. The findings of the diagnostic stage will be documented in the SMEs Diagnostic Form developed in the UEC/CCE 2012 project; 
Analysis of the data collected, identification of bottlenecks and problems, and development of recommendations for improving the enterprises performance in the key fields. All recommendations will be developed in close cooperation with the business owner. 
Continuing assistance to the enterprises in integrating the recommendations developed in the previous stage    
Noteworthy, in the implementation of this component, CCE &amp; CoE will rely on a pool of mentors whose capacity was developed during 2011 &amp; 2012 UEC-funded projects.    

The third project component will focus on medium-sized enterprises, which have the highest potential to create new sustainable job places, especially for fresh university graduates. If, on the other hand, a medium-sized company downsizes or shuts down its operations, many people lose their jobs and join the army of unemployed. 

The nature of services to be provided to medium-sized enterprises will depend on their actual and functional needs, which will be identified in diagnostic meetings with the enterprises management. Potential services include the development of new marketing strategies (for example, effective online visibility), feasibility studies for launching new business units or products, export strategies, product branding, business planning, development and implementation of a CRM system, etc. 
In addition, in this component CCE &amp; CoE will organize a number of training workshops for the business owners and managers from the senior and middle positions. This component will respond to the needs identified in the provision of consulting and mentoring services to the beneficiaries. Owners of medium-sized companies consider that there is a severe shortage of qualified people and &#x201C;industry-ready&#x201D; graduates in the local labor market. This is because secondary as tertiary educational institutions graduate youth, whose knowledge is irrelevant to the local private sector, and who do not have the required skill sets to immediately start implementation of their job duties from day one on the job. Furthermore, business owners themselves tend to establish businesses in the fields of their technical expertise (aluminum processing, food production, etc) and often they do not possess adequate knowledge in the business management fields. 
In addition to mainstream topics usually demanded by business owners, such as modern marketing; sales; financial management for non-financial managers; production management, we plan to add a new topic, Social Media Marketing, which has become increasingly popular in the past few years as customers are spending countless hours on the internet. However, up to date, local training organizations do not offer comprehensive trainings in this topic. 
CCE &amp; CoE team has a strong differentiation point in the field of business trainings: we engage in the training delivery the private sector practitioners, who then continue working with the participants through on-job coaching. This approach is entirely different of those currently used by other local service providers, which engage either university professors, who are far away from the everyday life of local SMEs, or young trainers without any practical and hands-on expertise (the latter approach is usually used by local private consulting companies pursuing profit making rather than being results-oriented). Moreover, the training usually ends with the last training session with no any follow-up activities afterwards.

The forth projects component will address the problem of deficient business skills by students - potential entrepreneurs. The local education system orients and prepares students to become job-seekers rather than job-creators; it does not develop skills critical for entrepreneurs such as market screening, ideas generation, problem solving, analytical skills, negotiation skills, etc. As a result, even those students, who have in mind interesting business ideas, often, feel intimidated to launch their businesses. They usually do not have the technical know-how in order to venture into the first critical steps of making a successful business.  
Efforts of the 2015 PROFIT project will be directed towards self-job creation and unemployment reduction among university students and most importantly those students who are on the verge of graduating. Encouraging early stage startups in Palestinian universities will not only create jobs for university graduates, but will also establish a solid foundation for new innovative and strong Palestinian companies that are capable of operating successfully in regional and international markets. 

Noteworthy, this component has been developed, and will be implemented in close collaboration with the Palestinian Investment Fund (PIF). The PROFIT project will be responsible for the selection of, and training the students- potential entrepreneurs, as well as mentoring them on the business plans development. The PIF will establish a seed fund to cover expenses related to developing and producing prototypes of minimum viable products and services. 

The entrepreneurship training within this component will be delivered by a pool of university teachers, whose capacity has been constantly developed throughout the SPARK project since 2010.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output: 1.1.1 - By the end of 2015, CCE &amp; CoE have developed a training course or a consultancy service  in a new topic demanded by CCE &amp; CoE clients  
The number of new technical topics added to the CCE &amp; CoE portfolio of services by the end of 2015  -- 1

Output: 2.1.1  Consultancy and mentoring services provided with the aim to grow the medium-sized enterprises  
The number of business plans, marketing strategies, operational plans, and other business type applications developed and accepted by the clients  beneficiaries - 25

Output: 2.1.2 - Capacity-building workshops delivered to owners and senior managers at existing SMEs
The number of trained companies owners and senior managers - 75 
Among them, women - 20

Output: 2.2.1  At least 7 iterations of the entrepreneurship development program have been delivered at BZU and partner universities  
The number of potential students - entrepreneurs completed the business training; - 150  (at least 30% are women and  100% are youth)
The number of student teams received mentoring services on business planning,  structuring, and launching  - 21

Output: 2.2.2  At least 5 startups have upgraded technical skills of their key personnel     
The number of students-entrepreneurs and startups employees completed the technical training - 50
The number of business plans developed by student startups - 21</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q1</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015Q4</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Birzeit University Center for Continuing Education</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olga Batran</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>97222984812</telephone>
   <email>obatran@birzeit.edu</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Birzeit University Center for Continuing Education
P.O. Box
BIRZEIT
Palestijns Bezette Gebieden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="410"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-23">120735</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
