<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-CN-F13AP00922</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving conservation of the Cao Vit Gibbon in Bangliang Nature Reserve</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. Programs in this element should be integrated with the Agriculture Area under Economic Growth and Conflict Mitigation and Reconciliation Area under the Peace and Security Category, when applicable and appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. This includes The purpose of this project is to conserve the critically endangered Cao Vit gibbon by demonstrating approaches to habitat restoration; piloting a seed-fund to support conservation&#x2013;friendly livelihood activities; and maintaining and strengthening trans-boundary cooperation for gibbon conservation between Vietnam and China. Specifically, this will be done by: 1) preparing detailed site-based plans for habitat restoration by making a survey of each priority site, completing a plan for each priority site, and having the plans approved by the nature reserve; 2) providing a two-day training for forestry and nature reserve staff on habitat restoration; 3) collecting forest tree seeds and using them to establish a nursery as close to the planting site as possible; 4) planting trees on degraded land not conducive to natural regeneration; 5) carrying out assisted natural regeneration techniques to promote seedling growth; 6) piloting alternative livelihoods (therefore cultivation of medicinal plants) to reduce pressure on the nature reserve through scoping and identification of pilot sites; 7) monitoring the pilot sites at least every two months and evaluating the prospects of them providing alternative livelihoods for local people; and 8) maintaining and strengthening trans-boundary cooperation between Vietnam and China by carrying out a study tour to allow Chinese and Vietnamese officials to exchange lessons learned and experiences..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAUNA &amp; FLORA INTERNATIONAL, I</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>068497069</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S.~assistance helps Tibetan communities improve livelihoods, promote sustainable development and environmental conservation, and preserve cultural traditions. In addition, foreign assistance funding also supports targeted programs that strengthen cooperation on combatting the spread of HIV/AIDS and other pandemic and emerging diseases as well as rule of law programs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-01">62721</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-17">31360.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time obligation</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2015-09-21"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
