<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">CoLoRes: Comunit&#xE0; Locali Resilienti. Donne e giovani costruiscono economie sostenibili e solidali a sostegno del processo di pace in Colombia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Contesto di riferimento della presente proposta progettuale &#xE8; la Colombia, nello specifico la regione del
Putumayo. La posizione strategica di questa regione, le sue condizioni geografiche, la debolezza istituzionale e
la ricchezza di risorse naturali da pi&#xF9; di 30 anni hanno favorito la presenza di attori armati, attratti soprattutto
dal controllo dello sfruttamento del petrolio, dalla coltivazione e commercializzazione della coca, dal traffico
di armi e da altre attivit&#xE0; illegali. Una condizione socio-economica complessa e fragile che colpisce in modo
particolare le comunit&#xE0; rurali e i soggetti pi&#xF9; vulnerabili, soprattutto donne e giovani appartenenti alle comunit&#xE0; indigene, afro discendenti e contadine. Questa situazione &#xE8; peggiorata nel 2020 a causa di un
aumento della presenza dei gruppi armati e delle restrizioni dovute alla pandemia da COVID-19.
Lo scopo principale dell&#x2019;iniziativa &#xE8; supportare queste comunit&#xE0; affinch&#xE9; possano migliorare le proprie
condizioni di vita e di lavoro, la propria resilienza ai cambiamenti climatici e agli effetti della pandemia in un
contesto di sostegno al processo di pace e alla salvaguardia della biodiversit&#xE0; amazzonica.
Per farlo, promuoveranno 7 filiere agro-forestali (asai, chontaduro, sacha inchi, caff&#xE8;, cacao, canna da
zucchero, ecoturismo/artigianato), legate alla biodiversit&#xE0; amazzonica, che siano a loro volta capaci di favorire
pratiche di adattamento al cambiamento climatico e allo stesso tempo di generare un incremento degli utili e
nuove occupazioni, in imprese di tipo associativo e inclusive, riconoscendo il ruolo centrale delle donne e dei
giovani.
Secondo la teoria del cambiamento delineata dall&apos;iniziativa, per consentire alle comunit&#xE0; di diventare
protagoniste di questo cambiamento, occorre concentrarsi su 3 assi di lavoro. Il primo &#xE8; volto a sostenere 27
iniziative produttive appartenenti alle filiere agro-forestali, di produzione e servizi, della biodiversit&#xE0;
amazzonica, legate a gruppi di giovani e donne. Il cambiamento che queste iniziative devono affrontare
riguarda in primo luogo i modelli associativi e organizzativi, che dovranno diventare efficienti, inclusivi e
capaci di generare nuove opportunit&#xE0; lavorative, rispettando le diversit&#xE0; di genere e culturali che
caratterizzano la zona di intervento. Si lavorer&#xE0; inoltre con partner strategici come il SENA, principale ente
pubblico di formazione professionale in Colombia, e la Confederazione delle Cooperative della Colombia
(CONFECOOP), su accompagnamento e assistenza tecnica alle organizzazioni di secondo livello.
COOPERMONDO accompagner&#xE0; questo percorso.
In secondo luogo, le stesse iniziative produttive potranno implementare processi produttivi e di
trasformazione sostenibili ed innovativi, andando a creare e diffondere soluzioni sostenibili per lo sviluppo di
prodotti della biodiversit&#xE0; amazzonica, arricchite dalla valorizzazione dei saperi locali tradizionali. Il progetto
infatti si inserisce e sostiene l&#x2019;iniziativa nazionale del Ministero dell&#x2019;Ambiente Colombiano (MADS)
denominata &#x201C;Negocios Verdes&#x201D;, che nasce nel 2014, per appoggiare iniziative produttive e commerciali che
valorizzino la ricchezza della biodiversit&#xE0; colombiana con un approccio di sostenibilit&#xE0; sociale, economica ed
ambientale. Nella regione del Putumayo l&#x2019;ente incaricato dello sviluppo del programma &#xE8; CORPOAMAZONIA,
partner di progetto che insieme a COOPERMONDO dar&#xE0; supporto nell&#x2019;elaborare strategie di
commercializzazione fondate sui principi dell&#x2019;eco-marketing che permetteranno alle imprese di promuovere
e commercializzare i prodotti con il certificato locale di Negocios Verdes. COSPE supporter&#xE0; ogni fase.
Il lavoro con le iniziative produttive verr&#xE0; articolato con il terzo asse, che permetter&#xE0; alle comunit&#xE0; locali, afro,
indigene e contadine di diventare promotrici di pratiche di adattamento al cambiamento climatico (ACC) e
incidere sugli strumenti di pianificazione ambientale del territorio,. con un percorso comunitario di analisi
sulle vulnerabili</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The reference framework of this project proposal is Colombia, and specifically the Putumayo region. The
strategic location of this region, its geographical conditions, institutional weakness and abundance of natural
resources have, for more than 30 years, favoured the presence of armed actors, mainly attracted by the
control of oil exploitation, coca cultivation and commercialisation, arms trafficking and other illegal activities.
This complex and fragile socio-economic situation particularly affects rural communities and the most
vulnerable groups, especially women and young people from indigenous, Afro-descendant and peasant
communities. This state of affairs worsened in 2020 due to an increased presence of armed groups and to the
restrictions caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.
The main aim of the initiative is to support these communities so that they can improve their living and
working conditions, their resilience to climate change and to the effects of the pandemic, all in a framework
of support to the peace process and to the protection of Amazonian biodiversity.
In order to reach such objectives, communities should promote 7 agro-forestry chains (asai, chontaduro,
sacha inchi, coffee, cocoa, sugar cane, ecotourism/crafts) linked to Amazonian biodiversity, which in turn
could foster climate change adaptation practices and at the same time generate increased profits and new
jobs, in enterprises that are associative and inclusive, recognising the central role of women and young
people.
According to the Theory of Change outlined by the initiative, in order to enable communities to become
protagonists of this change, it is necessary to focus on three lines of work. The first is aimed at supporting 27
productive initiatives belonging to the agro-forestry, production and services, and Amazon biodiversity
sectors, linked to groups of young people and women. The change that these initiatives must address
primarily concerns the associative and organisational models, which must become efficient, inclusive and
capable of generating new job opportunities, while respecting the gender and cultural diversities that
characterise the area of intervention. The project will also include strategic partners such as the Servicio
Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA), the main public body for professional training in Colombia, and the
Confederation of Cooperatives of Colombia (CONFECOOP), for support and technical assistance to
second-level organisations. COOPERMONDO will be assisting in this process.
Secondly, the production initiatives themselves will be able to implement sustainable and innovative
production and processing processes, creating and spreading sustainable solutions for the development of
Amazon biodiversity products, enriched by the valorisation of traditional local knowledge. In fact, the project
fits into and supports the Colombian Ministry of the Environment&apos;s (MADS) national initiative called
&quot;Negocios Verdes&quot;, which was launched in 2014 to support production and commercial initiatives that
enhance the richness of Colombian biodiversity with a social, economic and environmental sustainability
approach. In the Putumayo region, the body in charge of developing the programme is CORPOAMAZONIA, a
project partner which, together with COOPERMONDO, will provide support in developing marketing strategies
based on eco-marketing principles that will allow enterprises to promote and commercialise products with
the local Negocios Verdes certificate. COSPE will support each phase.
The work on productive initiatives will be articulated in the third line of action, which will allow local, Afro,
indigenous and peasant communities to become promoters of practices of adaptation to climate change
(ACC) and to influence the tools of environmental planning of the territory, with a communitarian approach in
the analysis of vulnerabilities and measures of ACC, enhancing local ecological and gender-focused
knowledge. COSPE and CORPOAMAZONIA will coordinate</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPERMONDO - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA COOPERAZIONE INTERNAZIONALE AL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/04/4" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="32" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural co-operatives</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43042" percentage="38" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education or training</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, devise and implement policies to promote sustainable tourism that creates jobs and promotes local culture and products</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve education, awareness-raising and human and institutional capacity on climate change mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrate climate change measures into national policies, strategies and planning</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Take urgent action to combat climate change and its impacts</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-11">1949905.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPERMONDO - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA COOPERAZIONE INTERNAZIONALE AL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">1169943.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPERMONDO - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA COOPERAZIONE INTERNAZIONALE AL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
