<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-24407</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRS Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRS Logistica S.A. (MRS or the company) operates a 1,674 km freight rail network connecting Brazils three largest industrial regions -- S&#xE3;o Paulo, Minas Gerais, and Rio de Janeiro -- under a 30-year concession granted by the Brazilian federal government in 1996.  The companys rail network consists of four primary lines and a branch line that link Brazils principal iron ore mines and steel plants, its largest consumer markets, and its principal sea ports.  MRS currently operates a rolling stock fleet comprised of 143 owned and 319 leased locomotives; and 1,890 owned, 1,858 customer-owned, and 9,638 leased rail cars.  MRS is implementing a five-year investment program that includes permanent way expansion, track reconfigurations, signaling improvements, and additional rolling stock acquisitions and upgrades, intended to increase the capacity of the companys network while also improving its efficiency, productivity, and safety.  The expansion is expected to increase the companys freight handling capacity from around 100 million tons p.a. at present to up to 160-180 million tons by 2009.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRS Log&#xED;stica S/A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-24407" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-12-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-03-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daniel Fran&#xE7;a, Financial Manager   E-mail:    dfr@mrs.com.br</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRS is headquartered in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with its principal operational offices located in Juiz de Fora in the State of Minas Gerais.  The company operates four primary rail lines and a branch line that link the States of S&#xE3;o Paulo, Minas Gerais, and Rio de Janeiro as follows:    Steel Line  370 km of single track rail running south from the mining quadrangle near Belo Horizonte in the State of Minas Gerais to Saudade in the State of Rio de Janeiro.  The Steel Line is used nearly exclusively for the transport of iron ore.  In Saudade, the Steel line intersects with the Rio to S&#xE3;o Paulo Line and continues to Barra do Pira&#xED;, where it interconnects with a series of branch lines that continue to Brisamar and the Atlantic ports of Rio de Janeiro, Guaiba Island terminal and Sepetiba.  Iron ore is transported on the Steel Line to MBRs Guaiba Island terminal and to CVRDs iron ore terminal at the port of Sepetiba for export, and to CSNs steel mill near Volta Redonda in the State of Rio de Janeiro for domestic consumption.  This branch line is also used to transport imported coke and coal from the port of Sepetiba to CSNs steel production facilities.    Central Line  566 km of single track rail running south from Belo Horizonte in the State of Minas Gerais to Barra do Pira&#xED; in the State of Rio de Janeiro through Juiz de Fora.  The Central Line is predominantly used for the north-south transport of cement and bauxite and for the south-north transport of empty iron ore trains returning to the mines in the State of Minas Gerais.  The configuration of the Central Line and Steel Line essentially double-track the Companys rail connection between the States of Minas Gerais and Rio de Janeiro.    Rio to S&#xE3;o Paulo Line  single track line running from Barra do Pira&#xED; in the State of Rio de Janeiro to S&#xE3;o Paulo.  The Rio to S&#xE3;o Paulo Line includes interconnection points with the Central Line and the Steel Line, making it the most congested segment of track operated by MRS.  The Rio to S&#xE3;o Paulo Line is principally used for transport of finished steel products, iron ore to supply the COSIPA steel mill in Cubat&#xE3;o, cement and bauxite transported south on the Central Line and then west to S&#xE3;o Paulo, and container traffic between the States of Minas Gerais, Rio de Janeiro and S&#xE3;o Paulo.      Santos to Jundia&#xED; Line  single track rail running south from Jundia&#xED; in the State of S&#xE3;o Paulo through the city of S&#xE3;o Paulo to the port of Santos.  The line is used principally for the transport of soy, containers and other products to the port of Santos.  The iron ore destined for COSIPA is also transported on this line to Cubat&#xE3;o, near the port of Santos. MRS is currently facing bottlenecks and constraints in efficiently handling the freight volumes being demanded and, as such, the Companys management has identified a series of capital investments to address various bottlenecks and position the company to handle the projected future freight handling volumes anticipated to serve the demand of its customers.      The key components of the companys five-year investment plan include:    - Permanent way expansion including:    -  the construction of additional sidings on the Steel Line to optimize train movements on a 195 km stretch on which pusher locomotives are used to climb a 1% grade and then need to return against oncoming trains;    -  the expansion of two rail yards and the rehabilitation of two sidings on the Central Line to shorten the distance between sidings on a stretch traveled by both southbound (loaded) and northbound (empty) trains;    -  expansion of a key siding at the interconnection point of the Steel and Central Lines in the State of Minas Gerais near the rail spur to the A&#xE7;ominas (Gerdau) steel mill;    -  the lengthening of five existing sidings in the S&#xE3;o Paulo area;    -  the addition and lengthening of two sidings on the Rio to S&#xE3;o Paulo line;    -  the lengthening of existing sidings to extend the 45 km double-tracked section in Rio de Janeiro between CSNs steel mill, Barra do Pira&#xED; and Brisamar; and    -  the expansion and addition of cross-overs in the marshalling yard for general cargo near Barra do Pira&#xED; at the beginning of the Rio to S&#xE3;o Paulo line;    -  Acquisition of locomotives: the purchase of 49 GE locomotives  29 refurbished locomotives already acquired in 2005 and 20 new locomotives ordered for delivery in 2006;     -  Acquisition of rail cars: proposed purchase of approximately 2,480 new cars between 2005 and 2009;    -  Locomotive maintenance: various upgrades to improve cabin layout and comfort, install locotrol distributed power systems, and perform preventive major maintenance on the companys fleet of existing locomotives;    -  Rail car maintenance: preventative maintenance on the companys existing rail cars including an increase of the axle rating to increase the carrying capacity of the company&apos;&apos;s iron ore gondola fleet;    -  Permanent way maintenance: preventative and corrective maintenance to the rail network and superstructures including rail grinding, tamping, replacement of rails, ties and ballast;     -  Rail maintenance equipment: Acquisition of an additional rail grinder, two high-productivity tamping machines, new shoulder cleaning equipment, the upgrade of track maintenance vehicles and the acquisition and maintenance of other new vehicles and equipment;    -  Existing signaling and telecommunications system: installation of additional hot box/hot wheel detectors, friction management systems, derailment detectors, and additional field signals on the S&#xE3;o Paulo to Rio line;    -  Safety initiatives: investments to protect existing rights-of-way with fences, construction of pedestrian and vehicular overpass bridges, and upgrading of level crossings and marshalling yards in metropolitan regions;    -  New signaling system: upgrade of the central control and dispatch center in Juiz de Fora, installation of cab signals, onboard computers and digital voice/data radios on the existing locomotive fleet for real-time mobile communications; and    -  Conveyor belt: the installation of a cable conveyor belt to transport iron ore on a portion of the 18 km, 10% grade stretch on the Santos to Jundia&#xED; Line between Paranapiacaba (summit) and the COSIPA steel mill in Cubat&#xE3;o near the port of Santos.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Rail Transportation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $50.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2005-12-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2006-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2005-12-21">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2005-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2005-12-21">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRS Log&#xED;stica S/A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/24407/mrs-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
