<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28512</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Constellation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazils national oil company, Petrobras, has announced plans to invest a total of US$174 billion over the period 2009-2013 to help meet the growing demand for energy in the country and the region.  To maximize the economic impact of such investment, Petrobras has sought to increase local private sector participation and involvement by setting local content requirements in its drilling contracts.  These requirements are expected to spur industrial activity and linkage opportunities in-country through the establishment of new shipyard and rig related infrastructure and equipment services.

In response to the opportunities presented by Petrobras plans above, Constellation Overseas, Ltd. (Constellation, the Company), the oil services subsidiary of the Queiroz Galv&#xE3;o Group (QG) and an existing IFC client, intends to expand its oilfield drilling services business by acquiring additional offshore drilling assets that would allow it to participate in Petrobras drilling program that is an integral part of the latters plan to develop significant oil reserves discovered offshore Brazil.  To achieve this, Constellation is raising equity to increase its capital base.  The proceeds from this placement will be used for the construction and/or acquisition of drilling rigs, drillships and/or floating production, storage and offloading facilities (FPSOs).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project offers a strong development impact:

Development of Brazils critical energy sector:   The Project will help build greater operating capacity and will strengthen the oil and gas support infrastructure in Brazil.  Although the country has reached self-sufficiency in oil, significant new investment is needed to realize its oil and gas production potential in order to meet the growing energy demand of the country and the region.
 
Promoting domestic private sector participation:  This is consistent with the Governments objectives to widen local participation and expand the role of local companies in the oil and gas sector.  Brazil is among the few developing countries that have made a concerted effort to grow multiple local players to provide offshore drilling services.

Providing local employment, training and development of local skills:  Each rig employs an average of 144 highly skilled workers, with nearly all employment associated with rig operations comprised of Brazilian nationals.  

Generating local linkage benefits:   As a Petrobras contractor, Constellation will be bound by the local content requirements for the construction of its new rigs/vessels.  Operation of the Companys rigs will generate demand for local goods and services, estimated at about US$10 million annually for each new rig.  

Promoting competition:  Constellations expansion into new offshore rigs will help enhance the quality of its output and thereby promote increased competition in the local drilling and drilling-related services industry.  It can help expand deepwater technology and capabilities to the sector, attract additional players to the industry, and create potentially a positive demonstration effect for similar companies and national oil companies in other developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIPEF CONSTELLATION COINVESTMENT FUND LP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28512" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-04-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-05-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queiroz Galv&#xE3;o &#xD3;leo e G&#xE1;s S.A. 
Address: Av. Presidente Ant&#xF4;nio Carlos No. 51, 6th  Floor. 
City: Estado do Rio de Janeiro, RJ 
Phone.: (21) 3231-2500   
Fax.: (21) 2215-1739 
Att.: Mr. Guilherme Lima
         E-mail: glima@qgog.com.br
         www.qgog.com.br</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Company seeks to raise up to US$500 million in equity to support the construction and/or acquisition of drilling rigs, drillships and/or floating production, storage and offloading facilities (FPSOs) for lease to Petrobras.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC - Private Equity/Venture Cap Fund - Sector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $103.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-04-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-04-13">103000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-04-13">103000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIPEF CONSTELLATION COINVESTMENT FUND LP</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28512/constellation">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
