<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-33421</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Orange Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the proposed project is:  (i) to support Sul Am&#xE9;rica S.A., a leading Brazilian holding of multiline insurance providers (the Company or SulAm&#xE9;rica) listed in the Level 2 governance listing segment of BM&amp;FBovespa, S&#xE3;o Paulo stock exchange (BM&amp;FBovespa: SULA11), during an important transitional period for the Company and the insurance sector in Brazil; and (ii) to facilitate Internationale Netherlanden Groeps  (also known as the ING Group) orderly divest the direct shareholding participation held by its subsidiary ING Insurance International B.V. (ING) in the Company (the Project). The Company is controlled by Sulasapar Participa&#xE7;&#xF5;es S.A. (Sulasapar), a holding company that is currently jointly controlled by Sulasa Participa&#xE7;&#xF5;es S.A. (Sulasa), holding company controlled by the Larragoiti family, with 55% and ING with 45%.  The proposed IFC investment consists of an equity investment of approximately BRL 400 million in SulAm&#xE9;rica through the purchase of units from ING, representing approximately 7.9% of the Companys total outstanding capital stock.  A unit is a hybrid security composed of one ordinary voting share and two non-voting preferred shares of Sul Am&#xE9;rica.  Sulasapar and ING had previously entered into an agreement providing for the purchase by Sulasa of INGs stake in Sulasapar for a combination of cash and units in Sul America, after which Sulasa will become the sole shareholder of Sulasapar. The closing of the transaction between Sulasapar and ING will only occur after all applicable regulatory approvals are obtained.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">i) Financial Inclusion:  There is a significant need in Brazil for health insurance. With a penetration of 25% of the total population, coupled with current demographic trends, the country needs to increase access to health insurance in the short to medium term. This situation is particularly pressing in less developed regions of the country such as the North and Northeast, where penetration levels are 50% of those in the south of the country. The Company is also increasingly providing insurance to individuals through SMEs, the fastest growing segment in its health insurance business.  Sul America&apos;&apos;s plan to grow its health and dental business is expected to contribute to solving the shortage of health insurance in Brazil and hence positively contributing to the development of the country.   ii) Insurance Sector Improvements:  There is significant potential impact from regulatory intervention on insurance and health sector in Brazil; policy and regulation will need to adapt so that private health care offerings can expand to meet increased demand as demographic changes in Brazil will make health care a major fiscal challenge. In this context, the company&apos;&apos;s plan to grow its health insurance premiums by approximately 13% per year will over the next five years contribute to the appropriate evolution of this sector and continue to support government efforts in meeting these challenges.  iii) Improve Market Practices:  The Company intends to further improve its health and motor claims handling process from an industry-leading 85% of claims settled in 3 months to 90% of claims settled in 2 months. Over time, other market participants would need to perform at a similarly high level, which could result in increased system efficiency, better service and customer satisfaction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUL AMERICA S/A</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-33421" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arthur Farme dAmoed Neto  Chief Financial Officer and Investor Relations Rua Beatriz Larragoiti Lucas, 121 Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil Telephone:  55 21 2506 8163  mailto:arthur.farme@sulamerica.com.br  ir@sulamerica.com.br</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General IFC Inquiries IFC Corporate Relations 2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433 Telephone: 202-473-3800 Fax: 202-974-4384</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sul Am&#xE9;rica is headquartered in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with offices in S&#xE3;o Paulo and other 98 locations (63 branches and 35 automotive centers) spread throughout 19 states in Brazil.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="524113" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-JC - Composite Insurance (Life and Non-life)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $197.60 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-05-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-16">197600000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-16">197600000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUL AMERICA S/A</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33421/orange-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33421/orange-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
