<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8502</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tecon Rio Grande Container Terminal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Brazil-Tecon Rio Grande Container Terminal (Tecon)            Region    Latin America and the Caribbean        Sector       Project No008502   Projected Board DateMay 20, 1998   Company NameTecon Rio Grande S.A.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	TRGs shareholders consist of: Wilport Operadores Portu&#xE1;rias S.A., a port services company owned by Wilson, a Brazilian maritime Group; Serveng-Civilsan S.A., a Brazilian construction company; and Stevedoring Services of America, a US-based international port operator.     Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The project cost is estimated to be US$69.5 million including civil works, equipment, contingencies, and financing fees.  IFC&apos;&apos;s proposed investment would include an A Loan of up to US$7.5 million, a B Loan of up to US$26.5 million, and a C Loan of up to US$5 million.    Location of project and Description of site    	The project is located on the western bank of the Rio Grande river, about 5 kms north of the Atlantic ocean and 7 kms south of the city of Rio Grande.  The leased area comprises 67 hectares, of which 20 hectares have been developed for container handling, and 750 meters of river frontage including an existing 300-meter quay. In addition to road access, the terminal is served directly by rail although the rail spur is not currently in use.  The new container berths would be built as contiguous extensions of the existing berth.     Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	TRG has been established exclusively to operate Tecon.  The purpose of the project is to expand Tecons handling capacity from 80,000 moves to 200,000 moves per year and to improve the overall efficiency and quality of the terminals services.  IFC would be arranging long-term financing for the project including possibly mobilizing debt from international sources.  Tecon is one of the first privately-operted ports in Brazil.  Accordingly, IFCs support of the project is expected to have an important demonstration impact on the port sector.      Environmental Category and Issues    	This is an environmental review category B project.  Environmental issues associated with the project include: dredging and land reclamation, vegetation protection and revegetation programs, control of stormwater run-off and protection of water resources, liquid effluents, including bilge waste effluent, solid waste management, handling and storage of dangerous cargoes, fire prevention and emergency response, and employee health and safety.          Maintenance dredging is conducted by the Rio Grande Port Authorities, including the main channel and the area in front of Tecons existing berth.  Tecon has made arrangements with the port to take surplus dredged material resulting from the expansion project.  Tecon will establish a vegetated green belt to esthetically integrate the area modified by the terminal with the surrounding scenery and to provide a noise and dust barrier.  Tecon will also preserve and maintain an 80-year-old grove of eucalyptus trees along the main access avenue.  For the expansion project, Tecon will collect stormwater runoff from all areas of the site and install oil/water separation equipment to meet the World Bank guideline of 10 mg/l.  Tecon Rio Grande uses an approved septic drain system for sanitary wastes, which will be modified or expanded as appropriate.  Waste water from the cleaning and washing of ship holds is not accepted at the Tecon terminal.  Solid waste is collected and disposed of through the Rio Grande municipality.          As part of the expansion project the terminal will have a dedicated area and all necessary procedures and equipment for dangerous cargo.  Tecon has an emergency response procedure in place and will update its response plan for the new activities and configurations brought about as part of the expansion.  Tecon has a formal plan for medical control and occupational health of its employees as required by Brazilian regulations.  Safety training is provided for all employees, and in-house training is provided in fire fighting techniques and equipment.    The  is  from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     April 20, 1998      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tecon Rio Grande S/A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8502" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-12-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-08-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BB - Port and Harbor Operations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $13.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-12-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-12-14">13000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-12-14">13000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tecon Rio Grande S/A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8502/tecon-rio-grande-container-terminal">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
