<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7268</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ipiranga Petroquimica S.A.  Expansion</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">REVISED Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Brazil-Ipiranga Expansion Project              Region    Latin America &amp; the Caribbean        Sector       Project No007268   Projected Board DateJanuary 31, 1997   Company NameIpiranga Petroqu&#xED;mica S.A. (IPQ)   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	IPQs shareholders include Ipiranga Qu&#xED;mica S.A. (34.1%) and Hoechst do Brasil (34.1%).  Several banks own another 24.7% and IFC owns the remaining 7.1%.  Ipiranga Qu&#xED;mica is the holding company for the petrochemical investments of the Ipiranga Group, which is involved mainly in the petroleum refining/distribution and petrochemical sectors. Hoechst do Brasil, a subsidiary of Hoechst A.G., is a leading Brazilian chemical company involved in the production of polymers, specialty chemicals, synthetic fibers and lubricants.      Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total Project cost is US$389.6 million.  IFCs proposed investment amounts to US$290 million, consisting of an A Loan of US$30 million and a B Loan of US$260 million.  The B Loan would consist of two tranches: (i) a US$90 million tranche payable in four years, and (ii) a US$170 million tranche payable in nine years.  The first tranche will be used towards restructuring part of the Companys short-term debt.    Location of project and Description of site    	Expansion of IPQs production facilities at Triunfo (37 miles from Porto Alegre in the state of Rio Grande do Sul) to install: (i) a high-density polyethylene (HDPE)/linear low density polyethylene (LLDPE) swing plant with a capacity of 150,000 metric tonnes per year (tpy), and (ii) a polypropylene (PP) plant with a capacity of 150,000 tpy.  The Triunfo complex comprises the Copesul naphtha cracker at the core of the facility and six second generation producers, in addition to IPQ.  The site is well-connected by road with the major market centers of the S&#xE3;o Paulo/Rio de Janeiro and Montevideo/Buenos Aires areas.     Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	IPQ is a producer of HDPE, with a domestic market share of about 35%.  HDPE is a plastic resin used in a wide number of household and industrial applications.  IPQs facilities consist of two HDPE plants with a nameplate capacity of 220,000 tpy.  The Company is in the process of completing the construction of a third HDPE plant with an additional capacity of 135,000 tpy. The plant is expected to come on stream in early 1997.  IPQ proposes to expand its capacity further in response to an increase in Brazilian and Conesul demand brought about by strong GDP growth and low inflation following the implementation of the Real Plan in 1994, and the greater economic integration of the Conesul region.  The proposed expansion will allow IPQ to benefit from the diversification of its product range and to access new end-use application sectors, thereby increasing IPQs competitiveness by bringing about greater economies of scale and lower operating costs.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a Category B Project according to the IBRDs environmental standards.  The existing plant conforms with all current Brazilian and IBRD standards.  The Project will not create any air emissions under normal operation.  For emergency cases and venting under process disturbances the facility is equipped with a flare.  In common with the Companys existing plants, the organic and inorganic effluents generated by the Project will be pre-treated on-site to remove oil and grease and to ensure consistent concentrations in the effluent before it is transferred to SITEL (the central wastewater treatment plant for the Triunfo complex).  Solid waste, other than polymers separated from water streams and sold to licensed companies for reuse, will not increase significantly.  IPQ has carried out public information/consultation for the expansion project based on Brazilian regulation.  The expansion project was announced in Diario Oficial Industria y Comercio and in Zero Hora, both in December 1995.      The  is available from the Public Information Center.       Host country location of environmental documents    Triunfo Petrochemical Complex, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil      Date SPI sent to PIC December 20, 1996   For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DISTRIBUIDORA DE PRODUTOS DE PETROLEO IPIRANGA S/A</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7268" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-01-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-05-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CA - Plastics Material and Resin</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $45.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-01-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1998-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-01-22">45000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-01-22">45000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DISTRIBUIDORA DE PRODUTOS DE PETROLEO IPIRANGA S/A</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7268/ipiranga-petroquimica-s-a-expansion">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
