<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-33683</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Companhia do Vale do Araguaia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate change mitigation:  Tree growth and addition of significant soil carbon will sequester nearly 100,000t CO2e p.a. Plantations have a positive impact on surface water balance and improve the region&apos;&apos;s drying microclimate. The sale of &quot;non-commercial&quot; thinnings and waste wood processing from processing to local agro-processing facilities substitutes for biomass partly derived from the clearing of native forest and vegetation.  ii.	Local economic diversification: The Company is in a region where local economic well-being is very dependent on cattle grazing and the cultivation of soy and corn.  The Project contributes to reducing the local economy&apos;&apos;s over dependence on too narrow a range of commodities and broadens the skill base of the labor market.  iii.	Employment generation:  Cattle grazing, soy and corn cultivation generate fewer jobs per hectare than plantation forestry.  Moreover, the Company operates within the formal sector with respect to its employment practices.  As such, the Project makes a contribution to generation of year-round jobs and does so in the formal sector.  iv.	Re-socialization of prisoners:  Through Funda&#xC3;&#xA7;&#xC3;&#xA3;o &quot;Nova Chance&quot; (translated as Fresh Start), a convict rehabilitative program sponsored by the Mato Grosso government, CVA has been employing inmates since the latter part of 2013.  The goal of Nova Chance is to break the cycle by which former convicts have a very high rate at which they return to crime after prison and, ultimately, are imprisoned again.  Most of the prisoners are from economically disadvantaged backgrounds such that - for example - they may not have formal sector work experience or bank accounts.   The program helps prepare them for life after incarceration by establishing and funding a bank account in their name with a cushion of savings following their release and provides recent work experience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Companhia do Vale do Araguaia (CVA, the Company) was founded in 2005 and is a privately owned Brazilian company engaged in the sustainable management of teak plantations in Midwestern Brazil. CVA planted nearly 6,500 hectares (ha) of teak on about 9,672 ha near the town of Agua Boa, is the eastern part of Mato Groso state (the Project).  CVA is managing the teak on a 22-year cycle whereby final harvests begin in about 2026, but there are periodic thinnings of the plantation stands, which generate wood sales in the interim.  The Company will install and operate a wood processing facility to produce and sell teak products to regional and international markets.  The balance between the total land of the Project and the area planted with teak is over 3000 ha, most of which CVA looks after in one of two forms: either as a Reserva Legal (general land set-aside), or as an &#xC1;rea de Preserva&#xE7;&#xE3;o Permanente (land reserves required for watershed or other ecological protection).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Companhia do Vale do Araguaia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-33683" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fazenda S&#xE3;o Jorge Rod. MT 240, km 23  CEP: 78635-000 &#xC1;gua Boa, MT  BRAZIL Fax: +55 (66) 3468-2770 Tel: +55 (66) 3468-3966</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Gilberto Francischetto Diretor Executivo Companhia do Vale do Araguaia Tel: +55- (21) 3923-8960</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is located in the Midwest region of Brazil, in the state of Mato Grosso, Brazils third largest state. The closest town to the Project is Agua Boa, located near the border to the state of Goias and about 650 km north east of Cuiaba, the state capital of Mato Grosso.  CVAs administrative offices are located in Rio de Janeiro.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1153" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A-DB - Plantation Forests</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $22.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-27">22000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-27">22000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Companhia do Vale do Araguaia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33683/companhia-do-vale-do-araguaia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/33683/companhia-do-vale-do-araguaia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
