<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-37708</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bauducco III</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pandurata Alimentos Ltda (&quot;Bauducco&quot; or &quot;the Company&quot;) was established in 1953 and is currently one of the leading baked products companies in Brazil. It is the largest producer of panettones (Christmas cake) with an 59% market share in Brazil, and leader in colomba pascal (easter cake - 92% of market share), toasts (74% of market share) and wafer biscuits (37% of market share). The Company produces baked products under 3 complementary brands (Bauducco, Visconti and Tommy) to target the entire spectrum of Brazilian consumers.  Bauducco is currently carrying out an investment program of US$66 million over the next 2 years to (i) increase the capacity of the plant in Minas Gerais for the production of toasts and mini cakes, (ii) implement a new line in its Guarulhos plant, (iii) construct a new distribution center in Alagoas to increase sales to the Northeast regions and (iv) associated working capital needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to have the following key developmental impacts:   - Development of modern food processing and distribution industry. With its wide product range, various size packaging, and far-reaching distribution network, Bauducco is well positioned to meet the growing demand for high quality food products to a diverse range of customers across the entire country. The expansion with further strengthen the Company&apos;&apos;s ability to do so.  - Growing operations in Brazil&apos;&apos;s frontier regions. Bauducco is keen on steadily increasing its presence in the frontier regions where it distributes lower priced, smaller package food products through a variety of retail outlets. North East sales growth in 2015 was in the 25-30% range and rise in sales is expected to continue even if in moderate pace.  - Employment creation. The launch of new production lines is expected to create 228 new direct permanent jobs and about 400 temporary jobs (the latter during the construction phase), enabling rural, low skilled workers to transition from agriculture and informal employment service, to receive training, and to move up the social and economic ladder. About half of Bauducco&apos;&apos;s employees are women and their share is expected to remain at this high level.  - Provision of training. The new employees have access to the Company&apos;&apos;s extensive training programs: it operates an e-learning site and offers rotations between different plants to familiarize employees with other plants and processes. Many higher ranking positions are held by the employees that have advanced by taking in-house technical and leadership programs which are 30-50% subsidized by the company.   - Continued involvement in community development. The Company provides the following services: 250 meals per day are prepared for the needy children of the community; training of and employment for 30 people with mental disorders is provided as part of the working relationship with the local medical institution; 200 handicapped people are given job opportunities at various sites of the Company. Persons with disabilities are first offered technical courses with the associated NGO and are later employed at the plants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pandurata Alimentos Ltda.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-37708" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alexandre dos Reis Neto Treasury/Finance Pandurata Alimentos Ltda. Phone.: 55.11.2573.9443 - fax: 55.11.2573.9451 e-mail:  mailto:alexandrer@bauducco.com.br</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pandurata Alimentos/Bauducco headquarters are located in Guarulhos, state of Sao Paulo. The Company owns 5 modern production facilities, which places the Company among the most competitive players in the market. Three factories are located in the city of Guarulhos (state of S&#xE3;o Paulo), one located in the city of Extrema (state of Minas Gerais) and one located in Rio Largo (State of Alagoas). The Company also owns distribution centers in Guarulhos and Extrema.   The project consists of (i) increase the capacity of the plant in Minas Gerais for the production of toasts and mini cakes, (ii) implement a new line in its Guarulhos plant, (iii) construct a new distribution center in Alagoas to increase sales to the Northeast regions.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="3119" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F-AI - Other Food</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $40.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-28">40000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-28">40000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pandurata Alimentos Ltda.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/37708">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/37708">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
