<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7545</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RODOVIA PRESIDENTE DUTRA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    BRAZIL-Concessionaria da Rodovia Presidente Dutra (Via Dutra)              Region    Latin America and Caribbean        Sector       Project No007545   Projected Board DateSeptember 3, 1996   Company NameConcessionaria da Rodovia Presidente Dutra S.A. (Nova Dutra)   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The Sponsors are Construcoes e Comercio Camargo Correa S.A. (Camargo Correa) and Construtora Andrade Gutierrez S.A. (Andrade Gutierrez).    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	 The estimated total project cost is US$525.5 million.  IFCs proposed investment would include an equity investment of up to US$10.0 million, an A-Loan of US$35 million and B-Loan of US$60 million.    Location of project and Description of site    	The Via Dutra Highway connects the two largest cities in Brazil, S&#xE3;o Paulo and Rio de Janeiro, passes close to several other large cities and connects to several other highways leading to population centers inland and along the coast, including the port of Santos.  Via Dutra is considered to be the country&apos;&apos;s principal economic corridor linking the country&apos;&apos;s two main metropolitan areas, and the industrial centers of the State of Rio de Janeiro (Resenda, Volta Redonda, and Barra Mansa) and the State of S&#xE3;o Paulo (S&#xE3;o Jose dos Campos, Taubat&#xE9;, and Jacare&#xED;).  The Highway also passes through agricultural districts and vegetated mountainous settings in the Serra das Araras region. It is a suburban and intercity highway with two travel lanes along the road and an outside shoulder in each direction near S&#xE3;o Paulo and Rio de Janeiro.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	In exchange for the right to collect tolls during the life of the concession, Nova Dutra is required to upgrade, restore, expand, maintain and operate the 407 km section of the existing Via Dutra Highway (BR-116/RJ/SP), linking Rio de Janeiro and S&#xE3;o Paulo for a 25-year period.  Given the newness of Brazils road privatization program, IFCs presence is needed to give comfort to investors and enable participation by commercial banks and other financial institutions. At present, only  short-term financing is available for such projects in Brazil. This project, as the largest of the first five Federal highways being privatized, will establish a new standard for highway services in Brazil, and will be a model for later privatizations. The reconstruction and upgrading of the Highway will provide a high quality road with modern services compared to the present poor level of service. The higher quality pavement will reduce vehicle operating costs and allow travel at higher operating velocity, thus reducing travel time.  Signaling, illumination and road barriers will all increase operating safety as will the redesigned road accesses. Accidents should decrease significantly from last years 14,000.  Additional lanes near Rio and S&#xE3;o Paulo will increase vehicle capacity and reduce congestion.  New overpasses will allow vehicles and pedestrians safe crossing of the Highway. Additional services to motorists will include emergency call boxes located at one-kilometer intervals.  A series of medical first-aid stations, with ambulance service, will be spread at approximately 70-kilometer intervals.  Emergency service vehicles will also be made available for towing disabled vehicles to the nearest service area.  The Project will employ 3000 people during the Initial Works and around 2,300 during the remainder of the project.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is an environmental review category B project; principal issues are air emissions, liquid effluents, solid waste, emergency response, resettlement, and employee and public safety.  The sponsor has presented plans to address these issues and to comply with applicable governmental and World Bank requirements; key actions include measures for air pollution control and wastewater treatment, employee training, and provisions for spill prevention, traffic safety and emergency response.  The sponsor is working with the local collectives and governmental authorities to ensure that the relocation of about 200 families located in the project right-of-way is handled in a fair and equitable manner.    The  is available  from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     August 2, 1996      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concession&#xE1;ria da Rodovia Presidente Dutra S/A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7545" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-02-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Utilities</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7545/rodovia-presidente-dutra">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
