<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-35271</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOXX URE-BA AMBIENTAL LTDA.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Avoided Emissions and Renewable Energy Promotion: WtE by incineration, compared to traditional landfilling of waste, eliminates methane gas emissions, a potent greenhouse gas (GHG), reducing greenhouse gas emissions. WtE also reduces air and water pollution levels and other negative externalities compared to landfills while also producing a reliable, renewable source of electrical power. The Barueri Project will produce approximately 117GWh of energy annually.  Land Resource Conservation: The volume and weight of the treated waste can be reduced up to 90% by incineration, thereby considerably reducing the demand of land for landfill purposes.  Demonstration Effect: Implementation by municipalities of the new National Waste Law has been slow. Barueri is one of the few municipalities with an integrated MSW plan, and one of the first mass burn WtE projects in Brazil, along with Osasco WtE project. The success of this Project will have strong demonstration effects for similar projects in the rest of the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment is a senior loan, of BRL42 million (approximately US$16 million), to Foxx URE BA Ambiental Ltda (the Project Company) for the construction of a greenfield Waste-to-Energy (WtE) facility in the municipality of Barueri, S&#xE3;o Paulo, Brazil (the Project). Along with IFC, Caixa Econ&#xF4;mica Federal (Caixa) will also be providing a senior loan to the Project Company of BRL183 million (approximately US$69 million). The Projects sponsor, Haztec Investimentos e Participa&#xE7;&#xF5;es S.A. (FoxxHaztec), is the first company to win a mass burn WtE contract in Brazil and is the third largest waste management company in Brazil.  Municipal Solid Waste (MSW) incineration and WtE refer to the same basic process of mass burning of MSW with an added energy-recovery component in the case of WtE.   In 2011, FoxxHaztec was awarded by the municipality of Barueri, through a competitive process, a 30 year private public partnership (PPP) contract to build operate and transfer a WtE facility in Barueri. The WtE facility will have a processing capacity of 825 tons/day (300,000 tons/year), sufficient to process the waste of Barueris 270,000 inhabitants and additional waste from surrounding municipalities corresponding to about 550,000 inhabitants. With an installed capacity of 19MW and a  17.3 MW continuous power generation capacity (14.75MW net capacity) the WtE plant is forecasted to produce approximately 117giga watt hours for export to the grid. The WtE facility will take 3 years to construct and will employ 47 people during operations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foxx Ure Ba Ambiental</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-35271" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="6"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoxxHaztec Rua Samuel Morse, 134  3&#xBA; andar Brooklin  S&#xE3;o Paulo  SP CEP: 04576-060 Tel: +55 11 5103.5300 / Fax: +55 11 5103.5301</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leonardo Santos  Chief Financial Officer  FoxxHaztec  Rua Joaquim Palhares, n.&#xBA; 40 - 1&#xBA; andar  Cidade Nova - Rio de Janeiro - RJ  Cep 20260-080 Tel: +55 21 3974.9149 / Fax: +55 21 3974.6705  email:  mailto:leonardosantos@haztec.com.br</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR-Brazil">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The WtE facility shall be constructed on land currently owned by Sabesp, in the Municipality of Barueri next to the Sabesp wastewater treatment facility along the Rio Tiete in the Sao Paulo metropolitan region in Brazil.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.0000000000 -55.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-DB - Waste to Energy - Waste</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.07 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/35271">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/35271">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
