<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41158230-MOZ006N</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique Cabo Delgado Joint Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The JR proposes a multi-sectoral response to the IDP crisis in Cabo Delgado, in line with the HRP 2021. The JR will be implemented in Cabo Delgado, being the province with the highest needs and will prioritise the following districts: Mecufi, Chiure, Metuge, Montepuez, and Ancuabe. The overarching objective of the JR is to provide 101,185 affected people with life-saving and life-sustaining goods and services CARE will implement WASH, NFI and Protection projects in Chiure and Montepuez. The other JR partners are: PLAN, Cordaid, Oxfam, SOS and Tearfund.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MOZ006N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MOZ006N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ-CDG-JR-parent" ref="NL-KVK-41198890" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-14">434125</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ-CDG-JR-parent">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PLAN International Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-16">412419</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ-CDG-JR-parent">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PLAN International Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-07">401968</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ-CDG-JR-parent"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Mozambique - IU Vendor</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-25">381870</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ-CDG-JR-parent"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Mozambique - IU Vendor</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-26">6764</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41198890-MOZ-CDG-JR-parent"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Mozambique - IU Vendor</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACC-R1</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of crisis-affected people who are also involved in the design, implementation, monitoring and/or evaluation of the programme</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ACC-I1" indicator-uri="https://www.dutchrelief.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="540"></target>
     <actual value="32495">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the 18th and 19th of October, CARE conducted PDM at the resettlement center in Massasse, Montepuez district, where 90 beneficiaries of the DRA project who received hygiene kits were interviewed. This activity involved 5 trained enumerators. Key findings include:
&#x2022;	100% of the respondents were satisfied with the quality of the distributed items from those (39% were satisfied and 61% very satisfied)
&#x2022;	99% of the respondents were satisfied with the quantity of the items while 1% said otherwise.
&#x2022;	100% of the respondents were satisfied with the registration process.
&#x2022;	88% of the responds did not how to do a complaint or suggestion.

Regarding the last finding (88% of the responds did not how to do a complaint or suggestion), CARE will strengthen messaging on how to access complaint and feedback mechanisms (such as the Linha Verde hotline and complaint boxes) prior to future distributions.

On the reporting period, during the distributions of hygiene kits, hygiene replenishment kits, family and kitchen sets and survival kits, CARE was strengthening messaging on how to access complaint and feedback mechanisms, such as the &quot;Linha verde&quot; hotline and complaint boxes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SHL-R4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people provided with non-food items</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="SHL-I1" indicator-uri="https://www.dutchrelief.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4500"></target>
     <actual value="6476">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the reporting period, CARE distributed 650 survival kits in the Educardo Mondlane resettlement center in Mueda district and 769 family kits (including kitchen sets) of which in Montepuezdis district: 235 family kits in the Massingir resettlement center, 53 family kits in the Nacololo resettlement center, 25 family kits in the Nairoto resettlement center, 23 family kits in the Namoro resettlement center, and in the Chi&#xFA;re district 433 family kits in the Megaruma resettlement center.
All of the family kits were including kitchen set.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WSH-R1</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people having regular access to soap to meet hygienic needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="WSH-I1" indicator-uri="https://www.dutchrelief.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10000"></target>
     <actual value="21760">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the reporting period, CARE received 1,750 hygiene kits, donated from the Foreign, Commonwealth &amp; Development Office (FCDO) through UNICEF/WASH Cluster, to distribute under the DRA response. 1,735 hygiene kits were distributed in Montepuez and Chi&#xFA;re of which 120 Hygiene kits were distributed in the Massasse transit center in Montepuez, 234 hygiene kits were distributed in the Ntele resettlement center and 1381 hygiene kits were distributed in the Maningane resettlement center.

The DRA-purchased hygiene replenishment kits were distributed 2915 of which in Montepuez district: 620 hygiene kits in the Massasse resettlement center, 528 in the Upajo resettlement center, 386 in the Ujama resettlement center, 366 in the Mirate resettlement center, and in Chi&#xFA;re district: 274 in the Chi&#xFA;re velho resettlement center, 333 in the Ocua resettlement center, 313 in the Chiote resettlement center and 95 to the users of the Friendly space for women and girls in Marupa resettlement center.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PRO-R11</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of persons reached by the implementation of specific GBV prevention measures</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PRO-I11" indicator-uri="https://www.dutchrelief.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-05-14"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1500"></target>
     <actual value="4259">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the reporting period, CARE conducted the following gender and protection activities:
&#x2022;	CARE in was able to disseminate GBV and PSEA including COVID 19 key messages through Radio Mozambique covering both the Cabo Delgado Province with a focus on the targeting locations (Montepuez and Chiure). CARE has disseminated GBV messaging through face-to-face sessions, covering topics such as prevention of sexual harassment, exploitation and abuse, local reporting mechanisms, taking into account a survivor-centered approach, and was able to reach to 4259 individuals whereby (909 girls, 356 boys, 2454 women and 540 men) in both Montepuez and Chiure.
&#x2022;	In order to support GBV case management, CARE has been working with caseworkers and community outreach activists that have been trained, particularly in the district of Chiure. CARE provided  2 sessions of a 3-day training on GBV case management on intenational satndard, however adapted to the local context. And in order to strengthen the refferal pathway mechanism and the coordination with GBV service providers, we also counted with GBV focal points from the government entry points (health, SDSMAS, GAMFVV, IPAJ). CARE was also able to successfully support a 3 GBV survivor to receive a proper assistance.
&#x2022;	In order to facilitate psychosocial support to IDPs, CARE conducted 2-training sessions for caseworkers and community outreach activists, including community leaders in both Chiure and Montepuez. This training was intended to strengthened the capacity of the caseworkers on how to provide psycological first aid and how to develop and promote positive coping mechanisms towards   distress and traumatic consequences of the conflict; with special focus on how this specifically and disproportionately impacts women and girls. In addition,PSS activities were carried out at the community level being able to conduct 10 sessions in total, (6 in Chiure and 4 session in Montepuz), and in total, there were 1266 individuals (915 women, and 351 girls).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
