<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41158230-NLRCET0001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners for resilience - Integrated risk management in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society organzations, Community based organizations, Local leaders, Government agencies, Private sectors</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact: Vulnerable people are more resilient to crises in the face of climate change and environmental degradation, enabling sustainable inclusive economic growth. Long term outcome: Enhanced policies, investments and practices for vulnerable communities to become resilient in the face of disaster risks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-ET</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31703105050</telephone>
   <email>general@carenederland.org</email>
   <website>http://www.carenederland.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">93811</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">253506</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">119224</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-25">46881</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-17">150217</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-08">134721</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensuring investors adhere to IRM principles</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensuring investors adhere to IRM principles and support communities to have increased resilience to climate shocks and impact by integrating IRM in their investment plans</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in investments (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID02" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve capacities of stakeholders at regional level to implement effective Disaster Risk Management policies</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve capacities of stakeholders (e.g. DRM Commissions; Ministerial Offices for Agriculture, Health; CSO&#x2019;s; private sector) at regional level to implement effective Disaster Risk Management policies</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in project and programme implementation (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID03" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving sustainable and proper management and utilisation of water and land resources</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving sustainable and proper management and utilisation of water and land resources in the catchment by all stakeholders providing sustainable development opportunities for local economies</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in project and programme implementation (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID03" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment strategies are based on the Environmental Impact Assessment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment strategies are based on the Environmental Impact Assessment that include IRM risk screening that involve local communities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in investments (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID02" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are unaware of benefits of risk-informed investments</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are aware of benefits of IRM (proof) investments. No update vs. the previous period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are aware of benefits of IRM (proof) investments.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to support IRM (proof) investments. One private sector entity has committed to work together with the local communities in line with the IRM principles, based on joint plan, as way forward</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to support IRM (proof) investments. the required capacity strengthening activities are undertaken and good partnership established with relevant stakeholders. And preparation are underway to review their EIA guideline, we are confident that the objectives under this trajectory will be achieved in Amhara Region</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are unaware of benefits of IRM (proof) investments. CARE engagement is still pending government approval</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have concrete (signed) plans for risk informed investments. There is a significant progress in achieving the desired change under this trajectory. All PfR alliance member organization have convinced the Federal and Local governments in Afar, Somali and Amhara regions to mainstream IRM in EIA guidelines by making use of the opportunity of revising/putting in place the guideline at national as well as Regional Levels. Therefore, the PFR alliance member Organizations are sure of achieving the desired change, as depicted in the Theory of Change, before the end of the project period. IRM sensitive Environmental and Social Impact Assessment guidelines are going to be strategic documents of the three regions of PfR operation areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have concrete (signed) plans for risk informed investments. There is a significant progress in achieving the desired change under this trajectory. All PfR alliance member organization have convinced the Federal and Local governments in Afar, Somali and Amhara regions to mainstream IRM in EIA guidelines by making use of the opportunity of revising/putting in place the guideline at national as well as Regional Levels.IRM sensitive Environmental and Social Impact Assessment guidelines are put in place at federal and the three regions of PfR operation areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have concrete (signed) plans for risk informed investments. There is a very interesting progress in achieving the desired change under this trajectory. joint support was rendered to the Ministry of Agriculture and Environmental Protection in updating the watershed and EIA implementation guidelines. All PfR alliance member organization have convinced the Federal and Local governments in Afar, Somali and Amhara regions to mainstream IRM in EIA guidelines by making use of the opportunity of revising/putting in place the guideline at national as well as Regional Levels. Therefore, the PFR alliance member Organizations are sure of achieving the desired change, as depicted in the Theory of Change, Before the end of the project period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have concrete (signed) plans for risk-informed investments</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security through the management of agriculture, livestock and rangeland practices</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in project and programme implementation (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID03" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are unaware of benefits of IRM in their projects and practices</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are aware of the importance of IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. We can conclude that we are on track to achieve the objectives. However, speeding up of implementation is crucial in all regions despite the context differs from region to region</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to implement IRM principles in their projects and practices. CARE has formally signed an agreement with authorities in Afar and launched the project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to implement IRM principles in their projects and practices. The link between private veterinary pharmacy owners and Community Animal Health Workers (CAHWs) was strengthened so that CAHWs can get sustainable access to drugs and provide basic animal health services to the pastoralists. Looking at the outcomes &amp; objectives we are slowly making progressing to achieve the objectives. The necessary preparation has also been made in order to speed up of implementation of the planned activities in the following years.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are planning to implement IRM principles in their projects and practices. there is a good indication that  communities are well aware about how ecosystem management and restoration and climate change adaptation can be integrated in the day to day agricultural practices of the community. With regards to the change in the agricultural practices of the community to be IRM sensitive. The efforts of the local government sector bureaus and offices to support the community practice to be IRM sensitive are also good demonstration. more has to be done with the local government to see the change in knowledge into practice.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are unaware of benefits of IRM in their projects and practices. CARE engagement is still pending government approval. In the meantime, the regional Afar government has committed to include IRM in its DRM strategy</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are unaware of benefits of IRM in their projects and practices. CARE has recently managed to gain approval for its project in Afar region. The recurrent drought which is hitting the country is  washing out the interest of the government stakeholders towards the PfR projects since more attention is given to emergency activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have started to implement IRM principles in their projects and practices. IRM has been mainstreamed in DRM strategy and implementation guideline, in DRM communication strategy, in Participatory Rangeland Management Guideline. Our efforts in building the capacity of CSOs &amp; government officials on IRM dialogue &amp; national DRM policy led to the development of these strategies and guidelines which mainstreamed IRM. 
Mainstreaming of IRM into Samera and University DRM post graduate training curriculum is also another success of the project to include IRM in teaching institution.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have started to implement IRM principles in their projects and practices. there is a good indication that communities are well aware about how ecosystem management and restoration and climate change adaptation can be integrated in the day to day agricultural practices of the community. With regards to the change in the agricultural practices of the community to be IRM sensitive, the efforts of the local government sector bureaus and offices is crucial to achieve the anticipated objectives under this trajectory. it is highly important that demonstration catchment sites should be established where the communities would have the chance to see the practical application of IRM approach and the linkage between DRR, EMR and CCA. However, the PFR consortium member organizations are well satisfied in terms of changing the knowledge and skill of communities on IRM and its linkage with their day to day agricultural practices. The need for government engagement is also underlined</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders have started to implement IRM principles in their projects and practices</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRM integration in regional DRM strategy and guidelines</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in development policies (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID01" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide access to climate fund for communities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in investments (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID02" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
