<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41158230-SSD014N</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Leadership and Advocacy (WLAI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WLAI seeks to address key socio-economic barriers affecting women&#x2019;s potential to contribute to social, economic and political progress in South Sudan, as a basis for improving women&#x2019;s quality of life, changing negative social norms, increasing women&#x2019;s influence in decision-making processes, and enabling women&#x2019;s economic empowerment. Based on CARE&#x2019;s Strategy on Gender Equality and Women&#x2019;s Voices and CARE&#x2019;s Female Entrepreneurship Framework, WLAI will address the unequal power relations and access to resources and opportunities that affect South Sudanese women. WLAI will focus on the Juba and Torit Counties and will be implemented in coordination with leading women rights organisations, national parliamentarians, and key government agencies at the national, state and county levels. CARE&#x2019;s support to WROs will strengthen their institutional and networking capacities, leveraging their potential to coordinate effective advocacy that will bring positive change to South Sudan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-SSD014N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-SSD014N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000005048" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16080" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-05">800000</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs- Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-31">600000</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs- Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-27">722576</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE South Sudan - IU Vendor</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs staff/members trained in media (including social media) and  community-based campaign design</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="32">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE conducted a one-day media training on 9th November 2021 in Juba. There were 41ppts (10m, 31f) derived from different media houses within Juba including Eye Radio, City review, Voice of America (VOA), Association of Media Development in South Sudan (AMDISS), South Sudan Broadcasting cooperation (TV &amp;Radio), female journalist network, Freelance journalist. Women Lead Organizations were also present alongside CARE project team. The workshop focused on the role of the media in amplifying the voices of women in South Sudan and how to strengthen coordination between the media and women led organizations to profile more women voices in the media. Some of the key recommendations reached were; WLOs should map out media houses have protection programs and Economic Empowerment, the media should advocate and create awareness on the rights of women and girls and their participation, empower women to have their voices heard, Challenge women to rise up, lobby Editors through the Editor&#x2019;s forum to issue a policy that includes women&#x2019;s voices in each story, empower WRO/WLO on media engagement and the art of public speaking, while inviting the media for events ensure there are high profile speakers to attract the media. 

One day advocacy training for the Women Lead Organization in Juba on 14th Dec 2021 and was attended by 13ppts(10F,3M) from 10 different organization. The aim of the training was to build the capacity of the women led organization on advocacy cycle on how to conduct effective advocacy.

On 12/11/2021, WAPO conducted Mentorship programmed for the capacity enhancement of potential women on various aspects including digital technology. The training was to make women aware of their political, and social rights in leadership positions, breakdown the systematic inequalities that women were experiencing in their daily life, strengthen the leadership skills of potential women who are holding positions in government and other institutions and allow women networking through digital technology. 24(2M, 22F) participants attended.   

On 14th December CARE organised one day capacity building in Juba targeting the technical working group members and network steering committee. The events was focusing on developing capacity of these leaders on advocacy, as well as developing WLO network advocacy strategy.  The members draft the draft advocacy strategies was develop and a follow up meeting was schedule with the rest of the network members to give inputs before its adopted in the next reporting period. Capacity training focused on What is advocacy, the current priorities of advocacy, the key stake holders and how to conduct effective advocacy. These training was attended by 13 participants from who are both members of the TWG and Interim body&#x2019;s 10 Female and 3 males.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs provided with small grants to organize advocacy events on 35% affirmative action and women&apos;s participation and leadership at all levels</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE remains commited to the operational subgrant awarded to two implementimg partners: the CENTER FOR INCLUSIVE GOVERNANCE, PEACE AND JUSTICE (CIGPJ) based in Juba  and the Torit-based WOMEN AGENCY FOR PROGRESS ORGANIZATION (WAPO). The main purpose of the grant is capacity strengthening of the partners to effectively implement advocacy activities on women and girls&apos; human rights especially on the full implementation of the 35% affirmative action at local,  State and National level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.5</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached via radio mass awareness campaigns on gender norms, women&apos;s rights,  participation and leadership</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.5" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20000"></target>
     <actual value="2512">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIGPJ conducted one live radio talk show in Yei on 25th- Nov-2021 on Radio Easter. The topic of the discussion was on the role of women in leadership and pertinent issues of women rights. Three panelists (1F 2M) facilitated the radio talk show. The show took place in Easter Radio FM in Yei , this stations Covers  20 km square and can reach up to  covering 16280 people. It has been estimated based on the link of the Radio station that has about 1,346 (480M 260W 380MY 226FY. 

On 30 Nov 2021, WAPO Developed and distributed low literacy IEC materials 100 T-Shirt during 16th days of Activism GBV.  35 male and 55 female benefits from IEC materials. 92(14m, 54f, 21fy,1f) individuals received copies of the ICE materials. The Material had key messages that talks about women empowerment and create awareness on 16days of activism against GBV.                                                                                                                                                                                                                             CIGPJ printed IEC materials such as T shirts 150 , Caps 50  and 2  role up banner , big 2  banners . This was done purposely to aid visibility of local partners and simplicity to better suit understanding of an ordinary person in the community during  WhenWomenRise campaigns. These IEC materials have been branded with all information related to project and the campaign which has been launched during this reporting period. 
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  
On 30/Nov/2021, WAPO organized four days continues community awareness on media and community base campaign #when women Rise on 35% affirmative Action, the campaign has been carried out in four blocks of fodofodo Ilangi, Nyong and Hai Messer, in Torit County. Participants were 201(33M, 93F, 10 MY, 71 FY).

On 13th December 2021, WAPO Facilitated public debates with local and state government (aired on radio) on 35% affirmative action held in Torit County at Dynamic Business Center. The topic of discussion was on 35% Affirmative Action agreed upon by parties in agreement for the resolution of conflict in South Sudan the WLO led organization had the opportunity to direct talk with leaders why the 35% is not fully implemented. This discussion helped get opinion of the public on the ongoing.

WAPO conducted media and community base campaign on 30th November,2021 on 35% Affirmative Action in four blocks of Torit County at Fodofodo. The main objectives for community awareness to Increase the understanding of community on 35% affirmative action and prepare the way for those women who don&#x2019;t understand their role in the society. The discussions based on women representations and decision making in community levels. The participants continue illustrated that early marriage, denial of girls right to education, peer group and high payment of school fees are the contributing factors affecting the representation of 35% affirmative action, The half day meeting brought together 65 participants (10M, 27F, 2MY and 26 FY.

On 17th December CARE and  WAPO conducted joint activity on community mass awareness campaign at Nyong Payam Torit County .The main objectives of the community mass awareness campaign in Hai Addis Sa baba Nyong Payam Torit County was to create awareness and educate the community on the existing vocational training institute and the importance of technical skill in the fields of carpentry and joinery, basic computer training, plumbing skills, tailoring, electrical and brick laying where the principle of the Torit vocational training center called up women and youth to enroll in December intake. A total of 187 people attended the event (30 males, 60 females, 70 male youth and 27 female youth).    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             On 29th Jan CIGPJ held a radio talk show in Juba at SAMA FM to discuss about the Women enterprise fund. There three penalist all from CIGPJ program manager, Executive director, and project officer. The main objective of the talk show was to create awareness among the ordinary citizens especially women and girls at the grassroot level on the establishment of the women development enterprise fund. The FM is sad to be covering 20km with population of 30,000. An estimate of 260 people tuned on to the discussion.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs/Women Forum members supported in taking part in regional feminist networks/events</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this reporting period there were no regional enagangment that fall within our portifolios that WLOs could attend.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.7</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants (disaggregated  by gender) in State and national level conferences on 35% affirmative action and role of women in nation builiding</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.7" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="520"></target>
     <actual value="108">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From 8th to 10th Dec 2021, CIGJP identified 8 (7women 1man) gender champions from the location of Juba Na Bari (Woman:1), Munuki Block B (Women:2 Man:1), Jebel Yesua (Woman:1), Gumbo Sherikat (Woman:1), Jabborona (Woman:1) and Gudele (Woman:1). Topics discussed were role of the gender champions, women empowerment and 35% affirmative action. The main objective of the orientation of the gender champions is to equip them with skills that can adequately employed during community awareness and campaigns on # when women rise.   

On 18th November, 2021 Women Agency for Progress Organization conducted a roundtable event on 35% affirmative action and role of women in nation building held in Torit at Women center. The key objectives of event was to help women, share issues that are hindering their participation in decision making, political and social affairs and to strengthen the role of women in nation building.  47 participants (1M, 25F, and 18FY joined the round table events from women right organizations, State Members of Parliament, organized forces and local chiefs. participants underlined that 35% Affirmative Action approaches need to go beyond community, Speakers emphasized the significance of political support if such initiatives were to be sustainable, Participants agreed that the 35% Affirmative Action provide a useful framework. Action point was to do engagement with different radio FM to pass the information to the grass root ,Need to pay attention However, a number of interventions pointed out that sensitization on the media and community meetings would be needed to assist women and to reflect more adequately on the specific situation in a State, particularly for societies that had experienced inter-communal conflicts.

On 4/11/2021, WAPO conducted Radio talk show (Radio series) on 35% affirmative action on transitional constitution and women right over 89.5 FM Radio Emmanuel. Its estimated that 800(350M,150F,300MY,100FY). There were three panelists drawn from the women led organisations, local justice sector. 1 male and 3 female.  
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               On 31st January 2022, CIGPJ conducted public awareness on the women enterprise development fund at Sinja Siri Yei. the awareness was to inform the public as specially women and girls on women enterprise development fund to support and upgrade women economic status in South Sudan. This community awareness brought together a total of 56 (30 women 18 men 4 Girls 4 Boys). The participants expressed high level of interest and enthusiasm, they went ahead to share to discuss pressing issues that   Influential women in the community are always left out during community meeting and decision are made in their absence, There is also high level of illiteracy amongst women in the community is dragging them behind Participants then requested for the need to train women in business startup and sustaining and finally argued CIGPJ to keep follow up and update women in Yei on the progress of such funding so that they can benefit from it.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of duty bearers/power holders reached via sensitization sessions on women&#x2019;s economic rights, empowerment led by VSLAs and WROs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation scheduled for Q3 &amp; Q4.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLAs that have joined State level VSLA Unions with support from WROs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Q2, WAPO organised 20 VSLA Groups in Torit.
In the month of November WAPO formed 21 Existing VSLA   groups earlier established under FEEDII project has been organized and formed in  Torit, Ikwoto, and Magwi counties .  These VSLA   will later be formed in to Payam,  and county level VSLA union. A total of 525 members are part of these groups (68 M, 193F, 147MY and 117 FY). These groups are in three counties covering different payam ,  in Ikwoto County, kwoto Payam ( Idimale, Lonyori, Itumi, LoshegereA and Loshegere B ) Hatire Payam and Imotong Payam ), Torit County, the payam include Ifwotu Payam (Gunyoro, Moti.) and Magwi County( Obbo, Omeo, and Paulonganyi,). Members of VSLA have been formed to payam and count level Union. The Executives who are the leaders of the VSLA attaned th state level meeting with WLO to bring key issues for discussion that face VSLA groups. A total of 90 participants attend meeting at the state level.     
                                                                                                                                                     
WAPO organized 20 VSLA groups into Payam and County levels networks in Torit held on 2nd December.2021 and in Magwi held on 7th December,2021. The objective were to register VSLA groups into state VSLA union, to enable them lobby for fund from the government, private sectors and other donors and to create wider space for VSLA groups in carrying out businesses and advocacy activities. The program drawn 5 leaders from each VSLA groups in Torit County include payam of  Ifwuto,and  Nyong  while in Magwi County include payam of Magwi, Obbo, Nimule and Mugali . A total of 100 participants 12M, 44F, 16 MY, 28FY.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of men/boys reached via discussion sessions on positive masculinities and women&apos;s rights using the men engage/EMAP tool</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="360"></target>
     <actual value="57">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 1st November 2021 Women Agency for Progress organization mobilized influential community to discuss topic on women rights and women and girl&#x2019;s empowerment. The discussion brough together (43) 26 Female and 17 male participants as ambassador to advance women&#x2019;s right in the community. Prior to the meeting Participants were briefed on their role as community leaders in advancing the voices of women and girls, how to raise women issues confidential and basic communication skills.                                    

On 18th- Nov 2021 CIGPJ conducted and identification Gender Empowerment movement groups where a total of 8 influential community leaders (4 women, 2 men, 1 female youth and I male youth) were identified. These leaders are men and women from respective communities in Yei to be ambassadors to continue with #WhenWomenRise campaigns to influence community leaders to advance women right and empowerment on Social political and economic participation. These influential community leaders (men, women, and youths (boys and girls) were mobilized from different communities representing different localities in Yei such as Lomuku, Mahad, Luparate, Jigomoni, Hai Leben, dare l salam, Luzira, Batari, Rwonyi and Nyonwe. They as well represented the various categories of individuals from the mentioned communities such as PLWD, teachers, chiefs, women leaders, youth leaders and religious leader.     
                                                                                                                            
On the 10th January 2022, WAPO carried out Engagement of men, boys, faith leaders, traditional chiefs and other informal power holders in dialogues on transforming social norms in Torit Main objective of the meeting was to enable participate internalized how social norms relate to socialization of boys which is full of practices, power and sexual violence. The participants defined socialization of boy child as how he must behave like a man through showing their strength, power over female. It&#x2019;s said that The harmful gender norms that lead to future gender inequalities are taught to boys and girls through their interactions with their family, friends and community as children Hence the meeting urged all parent to educate their children different if there is going to be equality in the community(13m, 1fy, 1my)  
  
On 19th January, WAPO organized half a day community discussion with different community members including faith based, women , men, chiefs and key influential leaders including boys and girls . The discussion focused on transformation of negative cultural norms. A total of 21 participants4M, 1F, 4FY, 12MY).  Participants defined social norms as set of rules that guides the society and some of these rules creates gender imbalances. These imbalance leads discrimination female in most cases, The   head chief of Ikwoto County emphasized to the participants to keep on adopting change on all the negative social norms that are affecting the community, so community leaders to start change in order transform the community.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of radio/TV dialogues on gender policy, women&#x2019;s entrepreneurship and economic empowerment organised</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 23 November 2021, WAPO conducted promotion enrolment of women and youth in government managed vocational training center to create awareness and advertise on the opening of 2021 December enrolment program, the radio talk show consists of 3 panelists. Director department of technical vocational training state ministry of education, Principle of Torit vocational training center and Women Agency for Progress Organization project officer. This was attended by 2300(600m, 800f, 1200my, 700fy).    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     
On 17th January, 2022 WAPO conducted engagement with local authorities such Chamber of Commerce, Ministry of trade and investment to discuss the need for enabling environment for enterprise development and transforms social norms and discriminatory practice in Ikwoto County .  The objectives of engagement of local authorities were to understand the factors that hinder the enterprise development in the community, to create awareness on social norms and discriminatory practices that affect the enterprise development and give recommendations for a more enabling environment for enterprise development. The engagement of local authorities brought together 30 participants: (11M 9F, 4MY, 6FY).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.6</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of public debates on 35% affirmative action aired on radio with support from WLAI</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.6" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 25/11/2021, CIGJP conducted a live radio talk show on the role of the women in leaders and women rights issues in Yei. There were 3(1F, 2M) panelist who facilitated the deliberations on the radio. Over audience during the talk show was estimated to be 1,346 (480M 260W 380MY 226FY) based on the radio catchment area and area population.

The SAA members and gender champion conducted a Radio talk show in Yei at Radio Easter 94.0 FM on 15th- Dec 2021. There were 4 panelists (2 men and 2 women). The topic discussed was the role of women in leadership and the challenges women leaders face. The station covers about 20 KM square and with 23000, inhabitants. It was estimated that 246 people (90 Men 40 Women 60 MY 56 FY) listened to the program.

CIGPJ team together with SAA leaders and gender champions held a Radio talk show in SAMA FM in Juba on 15th- Dec. 2021. There were 4 panelists (2 Men, 2 Female).  It&#x2019;s estimated that 340 (120 Men 70 Women 90 MY  60 FY) attended the radio talk show.  

Gender champion held a Radio talk show on 16th-Dec 2021 at Youth advance radio in Juba. The were 4(2Male 2Female). Its estimated that 280 people (90Men 60Women 80MY 50FY) attended to the program.

WAPO conducted media and community-based campaign on 17th January,2022 on Bad cultural practices in two Bomas of Ikwoto Payam at Hai Turuju on 17th January 2022 brought together 66 participants (16M,21F,13MY,16FY), on the 21st September 2022 carried awareness at Ifune Boma , 50 participants attended (4M, 24F, 13MY,9FY). The main objectives for community awareness are as follows, To change the minds of those women and men who have not had the opportunity to question gender roles attitude and beliefs and those who were unaware of their rights, To minimize the rate of early/forced marriages, and girl child compensation, To help them understand the role of gender and human right in the family.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth/women (disaggregated by age and gender) engaged via career guidance and employment opportunity meetings at the State level</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 29th January 2022 CIGPJ held a panel discussion on Women Enterprise Development Fund at the South Sudan Council of Churches (SSCC) in Juba. The panel discussion under the theme &#x201C;Economic Empowerment for Women&#x201D; which drew 28 participants (11Women 6Men 7Female youth 4Male youth) and was facilitated by CIGPJ program staff. The invitees included: participants from the Juba university, Civil society, faith-based groups, grassroot women, media, business community, representative from the ministry of trade and the youth groups. The main objective of the event was to create awareness amongst the women and the youth on the women enterprise development fund provided by the R-ARCSSS  and to push the respective ministry to urgently established responsible for overseeing and distribution of Women Enterprise fund.

On 17th January WAPO organized a similar discussion in Magwi country and brought youth, women to discuss key business opportunities and recommendation was the need to train women and youth in vocational skills. Participants also noted that some cultures donot allow women to engage in business and employment activity and are confined by domestic work which has to be done by men. A total of 23 participants (2M, 6F, 6M, 9FY). 

WAPO and Gender champions, leaders of VSLA groups recorded a message on the effect of excluding women in economic activities, this message was played on   Radio 97.5FM the voice of EE in Torit County and Radio 93.0FM The Voice of Freedom in Magwi County respectively.  Radio 97.5FM has an average coverage 85km square covering 21750 people and Radio 93.0FM has average coverage of 57km square covering 16,680 people. It has been estimated based on the link of the two Radio stations that has about 15014 people listening to the radio jingles. Out of the above figures, 780are men, 300 women, 210 are male youth and 100 female youths.  This run-on radio for 4 days starting from 19th-22 January 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Advocacy events organized by CSOs/WROs at the State and national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 2nd and 3rd of Dec 2021, CARE organised a two-day National Symposium on women peace and security under the theme &quot;Together for her: strengthening women leadership to achieve gender equality in South Sudan&quot;. The event was organised in Juba and attended by 54ppts (38F,16M). This event brought women from Torit and Juba. The purpose of the event was to create awareness on women peace and security, to uplift the voice of women from the state to the national level, to create platform for the women to dialogue build synergies and enhance collaboration and partnership. Some of the action points developed during the event were supporting and strengthening the women networks at the state, enhancing collaboration with the Government at the state level, need for similar events that will bring more women together to learn review and share experience.

On 19th November CARE organised one day events in Juba at HAMZA Inn hotel and brought participants from the different WLO to meet and form their technical working group. The purpose of this events was to identify members of the technical committee to support the network in drafting any advocacy statement, reviews and take upper hands in planning and follow up key advocacy meetings on behalf of the network as well as develop key advocacy messages that WLO can be using in their various organization. The Technical Working Group TWG formed was comprised of 7(3 male and 4 female) (Chairperson, secretary, and the board members). A total of 46 participants attended the events who were down from 32 WLO and 3 media house such as Juba Monitor, South Sudan Broadcasting cooperation SSBC and Juba ECO FM and Top FM.
 
On 18/11/2021, CIGJP organised a mobilization and orientation of the influential community ambassadors for the #WhenWomenRise campaigns in Yei, Central Equatoria State. The meeting was attended by 8 (2 m, 4 female -F, 1 male youth-MY, 1 female youth). These ambassadors were drawn from localities in Yei such as Lomuku, Mahad, Luparate, Jigomoni, Hai Leben, dare l salam, Luzira, Batari, Rwonyi and Nyonwe. They agreed to conduct the training through radio discussions, messaging, church awareness and identified community groups led by both men and women. 
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   
On 18/NOV/2021, WAPO conducted a round table events  on 35% affirmative action and role of women in nationbuilding, Women discussed challenges they face in political, economic and other leaderships positions for example appointment of state MPs did not reach 35%. 26 (1 M, 25 F) participants attended.    
                            
On 19/11/2021, CIGJP organised a mobilization and orientation of the influential community ambassadors for the #when women rise campaigns in Juba. 15( 8F,5M,1 MY,1FY) participants attended. The main objective of the meeting was to orient the community leaders on the role they are expected to play in promoting women&#x2019;s participation in decision and leadership roles at community level. Equally, the community leaders were equipped with advocacy skills, communication, and mobilization skills.  
On 10th Nov 2021, CIGJP organised a meeting with the Hon. Minister of Gender Child and Social Welfare for CES. The meeting focused on the implementation of the affirmative action of 35% quota for women, engendering peace process and mainstreaming gender in key transitional issues including the constitutional making process, Transitional Justice, and Local Governance as well as ways of ensuring all structures adhere to the 35%. 4(2M, 2F).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.5</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs/Women forum members supported in taking part in cross-learning visits aimed at supporting networking among CSOs/WROs (State/regional/global level)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.5" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 5/11/2021, WAPO conducted learning events with women in leadership/decision making processes to discuss on their challenges and lesion learnt. The participants were drawn from women right organizations, government representative and local chiefs attended the event, and the coverage was done 101 Mireya FM and Radio Emmanuel 88.9 FM. 25 Female attended.

On the 16th day of December 2021, WAPO conducted joint activity on the formation of Gender Empowerment Movement group mainly composed of men and boys, the activity was carried in Torit County. The gender empowerment movement composed of 16 (7M and 9MY) members with chairperson, secretary and information secretary that will bring them together once a while for meeting purpose. The main objectives of gender empowerment movement to promote development of gender equitable relationship between men, women, boys and girls at household, places of work and community levels. The objective is to 1. To change attitude of men on women active participation in society in seeing the positive side of women in paid work, peace building processes, leadership and community decision making, promote rights of women life free from violence, supporting women economic empowerment, the right of women to engage in key decision making in the house and seeing violence against women as unjust practices in the community, educate men about gender socialization reflecting on the types of masculine identity society expects of them being charge, the provider and being the strong sex.However, one gender empowerment movement was formed in Torit County during month of December 2021 that is composed of (9M 7MY).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.5</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of women leaders selected from existing/newly established networks trained in leadership, negotiation, coordination and communication skills</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.5" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="42">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 5th November 2021, Women Agency for Progress Organization conducted a one-day learning event with women in key leadership positions in Torit State. The main objective of this event was to create spaces for women leaders discuss key issues that are relevant to women in the state and discuss challenges and identify their strength to inform their advocacy for effective representation of women interests in public offices . Key issues identify was lack of spaces for women leaders to meet and discuss as they reflect on key challenges and opportunity for women in the state, Women leaders needs support in leadership and advocacy . A total of 45 participants attended 18  Female, 2 Female youth, and 25 male youth.     
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         On 12th November, WAPO carried out mentorship programmed for the capacity enhancement of potential women on various aspects including digital technology in Torit. The topic of discussion was the approaches of feminism as liberal and generous women and access of information through social media. Government representatives, women led organizations, community leaders and Business Community. objectives of mentorship program to strengthen the leadership skills of potential on how to use digital technology to break barriers that affect and inequalities that affect women and girls. A total of 24 participants attended the mentorship training, 22 Female and 2 Male.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Social Analysis and Action (SAA) groups established and supported through targeted capacity building</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 9th November, CIGPJ rejuvenated 8 existing Social Analysis and Action i with key objective Training them as TOT to create awareness and educate the community about the negative cultural norms that affect communities.  Through this groups CIGPJ talked about the campaign called #WhenWomenRise campaigns. The formation of SAA groups was done through influential community leaders, women and men groups including youth groups that implement a range of programs including peace building, Economic Saving groups and  women unions. The total identified number of SAA groups members are 181 (146F 35M.    
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                              
On  25/11/2021, CIGJP facilitated the formation of additional SAA group in Yei comprising of 22 members (6M,13F,1MY, 2FY), Leaders were oriented on their role in educating the community on the important of peaceful coexistence, women participation in decision making at household and community, communication skills, and also link these to 35% affirmative action enshrined in the Transitional constitution of South Sudan 2011.  

On 25/11/2021, CIGJP facilitated the formation of the SAA groups in Juba. This is equally a rejuvenation of 11 existing SAA groups in Juba. This was done through mobilization by the community volunteers as from 9th to 17th Nov. 2021 in the locations of Gumbo (F20 M5), POC (F3 8M), New site (F18 M2), Gudele B (F30 M10), Juba Na Bari (F20 M5), Gbongoroki (F15 M10), Joborona (F8 M5), Melekia (F25 M10), Gurei (F15 M3), Kapuri (F10 M2) and Lologo (20F 5M) giving a total of 249 members (184F, 65M).  
        
On 1-Nov-2021, WAPO conducted meeting for the Identification of male and female ambassadors for change from influential community leaders/ local chiefs in attendance 17 male and 26 females. This is to enable the ambassadors to send message from the grassroot and create awareness on harmful practices. 33(10M, 17F, 7MY, 9FY) attended.  
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     
 on 14th January, 2022  WAPO and CARE  conducted one day workshop  to community facilitators/Gender Champion in order to better provide support and  strengthen the capacity of SAA groups in Torit County   ,The objective of training was to spearhead and advance women right and gender equality at community .To equip gender champion  with  skills and SAA tools for awareness on the negative norms that leads to gender inequalities . A total of 20 participants: (1M, 6F, 7MY, 6FY.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                A similar training was conducted in Ikottos on 21st January 2022, and it brought together 25 participants: (13M, 1F, 6MY, 5FY.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLA members (disaggregated by age and gender) trained in economic opportunities, economic rights and gender norms</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="750"></target>
     <actual value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On January 13th and 14th WAPO Organized   business and employment opportunity meetings and career guidance sessions targeting youth and women at state levels. through appropriate media in Torit, Magwi and Ikwoto Counties. The targeted women, youth involve in business to give them career guidance on how to manage their businesses as well as encourage them to form enterprises and enrolled into vocational training institute to acquire skills to manage and sustain their business. A total of 33 participants: (13M, 10F, 6MY, 14FY). Participants mentioned that it is important to address this business and employment opportunity because some cultures don&apos;t allow women to engage in business and employment activity but rather confined by domestic works.      
                                                                                                                          
On 18th Janauary  WAPO also the same training to VSLA members In Ikwoto County with a total of 20 participants:(4M, 6F, 3MY, 10FY) In all these discussions the same issues were strongly repeated which is denial of women in some cultures to engage in business activities and the need to provide vocational training and small grants to women to start businesses. Issues such as women participants in economic activities were some key issues identified that require advocacy interventions. After the meeting, participants were selected as penalists to be hosted in a  radio discussion about these issues and to hear the perspective of the other community members.
                                                                                                                     
On 19th Janaury, 2022 WAPO conducted Training to women led VSLA and youth led VSLA groups on economic opportunity, economic rights and gender norms in Ikwoto County Team leaders of four different VSLA groups were brought and trained on Business opportunities, business startup. A total of 20 participants were reached M4, W6, MF3 FY 17</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of power holders/duty bearers (Payam, County and State levels) trained in women&apos;s rights, gender norms, and women&apos;s leadership and participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall there were twenty two duty bearers who attended the women leadership trainings in the various locations in Juba, Yei and Torit.
On 24th November CIGPJ conducted one day workshop in Juba at Intra Africa Hotel to equip the community leaders on their roles as SAA leaders . Topics covers were introduction to SAA, Role of Community leaders in Sustaining the SAA groups and  approaches  on how to enter community to conduct  discuss  on gender norm. A full comprehensive TOT training to the leaders is schedule to take place in March. A total of 22 participants attended workshop 15 Female and 7 Male.
                                                                                                                       
On December 15th CIGPJ identified Gender champion in Juba covering different Payam of Gumbo, Munuki, Jebel Yesua ,Joborona , Gudele . These Gender Champion were invited for an orientation in CIGPJ office where they were taken through their  role as  the gender champions which is to champion gender equality in their communities , Empowerment of women as solution to blech the huge gender gap that exist in Society  by creating awareness 35% affirmative action.  A total of 8 gender champion were identify and given orientation 7 female and 1 male.   

On 13th December Gender Champion identify by CIGPJ organized half a day community awareness discussion on social norms at Luparate in Yei. The discussion was focusing on giving women a space to be part of decision-making which is enshrined in the peace agreement in accordance with the  35% affirmative action provision. Empowering women who strengthen the social fabrics among communities and their engagement in public discussion if South Sudan is to achieve the 35% women Quota. A total of 25 participants including 15 women and 10 men attended this community discussion.

On 16th of December in Juba CIGPJ organized community awareness to community leaders and Gender Champions in Gbodokoro where issues of social norms were discussed such as household decision-making being headed by a man and role of a women. The discussion futured in key aspects of women empowerment and important of gender equality so that no one is left behind. It was also discussed that women are unable to take part in decision making or participate in community discussion because of the heavy responsibility lays on them a home. A total of 27 participants attended the discussion ,19 Female and 8 males.     

On the 13th January 2022, WAPO conducted comprehensive training of duty bearers at state level on human right, gender, gender norms and gender related laws and policies in Torit County at SPLM State Secretariat Hall.  The objectives of the meeting was To strengthen duty bearer&#x2019;s capacity in leadership and increase their contribution towards human right, To enable them to protect and promote women right issues within the state and community level. Continue community awareness rising to reduce harmful cultural practices. The training brought together 23   participants (5M, 11F, 1MY, 6FY).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.9</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of copies of book on community women leaders printed and distributed to relevant stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.9" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development of Profiles of Female leaders at state and national level is on going and will be complted in the next reporting period.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLA members (disaggregated by age and gender) provided with revolving funds for IGAs/entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will be conducted in the next reporting period in accordance with partners&apos; work plans</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLA members (disaggregated by age and gender) trained in financial literacy (basic bookkeeping and numeracy)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.1" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will be done in the next reporting period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of women VSLA members and women leaders trained in literacy and key aspects of digital technology</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will be done in the next reporting period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.10</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of viewers reached with documentary on community women leaders (public viewings + on-air viewership)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.10" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15000"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will be reported in the next reporting period according to partners&apos; workplan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.11</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of copies of the bi-annual magazine on women leaders printed and distributed to relevant stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.11" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="300"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This will be reported in the next reporting period according to partners&apos; workplan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Women&apos;s Parliamentarian Caucus members trained in relevant thematic areas of policy analysis and advocacy</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="180"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">To be implemented in Q3 &amp; Q4.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.8</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of power holders/duty bearers engaged in Community Score Cards exercises on 35% quota</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.8" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">WAPO implemented the community score card as an accountability tool to engage with duty bearers in Torit County at women center held on 16th December 2021. The objective was to find out whether local actors are accountable on the prevention of GBV and if they understand the low or are aware of the different GBV hotline that exist for purses of referring cases they received in local court. A total of 15 participant: (8M, 7F).    

WAPO and CARE project officers, conducted community score card interface meeting with community leaders in Ikwoto County at women center on 20th January 2022. The objective was to find out whether local actors are accountable on the prevention of GBV issues in the community and to identify issues and report issues happening in their community, 27 participants: (23M, 2F, 1MY, 1FY).  
                                                                                                                                                                                                                       
implementation of the peace agreement especially looking at the  35% which is still remain unfulfilled by the political leaders .this conversation was attended by  35 participants: (18F, 12M, 3MY, 2FY). hence Follow advocacy has been planned for next quarter.          

WAPO conducted one live radio talk show in Magwi on the 18th Dec, 2021 on 93.0FM Voice of Freedom. The topic of the discussion was on 35% Affirmative Action, and women participation in transitional constitution review process Six panelists from parliament, Community leaders and media were hosted on air to discuss this topics (6 Female) Radio Voice of freedom has an average coverage 57km square covering 16,680 people. It has been estimated based on the link of the Radio station that has about 2,500 people listening to the radio talk shows. Out of the above figures, 987(420M, 380 F, 100MY, 87FY)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
