<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41158230-NLRCUG0001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partners for resilience - Integrated risk management in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society organzations, Community based organizations, Local leaders, Government agencies, Private sectors</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact: Vulnerable people are more resilient to crises in the face of climate change and environmental degradation, enabling sustainable inclusive economic growth. Long term outcome: Enhanced policies, investments and practices for vulnerable communities to become resilient in the face of disaster risks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-UG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31703105050</telephone>
   <email>general@carenederland.org</email>
   <website>http://www.carenederland.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">126845</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">173817</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">163817</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-17">62683</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Uganda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-26">64162</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Uganda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-07">86908</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Uganda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-05-31">164728</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Uganda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-23">84859</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C-Uganda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41158230-MUL033N" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated risk management approach is mainstreamed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated risk management approach is mainstreamed in national disaster preparedness and management policy</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in development policies (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID01" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated risk management approach is mainstreamed in development policies re. climate change</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in development policies (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID01" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to supporting IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are actively engaged in IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. Although the Bill has not yet been assented to into Law, the Alliance has worked so hard to reach the level of final approval in Parliament. There is an appreciation of the process and stakeholder involvement to date. Main 5-year outcomes:
- the final draft includes 80% of PfR views and is ready for final tabling and assenting to which will cover the final 10%.
&#x2022; The formation of the standing committee on climate change.
&#x2022; The parliamentary forum on climate change 5 year strategy integrated IRM that will contribute to sustainability.
&#x2022;	Capacity strengthening on IRM
&#x2022;	Increased appreciation of climate change among legislators.
&#x2022;	Increased media reporting on climate change.
&#x2022;	Increased prioritisation on climate change issues in development agenda e.g. presidential aspirants</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are actively engaged in IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. PFR Uganda is close to achieving the change in the theory of change because policy makers are appreciative of the IRM principles. This is credited to the exposures and trainings they have received from the PFR programme. The Climate Change bill is IRM sensitive which means that its implementation will include the implementation of IRM principles. National government agencies and Local Government units have mainstreamed IRM components in inclusive council debates, plans and policies and laws as well as ordinances and by- laws. This has been achieved by influencing IRM responsive legislations, debates, oversight and budgeting of both the local leaders and Members of Parliament. 
These positive outcomes are attributed to the sustained constructive engagement between PFR Partners enabling the partners to interact, participate and engage with the Parliamentarians through their various structures including the Parliamentary platforms and committees and its members such as the Natural Resources Committee of Parliament, The Climate Change Committee, The Committee on Agriculture and the Budget Committee through the links and spaces facilitated by PFCC &#x2013; U. This sustained interaction has seen the recommendations and technical inputs from PFR alliance and partners debated in the floor of Parliament and sometimes considered as in the cases listed here in. We are confident of achieving the Theory of Change will be achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are actively engaged in IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. The appreciation of IRM among policy makers is point for satisfaction however the enactment of the climate change bill has taken too long and yet effects of climate change in Uganda are worsening. There is an urgent need to fast track the bill which will lead to financing of the policy hence implementation of the climate change policies. Significant milestones and key actions notably that: The Cabinet approved the Climate Change Bill, 2018 on 24th March 2019 and very soon it will be tabled before Parliament. This will be fast-tracked since the MPs are prepared and inducted on IRM approaches and practises; The Parliament of Uganda constituted Parliament Standing Committee on Climate Change on 23rd May 2019 in line with Article 90 (1) of Uganda&#x2019;s Constitution and in line with Rule 182 A of the Parliamentary Rules of Procedure. Rule 182 A (1) provides that the &#x2018;&#x2019;Committee on Climate Change shall provide oversight on the responsiveness of the Government to matters of climate change, its mitigation and adaptation&#x2019;&#x2019;. Therefore, this Committee will reinforce the work of PFCC-U in mainstreaming and integration of IRM approach in Parliament and overall government work and functioning. Lastly, the Parliament reviewed, amended and passed the National Environmental Law, 2018 with clear IRM approaches in them, since PFCC-U was part of the Technical working Group of the bill and ensured IRM components strengthens the bill. III.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to supporting IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. Main activities: Facilitate dialogues for integration of NCCP indicator guidelines into  local governrnents performance assessment system; Participate in CBA11, world meteorology day, etc.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to supporting IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. Main outcomes: PfR Uganda partners are recognised for their experiences in IRM: as a results a focal person has been assigned Under the Climate Change department. This recognition created space for PfR Uganda to effectively communicate and participate in the Climate Change Bill development. Worth to mention is that it is not common practice to assign a focal person within government structure; IRM interventions are included as part of climate change and mitigation indicators in the national Climate Change Indicator Guidelines. Four ministries (Agriculture and Animal Industry and Fisheries, Local Government, Water and Environment, Health) have revised their sector-specific reporting indicators accordingly; Otuke District committed to increase integration of DRR in its various departments; Members of Parliament drawn from the two committees (Committee on Climate Change and Committee on Disaster Risk Reduction)have been oriented on the linkages between climate change, disaster risk reduction and the sustainable development goals. The orientation enhanced the understanding on the linkages between these two policies: National Development Plan II and SDGs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are open to supporting IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. We stand at 60% in the theory of change and confident in the significance of changes realised because: 38% of PfR policy recommendations were adopted into the national climate change bill, 2017 by validation time; Stakeholder engagement and collaboration for further influencing of the bill; Assortment by district council to the natural resources ordinance and submission to State Attorney for approval, (Otuke); Adoption of revenue enhancement strategy by council(Otuke); Number of activities of duty bearers especially in regards to natural resources committee (number of trucks impounded as a result of CBMs work, budget allocations for 2018/2019) in Otuke district</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders demonstrate limited engagement in IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. Overall status: on track. Cordaid partners and Care &#x2013; carried out IRM GAP analyses as evidence. Cordaid partners facilitated different level- national and district level (regional) consultation on the draft climate change bill, Capacity building for CSOs and other stakeholders  such as Member of Parliaments ( MPs) , capacity building for Media, etc. Conducted National CSO symposium on CBA11 to influence decisions of key stakeholders. Registered and participated in CBA11 field visit and conference (exhibition, panel presentation on EBA). Conducted CBA11 reflection meeting (breakfast). Networking and building alliances with ACCRA consortium, CAN-U and others in the process of CC bill dialogue, etc. Capacity building for CSOs, CBOs, government officials and community structures.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders demonstrate limited engagement in IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks. The most significant outcome was that 40% of PfR&#x2019;s policy recommendations were adopted in the climate change bill and that the bill was put on the agenda of the cabinet for final review and approval. There are some challenges such as limited funding, the existence of many related prioritised bills and political changes which may lead to a delay in the passing of the bill. Nevertheless, there is increasing pressure by CSOs and Members of Parliament in ensuring the process is concluded and the bill is fast-tracked. Other major outcomes include the adoption of National Climate Change Indicators by the Climate Change Department, the integration of IRM principles into Uganda&#x2019;s Technology Needs Assessment tool, the joining of media houses to draft a climate change communication strategy which includes IRM, and the direction from the National Planning Authority to District Local Governments to mainstream climate change into their budgets and plans. The ToC remains valid, but it is devised to have new engagement strategies amidst the changing context to seize available opportunities and ensure more cabinet ministers put the bill on the agenda.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key stakeholders are actively engaged in IRM mainstreaming in policies and legal frameworks</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated risk management approach is mainstreamed in development policies regarding wetlands</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in development policies (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID01" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investments are risk informed and earmarked for IRM</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in investments (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID02" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects and programs are implemented based on integrated risk management principles</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of inclusion of Integrated Risk Management principles in project and programme implementation (0-5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="PFR-ID03" indicator-uri="https://partnersforresilience.nl/en/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
