<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41158230-SSD014N</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41158230" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Leadership and Advocacy (WLAI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WLAI seeks to address key socio-economic barriers affecting women&#x2019;s potential to contribute to social, economic and political progress in South Sudan, as a basis for improving women&#x2019;s quality of life, changing negative social norms, increasing women&#x2019;s influence in decision-making processes, and enabling women&#x2019;s economic empowerment. Based on CARE&#x2019;s Strategy on Gender Equality and Women&#x2019;s Voices and CARE&#x2019;s Female Entrepreneurship Framework, WLAI will address the unequal power relations and access to resources and opportunities that affect South Sudanese women. WLAI will focus on the Juba and Torit Counties and will be implemented in coordination with leading women rights organisations, national parliamentarians, and key government agencies at the national, state and county levels. CARE&#x2019;s support to WROs will strengthen their institutional and networking capacities, leveraging their potential to coordinate effective advocacy that will bring positive change to South Sudan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-SSD014N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41158230-SSD014N" ref="NL-KVK-41158230" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000005048" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16080" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-05">800000</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000005048">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs- Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-31">600000</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000005048">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs- Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-27">722576</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000005048"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE South Sudan - IU Vendor</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.11</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of copies of the bi-annual magazine on women leaders printed and distributed to relevant stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.11" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="300"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biographies  of female leaders have been developed and is being reviewed. Once it&apos;s finalized, the document will be printed and will be distributed to relevant skeholders in May 2022.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Women&apos;s Parliamentarian Caucus members trained in relevant thematic areas of policy analysis and advocacy</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="180"></target>
     <actual value="56">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE and CIGPJ conducted two activities targeting CES Women Parliamentarians on Gender Responsive Budgeting in Juba from 10th  &#x2013; 11th March 2022 and the second training targeted members of the Council of State - CoS and Transitional National Legislative Assembly - TNLA from 15th -17th March 2022. The training was intended to strengthen women parliamentarian caucus on Budget analysis and monitoring, Gender responsive budgeting, national budget planning analysis and their oversight roles. The training which were facilitated by professional from the University of Juba.   In both training a total of 56 women parliamentarian caucus participated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.9</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of copies of book on community women leaders printed and distributed to relevant stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.9" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE recruited a consultant to develop a booking keeping, and numeracy training manual. A draft has been finalized and is being reviewed. Once approved, it will be printed and distributed to relevant stakeholders in May. Similarly, WAPO developed 230 posters with low literacy content IEC materials which were printed and distributed on 8th of March, International Women&#x2019;s Day. The posters had messages on GBV prevention to educated community.  The beneficiaries are women forum, local chiefs, gender champion, VSLA group members, police gender unit, youth, and State Ministry of Gender staff.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs provided with small grants to organize advocacy events on 35% affirmative action and women&apos;s participation and leadership at all levels</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE remains committed to the operational subgrant awarded to two implementing partners: the CENTER FOR INCLUSIVE GOVERNANCE, PEACE AND JUSTICE (CIGPJ) based in Juba  and the Torit-based WOMEN AGENCY FOR PROGRESS ORGANIZATION (WAPO). The main purpose of the grant is capacity strengthening of the partners to effectively implement advocacy activities on women and girls&apos; human rights especially on the full implementation of the 35% affirmative action at local,  State and National level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.10</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of viewers reached with documentary on community women leaders (public viewings + on-air viewership)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.10" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="15000"></target>
     <actual value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIGPJ organized a one-day meeting with young emerging women leaders gathered to sharing experience and get to know each other. The forum was mentorship and building the CV of young and potential young women leaders.  The meeting brought together young women who art of the peace monitoring mechanism established known as CTSAMM young women leaders from high school and youth representatives in the RJMEC, a mechanism provided in the peace agreement to monitor the implementation of the peace agreement. The event consists of storytelling, sharing of talent, submission of biography which letter be published in the newspaper/magazine.  A total of 25 young women and youth members of parliament attended the event on 4th March 2022. Additionally, a video clip was recorded about the National Symposium and is expected to be shared with stakeholders in May.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.5</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs/Women forum members supported in taking part in cross-learning visits aimed at supporting networking among CSOs/WROs (State/regional/global level)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.5" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="32"></target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, CARE provided series of learning and experience sharing platform for WLOs in Juba and Torit to enhance the capacity and skill to successfully implement and monitor program and harvest successes of their joint advocacy and networking. activities conducted included Rapid Gender Analysis (RGA), monitoring and evaluation training, organizational capacity assessment training, the WLAI baseline validation workshop, mentoring and coaching, quarterly advocacy review meeting and joint advocacy against GBV and other forms of violations against women and girls. The advocacy initiatives included drafting open letters to the Rt. Hon. Speaker of the TNLA, and the Revitalized Joint Monitoring and Evaluation Commission (RJMEC). In Q2, 13 cross learning events were conducted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Social Analysis and Action (SAA) groups established and supported through targeted capacity building</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, CARE provided series of learning and experience sharing platform for WLOs in Juba and Torit to enhance the capacity and skill to successfully implement and monitor program and harvest successes of their joint advocacy and networking. activities conducted included Rapid Gender Analysis (RGA), monitoring and evaluation training, organizational capacity assessment training, the WLAI baseline validation workshop, mentoring and coaching, quarterly advocacy review meeting and joint advocacy against GBV and other forms of violations against women and girls. The advocacy initiatives included drafting open letters to the Rt. Hon. Speaker of the TNLA, and the Revitalized Joint Monitoring and Evaluation Commission (RJMEC). In Q2, 13 cross learning events were conducted.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of men/boys reached via discussion sessions on positive masculinities and women&apos;s rights using the men engage/EMAP tool</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="360"></target>
     <actual value="234">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From 1st - 4th March 2022 several meeting were conducted which resulted into formation of five (5) Social Action and Analysis (SAA) groups. A total of 88 participants attended the meetings (7 Male, 24 female, 24 male youth and 33 female youth). The team then facilitated a session to each SAA group to better equip them with skills to advance women&#x2019;s rights and to enable them to continue to educate communities of negative norms that are imposed on women and girls. WAPO conducted another meeting on  meeting to Identify male and female ambassadors for change from influential community leaders/local chief in Ikwoto County. In Juba, CIGPJ conducted community awareness on women rights and GBV at the Protection of Civilians (POC) 3 Site in Juba on 28th March 2022. This event was facilitated by SAA leaders. A total of 22(7 females, 12 males,  1 female youth,  3 male youth) participants attended the session and this included: Influential community leaders, faith-based groups, women, youth PWD and some students. In Q2, 3 SAAs were established.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.7</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants (disaggregated  by gender) in State and national level conferences on 35% affirmative action and role of women in nation builiding</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.7" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="520"></target>
     <actual value="602">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Q1 and Q2 303 participants were reached on affirmative action of which 200 were direct beneficiaries estimated to have tuned to the program. In Q3, 299 were reached.
During this reporting period, WAPO and CIGPJ have been able to conduct series of events at the national and state level on 35% affirmative action.

On 11th o March 2022, CARE supported women led organization with direct grants to conducted one day round table discussion on transitional justices. The discussion how women can effective be part and partial during the ongoing transitional justices process to enhance their contribution in policy processes. The discussion also provided a space to collect views and opinion of women, s views on the type of legislation they would want to see. A total of 24 participants attended 18 Female and 6 males, all participants came from across the WLO, government offices more especially women state government.
On 16th February 2022, WAPO conducted tea talk discussion with Women leaders and young women to established intergenerational leadership network in Magwe county. The meeting to discuss about women positioning in leadership, do awareness to increased understanding of all women and young women on 35%   to start preparing women for upcoming South Sudan Election, while being mindful of the challenges and opportunities they fore see until then. A total of 15 participants attended the meeting 12 Female and 3 Female youth. They women also share their frustration regarding the gap in fulfilling the 35% and women leaders which calls for leadership to be accountable for failing to respect the peace agreement. Recommendation was to continue raising awareness on the gap and identify and prepare women and youth women to be ready to take up leadership whenever called for.
On 9th March CIGPJ with support from CARE organized a high-level event on women peace and security in juba under the Theme equality today for sustainable tomorrow. The events brought together 260 participants 120 Female, 40 Male, 80 Female youth and 20 male youth across government, donors&#x2019; community, media, CSO/Business community and WLO. The events aimed at continued engagement awareness on the campaign which was launch in January known as WhenWomnRise campaign. Many activities took place, live dram, Poetry, muscle performance and several speeches including donor community. All the activities and speeches made directed towards empowering women to rise up.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.5</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached via radio mass awareness campaigns on gender norms, women&apos;s rights,  participation and leadership</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.5" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20000"></target>
     <actual value="14922">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Quarters 1 and 2, 12462 people were reached via radio mass awareness campaigns and in Q3 2460 people were reached.

Q3 Activity summary
WAPO held three radio talk shows on key issues affecting women. The first radio show was hosted by Voice of Freedom 93.0 FM on 22nd February which focused the status of the implementation of 35% affirmative action and women participation in Permanent constitutional review process. A total of approximately 560 members listen to the radio at the time of discussion 200 men, 60 Female Youth and 120 Female and 120 Male youth. WAPO also conducted another radio talk show in Torit on 30th April to educate the public on women&#x2019;s rights and 35% affirmative action. A total of 1900 listeners were  estimated to have listened to the deliberations. 650 were male, 570 women ,410 male youth and 270 female youth (how did you come with this figures to segregate participants by gender).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of radio/TV dialogues on gender policy, women&#x2019;s entrepreneurship and economic empowerment organised</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In previous two quarters, 5 radio dialogues on gender policy, women&#x2019;s entrepreneurship and economic empowerment were organised. In Q3,only 1 was organised
CARE Provided guidance to 6 identified WLO representatives and facilitated them to  meet with Rt.  Honorable speaker of the TNLA to discuss key issues in related to women economic empowerment and other pressing issues affecting women in the community including violations of women&apos;s rights. The meeting results into key action points where the speaker committed to have meeting with ministry of trad and investment and the Juba City Council to make business environment conducive for women to carry out business activities. the women recommended the need to reduce high tax imposed on women&apos;s businesses. After the meeting a press release was done by South Sudan Broadcasting Cooperation (SSBC) and was later circulated on TV. This activity took place on 29th of April in juba and a total of 9 women led plus one CARE staff accompany them women in this meeting.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLA members (disaggregated by age and gender) trained in economic opportunities, economic rights and gender norms</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="750"></target>
     <actual value="378">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the last quarters of implementation, 321 (13 girls, 28 boys, 37women and 18) VSLA members were trained on economic opportunities, rights and gender norms. In this quarter, 57 (21 women, 36 men) VSLA members benefited from the training.

Q3 Activity summary
On 17th February 2022, WAPO conducted a one-day training to VSLA groups on economic opportunities and economic rights and gender norms in Magwi County, Eastern Equatoria State. 57 VSLA members (30 women, 13 men, 8 girls and 6 boys) attended the training. The participants during the training also conferred on how negative social norms affect women in engaging in economic activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.6</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of public debates on 35% affirmative action aired on radio with support from WLAI</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.6" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the last two quarters of implementation, a total of 6 public radio debates were conducted on 35% affirmative action and in this quarter 3 radio debates were conducted.

Q3 Activity summary
WAPO held three radio talk shows on key issues affecting women. The first radio show was hosted by Voice of Freedom 93.0 FM on 22nd February. The  topic for discussion focused on  the implementation of 35% affirmative action and women participation in Permanent constitutional review process. A total of 560 members listen to the radio at the time of discussion 200 men, 60 Female Youth and 120 Female and 120 Male youth. WAPO also conducted another radio talk show in Torit on 30th April to educate the public on women&#x2019;s rights and 35% affirmative action. A total of 1900 listeners were  estimated to have listened to the deliberation aired via the radio that day; 650 were male, 570 women, 410 male youth and 270 female youth.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Advocacy events organized by CSOs/WROs at the State and national level</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the previous quarters, 10 advocacy initiatives were conducted and during reporting period, 3 advocacy activities were conducted.

Q3 activity summary
On 2nd February 2022, CARE in Juba conducted a one-day quarterly advocacy review meeting with WLOs in Juba to assess current context of South Sudan and key issues including the shrinking civic space for CSOs/WLOs engagement and reviewed an advocacy strategy  drafted by the WLAI Technical Reference Group. In Ikwoto EES WAPO conducted a round table event on 35% affirmative action and the role of women in nation-building in Ikwoto South Sudan and was attended by 58 participants (37 female and 27 male). On 8th  February, on the request of WLOs, CARE organized a meeting with UNOCHA representative to clarify on the organization&#x2019;s funding mechanism/processes as far as sub-granting to WLOs is concerned. WLOs members  agreed to follow up on funding towards WLO initiatives through the Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP). A total of 35 participants attended, 30 Female and 5 males.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of duty bearers/power holders reached via sensitization sessions on women&#x2019;s economic rights, empowerment led by VSLAs and WROs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="37">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the previous quarters, 10 duty bearers were engaged via sensitization sessions on women&apos;s economic rights, empowerment led by VSLAs and WROs. In this quarter 27 duty bearers were targeted.

Q3 Activity summary
In Yei County, CIGPJ conducted a meeting with VSLA members from three Bomas in Yei on 26th April 2022. The objective of the meeting was to connect the women VSLA members with international organizations (Women for Women and GIZ) that support Women Economic Empowerment programs in Yei. 26 participants (16 women, 4 female youth, 6 men) - 18 participants out of the 26 are duty bearers who attended the meeting.  WAPO facilitated a dialogue with policy makers, decision makers, WLOs, youth, and women to promote women economic rights and employment in Torit County on 23rd March 2022. The dialogue aimed at discussing the social economic factors affecting  women as far as  economic rights and employment opportunities are concerned. The activity brought several sectors of stake holders ranging from local government representatives, police officers, church leaders and among others making a total of 30 participants (07 males, 15 females, 03 female youth, 05 male youth). Out of the 30 participants 9  (4 women, 5 men) are duty bearers.  In conclusion, out of the 56 participants only 28 were duty  bearers and the majority of whom were female.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of power holders/duty bearers (Payam, County and State levels) trained in women&apos;s rights, gender norms, and women&apos;s leadership and participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.3.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="29">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the previous quarters, 4 (2 female, 2 male) power holders/duty bearers were trained on women&apos;s rights, gender norms, and women&apos;s leadership and participation.

During this reporting period (Q3) , WAPO organized a one-day training to community leaders to discuss issues related to women&apos;s rights  and forge ways that the community can embrace to support women&apos;s empowerment program. A total of 88 participants attended the training on 8th February and out of that only 27 were power holders/duty bearers drawn from Payam, county and the state level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth/women (disaggregated by age and gender) engaged via career guidance and employment opportunity meetings at the State level</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="172">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the previous quarters, 80 youth/women engaged on Career guidance on employment opportunity meetings at the state level and in Q3, 92 youth/women were reached.
 
Q3 activity summary
WAPO organized a one-day dialogue with policy makers on promotion of women economic rights and employment in Magwi (23rd February) and Ikwotoes (1st April) counties in Eastern Equatoria State.  The participants deliberated on policies and social factors that hinder to grow in business and getting employment opportunities. Participants recommended that development partners should design program that address capacity needs of women and youth in order to challenge the barriers. A total of 60 participants attended the dialogue (13 male, 23th female, 10 female youth and 14 male youth). Similarly, WAPO Engaged youths and women in dialogues on opportunities for formal or informal employment in Hatire Payam of  Ikwoto County  held on 25th April, 2022. The dialogue brought together 32 participants (4 male, 10 females, 11 male youth, 7 female youth).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs staff/members trained in media (including social media) and  community-based campaign design</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="32">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the previous reporting period (Quarter 2), a similar activity was conducted and reported and 32 CSOs attended. CARE and partners plan to conduct another activity in May and will be reported under this indicator.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.8</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of power holders/duty bearers engaged in Community Score Cards exercises on 35% quota</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.8" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="67">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period, WAPO conducted three community score card meeting on 23rd,29th of March in imatong and Ikwotos and on 29th April a similar meeting took place in Magwe. The three meeting targeted community leaders like chiefs, youth representatives in the community , and local government representatives including women chiefs in the community .The meeting was to find out weather local actors are accountable in prevention of GBV issues . The plenary discussion raised key questions by leaders likw what is GBV and how can they prevent it . the facilitators of the meeting who were WAPO explain GBV and its impact on women and youth participation . leaders then request for more education on this topic for them to better rule cases of GBV with informed decision , they seek for conducting mass awareness and translate some of the policies into local languages for people to understand.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLAs that have joined State level VSLA Unions with support from WROs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.1.2" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this reporting period, WAPO facilitated a dialogue with policy makers, decision makers, WLOs, youth, and Women in promotion of women economic rights and employment in Magwi County on 22nd /3/2022 at Dynamic Business Centre. The objective was to discuss the social economic factors affecting the women in economic rights and employment opportunity. The activity brought several sectors of stake holders ranging from local government representatives, police officers, church leaders and among others making a total of 30 participants (07 M, 15F, 03FY, 05MY). In Q1 and Q2, 20 VSLAs joined the state level union.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLA members (disaggregated by age and gender) trained in financial literacy (basic bookkeeping and numeracy)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.1" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="65">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 16th Feb and 29th of March 2022, WAPO conducted Financial Literacy training to 64 VSLA members in Magwi county, Eastern Equatoria State. The training was to equip the members with skills and knowledge on financial literacy such as recording and accounting for  their savings. Out of the total participants 34 Female, 5 male and 19 female youth and 7 male youth. The training improved their understanding on how to manage record of their savings.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.5</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of women leaders selected from existing/newly established networks trained in leadership, negotiation, coordination and communication skills</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.1.5" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="164">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 20th April 2022, WAPO conducted training on leadership, negotiation, coordination and 
In the last reporting periods, 120 women leaders benefited from capacity building training delivered by CARE and partners. In this quarter 44 women leaders participated in similar capacity building initiatives.

Q3 Activity summary
communication skills in Torit South Sudan. The training was attended by 30 women of which 22 were women leaders. On 23rd March 2022, WAPO conducted a mentorship program in Torit, Eastern Equatoria State (EES) attended by 20 participants (6women and 14 female youth) and none is a woman leader. On 26th March 2022, WAPO conducted learning event in Ikotos county, Eastern Equatoria State attended by 50 women of which none is a woman leader.  On 23rd March 2022, WAPO conducted a mentorship program in Torit, South Sudan attended by 20 women of which none is a woman leader. Another mentorship program was conducted in Ikotos  county on 29th March 2022 which brought together 56 women participants including 22 women leaders.  During this reporting period, the capacity of 44 female leaders were enhanced through leadership training and mentorship.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSOs/WROs/Women Forum members supported in taking part in regional feminist networks/events</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="1.2.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="32"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 23rd 2022, CARE linked eight South Sudan WLOs in South Sudan to International Women Peace Group (IWPG) from South Korea. The virtual meeting provided a platform for  women (WLOs representatives) to share women peace and security programs they are implementing in the country. The IWPG on the other hand, updated on some of their International and global peace and security initiatives with  women from across countries.  WLOs representative updated the South Korea team on their advocacy program to increase women participation in leadership and decision-making process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4.3</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of women VSLA members and women leaders trained in literacy and key aspects of digital technology</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.4.3" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="29">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">WAPO conducted training for VSLA members on numeracy and key aspects of digital technology on the 31st of March 2022. This training aimed at imparting knowledge and skills on  digital technology to VLSAs women members in Ikwoto South Sudan. The training also covered transactions   recorded in the book of account and basic record keeping and numeracy. 29 women VSLA members attended.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.4</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of VSLA members (disaggregated by age and gender) provided with revolving funds for IGAs/entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="2.3.4" indicator-uri="https://www.carenederland.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="150"></target>
     <actual value="330">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">WAPO provided revolving funding to 30 VSLA groups. In each group, 11 members in each group were given funds with aim of investing and expanding their  businesses and return the start up capital to the group for  other members to also benefit from it. A total of 330(51M, 168F, 29MY, 82FY) benefited from the training</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
