<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-17/HSS10/SA1/H/NGO/5157</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency lifesaving and gender sensitive high impact health services for hard to reach, undeserved and conflict affected IDPs and vulnerable communities in Leer county of Southern Liech state; Fangak county in Fangak state and Uror county in Bieh state.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leer, Fangak and Uror counties are among the most conflict affected counties in the country. Following the Jan-Feb-2017 sporadic conflicts in Leer county community had moved to deep islands /swampy area. These locations are the perceived hard to reach and safe for civilians from possible attack by an armed force, a considerable proportion of Leer community had moved to East ward to Fangak County. Currently Fangak county is hosting a community from Leer and Mayandint counties and a population from Atar and kaldak areas who fled to Diel area of New Fangak following the recent attack in February-2017.
In Uror county following the recent attack in Yuai payam, approximately 21,000 people had moved out of their home areas towards neighboring Nyirol and Akobo counties. Facility HMIS report from Walgak PHCC showed an increase in the number of general consultation and specifically the number of Kala azar cases who are seen in the facility has increased in the last two weeks&#x2019; time.
Most localities islands are hard to reach where the only means of transport to access those location is using canoe which might need travel for hours in the swamp. Security remains to be the main concern for humanitarian actors to respond to the emergency. Women, Girls, Boys and Men in these counties are the most vulnerable in terms of food insecurity, malnutrition and diseases. Active hostilities, in-accessibility and Insecurity are among the constraining factors limiting women, Girls, Boys and Men to move freely to more secure places to access assistance. 
In circumstance where there is a continued instability where security situation is fluid and continued displacements, women adolescent girls are usually exposed to sexual and physical abuses, an assessment conducted in Fangak county residents showed 7.3% had experienced SGBV within their family and close relatives.
In the absence of livelihood opportunities, many adolescent girls and women are forced/encouraged to have non-consensual sexual practices that leads to unwanted pregnancies and infections to HIV and other STIs.
Basic infrastructures including health facilities are limited and not effectively supported and the war has markedly destroyed a good number of the few existing ones. Women, Girls, Boys and men are forced to seek traditional ways of treatment. Women and Girls who are exposed to myriad gender base violence do not get special services including psycho-social support or treatment in case of rape. RH services in these conflict-affected counties are nearly nonexistent. Men and Boys from the battlefield are exposed to traumatizing experiences thus requiring psychological support. Immunization coverage is very low in these counties thus predisposing to outbreaks of diseases, Hence an outbreak response activities will be put in place to ensure that timely effective action is taken to curb associated morbidity and mortality.

Hence Nile Hope through this project will support seven mobile units three in Leer (Rubchai, Guang and Yang islands), two mobile units in Fangak County (Puom and Kuornyang) and in Uror county (Modit and Pulchol units) and a stabilization center will be opened in Leer island to be able to manage SAM cases with medical complications. These units will be responsible to conduct and integrated case disease surveillance and response activities to timely identify, and treat potential Measels, Cholera, epidemics in the locality, The team will also be trained on emergency response and to be able to timely manage cases and take appropriate epidemic response measures
Through these service mobile clinics targeted service will be provided to highly vulnerable people including SGBVs, EPampR, CMR, TB/HIV tracing and management, psycho social support to traumatized affected women and Men. Vigilance and close monitoring will be ensured and in events where there will be need for resources to be increased for the county.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Tolu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211920010329</telephone>
   <email>dtolu@nilehope.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Getachew Gezahegn</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211915611561</telephone>
   <email>getachew@nilehope.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-20">244599.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-5157">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-20">244599.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00065628">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-27">131299.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00068114">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-07">113299.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
