<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-17/HSS10/SA1/H/NGO/5107</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve the quality and availability of essential emergency primary healthcare services including Basic Emergency Obstetric  Neonatal Care (BEmONC) at the health facilities and scale up the mobile response in Mayendit, Leer and Panyijiar (Nyal) counties of the former Unity state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aimed to maintain the delivery of the emergency primary health care, treatment of  SAM with complication and scale up of rapid response services in Mayendit, Leer and Payinjiar counties in former Unity state and to enhance access to life-saving health services at the IDPs and the host communities. These two counties apart from Payinjar county, are much devastated by the conflict for the last 3years in terms of lost to human lives, destruction and looting of the health infrastructures and the livelihood of the inhabitants also severely ruined. People have continuously been forced out from their homes and hence could not access the health care services at the facilities. The data on the HNO for 2017 released earlier in the year by UNOCHA estimated the number of IDPs in Unity to be at 463,736 Over 5million people in the country need humanitarian assistant in a situation where the proportion of clinicians per patients is estimated at only 1doctor per 65,000 patients. And based on the population projection data released by NBS in the Jan 2017, the population of these 3counties is at 282,124. The recently released IPC reports in Jan 2017 also indicated that 61% of population in Guit, Koch,Mayendit, Leer and Panyijiar are population in crisis(Leer, Mayendit declared famine affected counties) i.e. emergency and humanitarian catastrophe and GAM rate at 30%.
Our strategic response plan in the provision of these emergency primary health care services shall include the OPD curative consultation at 9 PHCUs( GUAT,GANDOR, BOW, PILIENY in LEER county) and (DABLUAL,LUOM,JAGUAR,KUOK ,PABUONG in MAYENDIT County) and 4PHCCs of
9( RUBKUAY PHCC in Mayendit county and THORNYOR amp ADOK PHCCs in LEER County and DUONG PHCC in PAYINJAR County the 3counties combined with INTEGRATED HEALTH amp NUTRITION SERVICES in line with the MOH BPHNS policy. UNIDO will also support mobile clinic and outbreak response(cholera, Measels) activities at the swamps/highlands inhabited by the IDPs and have no health facilities specially in Leer and IDPs in Nyal. We will maintain special focus on the provision of Basic Emergency Obstetric amp Neonatal Care (BEmONC) services at the supported PHCCs through deployment of qualified clinicians and midwives, provision and distribution of essential emergency medical equipments and medicines and create community awareness in the utilization of the existing Family Planning services. We will support the health promotion activities through health education sessions and ensure the availability of the preventive measures specially the routine immunization (EPI) services at the facilities and the outreaches. We will also support the psychosocial and basic mental health services through updating the health workers on clinical management of sexual violence protocols to deliver the First aids such as protection and care for the survivors. HIV/AIDS prevention and treatment will also be supported through creating wider community awareness by information dissemination, provision of condoms and PMTCT and PEP at the supported health facilities and community levels.
And also with this project UNIDO will support the response to disease Outbreaks such as Cholera and Measles as we did in 2016 in Mayendit county, Leer highlands and Nyal. We will ensure that the hygiene promotion activities are conducted in collaboration with the WASH activities being implemented whether by UNIDO or other partners in those areas. We will deploy qualified clinical staffs who will continuously training the health workers on the treatment and identification of acute watery diarrhea cases and any abnormal trend will be reported on time.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal Intervention and Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal Intervention and Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Chany</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0955193919</telephone>
   <email>chanyadok@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Keah Ninrew</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0955008160</telephone>
   <email>ed@unidosouthsudan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Duk Stephen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0955550669</telephone>
   <email>programs@unidosouthsudan.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-28">245000.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-5107">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-28">245000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal Intervention and Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00065766">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-04">123111.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal Intervention and Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00068051">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-09">121888.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universal Intervention and Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
