<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-17/HSS10/SA2/WASH/NGO/6445</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency water,sanitation and hygiene promotion  services for under served and vulnerable population affected by conflict ,disease outbreak and acute malnutrition in Akobo and Uror  Counties, Jonglei State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan faces one of the world&#x2019;s most dire humanitarian crises owing to two years of brutal war that has left 7.5 million severely food insecure and 2.3 million displaced. This intervention is intended to focus primarily on life saving WASH activities that will include rehabilitation of emergency existing water facilities (boreholes, motorized boreholes, and emergency water treatment units), distribution of hygiene/sanitary kits and construction of emergency sanitation facilities and reinforce with emergency targeted hygiene promotion to reduce the risks of increased WASH related morbidity and mortality death 

This project is going be implemented in the three counties of Akobo and Uror Counties of Jonglei State  and is estimated to cost USD  167,279,52 for the period of six months where Nile Hope has already established a presence with well qualified local staff to ensure timely delivery of services with good standard. 

The targeted groups/ community women, children, boys, girls and men including IDPs, returnees and most vulnerable population. Organization has strong presence and well established team in these locations with full capacity to respond in emergency situation and support the cluster to achieve her objectives, Nile Hope will continue maintaining good working relationship with other cluster members, Education, Nutrition, health, food security/Livelihood and protection. This will include increased participation WASH coordination meetings as well various levels. Nile Hope will place more emphasis on sanitation and hygiene.
 
Inadequate WASH services in these three counties contribute not only to disease outbreak, but also to increased malnutrition. There is lack of improved sanitation and limited knowledge of hygiene practices specifically for those communities displaced by current conflicts and the host communities. To mitigate against this negative WASH impact in the above mentioned areas. Nile Hope has currently set up static and mobile team that is responding to this threat of epidemic and work closely with health sector  to ensure no further outbreak.

Through provision of improved water, sanitation and hygiene services and increased knowledge and coping capacity of affected communities to prevent outbreak of WASH related diseases such as cholera and diarrhea. This intervention will reduce the vulnerability of those communities who do not have access to safe water supplies and proper sanitation and hygiene in Uror and Akobo. This intervention is designed to improve the quality and access to services especially through rehabilitation of existing water points and household emergency water treatment, construction of sanitation facilities, promote good hygiene practices through trained and capacity building community based hygiene promoters. Nutritional status is greatly impacted by diarrhea and other WASH related diseases/ illnesses. Those most at risk and affected by the Cholera outbreak this past year were children under 5 years of age. With limited access to safe water and improved sanitation displaced groups are at an increased risk for potential disease outbreaks as was seen in the Wechjal -Akobo and New Fangak in 2016 outbreak of cholera 

Populations that are still displaced in 2016 could experience additional displacement as the insecurity and threats increase the desire for groups to seek further safety and security. As the crisis has become protracted, displaced populations and vulnerable host communities will continue to need sustained basic WASH services to support increased demand on limited infrastructure. Nile Hope will target conflict affected displaced and vulnerable host communities, with continued support those in remote rural of Uror and Akobo  .

The project will also remain focus and supportive to Internally Displaced Persons from Akobo West from the recent clashes in Akobo and Uror County.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Bilok</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211911401168</telephone>
   <email>johnbilok@nilehope.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paul Biel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211954264444</telephone>
   <email>otoang@nilehope.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-24">138942.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-24">28336.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-6445">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-24">167279.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00068609">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-31">32939.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00070244">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-03">111505.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00072173">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-23">22833.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
