<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-17/HSS10/SA2/NFI/INGO/6512</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving ES and NFIs to vulnerable conflict affected IDPs through Cash-Based Intervention modality to vulnerable communities in three IDP camps in Kajokeji, Central Equatoria State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PAH will provide life-saving ES-NFIs through Cash Based Intervention (CBI) to the most vulnerable IDP communities in the informal camps in Kajokeji County targeting 30,000 individuals (approximately 5,000 households) displaced due to the ongoing conflict around Kajokeji and neighboring counties coupled with the deepening economic crisis. The CBI will be conducted by the PAH Emergency Response Team (ERT) comprised of ES/NFIs specialists with rich knowledge and experience in CBI, supported by an on-ground monitoring team of 4 staff who will implement the project activities by conducting needs and market assessments, lead stakeholder meetings and selection of traders. A detailed market assessment will be conducted to identify the availability of NFIs in the market, assess the supply chain of items, check the quality of NFIs, and identify the suppliers/vendors of products and to identify risks of the CBI programme and mitigation measures. Meetings will be contacted with the potential traders and the the local authorities to explain the programme modality and contracts will be signed with the selected traders for the supply of the NFIs. In order to mitigate the risk of double dipping, tokens will be distributed during registrations and then withdrawn during distribution of vouchers. The registration will be done simultaneously in all the the camps to avoid double registrations. The commodity vouchers will be printed with security features and an expiry date, serial numbers and duplicates that will remain in the voucher book. The beneficiaries will have a window of time to access the NFIs from the vendors in the IDP settlements. The beneficiaries will redeem their vouchers for a selected number of NFIs determined during the needs assessment. All beneficiaries will get the same types of NFIs. At agreed times, the traders will then redeem the vouchers for payment by PAH through an agreed payment method.

The staff will also receive, record, solve/address queries and give feedback to beneficiaries. The team will also carry out verification and registration of targeted beneficiaries in the camps, distribute restricted cash vouchers, monitor the activities of the traders, and conduct messaging on proper use of the items to encourage their sustainable use. Each beneficiary household will be given the will to choose at most five most desired NFIs from a wide range of 10 types of household NFIs as long as the total value of the items is within the range of the restricted voucher. PAH will involve the beneficiaries at all the stages of the intervention to provide response best suited to the ES/NFI needs of the IDP community served, taking into account vulnerabilities of each represented group: men, women, boys and girls. 

In order to mitigate the risk of beneficiaries colluding with the vendors to get cash, a detailed needs assessment will be done at the beginning of the programme to ensure that the most vulnerable households are targeted. The M+E Assistants recruited from target communities will conduct voucher redemption monitoring for the traders.

Strong focus will be made to ensure that the most vulnerable groups (e.g. persons with disabilities, pregnant and lactating women, and unaccompanied elders/minors) in the community will be served appropriately according to their ES/NFI needs and in the manner not exposing them to additional stress. The response will be coordinated with the S-NFI cluster at national and state level. The identified information on the needs will be shared with partners and donors to ensure the best use of the partners&#x2019; capacity. The monitoring reports from the intervention will also be widely circulated to partners. A detailed Post Distribution Monitoring will be conducted at the end of the project to find feedback and impact of the cash-based intervention and lessons learnt will contribute to improvements of future response and creation of S-NFI cluster CBI strategy in the future</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polish Humanitarian Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polish Humanitarian Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emmanuel Lumaya</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211923082998</telephone>
   <email>emmanuel.lumaya@pah.org.pl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ewa Rodziewicz</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211955761153</telephone>
   <email>hom.ssud@pah.org.pl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jackson Godfrey Mungoni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211914343403</telephone>
   <email>jackson.mungoni@pah.org.pl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-25">178401.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-25">140843.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="10389">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-14">1956.65</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polish Humanitarian Action</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-6512">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-25">319245.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polish Humanitarian Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00068617">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-30">79600.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polish Humanitarian Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00074592">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-01">8953.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polish Humanitarian Action</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
