<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-17/HSS10/SA2/FSL/NGO/6559</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency Food Security and Livelihoods Support interventions targeting most vulnerable Internally Displaced Populations and Host Communities in Bor South County, Jonglei State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite recent ceasefire declaration by the South Sudanese President and announcement of the national dialogue process in December 2016, has created mixed reactions, with doubts on the feasibility of an inclusive peace process and implementation of the 2015 peace agreement. The country has witnessed escalating conflict, counter-insurgency further undermining efforts to create the previous status quo prior to the July 2016 conflict. Escalating violence, rapidly depreciating currency, hyperinflation, dysfunctional markets have exacerbated most vulnerable access to food among other appropriate crucial services more so among recently crisis affected areas such as Bor South County of Jonglei State (OCHA Humanitarian Bulletins January-May 2017 REACH Jonglei Situation Overview January 2017). As at June 2017, an estimated 5.5 million people in the country are experiencing moderate/severe food insecurity (IPC Alert June 2017).

Proposed actions will target 4,000 households 24,000 people (4000 men, 4000 women, 8000 girls and 8000 boys-includes youth and people with special needs) to be supported with fishing kits and nutrition dense vegetable kits as per the cluster and HRP 2017 strategy. These will mainly target recently displaced internally displaced persons (women, girls, boys and men-includes people with special needs and elderly) through FSL Cluster strategic objectives which are in line with the HRP 2017. CARD will target three (Makuach, Baidit and Anyidi) out of the six Payams, however, this will be based on partner allocation by FAO. Targeted beneficiaries will comprise of most vulnerable and recently displaced in the three Payams, with prioritization on women/child /elderly/disabled headed households. 

These actions will respond to prioritized locations taking into account cost effective measures. Fishing kits support interventions will enable beneficiaries with access to riverine areas/ rivers have immediate access to fish for food, income and livelihood rehabilitation (FSL Cluster Strategy Document, March 2017 HRP 2017).

CARD has been operating in Greater Equatoria since 2011 and now in Jonglei (Bor South) through the support of UNFAO, UNICEF among other donors with skilled competent staff, logistics and community goodwill, in addition to having good relations with the host communities, local leaders, RRC officials and state/county ministries of Agriculture and Animal Resources. These strong networks coupled with established local networks will be engaged and mobilized to rapidly implement the proposed activities herein whilst taking into account Do no harm approaches, accountability to Affected Populations, protection, HIV/AIDS prevention and awareness, conflict sensitivity, protection, environmental conservation and gender equity. 

The project will be in line with the HRP 2017 and second Standard Allocation FSL Cluster Strategy document that will prioritize frontline activities and priority counties (Bor South) of Jonglei State. This is also in line with the strategy document by targeting areas with most severe needs. 
The project will also incorporate the core principles and components of the Accountability to Affected Populations as part of the humanitarian obligations, via functional beneficiary feedback/complaints desks.  

Proposed activities emergency fishing and vegetable kits interventions are in line with the FSL Cluster Second Objective of livelihood protection through short term and medium term interventions respectively. These Kits will be prepositioned through FAO Core-pipeline to save on costs in addition to taking advantage of seasonality to enhance resilience. Proposed activities will be coordinated with relevant partners operating in Nutrition, Health, Education, WASH and Education to create a holistic approach and achieve better impacts of the project, including close coordination and collaboration with state level cluster leads and synergy generation at lo</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Relief and Developemnt</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Relief and Developemnt</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alex Imbwaga</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance and Admin Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0956909061</telephone>
   <email>aleximbwaga@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thomas Juma</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211955805326</telephone>
   <email>cardsouthsudanprogram@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moi Santino</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211955197819</telephone>
   <email>moisantino1979@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-16">99672.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-16">20327.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-6559">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-16">120000.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Relief and Developemnt</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00069835">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-29">38570</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Relief and Developemnt</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00068557">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-29">81430.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Relief and Developemnt</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
