<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>47135-XFIPPE023A</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="47135" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Land management in Atalaya, Ucayali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of Peru&#x2019;s Forest Investment Plan (PIP), to which this project is tied, which is expected to generate a transformative impact within the next 10-15 years, is to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions produced by deforestation and forest degradation, and enhance carbon reserves in sustainable forest landscapes, thereby helping to reach the national target of &#x201C;Declining net emissions to equivalent to zero in the category of Land Use, Land-Use Change and Forestry by 2021.&#x201D; In achieving this objective, the PIP is expected to generate two types of co-benefits: (i) reduce poverty of indigenous communities and other local populations, under a gender equality approach, by increasing income from management of sustainable forest landscapes and productive agroforestry mosaics; and (ii) reduce the loss of biodiversity and maintain forest ecosystem services. 
The project objective is to strengthen the capacity of forest dependent communities and enterprises to sustainably manage and use forest landscapes, in the Raimondi, Sepahua and Tahuan&#xED;a districts of the Atalaya province.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-23" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+1-202-458-1801</telephone>
   <email>cifadminunit@worldbank.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank, 1818 H Street, NW, Washington, DC 20433 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PERU</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
