<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:budgetline="http://diplomatie.be/oda/currentbudget.xlsx" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-2-10-1529</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-2-10" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Fourniture de services de protection de l&apos;enfance susceptibles de sauver la vie des enfants touch&#xE9;s par le conflit au Y&#xE9;men</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving child protection services for conflict affected children in Yemen - PG/2018/04</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Output 1: 400 children and adolescents released from armed forces and armed groups and from detention are identified, registered and their needs are assessed to provide immediate and life-saving response
- Output 2: 700 vulnerable children and adolescents provided with a package of child protection services to respond and prevent violence, abuse, exploitation and neglect (psychosocial support and life skills to be empowered, well-accepted, reintegrated and able to cope with their distress and are referred to appropriate health, education, legal and social cash transfers services).
- Output 3:  300 children and adolescents&#x2019; victims of recruitment and use by armed forces and at risk of recruitment and use including their caregivers engage in income generation, vocational training and livelihood support services to sustain their reintegration
- Output 4:  45,000 (22,500 male; 22,500 female) care givers, duty bearers, adolescent and children at risk, of which 30% are children, receive awareness raising on child protection issues
- Output 5:  Humanitarian support is provided in line with UNICEF&#x2019;s Humanitarian Action for Children appeals for Yemen. To ensure that vulnerable children and adolescents impacted by armed conflict in Yemen are better protected from violence, exploitation, abuse and neglect through preventive and response services that support their well-being and reintegration into their families and communities - Vulnerable children and adolescents impacted by armed conflict and at risk of exploitation, violence, abuse and neglect are provided with sustainable critical child protection services in their communities.

- Vulnerable children in Yemen are reached with life-saving humanitarian support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable children and adolescents impacted by armed conflict and at risk of exploitation, violence, abuse and neglect are provided with sustainable critical child protection services in their communities.
Additional Outcomes as defined in Yemen&apos;s HAC 2018, and to be further defined pending finalization of 2019 and 2020 HAC. The conflict, on-going in Yemen since 2015, has rendered Yemen one of the world&apos;s largest and most complex humanitarian crises. Roughly 80% of the country&#x2019;s population (22.2 million people) is in dire need of humanitarian assistance. Conflict caused the internal displacement of over 3.2 million people, has left over 1 million public sector workers without pay for two years, and undermined access to ports and airports, obstructing essential humanitarian and commercial deliveries.1 The outbreak of Acute Watery Diarrhea (AWD)/cholera has now reached over one million cases. The strain on an already weakened health system has been further compounded by the diphtheria outbreak in early 2018 that has now reached over 2,200 cases.2 In addition, 16 million people lack access to safe water.3 Children are the primary victims of this conflict: more than 6,000 have been verified as killed or maimed since the conflict began.4 Growing food insecurity, poor water and sanitation, and the spread of preventable diseases threaten millions more. 383,000 children under 5 are estimated to suffer from severe acute malnutrition (SAM) and require treatment.5 The damage and closure of schools and health facilities threaten children&apos;s access to education and health services, which renders children vulnerable to various protection concerns including early marriage, forced recruitment and psychosocial distress. The impact of this war on children will potentially be felt for generations.

Aligned to the Humanitarian Response Plan, UNICEF&#x2019;s Humanitarian Action for Children (HAC) has decentralized operations, with five field offices managing interventions locally, together with implementing partners. With the collapse of public services, UNICEF improves access to primary healthcare by providing supplies, covering operational costs, monitoring and responding to communicable disease outbreaks. Community management of malnutrition remains essential, especially in hard-to-reach areas. UNICEF&apos;s WASH strategy is integrated with nutrition and food security targeting immediate needs and strengthening long-term resilience of communities. UNICEF ensures uninterrupted access to safe water through rehabilitation works, and support for sustainable local management of water systems. The WASH, health and C4D AWD/cholera prevention/response plan focuses on high-risk areas, diarrhea treatment, chlorination of water sources, rehabilitation of waste water systems and hygiene awareness. UNICEF targets most vulnerable children in conflict-affected governorates with interventions including victim assistance, family tracing/reunification, documentation of child rights violations, mine/explosive remnants of war risk education and psychosocial support (PSS). For education, whilst rehabilitation of damaged schools, establishment of temporary safe learning spaces and provision of learning/pedagogical kits to children to provide a conducive learning environment will continue.
UNICEF publishes its&apos; HAC on an annual basis, to ensure it is adapted to the changing context and in line with the Humanitarian Response Plan. Targets may also be revised on a rolling basis dependent on emerging needs. The 2019 and 2020 HAC documents, as well as any mid-year revisions, will be shared with Belgium as and when they are published. This will provide up-to-date overviews of the situation, response strategy and programme expected outcomes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022;	400 children and adolescents formerly associated with armed forces or armed groups and other vulnerable children and young people; 
&#x2022;	700 vulnerable children and adolescents; 
&#x2022;	45,000 (22,500 male; 22,500 female) care givers, duty bearers, adolescent and children at risk, of which 30% are children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">NU UNICEF - Fonds pour l&apos;enfance - PRT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - Children&apos;s Fund - PRT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="1529" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-2-10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C3177" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-07" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date effective de fin de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-25" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date effective de d&#xE9;but de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date pr&#xE9;vue de fin de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date pr&#xE9;vue de d&#xE9;but de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>Info.DGD@diplobel.fed.be</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="4500566868">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-30">2791351</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="41122" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500566868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-14">2093513</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="41122" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - Children&apos;s Fund - PRT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500566868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-07">697838</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="41122" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - Children&apos;s Fund - PRT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.OPENXMLFORMATS-OFFICEDOCUMENT.WORDPROCESSINGML.DOCUMENT" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/29462_PROGDESCR_annex_2a_UNICEF_Yemen_Proposal_Belgium_October2018.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">annex_2a_UNICEF_Yemen_Proposal_Belgium_October2018.docx</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/29463_PROGDESCR_annex_2b_UNICEF_Bank_Account_Information.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">annex_2b_UNICEF_Bank_Account_Information.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/29464_PROGDESCR_annex_2c_2018_Yemen_HAC.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">annex_2c_2018_Yemen_HAC.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/29468_LEGAL_AGREEMENT_annex_6_Framework_Arrangement_UNICEF-Be_23sept_2016.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">annex_6_Framework_Arrangement_UNICEF-Be_23sept_2016.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/29735_KB_AR_MB_AM_1529_AM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1529_AM.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-26"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/29736_LEGAL_AGREEMENT_1529_CONV.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1529_CONV.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-26"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <budgetline:code>5451356026</budgetline:code>
  <budgetline:descr>54 51 356026 Humanitarian programs</budgetline:descr>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
