<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:budgetline="http://diplomatie.be/oda/currentbudget.xlsx" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-2-10-2134</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-2-10" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Am&#xE9;liorer l&apos;acc&#xE8;s &#xE0; une &#xE9;ducation de qualit&#xE9; pour les filles et les adolescentes au Tchad</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution in support of people of concern to UNHCR in Afghanistan, DRC, Ethiopia, Iraq, Lebanon and Chad</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">63,250 individuals will benefit from this project, among which 250 will directly benefit from the self-reliance and livelihoods programmes. UNHCR&#x2019;s activities, as presented in this proposal, aims to reach approximately 250,000 persons (including both refugees and internally displaced persons) in the provinces of Ituri, North Kivu, South Kivu and Tanganyika provinces and the Kasai region. At the start of 2019, Ethiopia was hosting 901,235 registered refugees in the 26 camps and urban areas and settings in Ethiopia. The majority of refugees originate from South Sudan
(46.6%) followed by Somalia (28.4%), Eritrea (19.2%), Sudan (4.9%), Yemen (0.2%) and other nationalities (0.7%). Out of the total refugee population, 56% are children, and 78% are women
and children. The Belgium government support will contribute to protection and lifesaving assistance of the total refugee population. The contribution of the Government of Belgium will go towards providing MPCA to 120,000 vulnerable IDP families (approximately 720,000 individuals) across Iraq. The contribution of the Government of Belgium will go towards providing a monthly MPCA of USD 175 per family to up to 33,000 of the most vulnerable Syrian refugee families (220,000
individuals) to assist them in meeting their most urgent needs. The amount of cash assistance provided is calculated based on a Minimum Expenditure Basket (MEB). MPCA recipients will
include female-headed households, persons with serious medical conditions, the disabled, women at risk, persons with specific legal or physical protection needs, children at risk, single
parents, older persons at risk, unaccompanied/separated children and minor-headed households.
 This project will benefit approximately 110,218 pupils from 3 to 18 years attending the schools where UNHCR operates in Chad, 95,189 of which are refugees and 47,719 of which are
refugee girls. It will also benefit 1,826 teachers, educators and education staff, of which 605 are women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bijdrage aan UNHCR interventies voor de vluchtelingen, IDPs en gastgemeenschappen in de meest ondergefinancierde operaties in de wereld, namelijk Afghanistan, DRC, Ethiopi&#xEB;, Irak, Libanon en Tsjaad. The project will contribute to the overall UNHCR Afghanistan programme including self-reliance and livelihoods through a whole of community approach to vocational and technical skills training, as well as to provide logistics and operational support for emergency response to internal displacement in Afghanistan. The project aims at supporting internally displaced persons as well as refugees from Rwanda settled in the Provinces of Ituri, North Kivu, South Kivu, Kasa&#xEF;, Kasa&#xEF; Central, Kasa&#xEF; Oriental, and Tanganyika in DRC, primarily through interventions in the areas of protection, basic needs and essential services, reintegration, security from sexual violence and exploitation, and community empowerment and selfreliance. The project aims to contribute towards the provision of essential services for refugees in Ethiopia, notably through the support to primary health care, reproductive health and HIV services, and persons with specific needs. The project will contribute to providing MPCA to 120,000 vulnerable IDP families (approximately 720,000 individuals) across Iraq allowing them to address their basic needs in the way they deem best, offering IDPs a degree of dignity and independence. Eligible families will receive either one, two, or three months of multi-purpose cash-assistance based on vulnerability criteria. The project will contribute to providing monthly MPCA to 33,000 of the most severely vulnerable Syrian refugee families to help them meet their basic needs such as shelter, food and medicine. The project seeks to improve access to quality education for girls in Chad by :

1) Supporting pre-primary education;
2) Providing a safe school environment;
3) Creating and supporting nurseries for schooling young mothers
and female teachers;
4) Recruiting and training female teachers;
5) Providing higher education scholarship for outstanding women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">R1. Vocational training / technical skills provided
R2. Warehousing provided and maintained; timely delivery of Core-relief items (CRIs) undertaken and project management services provided
R3. Situation of persons of concern to UNHCR monitored The project aims to support self-reliance and livelihoods through a whole of community approach in Afghanistan. 1. Self-reliance and livelihoods improved
2. Logistics and supply optimised to serve operational needs
3. Protection from effects of armed conflict strengthened R1. Situation of PoC monitored
R2. Cash grants or vouchers (multipurpose) provided
R3. Cash grants or vouchers (multipurpose)provided
R4. Community self-management supported
R5. Community sensitization campaigns implemented - Community peace education projects implemented - Projects benefiting local and displaced communities implemented
R6. The rights of person of concerns with respect to land, housing, property and documents are maintained - Capacity development supported
R7. Capacity development supported for protection actors - Co-ordination mechanisms established in regards to protection related activities
R8. Purchasing and timely procurement of supplies - Maintenance of vehicle fleet in adequate condition The project will support interventions in the area of protection, peaceful coexistence, reintegration and access to basic and domestic items for IDPs and refugees in Ituri, North Kivu,
South Kivu and Tanganyika provinces and the Kasai region. 1. Protection from effects of armed conflict strengthened
2. Services for persons with specific needs strengthened
3. Population has sufficient basic and domestic items 
4. Community mobilization strengthened and expanded
5. Peaceful coexistence with local communities promoted (IDPs and refugees)
6. Reintegration made more sustainable
7. Coordination and partnerships strengthened
8. Logistics and supply optimized to serve operational needs

 R1. Increased # of health facilities equipped/constructed/rehabilitated
R2. Increased # of women receiving post-test counselling and testing in PMTCT
R3. Increased percentage of persons of concern with disabilities who receive services for their specific needs The projects aims to contribute towards the provision of essential services for refugees in Ethiopia. 1. Population has improved health status amongst Sudanese Refugees inWestern Ethiopia
2. Population has optimal access to reproductive health and HIV services amongst Somali Refugees
3. Services for persons with specific needs strengthened for south Sudanese refugees R1. Multi-month multipurpose cash assistance provided This project aims at supporting vulnerable displaced families in Iraq through the provision of multipurpose cash assistance. 1. Population has sufficient basic and domestic items
 R1. Cash grants or vouchers (multipurpose) provided The objective of the project is to help refugees in Lebanon meet their needs through multipurpose cash Assistance.
The MPCA is an integral part of UNHCR&#x2019;s comprehensive protection response to refugees in Lebanon. The overall goal of MPCA is to improve the living conditions of vulnerable refugee
families and reduce their susceptibility to exploitation and other protection risks such as child labour and survival sex. 1. Population has sufficient basic and domestic items &#xF0B7; Reduced gap in access to education during conflict and crisis, for refugees and the internally displaced, both inside and outside camps;
&#xF0B7; Increased access to safe and quality education that promotes gender equality;
&#xF0B7; Barriers to gender equality and to quality primary and secondary education removed. The project aims at providing a safe school environment for girls and young women, facilitating early access to education and improving retention through the system.  Population has optimal access to education</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">NU HCR - Haut Commissariat pour les r&#xE9;fugi&#xE9;s - PRT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Office of the  High Commissioner for Refugees UNHCR_HCR - UNHCR - PRT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2134" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-2-10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-10" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date effective de fin de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-11" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date effective de d&#xE9;but de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date pr&#xE9;vue de fin de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date pr&#xE9;vue de d&#xE9;but de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>Info.DGD@diplobel.fed.be</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="4500625402">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-16">10000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="41121" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500625402">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-22">10000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="41121" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Office of the  High Commissioner for Refugees UNHCR_HCR - UNHCR - PRT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38932_PROGDESCR_2.1_UNHCR_proposal_annex_AFG.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1_UNHCR_proposal_annex_AFG.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38934_PROGDESCR_2.3_UNHCR_proposal_annex_ETH.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3_UNHCR_proposal_annex_ETH.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38935_PROGDESCR_2.4_UNHCR_proposal_annex_IRQ.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4_UNHCR_proposal_annex_IRQ.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38936_PROGDESCR_2.5_UNHCR_proposal_annex_LBN.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.5_UNHCR_proposal_annex_LBN.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38937_PROGDESCR_2.6_UNHCR_proposal_annex_TCD.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.6_UNHCR_proposal_annex_TCD.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38931_PROGDESCR_2_UNHCR_proposal_.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2_UNHCR_proposal_.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38941_KB_AR_MB_AM_2134_AM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2134_AM.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/38945_LEGAL_AGREEMENT_2134_CONV.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2134_CONV.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <budgetline:code>5452356083</budgetline:code>
  <budgetline:descr>54 52 356083 Humanitarian projects</budgetline:descr>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
