<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41201806-FGGTOC3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41201806" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transnational Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FGG TNI ToC 3: Improved Financial and Tax Systems</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI and partners from Indonesia, Colombia, Ghana and Nigeria aim to advocate their local and national authorities for democratization of public spending to improve public services provision. Internationally, TNI will advocate for sustainable and democratic sources of public finance based on empirical research. TNI will be mainly focusing on capacity building towards development alternatives to provide a basis for advocacy capacity building in the years after. TNI will be focusing on the water and sanitation sectors, and will support partners in Nigeria and Ghana on action-research on public spending in context of water provision in order to develop concrete policy proposals. Based on partnerships and achievements from previous years, TNI&#x2019;s partners in Indonesia and in Colombia will continue advocating on (re)building democratic public water system and community engagement in water resource and provision. TNI will initiate research and mapping of positive experiences of public finance generation and spending on public services and research into democratically organized public banking and public enterprise as viable ways to finance public infrastructure. TNI will also start mapping &#x2018;&#x2019;progressive cities&#x2019;&#x2019; worldwide, looking at finance, housing, water, energy, transport, food sovereignty, etc. Media outreach will be a key strategy in this work. This should lead to linking progressive utilities and cities, based on above mapping and building on remunicipalisation network and linking experiences. TNI will conduct research on the impact of TISA, CETA and TTIP on provision of public services. The global Reclaiming Public Water Network which TNI has coordinated for the last several years provides an enabling environment for TNI and partners to facilitate the linking of experiences at local and national level with developments and strategies globally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41201806-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41201806" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41201806-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41201806" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41201806-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41201806" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>tni@tni.org</email>
   <website>https://www.tni.org/en</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="27" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="29" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="29" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="15" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">3975300</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">3975300</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41201806-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41201806" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41201806-FGGTOC3" ref="NL-KVK-41201806" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">93131</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41201806-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41201806" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">580005</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">622743</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-31">214012</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-30">194717</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">174426</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">168667</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">147250</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">95251</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">276225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-31">177142</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-30">165689</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">141328</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">230188</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41201806-FGG" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome C: Alternatives Developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A range of alternative, people-driven, inclusive and sustainable approaches to the current financial and tax regime have been developed and advanced by civil society actors.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># alternative proposals to financial and tax and spending policies developed, piloted, and promoted with CSOs in LLMICs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.C" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Democratisation of public services &#x2013; TNI will promote its previous research, together with partners in LLMICs, which shows how public services can and have been democratized. The democratization of public services serves an alternative to corruption and inefficiency in public services, and to privatization of the public services. This includes public finance for universal public services, for which there is currently a lack of. Partners in LLMICs, with TNI&#x2019;s research support, are advocating to protect human right to water and sanitation, social protection and access to energy, housing and citizens participation with the aim of expanding public finance to deliver universal public services. 2 TNI is working with partners, including in LLMICs, to develop the concept of just transition and promote principles of energy democracy, especially at the municipal level. Under this TOC we focus on public spending for a just transition, including job creation, local economies, local sustainable energy production, including the six principles of energy democracy, the conditions for a just transition and workers&#x2019; rights. TNI is also working with unions and social movements in South Africa to help reform the national electricity provider Eskom, which provides electricity to several LLMICs in southern Africa. 3 Through the Transformative Cities initiative TNI, together with CSOs in LLMICs, will collate and communicate cases where alternative policy proposals on water, energy, housing, finance and food production have been successfully implemented, this evidence will further develop and strengthen alternative policy proposals in these areas. 4 With financial and advocacy support from TNI, a regional Latin American wide platform will develop proposals for legislation in relation to the recognition of community water systems in El Salvador. 5 Together with partners, we will work on data as commons at the municipal level on the idea of cities as a data safe harbour rather than waiting for global regulation. The idea is to reduce dependency on big tech and the large burden on the public budget of tech spending, while protecting citizens&#x2019; data as a city, while using data as commons to enable citizens to participate using digital tools designed by the cities to improve public services in the long term rather than companies who extract and marketise citizens&#x2019; data. TNI will work with pioneering cities in the Netherlands to develop lessons learned that can be shared with cities in LLMICs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Democratic public ownership: TNI co-published with 16 partners the book, The Future is Public: democratic ownership of public services, prepared around the international conference of the same name TNI and partners co-organised in Amsterdam in December 2019. The work and book continued to support national advocacy work throughout 2020. The entire book was translated into Portuguese, the summary report was translated to Dutch and launched. The global database includes 1442 examples of water, energy, healthcare and education services that have been de-privatised. The Covid-19 crisis provided an opportunity to link public services and public investment with democratic economy, human rights, development, tax, debt, healthcare, women rights and green transition. #FutureisPublic was used as hashtag by all 10 co-organisers of the UN Special Rapporteur event for common messaging, and in itself this was a recognition of the impact of the 2019 international conference titled &#x2018;The Future is Public&#x2019; and where the hashtag was first used. The conference paved the way for growing unity around the question of reclaiming public services.
In terms of energy, with partners including transnational union movements, TNI further developed the Energy Democracy framework by researching strategies and lessons learned for democratic energy models at national and local levels, and at meetings to map energy democracy. Energy democracy provides a new framework in which communities, local governments and workers have ownership over the energy transition and developing a new energy model. In 2020, they focused on the crucial significance of public ownership to enable the just transition and ensure universal provision of energy as an essential service.
With a special focus on alternatives for the electricity sector in South Africa: TNI, with academics, social movement leaders, environmental activists and unionists from South Africa, continued research to develop the restructure of a major public utility that operates across Southern Africa, including in LLMICs. The proposal can serve as a blueprint for publicly owned utilities in or servicing LLMICs. In 2020, TNI and these partners co-published a report on the proposal and op-eds on the proposal were published in the Mail, the Guardian and Daily Maverick.
(2) Public-Public Partnerships: Building on the work completed in the previous year, a telecommunications union in Colombia has created a semi-autonomous research unit on public-public partnerships within the union supported by TNI. Public-Public partnerships for public services serve as an alternative to private-public partnerships. This unit will also contribute to the implementation of the regional (Latin American level) training programme to be jointly launched in June 2021 by TNI, CLACSO and the union.
(3) Public finance for the 99%: through researching and promoting examples, TNI, with partners, including an India-based NGO, is contributing to the international discussion on changing finance. Finance for the 99% gives more ownership and benefits to local populations including a new social contract between cooperatives and local/regional governments to provide state financial support through low interest loans and subsidies. In 2019, TNI published the book &#x2018;Public finance for the future we want&#x2019;.
(4) Location based transformative policies and practices: The Transformative Cities initiative, which TNI facilitates, promoted stories of location based transformative policies and practices, including in Palestine, that show how to address access to basic rights (housing, water, energy and food) to an international audience through the Transformative Cities website, media coverage and an online award&#x2019;s night. 
(5) Ground water usage in Indonesia: an Indonesian research institute, with research and financial support from TNI, have continued to develop alternatives for Jakarta&#x2019;s groundwater usage including efficient water usage, control over groundwater use, new technology to reduce dependency on groundwater, and an increase in groundwater tax rates. The focus is now on what should happen after the private water contractors&#x2019; contract expires in 2023.
(6) Paying for the pandemic and a just transition: The TNI report &#x2018;Paying for the Pandemic and a Just Transition&#x2019; brought together ten progressive proposals that could pay for the costs of the pandemic and finance a just transition to a better world. The report outlines radical proposals for over $9 trillion in taxes and subsidies cuts to raise revenue to pay for the pandemic and a just transition. Prior to the report, in October, a webinar on the topic brought together scholar-activists and was attended by 270 people.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Through the Transformative Cities initiative TNI, together with yet to be determined CSOs, will collate and communicate cases where alternative policy proposals on water, energy, housing and food production have been successfully implemented, this evidence will further develop and strengthen alternative policy proposals in these areas. 2 TNI, together with a centre in India, will collate and communicate successful energy democracy cases, this evidence will further develop and strengthen energy democracy policy proposals. 3 With financial and advocacy support from TNI, a regional platform based in Bolivia will develop proposals for legislation in relation to the recognition of community water systems in El Salvador. 4-7 TNI will facilitate the global coordination for energy democracy coalition, which includes politicians. The coalition will develop and discuss proposals with partners relating to (1) public financing for energy transition, (2) energy as a commons and (3) ecofeminsim. Partners include global union network with members based in multiple LLMICs and a CSO in Palestine.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Energy Democracy: With partners including the transnational union movements, TNI further developed the Energy Democracy framework by researching strategies and lessons learned for democratic energy models at national and local levels, and at meetings to map energy democracy. Energy democracy provides a new framework in which communities, local governments and workers have ownership over the energy transition and developing a new energy model. During 2019, the focus was on developing the eco-feminism dimension of energy democracy through workshops with key partners. (2) Democratic public ownership: in December 2019, TNI co-hosted a major international conference &#x2018;Future is Public: democratic ownership of the economy&#x2019; with the City of Amsterdam. Participants came from 35 countries, including LLMICs (Guatemala, El Salvador, Bolivia, Indonesia, the Philippines, India, Myanmar, Kenya) and shared experiences and strategies for de-privatising public services and building democratic accountability. (3) Public-Public Partnerships: TNI&#x2019;s partner, a union in Colombia, and their local allies committed to establishing a social movement regional research centre on Public-Public Partnerships (PuPs) in Latin America. The unions are now officially supporting a training programme on management which will focus on PuPs. TNI provided networking with the unions and guidance about how to develop such a programme. (4) Public finance for the 99%: through researching and promoting examples, TNI, with partners, including an organisation based in India, is contributing to the international discussion on changing finance. Finance for the 99% gives more ownership and benefits to local populations including a new social contract between cooperatives and local/regional governments to provide state financial support through low interest loans and subsidies. In 2019, TNI published the book &#x2018;Public finance for the future we want&#x2019;. (5) Alternatives for the electricity sector: TNI, with a network of unions and a South African advocacy organisation, began a research project with academics, social movement leaders, environmental activists and unionists from South Africa, to develop the restructure of a major public utility that operates across Southern Africa, including in LLMICs. The proposal can serve as a blueprint for publicly owned utilities in or servicing LLMICs. In 2019, the proposal was developed further through workshops and the organisations involved was broadened. (6) Location based transformative policies and practices: The Transformative Cities initiative promoted stories of location based transformative policies and practices, including in Kenya, Nigeria and Palestine, that show how to address access to basic rights (housing, water, energy and food) to an international audience through the Transformative Cities website, media coverage and an award&#x2019;s night in December. (7) Ground water usage in Indonesia: the research institute in Indonesia, with research and financial support from TNI, has been developing alternatives for Jakarta&#x2019;s groundwater usage including efficient water usage, control over groundwater use, new technology to reduce dependency on groundwater, and an increase in groundwater tax rates. They continued to engage with the Governor of Jakarta and the media on the campaign in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) principles developed on energy democracy as alternative to energy privatisation, (2) proposal developed by local partner in LA with technical support from TNI on public water provision in the form of a citizens&apos; bill, (3) comprehensive proposal to reform Lagos state water company developed by local partner with financial and technical support from TNI;, (4) policy proposal to the UN new urban agenda developed with partners, demonstrating alternatives to privatisation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Research findings on remunicipalisation by TNI and partners - showing alternatives to privatisation - will be shared and promoted during debates on financing water services both in the 8th World Water Forum and in citizen alternative forum (FAME) in Brazil. 2. Transformative Cities initiative (an online community launched by TNI in 2017, aiming to popularize progressive alternatives and facilitates sharing of these experiences) will promote stories of transformative policies and practices, showing how to address social, economic and environmental problems in an imaginative, replicable, inspiring and transformative way. 3. Partner in Indonesia produces a proposal on policies for universal access to drinking water and wastewater treatment under public provision aiming at groundwater exploitation and stop land sinking to the government based on the research (2017) findings on excessive groundwater extraction in Jakarta. TNI provides financial support and technical research input. 4. Develop an alternative financial model, a progressive tax system and a way to finance public services and remunicipalisation through a report on the democratisation of finance, reclaiming the power to create public money. This will be done by TNI with an academic to explore the democratisation of finance as a credible alternative to debt driven finance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Energy Democracy: With partners including the transnational union movements, TNI further developed the Energy Democracy framework by researching strategies and lessons learned for democratic energy models at national and local levels, and at meetings to map energy democracy. Energy democracy provides a new framework in which communities, local governments and workers have ownership over the energy transition and developing a new energy model. 2 Remunicipalisation: in 2018, TNI, with partners, promoted the research on remunicipalisation TNI published in the book Reclaiming Public Services the previous year. TNI prompted the research at the FAMA (Alternative World Water Forum) in Brasilia in March. Work also began with partners on the second global survey on remunicipalisation in public services, with more unions and universities joining the research project, which will collect new cases by utilising their own networks and contribute to deepening analysis. 3 Public-Public Partnerships: TNI&#x2019;s partner, a local union, and their local allies committed to establishing a social movement regional research centre on Public-Public Partnerships (PuPs) in Latin America. With research support and guidance from TNI, the centre will research public policy with an emphasis on PuPs. 4 Finance for the 99%: through researching and promoting examples including from India, TNI, with partners, is contributing to the international discussion on changing finance. Finance for the 99% gives more ownership and benefits to local populations including a new social contract between cooperatives and local/regional governments to provide state financial support through low interest loans and subsidies. 5 Alternatives for the electricity sector: TNI, with local partners including unions, began a multi-sector research project with academics, social movement leaders, environmental activists, and unionists from Africa and other southern countries, to develop the restructure of a major public utility that operates across Southern Africa, including in LLMICs. The proposal can serve as a blue print for publicly owned utilities in LLMICs. 6 Location based transformative policies and practices: The Transformative Cities initiative promoted stories of location based transformative policies and practices that show how to address access to basic rights (housing, water, energy and food) to an international audience through the transnational cities website, media coverage and an award&#x2019;s night. 7 Ground water usage in Indonesia: an Indonesian Research institute, with research and financial support from TNI, has been developing alternatives for Jakarta&#x2019;s groundwater usage including efficient water usage, control over groundwater use, new technology to reduce dependency on groundwater, and an increase in groundwater tax rates. In 2018, the institute promoted their proposals in mainstream media, through meetings with the vice governor of Jakarta and their participation in the newly established The Drinking Water Governance Evaluation Team&#x2019;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Our partner in Colombia (trade union) met with Colombian delegates from the municipal services to discuss a public-public partnership for a state telecom company as alternative to privatisation of the company, in defense of public ownership and management of the telecom company. 2. TNI provided technical and financial support to partner in Colombia for the process of formulating a law for community water aquaducts. The bill on community water management was completed in 2017 and challenges the privatisation of public services. 3. TNI partner (financially supported by TNI) helped the Water Forum of El Salvador to develop a model for public water services, together with the state water company of El Salvador. The model is called &apos;Community water board and the state water company partnership&apos;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposals will be developed on energy democracy, democratisation in public services, and returning and creating public ownership. Proposals will be promoted on water supply in Lagos and Colombia.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome A: Enabling Environment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both the rights and the legal and political spaces needed to claim and defend those rights are protected for women and men, communities and civil society actors in LLMICs, enabling them to address misconduct and grievances successfully, and promote improved financial and tax policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.A.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># effective legal and other grievance mechanisms adopted or improved by corporations and/or financial institutions and development banks via which CSOs and communities can resolve grievances with governments, financial institutions and companies, and claim their environmental, human and worker rights.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.A.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.A.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms put in place or improved by governments and/or financial institutions and developments banks that guarantee access for civil society to (democratic) decision-making processes related to finance, tax and spending, including the right to resist developments.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.A.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency improved and space for policy dialogues expanded on the area of public finance, public spending, tax justice, management of common good in: - Nigeria (Lagos water privatisation), - Indonesia (Jakarta, groundwater and water provision) , - Mexico (Agua para Todos water school), - Colombia (legislation in related to the operation and recognition of community water utilities) TNI provides political financial supports especially by creating mutual learning, visibility, network building opportunities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 The Governor of Jakarta established an official advisory committee called &#x2018;The Drinking Water Governance Evaluation Team&#x2019;. The team is chaired by a senior civil servant with members from various groups including civil servants from water and environment related bodies, activists, directors of state-owned companies, and experts. Two out five members representing professionals are from TNI&#x2019;s partner, an Indonesian research institute. The team&#x2019;s main objective is to evaluate drinking water management to respond to the Supreme Court ruling. It is the first time such a committee has been established. TNI&#x2019;s partner, with research and financial support from TNI, has advocated for the remunicipalisation of the water utility.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected during this timeframe.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcomes in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcomes expected in this indicator in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcomes in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our partner in Nigeria started organising meetings throughout different communities in Lagos, to educate people about the government&apos;s plans and their implications of water privatisation in Lagos (Nigeria). The communities became the prime voice in the Our water Our rights campaign whereas communities had previously never been consulted for policy plans by the government. In this way, our work (TNI provides technical and financial support to our local partner ERA) strengthened the voices of communities in Lagos who got a seat at the table as a result.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Space for policy stakeholder dialogue expanded at the international level (GWOPA) on the area of management of public water as a result of continuous lobby and awareness raising by TNI and partners</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency improved and space for policy dialogues expanded on the area of TiSA, public finance, public spending, tax justice, management of common good in Nigeria, Indonesia, Mexico, Colombia [will be working on transparency in all these issues, but only expect one outcome change for the next year].</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome D: Agendas Set</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision makers prioritise improvement measures due to support from influential civil society actors, critical media attention, increased public awareness and effective scrutiny of financial and tax policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># proposals for improvement of financial, tax and spending policies discussed by private and public policy makers, and/or in academia, public agenda, media and social movements.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.D" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Policy makers and the media will discuss the proposals of a research institute in Indonesia (which were developed with financial and research support from TNI), for a transparent and inclusive transition to public water in Jakarta.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Philip Alston, the UN Special Rapporteur on extreme poverty and human rights released an important report on PPPs that sharply pointed out the negative impacts of PPPs for society and critical impacts for people in poverty. TNI&#x2019;s publication &#x2018;reclaiming public services&#x2019; was quoted in the report to address privatisation are seriously contested by local populations. (2) Leo Heller, the UN Special Rapporteur on water and sanitation and human rights was supportive in making a case that the Nigerian Government has failed to carry its obligation on water for the Nigerian people. TNI coordinated with affected communities and their organisations (Mexico /Puebla, Indonesia/Jakarta, Nigeria/Lagos) to report negative impacts of water privatisation as input to his final report on private sector participation in the water sector in the view of human rights. TNI connected with the Rapporteur and the Lagos water struggle and supported ERA to provide evidence of violation of human rights. (3) Several environmental organisations in South Africa changed their attitudes about unbundling Eskom, a state-owned power utility which operates in LLMICs, and supported the campaign to democratise Eskom as the integrated public company. TNI co-organised workshops with a South African advocacy organisation and a network of unions, to discuss the unbundling of Eskom and provided analysis demonstrating that transition without unbundling is possible and necessary to overcome the crisis Eskom was facing. (4) The Transformative Cities winners&#x2019; announcement was reported in 5 media outlets in Nigeria and 2 outlets in Mexico. Finalists in Nigeria, Kenya, Mexico and Spain did their own advocacy surrounding the award. TNI organised the Transformative Cities award. (5) The City of Amsterdam collaborated with TNI on the Future is Public conference and took a prominent role in the democratic economy debate. The conference included participants from LLLMICs and discussed democratic public ownership as a basis for a democratic economy, and public finance such as the green new deal. (6) The Syllabus, a prominent academic and journalist website featured the TNI co-hosted conference &#x2018;The Future is Public&#x2019; and quoted the report TNI authored for the conference. The conference included participants from LLLMICs and discussed democratic public ownership as a basis for a democratic economy, and public finance such as the green new deal. (7) Jakarta Governor Anies Baswedan made a firm political commitment to terminate private water contracts in Jakarta. TNI&#x2019;s partner, a research institute in Indonesia, has lobbied, with financial and research support by TNI, to stop the privatisation of Jakarta&#x2019;s water for many years.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) TNI&apos;s proposals on public ownership and publicness have been discussed by academia and social movements; (2) The governor of Lagos recognised the Lagos water crisis (put on the agenda by local partner with support from TNI) and the UN special rapporteur for Water and Sanitation picked up the issue to engage Nigeria on public budget reform and involvement of civil society</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1-5 Municipal policy makers in (1) Lagos, (2) Jakarta, (3) Bolivia, (4) El Salvador and (5) South Africa will discuss democratization of public services, including in water and energy, based on advocacy from local partners, with the support of research and analysis from TNI . 6 Media in LLMICs will profile transformative cities award nominees (including CSOs in LLLMICS) and their alternatives for water, energy, housing, finance and food production, with communications support from TNI. In the 2019 edition media in Kenya, India, Nigeria, Indonesia and Palestine have profiled the environmental and social rights struggles highlighted through Transformative Cities in these countries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) TNI&#x2019;s report &#x2018;Paying for the Pandemic and a Just Transition&#x2019; made over 46,000 impressions on twitter, thanks in part to a re-tweet from Thomas Piketty.
(2-10) In the context of the Covid crisis, a rare panel of eight current and former UN Special Rapporteurs (poverty, healthcare, water and sanitation, food, debt) came together in a TNI co-organised  webinar in mid-October, attended by over 500 people. They spoke on how the privatisation of public services had left societies defenseless under Covid conditions and the need to rebuild public services. The webinar was accompanied by an op-ed in the Guardian. That eight UN Special Rapporteurs came together was, itself, a rare opportunity, and that they all voiced critiques of privatisation was unique. Some of them (eg. Olivier De Schutter (ex food, now poverty), Leilani Farha (housing) and Leo Heller (water)) addressed public and community alternatives based on conceptions of the &#x2018;commons&#x2019;.
(11) INGOs who have tended to remain neutral on the question of ownership of public services, for the first time joined the narrative about the importance of putting services back in public hands, and move beyond the human right to water, health, etc narrative. They did so through showing their support for the above webinar,
(12) The Special Rapporteur on the right to water, L&#xE9;o Heller included contributions from TNI and partners in his final report where he assesses a range of risks to water services of private management, citing TNI&#x2019;s research. Heller came under heavy attack from the private water industry. Solidarity was quickly mobilised, with over 100 CSOs coming out in support of him.
(13-14) 11,000 people cast their votes in the 3rd annual Transformative Cities award, co-facilitated by TNI, (83% increase from 2019). The award and organisations involved were mentioned in 41 media stories in 2020. Participants included LLMIC Palestine.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of TNI&apos;s continued support to partner in Colombia (connecting them with regional partners), the municipal government in Colombia will be willing to develop a public-public partnership (PuP) with a strong publicly-owned enterprise of the region as the best way to recover the telecom unit (as an alternative to PPP or full privatisations).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 The United Nations Special Rapporteur on extreme poverty and human rights Philip Alston published a ground breaking report in September, addressing the negative impact of public-private partnerships on poverty and human rights and gender equity. The paper boldly argues privatisation undermines democracy by marginalising the role of Governments in deciding on the allocation of public goods and services, referring critics including TNI&#x2019;s reclaiming Public Services. 2 The Guardian Newsletter on alternatives called &#x2018;Upside&#x2019;, El Salto and Diario de Cadiz in Spain, Oneworld.nl, and National Herland India Newsclick from India discussed the Transformative Cities in their publications as a relevant initiative to highlight transformative practices globally in the areas of water energy and housing. 3 Mainstream media outlets in Indonesia; Jakarta Post, Kompas, Tirto, MetroTV News, Medcom, The Guardian, Kumparan, Republika, Okezone, Media Jakarta, published articles on issues relating to Jakarta&#x2019;s groundwater usage. The articles drew on an Indonesian research institute&#x2019;s research findings on the issues with Jakarta&#x2019;s groundwater usage and alternatives for Jakarta&#x2019;s groundwater usage. TNI provides financial and research support to the research institute. 4 An influential newspaper in the UK started to write critically on Public Finance Initiatives (PFIs), the journalist discussed the issue with TNI staff and TNI shared our research on the failures of privatisation with the journalist. The newspaper&#x2019;s articles on the need to stop PFIs in the UK formed an important part of the pressure on the UK Conservative Government who announced in 2018 that they would not sign any new PFIs. The UK was previously a major promoter of PFIs globally as a means to finance infrastructure and basic services. UK companies participate in PFIs in LLMICs. Their rejection of PFIs sets a powerful precedent for the halting of PFIs around the world. 5 The UK Labour party released its international policies which committed to stop PFI promotion in international cooperation and UK aid and to contribute to universal public services based on gender justice and public-public partnerships (PuPs) instead. TNI was asked to give further input on this policy document. TNI provided its experiences and expertise on PuPs in the water sector. 6 Public Services International (PSI), who has 20 million workers, represented by over 700 unions in 163 countries including LLMICS, decided to establish a working group to work on guidelines for workers to prepare and engage with remunicipalisation. TNI sits as an external advisor on the working group and the first meeting was held in December. 7 The Mayor of Cali in Colombia began negotiating a Public-Public Partnership (PuP) between EMCALI, Cali&#x2019;s public telecommunications with the telecom company (Antelo) of Uruguay in Montevideo. The PuP between the two companies would be the first PuP in the telecommunications industry anywhere in the world and would set a precedent for PuPs in the region. TNI facilitated the partnership between the two public entities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. In India, TNI organiseda workshop on energy democracy with local partners. As a result, politicians committed to advance policy engagement to organise an India national symposium on energy democracy in the coming year. 2. The UK Trades Union Congress passed a resolution on climate change that supports the energy sector being turned to public ownership. The text formally recognises TNI&apos;s Reclaiming Public Services publication as providing inspiration input for this resolution. 3. The Indonesian Supreme Court ordered termination of water privatisation and restoration of public management to ensure human rights in water provision. Our partner has supported the citizen lawsuit filed by the coalition against water privatisation. TNI has supported this partner in the last 8 years through research, expertise, media engagement, and financial support. 4. After strong advocacy by local partner, state telecom company in Uruguay committed itself to sign an agreement with the local municipal services company to provide technical assistance to the trade union. TNI has financially supported the trade union in this process to call for public ownership and management of the telecom segment. 5. TNI&apos;s research on remunicipalisation to prove the failure of privatisation in public services has become a reference point for progressive municipalist, labour and trade movements to develop alternative economic strategies. For example, the head of the energy cities alliance started using the term Energy Democracy in their reports and strategies. Other organisations are Our water, our Right campaign in Lagos, the Coalition of Jakarta Residents Opposing Water Privatization (KMMSAJ), Indonesia 6. Member of European Parliament Miguel Urban mentioned TNI&apos;s report on the Bailout Business when asking ECB President about the supervisory mechanism on auditing companies oligpoly Bailout in MEP speech. 7. TNI&apos;s work on energy democracy incited the SP in the Netherlands to call for a democratic public energy company in Groningen and has contributed to changing discouse on energy democracy in the Netherlands. TNI organised a conference on the NAM in Groningen in January 2017. 8. FGG&apos;s report on NCICD in Jakarta and subsequent media outreach has made the NCICD plan and land reclamation project in Jakarta Bay a subject of public debate in Indonesia, between factions in local government and ministries and agencies on the national level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposals on public ownership, energy democracy and TiSA will be discussed by social movements, the public, and policy makers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome B: Capacities Strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased capacity of civil society actors to research, network and advocate on financial and tax policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># CSOs and communities in LLMICs that lobby and advocate for improved financial, tax and spending policies, based on increased skills, knowledge or network contacts.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.B" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Based on TNI&apos;s financial support and technical research input, a research institute based in Indonesia will strengthen its research and develop policy proposals, which it will use to advocate in water policy dialogues and the media for a transparent transition to public water in Jakarta. 2 Financial and technical assistance through TNI&apos;s Transformative Cities initiative will strengthen the communications skills of CSOs in multiple LLMICS to support their advocacy for policy change in the areas of energy, water, housing, finance and food systems. In the first edition of Transformative Cities in 2018, TNI supported CSOs from Ghana, Tanzania, India, Bangladesh, Bolivia, Nicaragua, Zimbabwe, Nigeria, India and Indonesia. 3 TNI&#x2019;s financial and advocacy support will strengthen the policy advocacy skills of a regional platform based in Bolivia, who will mobilize to advocate for citizen water laws, including in El Salvador. 4 TNI will provide financial and technical assistance to a centre in India to better communicate their successful work in energy democracy to support their advocacy for policy change.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) With analysis and research from TNI, a Latin American congress of unions, which includes unions in LLMICS, advocated at the international level for a just energy transition in relation to energy utilities and governance, including public spending. (2-3) With communications support from TNI and increased profile and networks through the Transformative Cities Award, local groups organized online and offline local actions to promote their initiatives and attract public vote including two CSOs in West Bank and Gaza and Kenya. These actions were targeted towards the media, their constituencies and allies. The Transformative Cities Award showcases and promotes transformative initiatives that protect the right to water, energy, housing and food. (4) With financial and research support from TNI, and connections to other water de-privatisation groups, a research institute in Indonesia has continued to advocate for the remunicipalisation of Jakarta&#x2019;s water supply. (5) With financial and technical support from TNI, an environmental rights organisation in Nigeria continued to advocate towards the national and state governments for fair allocation of the public budget and democratisation of public water. In 2019, they hosted a major national summit on water, in which TNI participated and won the Transformative Cities Award in the water category. (6) With financial support from TNI, a platform based in Bolivia organised a meeting where the representatives of 52 organizations, including from LLMICs attended. The meeting facilitated the exchange of experiences around community water management from different dimensions to highlight the work of women and men across the continent who are in the front line defending the right of the communities to manage water by themselves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 With financial support and technical research input from TNI, a CSO based research institute in Indonesia will strengthen its research and develop policy proposals, which they will use to advocate for a transparent transition to public water and ongoing fight against water privatisation in Jakarta, based on the human right to water and through media and engagement with municipal policy makers. 2 With technical support from TNI, a research and advocacy group in the Philippines will set up a platform on urban policies in Manila with a focus on just transition, housing and transportation to advocate for more sustainable social rights. 3 With video training, resources and joint strategizing from TNI, a Nigerian NGO will continue to fight the privatisation of the Lagos water utility and advocate for the human right to water in Nigeria. 4 With joint strategizing, networking and resources from TNI, a regional platform who has members in Bolivia and El Salvador, will work with community organisations to advocate for recognition of their water systems. Currently, these community water system groups are excluded from legislation as a water service provider. 5 Financial and technical assistance through TNI&apos;s Transformative Cities initiative will strengthen the communications capacity and visibility locally and internationally of CSOs in multiple LLMICS to support their advocacy for policy change at the local level, and in some cases the national and international level, in the areas of energy, water, housing, finance and food systems. In the latest edition of Transformative Cities in 2019, TNI supported CSOs from Nigeria, Kenya, Palestine, India, Senegal, Mozambique and Indonesia.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1-2) With analysis and research from TNI, two networks of trade unions, both of which include unions in LLMICs, advocated at the international level for a just energy transition in relation to energy utilities and governance, including public spending.
(3) With communications support from TNI and increased profile and networks through the Transformative Cities Award, local groups organized online and offline to promote their initiatives and attract public votes including an environmental rights group in Palestine. Their actions were targeted towards the media, their constituencies and allies. The Transformative Cities Award showcases and promotes transformative initiatives that protect the right to water, energy, housing and food.
(4) With financial and research support from TNI, and connections to other water de-privatisation groups, an Indonesian research institute has continued to advocate for the remunicipalisation of Jakarta&#x2019;s water supply. In 2020, after their supreme court victory was overturned on appeal, they moved their focus to the contract expiration in 2023.
(5) With financial and technical support from TNI, an environmental rights group in Nigeria continued to advocate towards the national and state governments for fair allocation of the public budget and democratisation of public water, and to resist privatisation of Lagos&#x2019; state water company.
(6) With financial support from TNI, a platform based in Bolivia, facilitated the exchange of experiences around community water management from different dimensions to highlight the work of women and men across the continent who are in the front line defending the right of the communities to manage water by themselves. They then used this work in their advocacy for policies that support rather than block community centred water systems. 

(7) A global trade union federation representing 20 million working women and men in 163 countries, including LLMICs, published its own guidebook &#x2018;Taking our public services back in house: A remunicipalisation guide for workers and trade unions&#x2019;, based on their and TNI&#x2019;s collective work for the last 10 years. Beyond agenda setting in workers movement, this guidebook has been shared with and used as a resource by union members, including in LLMICs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Based on TNI&apos;s financial support and technical research input, partner in Indonesia will develop advocacy work on groundwater extraction to promote sustainable and inclusive water policies. 2. Based on TNI&apos;s financial and technical support, partner in Nigeria will increase their policy advocacy capacity towards the national and state governments on fair allocation of public budget and democratisation of public water.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 With analysis and research from TNI, a Latin American congress of unions including unions in LLMICS, advocated for energy transition in relation to energy utilities and governance, including public spending at the international level. 2+3 With training in policy orientated research, network facilitation and financial support from TNI, a social economy network from Ukraine and a union from Georgia authored research which they used in their advocacy on public spending priorities related to the environment and labour. 4-6 With training in policy orientated research, network facilitation and financial support from TNI, two local environmental movements in Nicaragua and a housing cooperative in Bolivia authored research they have used in their advocacy for improved public spending in relations to environmental and housing issues. 7+8 With communications support from TNI and increased profile and networks through the Transformative Cities Award, an Indian union continued to advocate for public support for housing for poor workers in India through the media and advocacy towards the regional and national government. While a CSO in Tanzania, continued to advocate towards the local government for affordable and just housing for displaced communities. 9 With financial and research support from TNI, a research institute in Indonesia continued to advocate for the remunicipalisation of Jakarta&#x2019;s water supply. 10 With financial and technical support from TNI, an environmental rights network in Nigeria continued to advocate towards the national and state governments for the fair allocation of public budget and democratisation of public water. 11 With financial support from TNI, a regional platform launched an international online campaign on community-based water management in Latin America. The campaign focuses on water defenders across the Americas, including in LLMICs, working with platform members to highlight the work of men and women across the continent who are in the front line defending the right of the communities to manage water by themselves.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. TNI supported a partner in Indonesia in mobilising, developing alternatives, and media outreach. The coalition was able to hold a debate based on the report published by FGG partners, with a presence of the national state planning agency, the Dutch embassy, the Dutch business experts, and journalists.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 CSOs lobbied and advocated for public water based on increased research and advocacy capacity</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">6 CSOs will lobby and advocacy on public services, tax collection, clean energy, and public water supply based on increased research and advocacy capacity.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome F: Practice Changed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is successful and sustainable implementation of: financial regulation by governments and financial policies in corporations; tax regimes and corporate tax practices; and accountability, transparency, safeguards and gender aware policies in public financial institutions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.F.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># concrete steps taken by public financial institutions and private actors to actively identify, prevent and mitigate adverse social, gender and environmental impacts of their investments, and concrete steps taken that advance socially just and sustainable development in LLMICs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.F.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI doesn&apos;t work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.F.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms for improved financial, tax and spending policies implemented and enforced by national, regional and international government bodies.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.F.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A water rights campaign led by TNI partner in Nigeria, mobilised public resistance and halted the Lagos State Environmental Laws (that would further criminalise the informal sector and deny peoples&apos; access to water). In 2017, the government allocated 185 million dollars of the budget to ensure clean water for people as a result of the campaign. TNI made a financial contribution to the campaign and TNI&apos;s expertise was used in the joint publication.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcome level results are expected in this time frame</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected for 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results in 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected during this timeframe.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcomes expected in this indicator in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcome level results expected within this timeframe.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome E: Policies Changed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">These include improved financial regulation by governments and improved financial policies in corporations; improved tax regimes and corporate tax practices; and effective accountability, transparency, safeguards and gender aware policies in public financial institutions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.E.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># measures taken by national, regional and international government bodies to ensure financial, tax and spending policies advance socially just and sustainable development in LLMICs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.E.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected during this timeframe.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) The Local Government in Cali, Colombia officially cancelled the privatisation of the city&#x2019;s telecommunication services. TNI provided research support to the trade union in the municipal utilities company of Cali who advocated to stop privatisation. (2) Trade Unions in South Africa, with research support from TNI, prevented the unbundling of Eskom, a state-owned power utility that operates in LLMICs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No outcomes expected in this indicator in 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) The Local Government in Cali, Colombia officially cancelled the privatisation of the city&#x2019;s telecommunication services. TNI provided research support to the trade union in the municipal utilities company of Cali who advocated to stop privatisation. 
(2) Trade Unions in South Africa, with research support from TNI, prevented the unbundling of Eskom, a state-owned power utility that operates in LLMICs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected for 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 The UK Conservative Government announced in 2018 that they would not sign any new Public Finance Initiatives (PFIs). The UK was previously a major promoter of PFIs globally as a means to finance infrastructure and basic services. UK companies participate in PFIs in LLMICs. Their rejection of PFIs sets a powerful precedent for the halting of PFIs around the world. TNI did interviews with the British press on the failures of privatisation and TNI worked with a key British media outlet that pressured the British conservatives.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">None of aimed changes have been achieved yet</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 country will leave the TiSA negotiations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.E.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># policies improved or introduced by public financial institutions and private actors on accountability, transparency and safeguards, and investment policies adopted that advance socially just and sustainable development in LLMICs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3.E.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of succesful advocacy work by our partner in Colombia, privatisation of Cali telecom company has been halted. TNI provided technical input and wrote a report on the situation in Cali and the role of advisory company Lazard, which led to public debate and discussions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected for 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results in 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected in the timeframe</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results in 2019</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">None of aimed changes have been achieved yet</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TNI does not work on this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lagos state water company acknowledges and adapts proposals to reform LSWC.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
