<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-21/DDA-3558/RA2/S/NFI/NGO/20405</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of  personal insulation (distribution of winter clothing and blankets) for the most vulnerable people in Maadan and Al Sabkha towns and its rural area of Ar Raqqa governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ten years of crisis have prevented the majority of the conflict-affected people from recovering or replacing their primary or complementary income-generating activities and now more people than before have exhausted their financial means and are not able to prepare adequately for the coming winter. Financial constraints limit the purchase capacity of entire/majority population, making Winterization the largest life-saving activity in the country, this includes like fuel, heating fuel, stoves, jackets, thermal blankets, shoes used for personal insulation. 
The suffering of the targeted people in the proposed intervention areas in Al Sabkha and Maadan towns and its countryside  in last harsh winter showed that poor vulnerable groups especially returnees who lost their livelihoods  resorted, to meet their needs to adapt their practices to improve resilience of health and health care to extreme weather, to use unconventional methods like burning plastics to warm themselves. where indoor pollution led to several acute infections and negative impacts on patients. Impacts on vulnerable poor families arising from cold waves include increased rates of respiratory conditions and emergency treatment especially among older people and children, most of them suffered infection of an asthma attack, irritation of the airways with acute respiratory. indeed, effects have been varying by age, gender, geography, and socioeconomic status. 
Moreover, the compound impacts of extreme cold weather events and COVID-19, vulnerable people have been exposed and faced multiple crises and coping with overlapping vulnerabilities, where the COVID-19 pandemic has affected and made vulnerable people more vulnerable to harsh weather risks.
So, this project proposal have focused on the situation of vulnerable population extreme weather impacts as assistance demand as extreme weather impacts on human health, therefore, as harsh weather has a profound effects on vulnerable poor human health and well-being, the project proposal aims to provide winterization assistances to the most poor families to contribute to help vulnerable people stay healthy despite cold waves will prevail the area of intervention as well contribute to minimize the spread of infectious diseases.
According, to to a new analysis shared by DoSA and SARC on population, vulnerable population and needs, that Maadan town is currently inhabited by around 76,000 most of them are returnees, meanwhile Al-Sabkhah is inhabited by around 115,000 persons most of them are returnees, and Hamdaniya population reads around 24,000 persons and located on the main road connects Al-Sabkhah with  Maadan.  
The assessment has revealed that the most needed winterization items to achieve the personal insulation of the vulnerable people in winter season have been clothes and blankets as winter jacket for (men, women and children), winter shoes for children and blankets for families.
The project goal has been to distribute 11,600 clothes and blankets pieces: 2,000 winter jackets for old men, 2,500 wither jackets for women, 4,100 winter jackets and 4,100 shoes for children, and 3,000 thermal blankets, benefiting 9,100 vulnerable people as of the agreed criteria 4,914 vulnerable people in Al Sabkha and 4,186 vulnerable people in Maadan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Bir Wa Al-Ehsan Association in Ras AlAin</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Bir Wa Al-Ehsan Association in Ras AlAin</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hussein alkash</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0932473712</telephone>
   <email>husseinalkash@Gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raymond Youssef</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0936082747</telephone>
   <email>raimond.you@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joumaa Ezzi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program staff</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0991160855</telephone>
   <email>ruralheart89@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ar-Raqqa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.95307500 39.00606200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">499813.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-20405">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-01">499813.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Bir Wa Al-Ehsan Association in Ras AlAin</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305417345-46">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-04">399850.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Bir Wa Al-Ehsan Association in Ras AlAin</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
