<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-21/DDA-3558/SA1/S/NFI/NGO/19618</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Distribution of winter clothes for children in Deir-ez-Zor governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the far eastern countryside of Deir ez-Zor governorate, the cities of Al-Mayadin and Abu Kamal are located, and they are considered in great need of services and in all sectors due to the lack of 
Non availability of basic services and because  the destruction that occurred in the two areas and their villages (Al-Bukamal, Hajin, Al-Jalaa, Al-Sousah, Al-Baghouz, Al-Busira, Mayadin, Buqrus, Al-Ashara, Dhiban, it is in ruins, but the people were able to return to their homes to start their lives again.These areas lack significantly and noticeably the basic necessities of life (from health care - water and sanitation services after the infrastructure was destroyed - Clothes, especially winter clothes for children
Not available opportunities for quality education due to the destruction of most schools.
 Most of the population are farmers and depend on entirely in securing their income from agriculture, as it is a fertile and prosperous agricultural area, and the Euphrates River is the main source of water for irrigating crops, but at the beginning of May 2021 of this year the rate of flow of the Euphrates River to the Syrian lands decreased by 50%, which negatively affected the economic situation of the community, especially On agriculture, the region suffers from a clear weakness in the field of trade and relies on other governorates to secure its needs, with a noticeable return of the people to their homes and with the presence of a breadwinner They are still displaced from other areas, as well as the presence of random camps for the displaced and with the approach of winter
The Syrian Al-Yamamah Association sees a very urgent and urgent need to provide winter clothes for children who are more affected by the cold. 
as such he several-fold increase in prices of essential commodities needed to protect families from cold temperatures combined with the deteriorating economic situation of households has left many Syrians unable to protect their children from the harsh weather conditions especially during the winter time. This is particularly true about families who have been displaced several times during the conflict and continue to live in dire conditions. In 2021 This is the reality of the situation in the eastern countryside of Deir ez-Zor
Especially after the spread of COVID-19 and the imposition of lockdown and restriction of movement between governorates and the devaluation of the Syrian pound against the dollar significantly, sometimes reached 5000 Syrian pounds per dollar.
The main objective of programme is to protect the most
vulnerable children especially those affected by the conflict and displacement from harsh weather conditions.
 the local procurement of winter clothes also directly supports local economy and recovery process, and enhances community resilience through the multiplier effect of the cash that injected in the local economy. Moreover, programme will support affected IDP and local community families in areas have been under dire living conditions for years of the conflict. 
Eastern countryside of Deir ez-Zor Like other Syrian areas, it has experienced the current crisis and to fighting acts which forced its residents to flee to safe area but after safety and stability were regained to their city, most of its residents returned to their city. But most homes were destroyed and living means were limited and the infrastructure like schools, bakeries, dispensaries, potable water plants and sewage were destroyed.
According to the statistics of the Relief Subcommittee in Deir ez-Zor about 630000 lives Eastern countryside of Deir ez-Zor but they are in urgent need for support and help In all sectors, with a focus on providing food, especially winter clothes for children
the target population returnsees and IDPs and host communities
The eastern countryside of Deir ez-Zor is still receiving returnees from al-Hol camp in al-Hasakah governorate to their homes in (Hajin, al-Baghouz, al-Susah and Thiban,</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Al Yamama Charity Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Al Yamama Charity Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azzam Alhmd</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0933966010</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Projects Manager</telephone>
   <email>azzamalhmd@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">joud al ghdeer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0991829772</telephone>
   <email>joudalghdeer@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deir-ez-Zor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.33188500 40.14607100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">84557.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">415436.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-19618">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">499994.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Al Yamama Charity Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305297206">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">199997.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Al Yamama Charity Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305490423-424">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-25">149998.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Al Yamama Charity Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305596522-523">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">149998.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Al Yamama Charity Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
