<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-21/DDA-3558/SA1/H/NGO/19499</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the delivery of the essential package of  health care services to the vulnerable groups and IDPs in Homs  Hama suburb and Hama downtown by medical caravans</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After identifying the initial needs by OCHA-WHO in the affected Syrian areas in addition to HeRams reports, Youth Charity based on these reports carried out its own assessment by studying and analyzing the situation through visits by the survey team of the Youth Charity to the Targeted areas and with key people to reach an accurate study and determine the need optimally, and an important reason that helped in the ease of access to execute survey is that some of the team members are from the population of the targeted areas, and which helped to gain more confidence and As agreed and coordinated with Dr.Nadia Al Jamali WHO - Homs sub-office she had already agreed to the selected areas because these areas need medical services.
The project aims to provide its medical services to 17,225 of the 81,047 poor people and health needs in Hama center, Al Hamrah and Al Qusayr by three Medical caravans contribute to: 
1) Increasing access to health care through the provision of comprehensive and integrated essential health services to cover the health needs of vulnerable populations, including Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn, and Child Health (RMNCH), as well as continuity of treatment for people who live with non-communicable disease.
2) Improving access to Trauma care management including comprehensive phased trauma, with support to the referral pathways for trauma cases.
3) Restore, strengthen, expand health services to deliver an essential package of care adapted to a rapidly increasing number of consumers to provide an integrated, comprehensive basic essential health care package that addresses common diseases, and injuries, including diagnostic services at primary and secondary levels targeting the most vulnerable groups while promoting community cohesion among populations, served, addressing inequalities in access to care targeting returning and receiving communities.
 And referral system will be executed in coordination with local hospitals in the area (to beneficiaries who are unable to travel) and with hospitals in Damascus (to beneficiaries who are able to travel). And medical services include free medication and the source of medicines is the Pharmacists Syndicate. Trauma services will be provided in the emergency clinic in Caravan Medical clinics by the emergency physician in the following cases: emergency wounds, fractures, and abscesses.
Youth Charity looking for support people under the poverty line, people with medical need&#x2019;s, people that don&#x2019;t have any carrier to start with, children&#x2019;s who faced financial difficulties to follow-up with their schools years, pregnant ladies who can&#x2019;t handle the cost of The medical attention they may require, the spread of COVID-19, lack of services In the clinics that request more laboratories.
The issue of non-occurrence of gender-based violence, violence against children, and child labor will be pursued.
Precautionary procedures are taken in the project related to Covid-19 virus prevention measures:
- Daily sterilization of clinics.
- Keeping safe distances among people.
- Sterilization for each beneficiary of medical services and psychological support upon entry.
- Posting educational posters to prevent coronavirus.
The number of beneficiaries was determined according to a specific logical study, where approximately /50/ patients are received per day in one clinic, Those patients in return will receive medical consultations by specialized doctors in addition to medical analysis, surgeries. 
The locations of the two Medical caravans will be located in:
1- Hama, Al Hamrah.
2- Homs, Al Qusayr, And provide the primary medical services.
And Hama downtown that will be covered by a medical caravan which has been established on 12 April 2021 in cooperation between Youth Charity and Hama governorate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Charity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Charity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Darin Matroud</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Department Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0956444204</telephone>
   <email>shababdhm@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hama</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.13374200 36.76129100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homs</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.72996100 36.71973100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">78726.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">276855.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-19499">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">355582.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Charity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305297207">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-23">142232.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Charity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305490373-425">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-25">106674.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Charity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305596524-525">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">106674.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Charity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
