<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-21/DDA-3558/SA1/E/NGO/19637</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Educational Rehabilitation Project(3)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project that aims to provide several educational services through implementing  some activities in some Homs rural areas, these activities including :
- rehabilitation of one school (, Ghazi Alabd in Aldar alkrerah  )
- Self-learning for students whose learning stopped due to unfortunate events in the following areas (Sukarah,  daier balbeh ,  and kaferlaha  ) The self-learning materials help students to acquire basic knowledge in the subjects of Arabic, English, Mathematics, and Science from the first to sixth grades So that it enables students who have been out of school to obtain the information and skills required to obtain the basic education and continue their educational journey.
AOUN will conduct a pre-test to children in coordination with DoEs and will create a database on child-level including (registration info, results of the placement test, number of sessions attended for each subject) in addition to the results of post-test and will share it with relevant DoEs and UNICEF. 
Aoun will provide self-learning sessions for students who have not been to school before (literacy classroom). Those students need more attention and support so they will be grouped according to their age and level and not mixed with younger students in order to save them from any kind of harassment or misunderstanding.
All children will receive bags with stationery in addition to Self-learning materials and Edutainment and life skills activities (such as games, sport, free play, and others) These activities will be useful to promote the well-being and flexibility of children.  Unfortunately, children&#x2019;s opportunities for recreation are often restricted and they are facing very difficult life circumstances. For that matter, it is crucial to provide children with edutainment activities that will stimulate the development of specific capacities and resources (e.g. emotional self-regulation, collaboration, problem-solving, etc.).
- Remedial classes for students whose at risk of stopped learning causing social and economic impacts of COVID 19 in these areas (Sukarah, Alhelaleah, daier balbeh , Alqusaier and kaferlaha )The registration of children will be based on:
-	Those with poor results in order to improve their level and prevent their dropping out (The school records which is less than 65% of the full mark)
-	Vulnerable children who have an Education gap in previous years (previous dropouts) that affect their performance in current grade.
-	Children who have learning difficulties.
the project aims to provide facilities that are equipped with fully qualified teachers to help self-learning  and remedial classes process
	Provide professional development for resource teachers:
Aoun believes in the significance of having trained staff and especially the resources teachers as having teachers equipped with updated knowledge means helping students in a better way. The project will support the training of (30) teachers on Active Learning, PSS and SLP.
The targeted areas are already facing a lack of teaching staff. Thus, AOUN will make sure in coordination with DoEs that the recruiting process of resource persons will not influence on his / her work with DoEs (especially for the teachers with temporary contracts),
Aoun staff will hold an introduction about the implementation of the project for teachers in addition, teachers will receive special awareness sessions on COVID-19 prevention measures and how to deal with children during COVID pandemic. Each teacher will be provided with school subjects (SLM, books, guides) and teaching materials. 
- Outreach through young people with social mobilization activities BTL, inclusive of households visits, community participation, and Initiatives
-	Volunteering teams are responsible for:
conducting door to door visits, 
conduct focus group discussions for parents/caregivers and Initiatives
distribution of campaign material such as posters and flyer</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Charity Association - Aoun for relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Charity Association - Aoun for relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AmIr Atassi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Member of Head</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0935982222</telephone>
   <email>amiratassi@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waseem Mandwo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Member of head</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0944545450</telephone>
   <email>wmandwo@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homs</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.72996100 36.71973100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-08">331754.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-08">15960.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-19637">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-08">347715.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Charity Association - Aoun for relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
