<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-19/DDA-3558/SA1/H/UN/14086</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance access to prosthetic services for persons with disabilities from Dara&apos;a and Quneitra</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Previous reports estimated that roughly 45 percent of the injured population due to the crisis develop permanent disabilities of whom 15% undergo amputation. In the areas with risk of explosive hazards, it is expected to encounter a higher rate of people living with amputation as it is reported that 50% of victims suffered a limb amputation. for example in the southern areas, there is a lack of information on the presence of any services and no official nor reliable data on the number and types of injuries. Anecdotally, the directorate of social affairs in Dara&#x2019;a reported 400 persons are living with amputation. While amputation is a devastating injury affecting not only the body function but also the mental health of its victim, the physical rehabilitation program is rather simple and straightforward, where significant improvement can be achieved by the provision of prosthetic services leveraging the person to a level of full autonomy and independence. 
Under its program to support the resilience of PWDs towards socio-economic inclusion, UNDP has been contributing to support in filling in the gaps of lack of services. Building on this experience and in-house technical capacities, and to expand the support to underserved areas, UNDP is planning to support the provision of comprehensive prosthetic services to people in need in the southern areas of Dara&#x2019;a and Quneitra. 
To this end UNDP will create a project team consisting of operational and technical staff to manage and monitor the activities of the project that can be divided into the following:
1. Establishing coordination mechanism with the health sector and physical rehabilitation working group in addition to the ministry of social affairs and directorates in targeted governorates. 
2. In-depth need assessment: Starting from the data at the respective directorate in each targeted area, the project will analyze the available data and follow-up with identifying cases eligible for inclusion in this project. selection criteria are:
 Persons with unattended cases of amputation
 All types of amputation
 All ages group 
 Persons living in the targeted areas (host communities and internally displaces population)
For prioritization, the project will follow the following criteria:
 Women 
 Children
 Members of families with more than one PWD 
 Members of families who lost their breadwinner 
 IDPs
While the assessment will serve mainly as data for the physical rehabilitation service delivery, it will also serve as a useful source of information to ensure proper implementation of protection, gender and GBV mainstreaming. 
3. Facilitating access to comprehensive prosthetic services: The project will provide the necessary inputs (financial, technical and human resources) to ensure the delivery of comprehensive physical rehabilitation services to persons with amputation while covering needed transportation fees and accommodation on top of the services&#x2019; cost.
With the support of in-house technical capacities, a close follow-up and monitoring will be implemented for each case to ensure the proper delivery of physical rehabilitation services, in addition to the proper and safe logistical arrangement that takes into consideration protection and gender issues. 
The physical rehabilitation package will consist of the following services provided by contracting local service provider: 
 Medical consultation and prescription of the prosthesis 
 Fitting of a prosthesis 
 Pre and post physical therapy 
 PSS and mental health services
 Technical follow-up and maintenance for 6 months post-delivery
4. Conducting case management for each case to enhance the resilience of targeted beneficiaries. This package will include:
 Awareness-raising sessions on the rights and entitlement of PWDs
 Case management and referral pathways to other services (health, social, educational and livelihoods). The project is expected to benefit 120 persons with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khotwa Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relive and Development center (RDC) of Syrian Catholic archbishopric</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Louay Fallouh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00963958880024</telephone>
   <email>louay.fallouh@undp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dar&apos;a</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.62410200 36.10494400</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quneitra</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.08619600 35.87256000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">46233.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">281253.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">93237.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-14086">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-11">420724</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304315192">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-13">420724</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
