<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-19/DDA-3558/SA1/E/INGO/14018</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education assistance for conflict-affected people in East Ghouta and Dar&#x2019;a</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will provide education support to conflict-affected populations in East Ghouta (Duma and Ein Terma) and Dar&#x2019;a (Kherbet Ghazala and Sheikh Miskine) as prioritized in the 2019 SHF Allocation in coordination with other actors. DRC will flexibly intervene where most needed, including where DRC is strategically positioned for access in comparison to other responders. DRC has existing operational presence in East Ghouta and Dar&#x2019;a and will use this Action to scale-up assistance, ensuring a comprehensive response to the population in need. DRC will target a total of 9,544 beneficiaries under this action. Coordination with other actors will maximize response efficiency. 

With access to East Ghouta as well as Dar&#x2019;a facilitated through SARC, DRC stands ready to begin activities for this project as soon as it is funded. According to DRC assessments and service mapping, Ein Terma, Duma, Kherbet Ghazala and Sheikh Miskine remain areas in East Ghouta and Dar&#x2019;a with high levels of education needs with few humanitarian services available. The provision of education services inside Syria is limited, with limited access to safe school buildings, massive dropout rates, and a lack of qualified teachers able to handle the overcrowded classrooms characterizing many of the functional schools. Child labor, child recruitment, and early marriage all interfere with children&#x2019;s ability to attend school, often resulting in children dropping out. These children join their peers who have been removed from the formal education system by their parents due to fears for children&#x2019;s safety, lack of available schools, and inability to learn in the often overcrowded and chaotic education system. 

In order to reduce, mitigate and address the education needs, DRC proposes a program, inclusive of the Self-Learning Program, remedial classes, teacher training, parent-teacher associations and school rehabilitation, which will be provided inside MoE schools, targeting vulnerable and underserved students which will support pathways to safe reintegration into formal education. DRC will assess schools long-listed by MoE, targeting schools based on scoring criteria that accounts for a number of variables, including the proportion of IDPs in the student body, the number of dropouts per school, classroom occupancy, and the availability of learning materials among students. The soft activities will provide learning pathways for children who are out of school to reintegrate into formal education as well as reduce the number of dropouts, while school rehabilitation will provide the safe and comfortable learning environment needed. The project accords with the education sector&#x2019;s strategy providing education assistance to conflict-affected people in East Ghouta and Dar&#x2019;a. Project locations will remain flexible to enable DRC to respond to the most critical needs expected locations include Duma and Kafr Batna sub-districts in Rural Damascus and Kherbet Ghazala and Sheikh Miskine sub-districts in Dar&#x2019;a.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-EDU-156694-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valeria Bacci</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0942000984</telephone>
   <email>valeria.bacci@drcsyria.dk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dar&apos;a</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.62410200 36.10494400</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Damascus</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.32451400 36.21611100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-12">574084.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-14018">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-12">574084.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304318523">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-14">459267.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
