<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27560</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himadri Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himadri Chemicals &amp; Industries Limited (Himadri or the Company) is Indias largest producer of coal tar pitch which is utilized in the production of aluminum and graphite. Himadri is known as one of the highest quality producers of coal tar pitch in the world, and its products are used by several, major international customers.  The company is also only one of three companies worldwide that is able to produce zero Q.I. Coal Tar Impregnating Pitch, a high quality pitch used for impregnation of graphite electrodes, and it is the only company outside Japan able to manufacture it.  Himadri uses coal tar in India as its raw material which is a by product of recovery type high temperature coke oven batteries.  The Company distills such into useful coal-tar pitch and derivatives, thereby creating useful economic value from a low-value feedstock. During the manufacturing process, the company also produces various industrial oils as by-products that can be further used as feedstock for the production of carbon black, a key input for tire manufacturers.   Given strong demand, Himadri is expanding its present coal tar pitch distillation capacity of 169,000 metric tons per annum (mtpa) in India to 400,000 mtpa.  Phase I consists of (i) increasing its distillation capacity to 250,00 mtpa, (ii) setting up a 50,000 mtpa carbon black production facility and (iii) constructing an associated 12 mega-watt waste-heat recovery based power plant (together, the Project).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is expected to have a strong developmental impact including environmental efficiency, employment generation and increased business opportunities for the local and wider areas.  - Carbon Footprint/Climate Change:  Once the expansion is completed, waste heat generated in the production process will be used to (i) generate the entire amount of power that the plant complex would consume and generate a surplus to be sold to the local grid &amp; (ii) meet the entire heating needs of the production process, thus eliminating the current need for burning oil or any other fuel to produce heat. Both these impacts will significantly reduce the companys carbon footprint, even with a significantly expanded plant capacity.  - Investment in the lesser developed Eastern Region of India:  Himadris plants are located in the eastern region of India, an economically laggard area with one of the lowest per-capita incomes in the country.  The eastern part also has the largest concentration of poor in India, and its advantages in terms of low wage rates are offset by its poor business environment and the absence of adequate infrastructure. Since the economy is primarily agrarian, this project would help strengthen and diversify the regions economic base and create new jobs.  It is anticipated the project would require 150 additional employees.  - Local supplier linkages:  Himadri sources a large portion of its raw material from domestic steel producers in India.  As various components of the Project come on-line, Himadri will require additional large amounts of coal tar from the steel producers, providing the industry with additional sales outlets, revenue generation and flexibility in disposing of waste products.  - Efficient Waste Recycling:  Reprocessing of waste coal tar from the steel industry into value-added products through this Project results in minimization of indiscriminate disposal of waste from steel mills and helps improve the overall ecological footprint.  Proposed key indicators to track the developmental impact of the project include:  - Surplus power made available to the local grid. - Direct employment generation. - Volume of domestic coal tar supply distilled by the company into higher-value products.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himadri Speciality Chemical Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27560" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-04-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-04-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Soumen Chakrobortry Himadri Chemicals &amp; Industries Ltd.  Mahistikry Unit  Mahistikry,  Haripal, Hooghly, West Benegal, India</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is located in a designated industrial area north of Kolkata, India along a major national highway. The nearest community is approximately two kilometers away. The coal tar pitch expansion project and the carbon black project are at the existing site.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC - Carbon Black</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $46.50 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-04-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-04-02">21500000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-04-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-04-02">25000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-04-02">25000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himadri Speciality Chemical Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-04-02">21500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himadri Speciality Chemical Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27560/himadri-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
