<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-531872</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INCaF IHDC Small Hydros</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INCaF is contracting with Dodson-Lindblom HydroPower Private Limited (DLHPPL) and Ascent Hydro Projects Limited (Ascent) on a joint and several basis to purchase Certified Emission Reductions (CERs) generated by the two companies small hydro projects in India.  DLHPPL and Ascent are Indian companies, established in 1997 and 1994 respectively, that are 100% owned subsidiaries of Dodson-Lindblom International (DLI or the Sponsor), a wholly-owned subsidiary of DLZ Corporation of the U.S.  IFC is also lending to these companies, on a joint and several basis (Note that a Summary of Project Information for IFCs investment project with DLI Small Hydros, known by the name IHDC, was already released on June 16, 2005 by IFC). As of June 20, 2006, the project name changed from DLI small Hydros to IHDC Small Hydros. The reason for this change was because the first sponsor, DLI, formed a new company, IHDC, as a special purpose vehicle to own the projects and facilitate the investment of additional investors.

In 2002, IFC and the Netherlands established the IFC-Netherlands Carbon Facility (INCaF) and an associated Trust to enable IFC to purchase, for the benefit of the Netherlands, certified emission reductions (CERs) under the framework of the Clean Development Mechanism (CDM) of the Kyoto Protocol.  INCaF will purchase CERs from DLHPPL and Ascent generated between 2001 and 2012.  INCaFs purchase will be approximately 90% of the total amount of CERs expected to be generated by the Project during the period from 2001 to 2012.

The Project comprises a package of six small- and mini-hydroelectric generation plants located in three states in India including: 
-  the construction of three greenfield mini-hydroelectric generation facilities in the state of Himachal Pradesh (Sechi, Melan and Panwi);
-  the acquisition, rehabilitation and refurbishment of an existing 34 MW facility in Maharashtra (BH II); 
-  an existing 12 MW operational facility in Maharashtra (BH I); and, 
-  the completion of a 2.2 MW mini-hydropower plant in Madhya Pradesh state (Birsingphur) currently under construction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IHDC DODSON LINDBLOM HYDRO POWER PVT LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-531872" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-12-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Shyam Vaidya
Managing Director
Bldg. No. 2 / RH -1
Visava Enclave
D.P.Road, Aundh
Pune  411 007
India

Phone: +91 020-2588-5235
Fax:  +91 020-2588-5234
E-mail: ahpl@vsnl.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The BH I project is located on Lake Arthur Hill Reservoir in the Upper Pravara River Basin in Maharashtra state. The nearest town, Ghoti, is 36 km away from the project site.  BH I was constructed in 1986 by the Government of Maharashtra Irrigation Department, and rehabilitated by the Sponsor upon acquisition in 1996.   

The BH II project is located 10 km downstream of BH I on the Pravara River in Maharashtra state.  BH II was constructed in 1999 and operated until today by the Government of Maharashtra Irrigation Department.  Upon acquisition of BH II, the Sponsor will rehabilitate and refurbish the project site.

Birsingphur project is located in the Umaria District, about 180 km northeast of the city of Jabalpur in the eastern part of the State of Madhya Pradesh.  The project is located within the fence of the Sanjay Gandhi Thermal Power Station, an 840 MW coal-fired power plant owned and operated by the Madhya Pradesh State Electricity Board.  The sponsor is finalizing construction of the Birsingphur plant and will start commercial operations shortly.

The three greenfield mini-hydro plants will be located in the state of Himachal Pradesh.  All are located in the mid-range Himalaya mountains at elevations of around 2,000 meters.  The climate is of the tropical monsoon nature, with a maximum summer temperature of around 30 degrees celsius and a minimum winter temperature below freezing.  The exact location of each project is:
-  Sechi: located on Sechi khad (stream), a tributary of the Sutlej river, near the village of Samej in the district of Shimla;
-  Melan: located on Melan khad, also a tributary of the Sutlej river, in the Kinnaur district; and,
- Panwi: located on the Panwi khad, also a tributary of the Sutlej river, very close to the Melan khad, in the Kinnaur district.  

Access roads to the Sechi and Panwi sites are via a state road and a bridge from a national highway, respectively.  Access to Melan is currently very limited; however, a bridge is being constructed by the Himachal Pradesh government which will provide adequate access to the project site.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">XX - Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/531872/incaf-ihdc-small-hydros">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
