<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9950</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SREI II International Finance Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    India  SREI II      RegionAsia and the Pacific   SectorFinancial Services   Project No009950   Projected Board DateMarch 31 2000   Company NameSREI International Finance   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    The Kanoria family, a joint business family from Calcutta, controls 50.6% of SREI International Finance, with rest of the ownership allocated among: IFC (9.1%), DEG (the German governments development agency)(3.5%), FMO (the Dutch governments development agency)(6.1%), domestic financial institutions and banks (14.3%), and non-resident Indians and the general public (16.4%). SREI International Finance is a publicly traded company in India.   The Kanoria family has been operating SREI since its inception in 1989 and has demonstrated a strong track record in efficiently managing the operations of the company.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    IFC Loan: US$10 million; IFC equity: US$5 million.    Location of project and Description of site    	SREI International Finance is headquartered Calcutta and has several offices throughout the country.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    SREI&apos;&apos;s primary area of business has been financing (under lease and hire/purchase arrangements) heavy construction equipment to infrastructure related projects. In addition, a small portion of SREI&apos;&apos;s business is in small and medium scale infrastructure project financing and this segment is expected to represent a larger share of the company&apos;&apos;s future business volume.    The project consists of making available a credit facility of US$10 million and an investment of up to US$ 5 million in subordinated bonds (with warrants) issued by SREI. The purpose of the funding is to allow SREI to further expand its small and medium scale infrastructure finance activities in the power, transportation and port sectors. The need to develop Indias infrastructure sector, to underpin the ongoing economic liberalization efforts as well as to ensure sustained economic growth and export expansion, is today widely recognized. The demand for infrastructure investment is expected to grow substantially as the process of industrial modernization accelerates and urbanization continues. A major constraint on private infrastructure investment, however, has been the lack of necessary market mechanisms to provide funds in terms of maturity, structure, and volume required. This is true not only of the larger infrastructure projects, but also small to medium sized projects, which are wholly dependent on local financial institutions for financing, particularly for debt financing. SREI is one of the few private financial institutions in India that have been engaged in financing assets in the infrastructure sector.	    	     Environmental Category and Issues   	   This is a category FI type 2 project according to IFCs environmental review procedure. SREI has committed to continuing to operate their environmental management system that will ensure that investments are consistent with applicable host country environmental laws and regulations as well as applicable World Bank Group environmental, health and safety guidelines and policies; confirming that appropriate individuals who will have responsibility for environment; attending IFCs environmental management workshops; submitting an environmental management plan; ensuring that category A projects are cleared by IFCs Environment Division; and submitting an annual environmental performance report   	       Date SPI sent to Infoshop     February 25, 2000      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SREI INTERNATIONAL LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9950" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-06-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-07-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LB - Leasing Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $14.98 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-06-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-06-13">14980000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-06-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-06-13">14980000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SREI INTERNATIONAL LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9950/srei-ii-international-finance-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
