<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-42834</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suguna III Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Greater farmer incomes: The most significant, expected Project-level outcome is the impact on the incomes of poultry farmers who participate in Suguna&apos;s outgrower (contract farming) model or use the Group&apos;s inputs for independent poultry production. 
2. Increased consumer access to affordable and high quality food products: Depending on how the final product composition evolves as a result of the Project to what is currently available in the market, consumers may benefit from increased access to high-quality, affordable poultry products. 
3. Market creation: At the market level, the Project is expected to contribute to integrating farmers into the poultry value chain by transferring its experience and business model to Bangladesh and advancing the sophistication of contract farming in this underdeveloped market through demonstration and replication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The group of companies known as the Suguna Group consolidated under the holding company Suguna Holdings Private Limited (SHPL or the Group or Suguna) was initially established in 1984 and is one of the leading poultry integrators in India with operations covering all areas of the poultry sector. Sugunas fully integrated operations cover broiler and layer farming, hatcheries, feed mills, and processing plants across 20 Indian states and one union territory, and have an overseas presence in Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, and Kenya. The main operating company under SHPL is Suguna Foods Private Limited (SFPL) in India, which generates over 97% of the Groups revenues.   Suguna is planning (i) a capacity expansion consisting of the construction of poultry infrastructure including potentially a hatchery, processing plant, poultry environment-controlled shed, premix plant, and related poultry assets, as well as incremental working capital financing, through a US$42.9 million investment at SFPL in India to further expand its operations in northern and eastern India, primarily in Uttar Pradesh, Odisha and West Bengal; and (ii) the construction of feed mills, breeders, and hatcheries in Bangladesh and Kenya through a US$15.9 million investment in Suguna Food and Feeds Bangladesh Pvt. Ltd. (SFFBPL) in Bangladesh and a US$8.4 million investment in Suguna Poultry (Kenya) Limited (SPKL) in Kenya in order to capitalize on the growing economy and expanding poultry sector in both countries, for a total overall investment across India, Bangladesh, and Kenya of US$67.2 million (the Project)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUGUNA HOLDINGS PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-42834" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  1020, Avinashi Road, II floor, Above AUDI Showroom, Coimbatore 641018 India</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suguna Holdings Private Limited  Deepak M. Row  Vice President, Finance and Strategy  +91-422-4346939  deepak@sugunaholdings.com  1020, Avinashi Road, II floor, Above AUDI Showroom, Coimbatore 641018 India  www.sugunaholdings.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SHPL headquarters is located at 1020, Avinashi Road, II floor, Above AUDI Showroom, Coimbatore 641018 India. The Project is expected to be carried out at the following locations:  &#xA0;  SFPL:   Suguna Foods Private Limited, Plot No - 19,20 &amp; 21, Jayamangal Industrial Area, Khurda - Tahasil, Dist - Khordha, Odisha  752101, India  Suguna Foods Private Limited, Plot No. - A - 13 &amp; A - 14,&#xA0;Panagarh industrial Park,&#xA0;Panagarh,Dist - Burdwan, West Bengal  713148, India  Suguna Foods Private Limited, Plot No. - 201, 202, 203, 205 &amp; 206, MK Road, Deotala Village, Gazole PS, Malda Dt, West Bengal -732124, India   Suguna Foods Private Limited, Plot No. - LR / 1355, 1356, 1363, Ratanpur, Onda, Bankura - Dist West Bengal  722152, India  Gorakhpur Industrial Development Authority, Plot No. F-6, 15 GIDA, Jidiyan, Thasil, Sahajanwa, Gorakhpur, Uttar Pradesh  273209, India   &#xA0;  SFFBPL:   Breeder Farm: Suguna Paitapukur Project, Bamlahal, Paitapukur, Dag RS 1101, 1123, 1125, 1127 &amp; 1125, Post Office Chobbishnogor, 6000, Thana/Upazilla Godagari, Rajshahi, Bangladesh  Breeder Farm: Suguna Narayanpur Project, Narayanpur, Uchadanga Narayanpur, Dag RS 394, 1119, 1120, 1122, 1123, 1124, 1125, 1126 JL: 61, Post Office Kharikulla Narayanpurrman, 6311, Thana/Upazilla Tanore, Rajshahi, Bangladesh  Feedmill: Mirzapur, Mirzapur under 5 No. Mirzapur Union (Ward-07), Dag 371, 372, 373, 369, 378, 354, 359, 361, 360, 358, 351, 352, 353, 347, 348, 382, 384, 385, 386, 415, 381, 362, 379, 380, 383, Post Office Mirzapur, 5840, Thana/Upazilla Sherpur, Bogra, Bangladesh    &#xA0;  SPKL:    Breeder Land: Plot L.R. No. Kjd/Ildamat/9448, Off Namanga Road, Kajiado, Kajiado County, Kenya   Feedmill Land: Plot L.R. No. 7240/480, Near Shell Petrol Station, Thika Garissa Road, Thika, Kiambu County, Kenya  Interim Feedmill at Thika: NEW OSHWAL DISTRIBUTORS LIMITED, Go Down Numbers 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 and 9, On Title Number: Thika Municipality Block 13/318, Thika, Kiambu Country, Kenya</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="112" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A-BB - Poultry Farming</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $53.92 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/42834">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/42834">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
