<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26609</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rain CDG Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Development Impact: 

This transaction complements the development outcomes achieved out of IFCs previous project with Rain, which eliminated the primary use of fossil fuels by the Companys operations.  The single largest development impact of the transaction is that over the five year transaction horizon, the generation of an estimated 825,000 tonnes of carbon dioxide equivalent will be eliminated, while a total of 2.5 million tonnes of carbon dioxide will be eliminated assuming an estimated 15 year life of the project.  Through supporting an Indian company gain access to carbon finance in the way this transaction is structured, the project could encourage similar deals with local companies.

- World Bank Group Strategy: 

The project is compatible with the overall WBG and IFC strategy to support the development of competitive local industry in India. In particular, the proposed transaction is consistent with IFCs approach to Climate Change by helping reduce greenhouse gases and expanding the market for carbon finance.  

The World Bank Group Country Assistance Strategy (CAS) for India aims to strengthen the enabling environment for sustainable privatesector-led growth and support critical interventions of special benefit to the poor and disadvantaged. To support these objectives, the World Bank Group will concentrate its assistance on improving government effectiveness and on promoting private sector-led growth by:

- Facilitating greater competitiveness through: 

improvements in the investment climate;
improved financial intermediation to the private sector; and
direct support to firms to promote sustainable growth and competitiveness;

- Improving the quality and quantity of infrastructure through greater private sector participation; 
- Promoting the provision of private health services; and 
- Improving rural productivity and growth through greater private sector investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed transaction involves providing an IFC Carbon Delivery Guarantee (CDG) for Certified Emissions Reduction Credits (CERs) generated by Rain Calcining Limited (Rain or the company).  Rain is based in Vishakhapatnam in Andhra Pradesh, India with an installed CPC capacity of 600,000 tons per annum (tpa).  Rain has been an IFC client since the companys inception in 1993-94.  In 2004, IFC financed Rains expansion, which involved establishing a new 300,000 tpa kiln and associated facilities, doubling the Companys CPC capacity.  A significant added benefit from this project was that waste heat from the new kiln could be used to eliminate Rains dependence on fossil fuel for power generation, leading to CERs.  In 2007, Rain&apos;s CER project was registered with the Clean Development Mechanism Executive Board with an annual baseline GHG emissions reduction estimated at about 164,000 tonnes of carbon dioxide equivalent.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RAIN CII CARBON (VIZAG) LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26609" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-12-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-07-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N. Jagan Mohan Reddy, Managing Director
Rain Calcining Limited 
Srinagar Colony; &quot;Rain Center&quot; 34 
Hyderabad, 
Andhra Pradesh 500073
India

Telephone: +91 40 40 40 1244
Fax: +91 40 40 40 1214

The Environmental documents will be placed at two locations.  

- The companys plant: Scindia Road, Naval Base (P.O.); Visakhapatnam  530 014 A.P.  India;
- District Library; Marritatnam; Visakhapatnam, A.P.  India.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Rain facility is located on a 42.5-acre site, in the Visakhapatnam Port Area. The site is approximately three kilometers from the deep water dock where green petroleum coke, the main feedstock,  is discharged and export shipments of calcined petroleum coke are loaded.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Other Petroleum and Coal Products</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $39.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-12-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-12-18">39000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-12-18">39000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RAIN CII CARBON (VIZAG) LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26609/rain-cdg-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
