<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kanoria Chem</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kanoria, which was established in 1960 to set up production facilities of chlor alkali chemicals, has since diversified into other specialty chemicals such as alcohol chemicals and various chlorine derivatives.  As a result, over the years, Kanoria developed a strong manufacturing capability and integrated production facilities in Renukoot, Uttar Pradesh and Ankleshwar, Gujarat.    The company is now in the process of increasing the production capacity of its caustic soda and chlorine derivative products to improve its profitability and growth while better serving the increasing needs of its growing customer base.  In addition, the company plans to invest over $25 million to gradually reduce production of caustic soda based on mercury cell technology by increasing production based on more environment friendly membrane cell technology. The company also has plans to finally phase out its mercury-cell based caustic soda capacity and replace it with more environmentally friendly membrane-cell based technology over the next few years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment plan is expected to assist Kanorias efforts to become more internationally competitive by improving the companys operational efficiencies, rationalizing its capacities to meet market demand and achieve economies of scale.  Specifically, the following developmental benefits are expected to be achieved:   - Sustainability Impact:   The replacement of the companys mercury cell plant with a significantly more environmentally friendly membrane cell plant, in addition to the upgrading of the companys health and safety practices, would be among the benefits realized by the company.  The companys shareholders and management have developed a time table to eliminate mercury cell technology from its operations.  In addition, this conversion will have additional positive environmental impacts since the new membrane cell plant will be about 20% more energy efficient than the mercury cell plant.  Moreover, over time the companys need to handle and sell liquid chlorine is also expected to reduce.   - Community Engagement:    Kanoria is active in various community and social development programs.  The increased financial stability afforded by the IFC financing should enable the company to afford to continue with such efforts.  - Local Expenditures:  The company sources a significant amount of materials and other services from local sources.  As the company and its operations grow, such purchases from local suppliers and service providers should also increase.  - Preserving Employment: The company currently employs 1,055 salaried employees and an additional 1,295 contract workers.  The IFC financing is expected to help the company preserve jobs in a competitive and capital intensive industry.  The key development indicators that are proposed to be monitored during the life of the IFC investment are:   - reduction in amount of mercury sludge discharged;  - reduction in amount of liquid chlorine sold;  - annual spending on local SME suppliers;  - annual spending on/implementation of community and social development programs; and  - direct employment levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KANORIA CHEMICALS AND INDUSTRIES LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25015" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-04-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-04-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. N. K. Nolkha, Chief Financial Officer Kanoria Chemicals &amp; Industries Ltd. Park Plaza, 71 Park Street Kolkata 700016 India Telephone:  +91 33 2249 9472 Fax:  +91 33 2249 9466    ESRS (Environmental and Social Review Summary) and the summary of the same is available at the website of IFC and will also be available at following address of KCIL for perusal from 19.03.2007 to 18.04.2007 between 10.00 AM to 5.00 PM on working days.        Local Address:  Renukoot Chemical Works P.O. Renukoot  231 217, Dist. Sonebhadra, Uttar Pradesh INDIA. Phone: +91 5446 52044 Fax: +91 5446 52088</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The company plans to invest up to $35 million in capacity expansion in its caustic soda plant at Renukoot. The capacity of this plant was expanded recently to 90,000 tonnes per annum (tpa) and it will further go up to 130,000 tpa after the implementation of the proposed investment, which is scheduled to be completed by March 2008. The key demand driver for caustic soda is the aluminum industry in eastern India which is undergoing significant expansion resulting in increase in demand for caustic soda from the current 280,000 tpa to more than 800,000 tpa in the next 5 years.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BA - Alkalies and Chlorine</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-04-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-04-26">15000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-04-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-04-26">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-04-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-04-26">15000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KANORIA CHEMICALS AND INDUSTRIES LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-04-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-04-26">5000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KANORIA CHEMICALS AND INDUSTRIES LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25015/kanoria-chem">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
