<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28571</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCIL CPLP Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Carbon India Limited (CCIL) is a leading carbon black manufacturer in India. CCILs manufacturing facility is located in Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India and the Company sells its carbon black to tire and non tire companies across the country. The Company also operates a 15MW waste heat recovery power plant and sells the power to the national grid. To become more competitive, the Company has embarked on several cost reduction initiatives to improve its operational and financial performance. The proposed Project is one of these many initiatives.  This Project consists of four (4) individual sub-projects including the installation and commissioning of new reactors, air blowing and drying systems. These sub-projects will reduce costs and increase productivity of both the carbon black and the power production. They include the installation of: i) a highly energy efficient air blower that will reduce the oil consumption and provide a spare for existing Hard Black side process air blower, avoiding production loss; ii) an improved carcass reactor that will reduce electrical and thermal energy consumption during the conversion process; and iii) two smoke drying systems that will reduce the need for waste gas from the dryer now used to dry wet carbon black pellets, gas which will then be used for steam and power generation.  Total expected annual cost savings is $2.2 million.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Project supports cleaner production at the CCIL plant, which makes more efficient the use of inputs such as raw materials, energy and water along the chain of production. It results in cost savings and environmental benefits with fewer waste and lower CO2 emissions. The Project will also generate a few new employment opportunities during the implementation phase.     The key development indicators that are proposed to be monitored during the life of the IFC investment are:     - Annual electricity savings - Annual oil savings - Reduction in emissions - Loss reduction/ productivity increase - Power generation increase  The Project fits well with the objective of CPLP to finance CP investments that provide quantifiable cost saving benefits and positively impact the environment. This reduction in cost will enable the company to remain competitive in an industry where higher production cost have squeezed margins, and maintain its level of operations and of employment, as well as its current clientele. It will also provide incremental carbon black sales from the improved efficiency of its operations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTINENTAL CARBON INDIA LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28571" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-06-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Rakesh Dhamani Chief Financial Officer  Continental Carbon India Limited     T: +91 120 2840505 ext 331 F: +91 120 2840504</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project will be implemented at the carbon black plant located in Ghaziabad, State of Uttar Pradesh, India. Uttar Pradesh (UP) has the highest population of any state in Indian (190 million people). UP is also one of the poorest states. Between 1999 and 2008, the economy grew only 4.4% per year, one of the lowest rates in India. In 2003-4 per capita income was $212, less than half that of national per capita income of $450. Over the past decade, UPs GDP growth has significantly lagged behind the All-India averages, as well as the averages for the 16 major states. UPs per capita income only grew at 3.1%, one of the lowest in all major states, while the national average was 8.6%.     The Project includes the installation of: i) a highly energy efficient air blower that will reduce the oil consumption and provide a spare for existing Hard Black side process air blower, avoiding production loss; ii) an improved carcass reactor that will reduce electrical and thermal energy consumption during the conversion process; and iii) two smoke drying systems that will reduce the need for waste gas from the dryer now used to dry wet carbon black pellets, gas which will then be used for steam and power generation. Total expected annual cost savings is $2.2 million</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC - Carbon Black</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-06-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-06-16">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-06-16">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTINENTAL CARBON INDIA LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28571/ccil-cplp-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
