<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28199</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Granules CPLP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Granules India Limited (Granules) is a leading Contract Manufacturing Organization (CMO) supplying high volume Active Pharmaceutical Ingredients (APIs) and Pharmaceutical Formulation Intermediates (PFIs) to the bulk over-the-counter (OTC) drugs industry in the U.S., Europe, Latin America, Australia and India. Paracetamol (used in Tylenol and Panadol brand names in the U.S. and Europe, respectively) and ibuprofen (Advil and Motrin) are the companys main products, but it also supplies the industry with guaifenesin (ultimately used in cough medications) and metformin (anti-diabetes drug ingredient).  The company has four production units in three locations in the vicinity of Hyderabad, in south India. Granules management and IFCs industry specialist have identified a number of energy and water efficiency projects, including solvent recovery as well as cleaner production improvements at the companys Jeedimetla API facility, which will have beneficial environmental impacts (together, the Cleaner Production project). For example, the company will recover more of the steam and condensate used in production and recycle them, thereby reducing its energy and water intake. Variable Frequency Drives (VFDs) and appropriate scaling of certain motors and cooling towers will further contribute to the companys energy efficiency and bottom line.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project benefits are described in detail below:  Energy and Water Efficiency:   Condensate recovery: Steam is used in operations, and then condensed into water. This is pure, distilled water which should be re-used completely. After proposed modification, the overall water consumption would be reduced but the cooling tower efficiency would also improve and boiler efficiency would increase;    Replacement of oversized motors  it is energy-inefficient to use motors that are too large for the equipment they serve;    Installation of VFDs  these will automatically reduce the electricity current drawn by the engine when its load is reduced, saving on energy costs;    Replacement of cooling towers: The cooling towers are not operating efficiently. The water temperature is 40 C. If it is brought down to 30 C, as designed, the batch times would be reduced due to faster cooling and hence energy used in agitation, centrifuge and pumping would be reduced. Additionally, cooling water circulation rate would reduce and one cooling water circulation pump can be shut off. Also, by isolating the tower that takes water from vacuum pumps, any solvent contamination can be restricted to that tower only and can be easily treated.  Solvent Recovery from reactors and waste water can be improved by a more efficient process of chilling vapor at normal pressure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GRANULES INDIA LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28199" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-05-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bhaskar Krishna Arumugam, Chief Operating Officer  Granules India Limited My Home Hub Second Floor, Block III Madhapur Cyberabad Hyderabad- 500 081  +91-40-6676-0000 www.granulesindia.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Established in 1994, the Jeedimetla facility has been built as a multi-product facility. At this facility several APIs and PFIs have been commercialized over the last few years. This site meets the latest WHO cGMP standards and has been inspected by US FDA, Australian TGA &amp; German HA. The facility is in an industrial development area about 25 km from the citys railway station.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FA - Pharmaceuticals and Medicine</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-05-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-05-29">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-05-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-05-29">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GRANULES INDIA LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28199/granules-cplp">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
