<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-36727</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Warehousing Corporation (Nhava Seva) Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continental Warehousing Corporation (Nhava Sheva) Limited (CWC or the Company) is a leading owner and operator of cargo handling facilities engaged in logistics management, and cargo handling in container freight stations (CFS), inland container depots (ICDs) and multimodal cargo handling terminals (MMTs)/private freight terminals (PFTs) in India.  Currently, CWC has five operational facilities  four CFS (at Chennai, Tuticorin and Mumbai) and one MMT (in Hyderabad). Two new MMTs are expected to be operational in Calendar Year 2016 at Ahmedabad and Panipat. The main operations at the CFS include bonded warehouse storage, export-import warehouse storage and dispatch (unloading from cleared containers and stuffing of containers after clearance), customs clearance and open yard storage and handling (for steel, stones, etc. depending upon the goods handled and client relationships).    Additionally, the MMTs have a rail yard and domestic warehousing space.  The operations at the MMT primarily involve: (i) loading/unloading of containers/other cargo from trains and the associated operations; (ii) movement of road transport vehicles/trucks and container railway trains; (iii) receipt and dispatch of containers in the terminal area; (iv) storage of containers and also loading of containers; (v) storage of cargo in the warehouse and dispatches; (vi) maintenance of equipment; and (vii) other activities such as office/administrative functions. The Company has five subsidiaries: (a) Delex Cargo India Private Limited (DELEX) (100% owned by CWC): DELEX provides third party logistics (3PL), express cargo (surface and air) and air cargo sales handling services. As part of the 3PL services, it provides warehousing, intra-city last mile delivery technical logistical and bulk material management services. The express cargo business is mainly door-to-door domestic parcel deliveries through air and surface for large corporates. DELEX is also the General Sales Agent (GSA) and General Handling Agent (GHA) for one of the airlines.  (b) Continental Multimodal Terminals Limited (CMTL) (95% owned by CWC): CMTL operates its MMT at Hyderabad.  (c) Chetana Multitrade Private Limited (CMPL) (100% owned by CWC): CMPL was hitherto 100% subsidiary of India Infrastructure And Logistics Private Limited (IILPL), which was acquired by CWC in 2013. CMPL has currently no operations, however, it owns land in Panipat. It was earlier envisaged to use the land for CWCs expansion plans. However, as CWC has since acquired additional land adjacent to existing MMT in Panipat, CWC is in the process of selling the shares in the company.  (d) Huma Multitrade Private Limited (HMPL) (100% owned by CWC): HMPL was also a 100% subsidiary of IILPL and thus was acquired by CWC in 2013. Like CMPL, HMPL also does not have any operations but owns land in Panipat. CWC is in the process of selling the shares in HMPL as well.   (e) Continental Mega Food Park Private Limited td (CMFPPL) (100% owned by CWC): CMFPPL was incorporated in 2014 for setting up a Mega Food Park within the CWCs MMT facility in Panipat under Government of Indias (GoIs) scheme for Mega Food Park. CMFPPL awaits formal sanction from the GoI for the establishment of the Food Park. Under this food park, CMFPPL will develop grain silos, warehouses, cold storages and grain processing (mainly rice polishing and packing) facility within the MMT in Panipat which will be leased for three to five years.  As the developer of the food park, CMFPPL will also be responsible to provide common infrastructure including power supply, water supply and treatment, wastewater treatment plant, roads and back-up power through diesel generator sets.  CWC plans to expand its network of operating assets by (i) adding MMT cargo handling facilities at two locations in India; and (ii) adding nine express logistics centers (for DELEX operations) with 1.5 million square feet of rack space at key locations across India over the next 2 years at a cost of US$90 million to strengthen its distribution capabilities (the Project).  Post implementation of the project, CWC will have a network of four CFSs and five MMT facilities with distribution capabilities across all key locations in the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFC is expected to have the following development impact through this investment: - Support for a developing sector: Increased freight movement on railways is a key initiative for the new Government as it will improve logistics activities in the country and boost economic growth. This investment will help fund multimodal cargo handling facilities that will handle both domestic and EXIM cargo. - Demonstration effect: The investment in the railway logistics sector will have a positive demonstration effect in developing this sector and attract more private capital. - Building competiveness: Currently, the Indian logistics sector is dominated by 2-3 major players. This investment will strengthen the competitive advantage of an emerging logistics player and provide for a diversified competitor landscape.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTINENTAL WAREHOUSING CORPORATION (NHAVA SEVA) PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-36727" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Address: Continental Warehousing Corporation (Nhava Seva) Ltd., 404, Samarpan Complex, Chakala,  Andheri (East), Mumbai  400099, India. Phone: +91 22 61116999 Email:  mailto:ramdas@cwcnsl.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Name: Mr. Suresh Periasamy Address: Continental Warehousing Corporation (Nhava Seva) Ltd. 404, Samarpan Complex, Chakala  Andheri (East), Mumbai  400 099, India. Phone: +91 22 61116999 Email:  mailto:suresh@cwcnsl.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CWC is headquartered in Mumbai and the project will be located at a number of sites across India. These sites will be greenfield in nature and will be a combination of rural and urban sites.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="488" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-BD - Other Support Activities for Transportation (Grain Terminals, Cargo Terminals, Airport Operations)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $84.49 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-31">24850000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-31">59640000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-31">59640000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTINENTAL WAREHOUSING CORPORATION (NHAVA SEVA) PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-31">24850000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTINENTAL WAREHOUSING CORPORATION (NHAVA SEVA) PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/36727/continental-warehousing-corporation-nhava-seva-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/36727/continental-warehousing-corporation-nhava-seva-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
