<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11230</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mahindra Farm Services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Each ASC system will consist of the hub ASC and a number of related kiosks (spokes).  Each ASC will be able to provide farmers with: (i) appropriate inputs (seeds, fertilizers, chemicals); (ii) rental equipment; (iii) information (agronomic practices, market information); (iv) contractual farm-input-application and advisory services, and (v) access to crop finance from commercial banks all under a one-stop-shop concept. Each ASC will be staffed with qualified and suitably trained personnel who will transfer knowledge of good agricultural practices to farmers.     Developmental Impact:    The objective of MSSLs business model is to improve farming profitability and sustainability by increasing agricultural yields, reducing production costs and chemical pest control dependency. Current less-than-optimal production in India is attributable to the failure to integrate quality agriculture inputs, scientific farming techniques, mechanization, and finance. Indian farmers often do not trust existing input distribution channels because of the prevalence of poor business practices and spurious products. The public extension systems reach is limited and the contribution of the private sector is typically motivated by the sale of specific products. MSSLs intention is to become an agent for change in Indian agriculture through an integrated approach that will provide unbiased solutions oriented to individual farmer success.  Moreover, the project will benefit the health and well being of farmers and the environment by promoting integrated pest management (IPM) and non-chemical methods and informed management of chemical products.       Farmers will be able to access better and more appropriate and fair priced inputs, rental equipment, and extension services as well as assistance in marketing the crops through market information and brokerage services. Farmers will also have access to crop loans from  commercial banks at reasonable interest rates enabling investment in modern agricultural techniques and migration to higher value crops. These benefits are likely to spread to non-participating farmers as they will observe the yield improvement and will consequently modify their own crop management techniques.     The project is also expected to generate a substantial number of new jobs in rural areas. The venture is expected to cover 180 districts in India creating jobs for rural residents in the areas of agricultural extension, retailing, logistics, and farm equipment operations.  In almost all cases the local agricultural service center will employ staff and contractor from the vicinity of the project.       IFC&apos;&apos;s role       IFC&apos;&apos;s involvement in the project will assist the company to: (i) enhance its credibility for the expansion of the franchise and client base, (ii) help promote Integrated Pesticide Management plans to reduce the reliance on chemicals and use chemicals only when they are required; and (iii) gain from IFC knowledge/sources on global agri-trends and insights on successful agri-projects across the globe. In addition, IFC&apos;&apos;s participation as an equity investor is expected to provide comfort to potential investors when the Company goes public in the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MAHINDRA AGRI SOLUTIONS LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11230" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-03-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-08-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mahindra ShubhLabh Services Limited    3rd Floor Mahindra Towers    Worli, Mumbai - 400 018   Phone: 022-389-6824   Fax: 022-389-6109</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN-India">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSSL, headquartered in Mumbai, plans to develop 180 Agricultural Service Centers (ASC) in India&apos;&apos;s major agro-climatic areas. To further penetrate the local markets, up to 10 internet-based kiosks will be set up around each center. The regions and general locations for the establishment of agri-centers have been strategically selected. One hundred and fifteen will be located in the northern states and sixty-five in the southern states. Currently, two farm centers are operating in four districts (Madurai, Tiruvarur, Nagappattinam, Thanjavur) in Tamil Nadu state; one farm center in one district (Nalgonda) in Andhra Pradesh state; two farm centers in three districts (Kota, Bundi and Alwar) in Rajasthan state; and two farm centers in two districts (Raichur and Kopal) in Karnataka state. In addition to this four more centers, at Tirunelveli district - Tamil Nadu State, Davangere district - Karnataka State, Nagaur and Jaipur districts - Rajasthan State, will be operational soon.  All of the centers are and will be located in rural areas in small towns and villages. The sites are on rural roads - in general on agricultural or commercial land.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.0000000000 79.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AJ - Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $2.20 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2003-03-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2003-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-03-27">2200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2003-03-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-03-27">2200000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MAHINDRA AGRI SOLUTIONS LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11230/mahindra-farm-services">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
