<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-16/DDA-3482/R/FSL/UN/2339</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urgent shortfalls in the joint UNRWA-WFP food assistance programme serving Bedouins and herders in Area C.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2009, WFP and UNRWA have provided jointly regular food distribution to approximately 30,000 people, in 85 localities across Area C of the West Bank. The assistance aims at protecting and assisting vulnerable herding and Bedouin communities, both Palestine refugees and non-refugees, to maintain their livelihood and way of life in the face of political and environmental challenges.

Territorial fragmentation continues in the West Bank and herding and Bedouin communities living in Area C face increasing movement restrictions, limiting access to range land and natural water resources. The Israeli occupation, expansion of illegal settlements, and displacement of Palestinian communities over the past decade, combined with difficult environment conditions, have forced herding and Bedouin communities in Area C to rely on bought fodder and tinkered water, which is unsustainable. 

The access of the herding and Bedouin communities to basic humanitarian assistance is hampered by Israeli policies and practices which include demolitions that target homes as well as livelihood structures such as animal pens and water cisterns and confiscation of humanitarian aid from shelter repair materials to community kindergarten equipment. As a result, herding and Bedouin communities in Area C are falling deeper into poverty and debt. Food insecurity is particularly high among the communities living in Area C (26%) compared with the other areas of the West Bank (17%).

Food assistance that WFP and UNRWA provide together offsets the economic losses incurred due to limited grazing lands and a reduced number of animals being raised. It enables communities to continue their way of life on their land, and supports enhanced food consumption, particularly for women and children in the communities. 

The project ensures all families in targeted communities receive a quarterly parcel of food comprised of wheat flour, lentils, chickpeas, oil and salt. Food commodities are supplied by WFP while UNRWA provides logistical support for internal transportation and distribution. WFP monitor and report on the project. 

With the absence of a political solution, this project is one of the few reliable, predictable forms of assistance the international community has been able to provide to these vulnerable communities that are facing imminent threats of forced displacement. Along with addressing food security concerns, the project provides regular UN presence and a gateway for other support the international community is providing - including legal support, health, education and social services. The importance of the project goes beyond the food security benefits and contributes to building community resilience and has secondary impacts on livelihoods, access to services and protection for a particularly vulnerable population facing political and environmental challenges. 

The joint WFP-UNRWA food assistance to herding and Bedouin communities in Area is integral to WFP`s protracted Relief and Recovery Operation (200709) &apos;Food Assistance for Food-Insecure Populations in the West Bank and Gaza Strip&apos; &#x2013; which aims to meet immediate humanitarian needs while facilitating early recovery and longer-term food security for vulnerable and food insecure non-refugees. The project fully aligns with the Social Protection Sector Strategic Plan and the National Development Plan for 2014-2016. WFP`s interventions are part of the Palestine Food Security Sector, of which three Palestinian line ministries, namely the Ministry of Agriculture, the Ministry of Planning and the Ministry of Social Affairs, are members. They are in line with UN Humanitarian Country Team procedures, the overall inter-agency appeal priorities, as specified in the Humanitarian Needs Overview and Humanitarian Country Plan documents. Funding for this project is appealed for by WFP in the 2016 Humanitarian Response Plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daniela Owen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP Representative and Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+972 (0)54 677 3150</telephone>
   <email>daniela.owen@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-04">200256.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-2339">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-04">200256.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301673897">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-24">200256.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
