<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-16/DDA-3482/oPt/PROT/INGO/3125</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Structured, multi-sectoral, safe, confidential, life-saving prevention and protection GBV services provision in Bedouin Communities of Area C through mobile clinics assistance, home visits and HelpLine (focus on legal aid and documentation and monitoring of violations)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">APS proposes to support GBV survivors in 5 isolated Bedouin communities located in Area C of the West Bank suffering high rates of GBV, alarmingly increased as a direct consequence of the most recent escalation of violence in October across oPt.  The proposed project is focus on enhancing and strengthening the GBV multi-sectoral response in two specific components: (i) provision of legal aid need-based services (specialized counselling for GBV survivors -for adults and for children based on their different needs-, legal accompaniment through the legal process, court file preparation, referral and monitoring of legal-administrative and court proceedings) accessible for the beneficiaries through the mobile clinics, home visits and GVB Helpline and (ii) monitoring and documentation of violations of grave GBV conflict-related violations through a standardized data system, supporting CBOs to boost their capacities in accurately collection of relevant data, documentation and monitoring of IHL violations for the purpose of increasing the accountability channels. While it has been proven that the GBV multi-sectoral emergency response cannot be defragmented to effectively assist the needs of the GBV survivors (to be able to seek accountability for violations and have the strength to go through a legal process, they require to prior cover their SRH needs and deal with stigma and trauma through PSS specialized support), APS is already providing SHR and PSS support on the targeted communities. Thus, the emergency intervention under the proposed intervention seeks to assist uncovered urgent needs of the multi-sectoral GBV response on the legal component, crucial to immediately address and increase the accountability gap for the Bedouin population (and specifically women and girls) systematically suffering IHL and IHRL violations. Throughout the legal aid and documentation processes, GBV survivors continue to have access to psychosocial support: this emotional and social support is essential for survivors pursuing the complex process of legal justice and it is also crucial to mitigate the potential risk of backlash given the sensitive nature of the subject. If the humanitarian intervention proposed could not be implemented that would mean that the GBV multisectoral response would remain unaddressed and defragmented, being harsher for GBV survivors to overcome trauma for the IHL and IHRL violations suffered, as having the chance to claim accountability and redress though legal counselling and representation as well as through the documentation of violations is an essential part of the recovery process for them. Legal aid is a critical and necessary element to ensure an adequate and multi-sectoral GBV approach to be successful in aiding survivors to maintain their safety and to seek accountability and obtain justice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAWA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marta Gil</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 972 (0) 527994764</telephone>
   <email>mgil@aporslidaridad.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-12">50064.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-12">24621.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-3125">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-12">74686.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301997459">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-21">74686.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIANZA POR LA SOLIDARIDAD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
