<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-16/DDA-3482/R/PROT/NGO/2336</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Rapid Psycho Social Support for Conflict Affected Children and Adults in Hebron.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The political violence that started at a flashpoint in Jerusalem in September 2015 shows no signs of abating, and proves to persist longer than expected, with an upward wave of violence that continue to impact thousands of Palestinians throughout the West Bank. Daily aggressions, hostilities and increased restrictions by the Israeli army and settlers against Palestinians swirl to fuel and lead to further violence. 

In light of the perpetuated violations of human rights against Palestinians since September 2015, the protection of children and adolescents remains substantial to the immediate and long term psychosocial and physical well being of the Palestinians in general, and for the community in Hebron in particular, a focal point of violent unrest, that witnessed the highest number of causalities since September 2015. A sharp increase have been witnessed in the settlers&#x2019; violence over the past few months, the unlawful killing, forced displacements, arrest and torture, limited access to services, have all taken a toll on the coping mechanisms and psycho-social well being of thousands of Hebronites. Particular areas in Hebron such as the Old City (H-2), areas and villages nearby the settlements, are even more vulnerable to higher insecurities. While the escalation of violence affected almost every person in Hebron including women, men and youth differently, the parents and families who are impacted by the killing of a family member, the young men and women who were arrested and tortured by the Israeli army and the schools&#x2019; children and teachers in schools located in intense conflict zones are probably the most affected. With no doubt, there is a lack of proper protection measures from ongoing military activities and settlers&#x2019; violence while mobility to access psycho social support services remains remarkably limited. 

The proposed project aims at empowering a vulnerable population of families impacted by the killing of a family member, ex-detainee children and their families, paraprofessionals (teachers and school counselors) and school children in 8 schools in the most impacted areas in Hebron. The project will provide the target groups with rapid empowerment and protection services that address the immediate needs for psychological support and counseling stress management and stress release such immensely needed services that will serve as entry points for providing initial and immediate psycho social support. 20 families (comprising of around 100 family members) will be provided with family intervention that will include psychological support and family counseling for direct family members. When needed, family members will be referred to more specialized individual counseling and psychological assistance. 50 ex-detainee children will be provided with post trauma rehabilitation services including group counseling, academic and vocational rehabilitation services that will facilitate their re-integration and put them on the right track. Additionally, the project will serve around 1000 children, 200 paraprofessionals (teachers and schools counselors) in 8 schools located in areas that are highly impacted by settlers and military violence. The schools are governmental schools nominated by the Ministry of Education to be provided with psychological support, stress management and stress release activities for staff and children. The project will work on supporting the staff and improving their competencies in stress management and protection related issues within the framework of their work and intervention with children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Men&apos;s Christian Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Men&apos;s Christian Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghada Ghabboun</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+970 2 277 2713</telephone>
   <email>gghabboun@ej-ymca.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.98598100 35.29994700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-11-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-07">137462.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6303752422">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-08">33938.96</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Men&apos;s Christian Association</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-2336">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-07">137462.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Men&apos;s Christian Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301791864">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-12">68731.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Men&apos;s Christian Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302164305">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-23">68731.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Men&apos;s Christian Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
