<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-19/UKR_CBPF/SA1/P-FSL/INGO/13730</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building resilience of vulnerable conflict-affected individuals in 7 isolated settlements in Bakhmutskyi and Volnovaskyi rayons in Donetska oblast and Novoaidarskyi and Stanichno-Luhanskyi rayons in Luhanska oblast to withstand harsh winter months through provision of community-based home care, Cash for Work and electronic food  vouchers.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to reduce acute multiple vulnerabilities of conflict-affected populations in isolated settlements during winter months through a comprehensive emergency support and strengthened local capacity. It seeks to provide multi-sectoral assistance to vulnerable people including elderly and persons with disabilities in seven isolated settlements along the contact line not covered by the government social protection scheme, including in Zaitseve, Bakhmutskyi rayon Starohnativka, Volnovaskyi rayon of Donetska oblast, Kriakivka, Krymske and Shchastia, Novoaidarskyi rayon and Heivka and Stary Aidar in Stanichno-Luhansky rayon of Luhanska oblast.
Within the proposed project, capacity of 180 vulnerable community members will be built to provide peer-to-peer vital home-based care to 900 elderly and persons with disabilities during critical winter months. The proposed project created synergies between the different project components in which protection home-based care activities will be provided by other vulnerable community members participating in Cash for Work activities under the Food Security component. By engaging and strengthening capacity of community-based volunteers, the majority of whom are women, the project will enable local communities to address protection concerns of isolated vulnerable people while providing short-term employment to other vulnerable individuals in the same settlements. The local capacity built within the project will become a resource for the reinforcement of social cohesion within these communities.
To build resilience of project beneficiaries and maintain their food security levels which drop during winters due to seasonal increase in food needs, food electronic vouchers (e-vouchers) will be provided to 1080 beneficiaries for three winter months. E-vouchers will be provided in cooperation with 4 TGH partner shops located in project locations who will ensure home deliveries to vulnerable beneficiaries.
The TGH innovative e-voucher modality implemented on the basis of mobile phones and web money allows reaching remote locations along the contact line often not covered by aid projects. The modality proved to be cost-efficient, appropriate and comfortable for beneficiaries and shops, and allows for real-time monitoring and informed decision-making (See details on the e-voucher modality in Annex).
The proposed project is based on previous TGH projects implemented within 2017-2019 and takes into account potential risks and suggests the following mitigation measures:
 Access to isolated communities is restricted by local authorities: TGH collaborates closely with local authorities and communities, has access to all project locations and will continue implementing extensive acceptance measures to sustain good relations.  
 Community volunteers do not have motivation to participate in the project: To mitigate the risk, Cash for Work modality is envisaged with remuneration adequate to ensure maintenance of food security levels at required level. Besides, food e-vouchers will be provided to enhance their resilience. 
 Inadequate provision of home-based care: The risk is low as the project will engage motivated individuals recommended by community members. Implementation of work plans and provision of services will be closely monitored by TGH.
 Local shops fail to deliver relevant services: Results of PDM from TGH projects demonstrate 99% satisfaction by services provided by partner shops. In case of risk, TGH will assign beneficiaries to neighbouring shops and ensure home deliveries if required.
TGH employs 12 staff members including dedicated Programme Logistics, Finance and Administrative teams based in Kramatorsk, has experience in implementing similar projects in isolated settlements.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triangle Generation Humanitaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triangle Generation Humanitaire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HUKR19-11-151857-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HUKR19-2-151884-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Svetlana Ryazantseva</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+38 66 144 70 62</telephone>
   <email>assist.hom.ukraine@trianglegh.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dina Urazbaeva</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+38 95 868 75 69</telephone>
   <email>ukraine@trianglegh.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UKR14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04760900 37.67396200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UKR44">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luhanska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.98548500 39.01766300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="75" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HUKR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-10">81456.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-10">123543.04</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6307141855">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-05">1146.25</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triangle Generation Humanitaire</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-13730">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-10">204999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triangle Generation Humanitaire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304261277">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-15">204999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triangle Generation Humanitaire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
