<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-19/UKR_CBPF/SA1/P-WASH/NGO/13752</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistance to elderly people living alone and people with disabilities living close to the contact line in Government Controlled Areas of Donetska and Luhanska oblasts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our project is aimed at providing comprehensive assistance to elderly people living alone, the most vulnerable elderly people and people with disabilities living in 24 settlements with limited access along the &#x2018;contact line&#x2019; in Government Controlled Areas of Donetska and Luhanska oblasts. Within the framework of the project, we will carry out the following activities:
- 19 social workers from among local residents in communities with limited access along the &#x201C;contact line&#x201D; will provide assistance (daily care) to elderly people living alone, the most vulnerable elderly people and people with disabilities, where public services, transportation links and basic services are not available or are not available in full
- 7 social service workers provide services to provide with hot meals elderly people bedridden and with impaired mobility, with disabilities who cannot cook their own meals
- 100 beneficiaries will be provided within one year with assistive devices
- 100 beneficiaries will be provided daily with the required number of adult diapers 
- about 100 beneficiaries are provided with hot meals daily.
- we provide social accompaniment to the beneficiaries
The project will be implemented through a network of local employees who, on an ongoing basis within a year, will cover 24 completely (partially) isolated from access to basic services, public transport, government agencies settlements along the &#x201C;contact line&#x201D;. 
During the implementation of the project, we will be able to provide assistance and protection to 550 beneficiaries regularly throughout the year.
The target group of the project are elderly people living alone, the most vulnerable elderly people and people with disabilities who need support. 
The aim of the project is to ensure decent living conditions for elderly people living alone, the most vulnerable elderly people and people with disabilities as well as providing this category of persons with the right to a decent old age.
For the project, we identify the following risks:
1) The safety of project personnel is at risk during activities in settlements along the &#x2018;contact line&#x2019;. To minimize risk, all personnel working in high-risk areas will undergo safety training.
2) High staff turnover. To minimize the risk, the operations manager will work with the team, determine their needs and provide the necessary recommendations when necessary.
3) Possible manifestations of corruption in the organization. To minimize this risk, our organization has a number of organizational policies that prevent corruption the organization passes regular external audits.
NGO &quot;Proliska&quot; has been operating in Luhanska and Donetska oblasts since July 2014. Our organization has got many years of experience in implementing projects in the conflict zone: from 2016 to the present, we have been the executive partners of UNHCR in 2016-2018 we were the executive partners of UNICEF, since 2019 we have been the partners of the Ministry of Temporary Occupied Territories and Internally Displaced People. Currently, the organization has 100 employees who are the members of the communities along the &#x2018;contact line&#x2019;.Thanks to this, we have a positive reputation in the communities and access to all the settlements with limited access where we carry out activities.
Our employees are qualified specialists, having mainly 5 years of experience of work in the conflict zone. All staff are trained to prevent SGBV and PSEA. 10 field office coordinators are the leaders of local communities and have experience in identification of protection risks and finding solutions for them through community initiatives implementation, advocacy interventions and other activities. 10 caseworkers possess knowledge of typical problems, and as a result of internal training, experience and analysis, they effecti</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yevhen Kaplin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of organization</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380993225225</telephone>
   <email>yevhenkaplin@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UKR14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04760900 37.67396200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UKR44">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luhanska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.98548500 39.01766300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="87" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="13" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-23">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-23">183000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-13752">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-23">213000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304282865">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-25">213000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
