<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-278093</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2018 &#x2013; Sustainable Integration of Philippine Smallholder Farmers into the Global Cacao Value Chain</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Philippines has a persistent rural poverty problem due to small farm plots, ageing farmers, lack of knowledge and general lack of economic opportunities. This project will contribute to the achievement of SDG 8 by creating sustainable income opportunities for smallholder farmers in the Philippines by developing a more robust and diversified agri-industry based on sourcing from smallholder farmers. The project will develop a clear pathway for farmer groups to commercially engage in the global cocoa value chain of Mars and Kennemer Foods. More specifically, Mars and Kennemer Foods have developed a unique mutually beneficial program providing farmers with technical support and long-term financing. The project will support 1,000 smallholder farmers in participating in the grower program. Support provided by PBSP in collaboration with other the partners includes establishing collaborative models and structures among smallholder farmers to build voice, create economies of scale, increasing technical know-how, and access to finance for planting cacao within an integrated cropping system.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at creating sustainable income opportunities for smallholder farmers in the Philippines by developing a more robust and diversified agriindustry, which is based on sourcing from smallholder farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-31648</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001232</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Policy and Administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-278093-33230" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
