<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-278481</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NDC Partnership 2018-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerating the implementation of NDC&#x2019;s under the Paris Agreement and promoting ambitious climate action. Further, to improve the regulatory environment and thereby attract private investors to climate and clean energy sectors in developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The NDC Partnership is a coalition of countries and institutions sharing a set of guiding principles and working in a coordinated manner to advance climate action and sustainable development through the implementation of Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) under the 2015 Paris Climate Agreement. Leading up to COP26 in 2021, the objective of the support is that Member countries advance achievement of mitigation and adaption targets in line with Paris Agreement and commit to higher ambitions, over time, for greenhouse gas reduction and enhanced resilience mechanisms, ensuring climate-development linkage.

Key results will be: Support to implementation strategies and raising of ambition Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC partnership plans); enhanced country engagement and coordination across government agencies and country stakeholders; improved coordination between Member countries and development partners, matching country climate needs (demand) with resources (supply) within NDC Partnership Plans; increased country access to knowledge re-sources, capacity building support initiatives and peer to peer learning and increased access to climate finance by Member countries due to more bankable NDC&#x2019;s.

Link to the 2020 annual report of the NDC-Partnership: https://ndcpartnership.org/partnership-action-pia-2020-report</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-46468</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001289</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-278481-33328" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
