<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-267980</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(WWF) Twinning Project for variable Renewable Power Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will address the need for rapid electrification of Myanmar and to ensure that the Ministry of Electricity and Energy (MoEE) has the capacity to make use of the renewable energy generation potential and handle variable renewable energy in the power sector. The project has a collaborative approach, bringing in expertise from both public and private sectors. The specific objective of the project is to increase the knowledge and capacity of MoEE on integrating renewable power into the grid. Denmark has significant experience in integrating wind power into the grid and there is an opportunity to create a twinning project, which will enable knowledge exchange and collaboration between the two countries. The activities include hands-on trainings, study visits, executive trainings, graduate-level studies and close collaboration between Danish public and private sector experts and MoEE experts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017 - 36864</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017001197</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-267980</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-267980-32166" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2019, MoEE&apos;s power plan includes a target of at least 20% variable renewable power projects in the generation mix.</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="266554" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2019, three MoEE departments and 22 officers and staff working on renewable energy and grid operations will have demonstrated capacity on on planning, feasibility study evaluation and economic analysis of integrating variable renewable power into the grid.

By end of project in February 2020, with 6 month extension, 6 MoEE departments, 32 officers and staffs working on renewable energy and grid operations have demonstrated capacity on planning, feasibility study evaluation, and economic analysis of integrating variable renewable power into the grid. Myanmar aims to meet its development goals of achieving 100% electrification by 2030, with a commitment to derive 8% of the power generation via renewable energy by 2021, increasing to 12% of renewable energy generation by 2025.</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
