<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-270222</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2017 - Fresh Fruit Nexus: Sustainable livelihoods for refugees and farmers in Northern Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In partnership with Nordic Fruit and Lishe, Danish Church Aid aims to catalyse sustainable market development and entrepreneurship in West Nile, Uganda, host to more than 1 million refugees, by training smallholder farmers to grow certified organic fruit and vegetables for export. The development objective is to improve smallholders&#x2019; livelihoods through increased income opportunities for refugee and host community farmers, especially women and unemployed youth, creating at least 229 jobs and income opportunities for 1,650 farmers in the fresh fruit and vegetable value chain (contributing to SDG targets 8.5 and 8.6). The commercial objective is to promote an energy efficient and responsible supply chain for organic products to ready-to-sell markets, including Denmark (contributing to SDG targets 8.1 and 8.2), via sea transport to reduce CO2 emissions. It links SDG 8 with the &#x201C;leaving no one behind&#x201D; principle through local market development.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development objective is to contribute to creation of sustainable livelihoods by improving income security for refugees and host community, especially women and youth, through creation of income opportunities in the organic fresh fruit and vegetable value chain. The commercial objective is to boost local market development through sale and export of organically certified fresh fruits and vegetables, based on a sustainable business case through responsible supply chain management from farmer to consumer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017-35998</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017001254</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-270222-31900" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
