<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-274141</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SSC Strengthening intellectual property rights in the Islamic Republic of Iran</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Sector Cooperation on intellectual property rights Between Denmark and he Islamic Republic of Iran, Phase I

The Strategic Sector Cooperation on intellectual property rights is a peer-to-peer cooperation between the Danish Patent and the Iranian Trademark Office and the Intellectual Property Center. The objective of the Strategic Sector Cooperation  is to enhance efficiency and effectiveness in registration, management and enforcement of intellectual property rights in the Islamic Republic of Iran. To consolidate the development of the Iranian Economy and spur employment, Iran has made it a priority to improve their business and entrepreneurial environment. the Islamic Republic of Iran has emphasized that this would include strengthening the protection of the intellectual property rights in Iran, which is considered a key prerequisite for generating innovation and attracting knowledge-intensive enterprises.

The sector cooperation will therefore focus on: strengthening the capacity of human and administrative resources in the Intellectual Property Center of Iran; Reinforce institutional capacity within and interaction between intellectual property actors in Iran; align Iranian intellectual property legislation and guidelines to existing international best practices and norms; and increase awareness on intellectual property rights to relevant users and Iranian consumers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001123</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-274141-32932" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
