<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-275269</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICRW Partnership 2018-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development objective is to undertake research and inform targeted policy dialogues on a comprehensive and rights-based approach to Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment.  The goal is to expand the discussion to include a rights-based approach to women&#x2019;s economic empowerment, including important parallel investments in health, education and social protection as critical enablers for WEE. This allows ICRW to resurface women&#x2019;s rights as a platform for WEE.

Achieving gender equality is an imperative that cannot be sidestepped. Never has this been more important as women&#x2019;s rights are being attacked, funding for global access to reproductive health care services reduced and hard-won progress on gender equality reversed in many countries around the world. Persistent gaps remain in women&#x2019;s rights and status, their ability to work, their ability to meet care needs, to defend against entrenched levels of violence and limited freedom to make their own choices. Reducing gender inequalities requires smart and sustained investment in policies and approaches that have proven impact in dismantling obstacles to women&#x2019;s rights and empowerment. 

Yet, adopting a frame of gender equality and women&#x2019;s rights is unlikely to be persuasive to the institutions most in need of change at this moment. ICRW proposes to conduct policy research and develop targeted advocacy efforts in coalition with other INGOs and partners to highlight how WEE is multiplied and magnified where concurrent and parallel investments are made in women&#x2019;s rights to health, education and social protection as well as other key rights to property, identification documents, information and assets, that enhance their economic potential and reach. ICRW will also incorporate these messages into a curated suite of briefings and strategic guidance to officials in the Danish Government to use in their engagements in Washington.

ICRW&#x2019;s monitoring framework will be informed by their theory of change and will track key outputs a</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-29843</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001147</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-275269-32999" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multilaterals and key development initiatives incorporate more transformative WEE considerations in program design, governance and application</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="266389" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct research, inform and engage key multilateral institutions focused on WEE on a rights-based and comprehensive approach through research, coalition-building and direct policy dialogues, including through briefing members of the Danish Government accordingly</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
