<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-269024</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank Women Entrepreneurs Finance Initiative (We-Fi)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of We-Fi is to address financial and non-financial constraints faced by women-owned/led small and medium firms in IDA and IBRD eligible countries and territories. Thus, We-Fi is relevant for SDGs 1, 5 and 8 and the facility is compatible with Denmark&#x2019;s strategy &#x2018;The World 2030&#x2019;. With its clear focus on women-led enterprises, We-Fi has the potential to be a very relevant initiative through which Denmark can promote both the gender equality priorities and focus on strengthening the SME sector in developing countries.

The We-Fi aims to achieve this by leveraging more than USD 1 billion in commercial and interna-tional financial institution finance for entities that provide women entrepreneurs with access to debt, equity, venture capital, insurance products, capacity building, networks and mentors, and opportunities to link with domestic and global markets; and for governments to improve the business environment for women-owned/led small and medium firms.  

Since We-Fi is a multi-donor financial intermediary fund it is not possible to attribute specific outputs to the Danish financing. Therefore, it is not possible to develop a results framework or theory of change specifically for the Danish support. Instead the Danish contribution is based on We-Fi&#x2019;s theory of change (see annex 3), while reporting on the facility&#x2019;s progress will follow the overall We-Fi results framework (see annex 2). Trough participation in the Governing Commit-tee Denmark will be able to influence the further development of the We-Fi results frame and promote the establishment of a base line for monitoring of results. The Facility Level Results Framework includes a mix of output indicators capturing the financial mobilization objectives and the improved capacity of institutions to serve female SMEs, as well as intermediate outcome indicators &#x2013; such as number, sales/profits, and employment creation, of the final beneficiaries. The Governing Committee may adapt tracking and monitoring</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s equality organisations and institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-269024-32237" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-269024-33881" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
