<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285599</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cool Coalition</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall, the Cool Coalition&#x2019;s aim is that government and industry take, or firmly commit to taking, action to meet demands for cooling in a comprehensive manner, which is linked to the nationally determined contributions (NDC&#x2019;s) enhancement and &#x2013; implementation and are in line with the Paris Agreement, SDG 7 as well as the Kigali Amendment. The Danish funding solely focuses on developing country government and industry with significant presence in developing countries. Cool Coalition is established as a platform that brings together actors from government, cities, international organisations, businesses, finance and academic institutions and civil society to facilitate joint action, knowledge exchange, technical assistance and advocacy.

The first engagement supports the overall work of the Cool Coalition and consists of four work streams: 1) Establish a platform, &#x201C;the cool hub&#x201D;, 2) Collecting and developing partners tools and standardised guidelines and tracking progress on efficient, climate friendly cooling, 3) Providing advisory support activities and 4) Enhance advocacy and awareness raising material.

The second engagement is directed at the efforts that UNEP and the Cool Coalition will undertake in India to support the transition to efficient, climate friendly cooling.

Results can be found in the annual reports here:</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Cool Coalition is a unified front to seize this opportunity, linking the Kigali Amendment to the Montreal Protocol, the Paris Agreement on Climate. Change, and the Sustainable Development Goals. It is a coalition of proactive governments, businesses, and civil society organizations that aims to inspire ambition, identify solutions, and accelerate progress toward efficient and climate-friendly cooling.

The Cool Coalitions takes a cross-sectoral and holistic approach to reducing emissions from the cooling sector by looking at a broad range of solutions, ranging from district cooling to nature-based solutions to highly efficient and climate-friendly cooling technologies that use low- or zero GWP refrigerants.

As members of the coalition, we commit to act boldly to get the best cooling solutions adopted at scale and within a meaningful timeframe.

To that end, we will:
&#x2022; Advocate: Raise awareness on efficient and climate-friendly cooling
&#x2022; Collaborate: Actively participate in a community that breaks down silos and promotes cross-cutting actions for efficient and climate-friendly cooling
&#x2022; Act: Help secure and/or make commitments on efficient and climate-friendly cooling</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019-36419</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019001249</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="231" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Policy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B032" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285599-34076" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285599-34715" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
