<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-278017</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2018 &#x2013; Pushti Ambassador Partnership &#x2013; creating jobs for female micro-entrepreneurs in Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Create income opportunities for 5000 female micro-entrepreneurs in Bangladesh by developing a sustainable sales network targeting low-income consumers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &#x201C;Pushti Ambassadors Partnership &#x2013; Creating jobs for female entrepreneurs in Bangladesh&#x201D; will contribute to women&#x2019; economic empowerment and improved nutrition in rural Bangladesh. The project is a partnership between Arla Foods, who will provide affordable dairy products to help grow the income of rural female micro-entrepreneurs and micro-entrepreneur network partner iSocial who run networks of rural female micro-entrepreneurs, BoPInc, who is an expert on BoP marketing and distribution, and DNet who will implement the recruitment and training program of iSocial. The development objective is to create 200 decent jobs and income opportunities for 5,000 female micro-entrepreneurs in rural areas over the life of the project. The project will extend rural distribution networks using innovative tools with the ambition to scale up to around 22,000 women by 2030, and serve as a model for economic empowerment through increased income opportunities in Bangladesh and beyond. Arla&#x2019;s objective in this project is to increase access to affordable nutrition by reaching 1,25 million rural consumers over the life of the project. In parallel, Arla is committed to develop the local dairy value chain leading to off-take milk from local dairy farmers. Malnutrition challenges will be addressed through improved access to safe and nutritious food in a strategic combination with behavioural change campaigns.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-31494</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001227</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-278017-33225" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
