<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-269875</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation of water sanitation and environment programmes in Uganda (1990-2017)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The evaluation of the water, sanitation and environment programmes in Uganda since 1990 encompasses three objectives:
&#x2022; To document the results and achievements through cooperation in the sub-sectors.

&#x2022; To analyse the value added through Danida support to the sub-sectors, including the effectiveness and impact of the evolving and changing partnerships with key public and private sector stakeholders in Uganda over 25 years.

&#x2022; to extract lessons learned that will be relevant for: 
a) improved national water and sanitation provision and water resource management as well as adaptation to climate change in the context of the sustainable development goals, particularly &#x201C;clean water and sanitation&#x201D; (SDG6) and &#x201C;climate action&#x201D; (SDG13); 
b) further assistance to water resources management in northern Uganda; 
c) initiatives concerned with water resources in strategic sector cooperation programmes (including private sector involvement); 
d) water supply and sanitation initiatives in the context of humanitarian assistance.
Thus, it is envisaged that the evaluation will be an important means of assessing the outcomes and sustainability of the substantial support provided by Danida in the sub-sectors. Potential target audiences include other development assistance agencies, as well as government services and non-governmental organisations in Uganda. A particular effort will be made to ensure effective communication of the conclusions and main lessons learned from the evaluation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-269875-32337" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
