<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-273688</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CISU Climate pool funds (2018-2021)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Civil Society (CS) in developing countries strengthened to advocate effectively and strategically on behalf of  poor and climate vulnerable groups: app. 235.000 people from vulnerable and marginalised target groups have increased their resilience to climate change
- National and community-level climate change policies, planning frameworks and information systems &#x2013; especially with a view to adaptation - are strengthened
- CISU Civil Society Fund effectively supporting Danish civil society climate action, and climate features strongly in the Civil Society Fund with relevant results.  Danish Civil Society Organisation&#x2019;s capacity to work with climate capacity building and advocacy with partners is strengthened.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CISU &#x2013; Civil Society in Development &#x2013; is an independent association of 270+ Danish civil society organisations (CSOs). All members are, together with partners, actively engaged in development work in Asia, Africa, Latin America, or Eastern Europe - either as their main engagement or as part of their activities. The Civil Society Fund supports interventions carried out in cooperation between Danish organisations and their partners in Asia, Africa, Latin America, or Eastern Europe and covers interventions working towards all 17 UN Development Goals. The Civil Society Fund contributes to enabling poor and vulnerable groups to make their own efforts towards improving conditions which they see as important, relevant, and necessary, and which &#x2013; structurally and in the longer term &#x2013; help advance their lot in society at the local, national, and global level. 

This specific grant contributes to climate action with the following results:
- Civil Society in developing countries advocate effectively and strategically on behalf of  poor and climate vulnerable groups
- National and community-level climate change policies, planning frameworks and information systems 
- Danish civil society climate action, and climate features strongly in the Civil Society Fund with relevant results.  Danish Civil Society Organisation&#x2019;s capacity to work with climate capacity building and advocacy with partners is strengthened

Learn more at: https://www.cisu.dk/puljer/civilsamfundspuljen</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-15230</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001253</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-273688-33271" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
