<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-280136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Sector Cooperation &quot;Strengthening Official Statistics in Ghana&quot;, SSC inception project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Sector Cooperation on Statistics Between Denmark and Ghana, phase Inception

The Strategic Sector Cooperation on Statistics is a peer-to-peer cooperation between Statistics Denmark and Ghana Statistical Service. The overall objective of the Strategic sector cooperation is to improve the statistical system of Ghana and therewith the foundation for evidence-based policy making and democracy &#x2013; through increased availability of internationally comparable, independent, accurate and timely statistics. The supply of relevant, timely and usable data is essential for countries to set priorities, make informed choices and implement better policies for sustainable development. Hence, capacity development of Ghana Statistical Service will not only improve the monitoring and reporting of the SDG&#x2019;s, it will also improve the long-term framework for achieving the SDG&#x2019;s. 

The project assists Ghana&#x2019;s steps towards improving quality, data coverage, administrative data systems as well as dissemination and use of official statistic in collaboration with Ghana Statistical Service. The project draws on Statistics Denmark&#x2019;s experiences and regulations with digital statistical production (e.g. quality principles), and will address a range of areas including developing an open databank available for the public, setting up a quality management system and improving population figures and economic statistics, which will provide Ghana with relevant and easily accessible statistics and support informed decision making.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019001031</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-280136-33524" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved framework conditions for sustainable development</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="269520" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">SSC contributions in 2019 to framework conditions within statistics in Ghana: &quot;Yes &quot;.

Score: Yes or No. Yes meaning a project document has been signed

The planned output targets in the project have been met in 2019.</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
