<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-278029</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2018 &#x2013; WeGrow Increasing innovation and livelihoods in agriculture in Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is a partnership between CARE, BLUETOWN and local strategic partners. The project promotes digital transformation as an enabler for development by innovating and piloting digital agriculture services for Ghanaian farmers that will ensure more sustainable and resilient production and improved market linkages for smallholder farmers. The project will test the commercial viability of agricultural content on BLUETOWN&#x2019;s LOCAL CLOUD, a new innovative platform for distribution of digital content to be developed and managed by commercial content providers. SDG 8 is targeted by promoting inclusive and sustainable economic growth through increased productivity in the agricultural sector, brought about by technological upgrading, innovation as well as improved resource efficiency and climate resilience in agricultural production. Additionally, the project explores the promotion of entrepreneurial business models for youth enabled by connectivity.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute to enhanced livelihoods of rural communities through digital inclusion making agriculture attractive for future generations of farmers in Ghana</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-31671</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001228</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Policy and Administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-278029-33221" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
