<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-275866</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RDPP II 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strat. objective: Refugees and host populations living in displacement affected communities access their rights, are safe, self-reliant, and refugees are able to avail themselves of a durable solution	

Thematic objectives:
Thematic area A: Livelihoods towards durable solutions: Access to safe and sustainable livelihoods opportunities for displacement-affected populations, in support of durable solutions is improved. The thematic area focuses on improving employability skills through 1) market-based trainings and linking job-seekers with the private sector; and 2) improving decent work through improved capacity of national partners and creating sustainable businesses with transferable potential 

Thematic area B: Upholding and expanding protection space: Protection space for vulnerable refugees and host communities is expanded. The thematic area focuses on improving capacity of local authorities and civil society actors through 1) training to improve protection focusing on SGBV and child labor rights; and 2) improved social cohesion and reduced tensions through conflict mitigation

Thematic area C: Research and advocacy: A more conducive environment for durable solutions. The thematic area focuses on supporting a more conducive environment for durable solutions through 1) access to high quality and relevant research to inform evidence based advocacy; and 2) policy dialogue and advocacy efforts of national actors related to protracted displacement, durable solutions and rights of vulnerable groups</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2017-29370">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-275866-33041" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
