<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-279495</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DUF - Pool grant, since 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Danish Youth Council (DUF) is an umbrella organization that represents 80 children and youth organizations and more than 600,000 Danish children and young people. The umbrella holds one diversity of Danish young people - from scouts, role players, believers and youth politicians to young people in pupil and student organizations, youth clubs, disability associations, and environmental organizations, and DUF works to promote young people&apos;s participation in association life and in democracy. In line with that is the purpose of DUF&apos;s global youth program is to increase youth involvement and influence in development cooperation by giving young Danes and young people in the south platforms and opportunities to take responsibility and create the changes they want - locally, nationally and globally. Read more at: https://duf.dk/internationalt-arbejde/dufs-internationale-pulje

Indicators:
Number of Danish civil society organizations that are engaged in development cooperation through pool grants granted in 2021: 12

Number of civil society organizations in the global south that are engaged in partnerships with Danish civil society organizations through pool grants granted in 2021: 18

Number of people directly reached through development projects funded by pool grants completed in 2021: 124,046 children and young people

Number of countries that Danish civil society organizations carry out development projects through pool grants granted in 2021: 15</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To expand the Danish Youth Delegate Programme with two delegates on the thematic area of technical and vocational education and training (TVET) and job creation with the purpose of 1) engaging a group of young stakeholders traditionally not engaged in the Danish development cooperation and 2) ensure that this group of youth is represented in relevant multilateral fora as well as the ministry&#x2019;s work on TVET and job creation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unallocated / Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-279495-33405" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
