<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-270228</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2017 &#x2013; Organic hazelnut value chain creates income and decent employment in Western Georgia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable hazelnut production and transparent and profitable marketing channels reduce poverty through creating stable income and decent employment opportunities for Georgian farmer families.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is that sustainable hazelnut production and transparent and profitable value chains create income and decent employment opportunities for Georgian farmer families. The project is a partnership between HEKS/EPER, PAKKA AG, ANKA Fair Trade and Biological Farming Association Elkana, and will enable a significant and growing number of farmer families in Georgia to improve their livelihoods in a sustainable way by adopting organic and fair-trade hazelnut production practices and by enabling them to sell their produce profitability via traceable and reliable value chains. To achieve this, the project will enhance efficiency of producer cooperatives, connect them with the buyer and the private sector service providers as well as contribute to positive changes in the business enabling environment and thereby also enhance the economic viability of the actors in the value chain. The clear business orientation of the project will ensure sustainability of the results beyond the project implementation.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017-38488</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017001255</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-270228-31901" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
