<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-271685</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and Law Enforcement Reforms: Transformative approaches to Gender Equality and Women&apos;s Empowerment (UN Women).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the project will be achieved by piloting innovative local models of participatory gender-responsive planning and budgeting and GBV prevention and response that will inform and, to the extent possible, be institutionalised in national policy on decentralisation and law enforcement reforms. The project will apply the Community Mobilization for Empowerment methodology that has been successfully piloted in Ukraine. The results of the gender-responsive pilots in Donetsk and Luhansk oblasts will inform policy-making for potential institutionalisation and replication across the country. 
 
The project will build on the multi-stakeholder partnership established through previous efforts of UN Women with the Ministry of Internal Affairs, Donetsk and Luhansk oblast administrations, women&#x2019;s groups and community groups at the local level. Ministry of Regional Development, Construction and Housing and Communal Services will be another key government partner of the project in Ukraine. The project will be implemented in close coordination with UN and other international development partners, in particular the ones working on decentralization reform (USAID Dobre project and U-lead).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="403.Ukraine.1-31/2018-7075">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-271685-32635" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
