<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-283639</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment to IFU for investment in Climate Investor 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the UN an estimated 2.1 billion people lack access to safe and readily available water, and more than 4 billion people lack access to sanitation compatible with the SDG 6 on water and sanitation. Inadequate water and sanitation systems at all levels in developing countries have great negative impact on social and economic development. There is an urgent need to increase investments in the water sector.

The inadequate water and sanitation investment level is two sided: a) International development assistance and public authorities in developing countries have inadequate resources, and b) the private sector is not ready to invest due to a perceived unattractive risk-return balance.

Development objective: Contribute to improved access to safe drinking water; improved effective wastewater treatment and effective use of water resources in developing countries in support of the achievement of SDG 6. 

Immediate objective: 
1.	CI2 operational as an innovative international blended finance vehicle for the promotion of responsible and sustainable commercial water and sanitation investment solutions that can be scaled to accelerate progress towards achievement of SDG 6.
2.	Strengthened IFU and the Danish water sector&#x2019;s experience and opportunity to engage in an increased number of water infrastructure projects in developing countries</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="2019-18118">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water supply and sanitation - large systems</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-283639-33837" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
