<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-277597</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlantic Council Partnership 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our objective is to forge digital resilience during a time when humans are more interconnected than at any point in history. Ideas and information travel quickly&#x2014;knowledge and inspiration can move around the world in an instant, as can manipulation and misinformation. 
As in Europe and the United States, people in the developing world are also targets of disinformation, misinformation, and propaganda, making it difficult for those in developing communities to base decisions on objective information. For instance, human smugglers and criminal networks use information technology to solicit clients with lies about the costs, risks, and possibilities related to migration. Adverse state-actors increasingly manipulate people in the developing world with misinformation and propaganda that skews their perceptions of international political dynamics and international values. 
The purpose of this project is to explore how countering disinformation and propaganda using exclusively open and transparent sources utilized by the DFRLab can be applied in the developing world, with a specific geographic focus on West or North Africa and a substantive focus on potential migrant populations. DFRLab will place an emphasis on tailoring its methodology to account for local conditions and impact by adjusting for what works and what can be embedded with actors in the region. 
The overarching goal in all things at the DFRLab is to forge digital resilience during a time when humans are more connected and have more access to information than at any point in human history. This is especially acute in the developing world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-29844</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018001241</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-277597-33165" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
