<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-275181</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Explorer 2018 DESMI RO-CLEAN</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danida Innovation &amp; Business Explorer (DIBE) offers financial support to Danish companies, including start-ups, that wish to investigate concrete business opportunities contributing to the achievement of the Sustainable Development Goals and the Paris agreement. DESMI EnviRo-Clean, whose purpose is precisely to reduce the pollution of plastics in the oceans is therefore, seeking to test ifthe collected waste can be used to generate resource i.e. pyrolysis oil. The aim ofthe project is to test the pyrolysis technology for mixed waste feedstock, collected from rivers or lakes in India. This technology finds a lag between experimental studies and scaling up of the technique especially when it comes to mixed feedstock with large percentage of waste with low calorific value and high contamination of waste. The technology will be developed, such that it is a mobile unit fitted inside a 20 to 40 foot container instead of stationary processing plant. This ensures that the mobile pyrolysis unit can be moved closer to the waste collection points, when required. The purpose of this project is to prove the sustainability of the process with pyrolysis technology to mitigate waste of mixed feedstock, collected from rivers or lakes besides reducing the damage to the local environment</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of this project is to prove the sustainability of the process with pyrolysis technology to
mitigate waste of mixed feedstock, collected from rivers or lakes besides reducing the damage to the local
environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018-23031</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-275181-32993" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
