<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-270232</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A network of JazzCash Guddi Bajis to increase Women&#x2019;s Financial inclusion in Pakistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase women&#x2019;s economic opportunity and financial inclusion in Pakistan, by creating a commercially sustainable model of women retailers as mobile financial services agents.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &#x201C;Empowering Pakistani Women Through Financial Inclusion and Economic Growth&#x201D; is a partnership between Unilever, who will support and supply women with fast moving consumer goods, RSPN, who will recruit and train the female sales agents called &#x2018;JazzCashGuddiBaji&#x2019;s&#x2019;, Mobilink Microfinance Bank Limited (Jazz), who will provide access to finance to retailers and their customers via their JazzCash application, and BoPInc, who is an expert in facilitating partnerships and developing inclusive business models with micro-entrepreneurs. The development objective of the project is to create decent employment and income for 3,000 women retailers in 10 districts in Pakistan and to expand financial inclusion of women in Pakistan. The project is expected to grow exceptionally after the life of the project to create increased income opportunities for 15,000 women and advance progress on SDG 8 and 5.  
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017-35941</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017001256</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-270232-31902" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
