<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5104006401-RSS-12182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EHPSA - Regional HIV&amp;SRHR Research progam</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EHPSA - Regional hiv&amp;SRHR forsknings program 2014-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att bidra till framtagandet av en b&#xE4;ttre evidensbas genom Regional Research and Innovation Fund (RRIF), som syftar till att generera evidens kring de mest effektiva ansatserna f&#xF6;r HIV prevention bland utvalda utsatta befolkningsgrupper (m&#xE4;nniskor i f&#xE4;ngelser, unga 10-24 &#xE5;r och HBT personer). Syftet med RRIF f&#xF6;der in i det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let att s&#xE4;rskilt utsatta grupper ges tillg&#xE5;ng till och anv&#xE4;nder sig av effektiva HIV preventiva metoder och detta baserat p&#xE5; evidens. 
Insatsens aktiviteter kommer att innefatta test av pilotprogram i f&#xE4;lt och spridning av resultaten av dessa. RRIF kommer att ledas av HLSP-Mott MacDonald som utg&#xF6;r den genomf&#xF6;rande partnern upphandlad av DFID. Regionalt baserade forskningsinstitutioner kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra olika forskningsprojekt koordinerade av HSLP-Mott MacDonald. Det f&#xF6;rutses att denna insats &#xE4;ven kommer att utg&#xF6;ra en m&#xF6;jlighet f&#xF6;r kompetensst&#xE4;rkande f&#xF6;r de forskningsinsitutioner som kommer att delta och &#xE4;ven att st&#xE4;rka partnerskap mellan institutioner. DFID &#xE4;r den huvudsakliga givaren f&#xF6;r denna struktur och bidrar med 55 MSEK. Sida &#xE4;r partnergivare med 45 MSEK i bidrag. 
DFID och Sida kommer att f&#xF6;lja riktlinjerna f&#xF6;r delegerat partnerskap i denna 100 MSEK RRIF. Sida st&#xE4;ller sig bakom de interna riktlinjerna och processerna som DFID till&#xE4;mpar baserat p&#xE5; det delegerade partnerskapsavtalet som kommer att undertecknas.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Regional Research and Innovations Fund (RRIF) is a critical component of the 4 component regional HIV programme; Evidence for HIV Prevention in Southern Africa (EHPSA) developed by DFID. The EHPSA Programme aims to strengthen evidence for effective HIV preventative interventions among three selected populations: (i) young people (particularly adolescent women aged 10 to 24 years), (ii) prisoners and (iii) LGBTI. The research funded through the RRIF should help build an effective evidence base to mount a more innovative, effective and efficient prevention effort in the region. The EHPSA programme is therefore designed to take on a catalytic function in the region, to establish &#x2018;good practice&#x2019; for evidence based HIV prevention and looks to disseminate findings which are also intended to influence the creation of favorable policy in the long-run. 
This intervention will be funded by DFID and Sida through a Delegated Partnership Arrangement where Sida will contribute 45 MSEK to this 100 MSEK intervention. Through this type of arrangement, DFID; the Lead donor will utilize its internal control mechanisms to implement this intervention through a Management Agent; HLSP-Mott MacDonald who were procured following rigorous selection process. This intervention will be implemented from 1st April 2014 through to 31st March 2018. Research institutions in the eastern and southern African region will be the awarding institutions to implement the research under the coordination of the management agent and it is foreseen that this intervention will be an opportunity for research institutions to develop capacity and strengthen partnerships to support the development and up to date maintenance of the regional evidence base. The intervention activities will include field testing of pilot programmes and the effective dissemination of findings two stages; mid-term in 2016 and full time dissemination in 2018.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selected vulnerable populations (prisoners, young people and LGBTI persons) have access to and are utilising highly effective HIV prevention methods based on evidence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DFID/Department for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regering i givarlandet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3207043.834458228</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2609943.8862064467</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">116870.2156255478</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3207043.834458228</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2609943.8862064467</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">116870.2156255479</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">6559862.388664</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">3207043.834458228</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">2609943.8862064467</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">116870.2156255478</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BackgroundThe Evidence for Prevention in southern and eastern Africa (EHPSA) 2014-2018 is a regional programme generating evidence of what works and why for HIV prevention in Africa among adolescent girls, prisoners, and men who have sex with men (MSM) and developing strategies to inform policies and programmes for these groups. EHPSA&#x2019;s ambitious outcome was &#x201C;HIV prevention strategies for key vulnerable populations (adolescents, MSM, prisoners) are in place and based upon evidence.&#x201D; The EHPSA approach focussed on a series of policy and programme relevant research and evaluations, coupled with a coordinated approach to Evidence into Action (EiA) in the region.
The programme supported by&#xA0;Sweden, Department for International Development (DIFID) and the World Bank (WB), was planned to conclude by 31st March 2018. However, there were funds remaining from DFID and the WB&#xA0;which prompted a request for a no-cost extension until 31 August 2018 from Mott McDonald (MM) which is the grant manager and implementing organization. Sweden&apos;s final disbursement to DFID was made in December 2016 and Swedish funds were exhausted at the end of 2017. The programme completion report 2014-2018 was not submitted on time due to&#xA0;the change of&#xA0;management section within the DFID which delayed the review. 
The major focus of the programme (over 70% of resources and 65% of output weighting) is on the Regional Research and Innovation Fund (RRIF) which includes four&#xA0;co-funded impact evaluations led by the WB. Since 2014, eight research programme and three major impact evaluations have been completed as planned, with the fourth major evaluation completing in 2019.&#xA0; A four-month time extension in 2018 allowed the programme to capitalise on opportunities for policy engagement as well as enable researchers to present findings at the International AIDS Conference in Amsterdam. 
AchievementsThe area of &quot;Influence on policy and practice on HIV prevention in the region&quot; has been progressing with some notable achievements within the programme time frame. For example: - The baseline and mid line data from the Sitakhela Likusasa impact evaluation in Swaziland have already influenced the new national HIV strategy, with specific interventions to keep young women in school with specific interventions to support and provide a livelihood for those who are not in education, employment or training.- In South Africa the Mzantsi Wakho findings influenced the 2017 Adolescent and Youth Health Policy where researchers were invited to co-author the final drafts of the policy. Two sections of the UNAIDS 2018 Global AIDS Report feature EHPSA-funded findings from this study.&#xA0; In these ways, the study has played a role in shaping the global normative environment for HIV prevention for adolescents. - In Kenya, the Anza Mapema study on HIV services for MSM, including the provision of pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) presented findings regularly to the local health authorities and the national technical working group on STI, PrEP and key populations. The study has informed the approval and implementation of PrEP as a national programme. 
Research publications has been on track to exceed targets, with 22 papers published and 52 in preparation. The programme has hosted 19 regional engagement events with researchers, policy makers and community based organisations on HIV prevention for adolescent girls, MSM and prison populations. 
Overall, the programme has developed an innovative approach to put EiA by convening innovative regional meetings (on tackling HIV prevention in prisons, and amongst MSM and in adolescent populations), disseminating information and involving policy makers from the start in research planning, implementation and uptake of lessons for implementation (to shorten the typical seven-year gap between new evidence and its uptake into policy).&#xA0;
The focus on EiA has been central to the programme, both through&#xA0;the&#xA0; approach of direct engagement of national HIV policy makers in impact evaluations, and the EHPSA team innovation on evidence into action across the RRIF research portfolio. All the EHPSA research programmes were led by African institutions.
The comprehensive &quot;EiA-strategy&quot; has been a particular area of strength and will contribute to global evidence in this field. As with all research and evidence programmes, it is expected that the impacts of evidence on HIV prevention will continue to be realised over the coming years.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51040064" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061702" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3700000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional SRHR 2015-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt SRHR 2015-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
