<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5105007301-RSS-33181</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Tralac 2015-2020, fas II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tralac 2015-2020, phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Trade Law Centre NPC (Tralac) &#xE4;r en icke-vinstdrivande organisation baserad i Sydafrika som utvecklar handelspolitisk och handelsr&#xE4;ttslig kapacitet i s&#xF6;dra och &#xF6;stra Afrika. Tralac bedriver kapacitetsbyggnad i regionen genom bevakning och analys av handelsfr&#xE5;gor, utbildnings-/tr&#xE4;ningsverksamhet, policydialog och delgivning av handelsrelaterade kunskaps- och analysprodukter till intressenter ber&#xF6;rda av handelspolitiska  processer i regionen.

Tralacs verksamhet syftar till att utveckla kapaciteten i s&#xF6;dra och &#xF6;stra Afrika s&#xE5; att denna region ska kunna tillhandah&#xE5;lla de positiva utvecklinseffekter internationell handel kan medf&#xF6;ra.

Organisationens verksamhet v&#xE4;gleds av ett strategiskt ramverk som str&#xE4;cker sig &#xF6;ver perioden 2015-2019 (sydafrikanskt budget&#xE5;r). Det strategiska ramverket inneh&#xE5;ller tre huvudpelare inom vilka programverksamheten sker: i) handelspolitisk bevakning och analys, ii) utbildning, iii) policydialog.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tralac develops trade law and trade policy capacity in Eastern and Southern Africa. Tralac is a not-for-profit registered Company in South Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TRALAC/Trade Law Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">949070.5040750715</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467480.8625021913</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">949070.5040750715</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467480.8625021913</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-03-01">1423605.756112</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">949070.5040750715</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">467480.8625021913</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid/document.se/ethiopia/agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid/document.se/ethiopia/amendment-i-agreement-on-core-support-to-tralac.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment I Agreement on core support to Tralac</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid/document.se/ethiopia/signed-amendment-1-on-core-support-agreement-51050073.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signed Amendment 1 on Core Support Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid/document.se/ethiopia/decision-contribution51050073.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Annual Narrative report 2019/20 has a very interesting introduction, highlighting the following key messages and trends in the trade policy landscape of Africa and beyond: 1. Effects of the Covid-19 pandemic devastating, opportunity to develop production capacity and strengthen intra-African trade : unilateral actions including border closures severing livelihood of millions of households that depend on cross-border trade, shortage of goods, increased queues at borders,&#xA0; absence of effective regional collaboration wihtin RECs.&#xA0; The pandemic has accentuated the need for development and diversification of productive capacity to reduce vunerability and dependence of imported goods and exports of a limited commodity based basket of goods. Promotion of regional and continental value-chains and supporting intra-African trade is ever more important. 2. AfCFTA entered into force, but trade under the regime not yet possible. the two basic criteria for free trade are preferential tariff concessions and preferential rules of origin - these are still under negotiation. RECs and their specific trade regimes will remain. It is possible that the AfCFTAs main contribution will not be in tariff liberalisation&#xA0; will be most effective in trade facilitation and possibly improvements in trade governance. 3. Global trade governance in disarray. WTO facing serious challenges and lack of progress.&#xA0; Output and achievements The report provides key data on activities, output and impact of tralac as a whole.&#xA0; All targets indicated in the 2019/20 Log frame were met and when looking at tralac as a whole one is surprised by the volume and quality of its output.&#xA0; There were some savings in the budget as more funders came on board, some products were produced in-house rather than by consultants etc. These were used for a noc-sot extension in 2020. Tralac&apos;s geographical spread keeps widening, but is focused on following important trade negotiations and agreements such as South African matters, SACU, REC, Tripartite or AfCFTA-related. Their outreach is impressive and takes place through a multitude of channels and formats, ranging from specialised training and workshops, to research papers, briefs and blogs to their website and social media platforms. Tralac states: &#x201C;It is through our online presence that our audience can actively engage with our work at any time anywhere in the world.&#x201D; The year 2019/20 at a glance shows: 80 publications, 14 capacity building workshops, 13 policy dialogue fora, 234 individuals trained. In addition to the regular activities such a daily newsletter, trade briefs, maintenance of the continuously updated website, tralac expanded its geographical focus and presence during 2019/20 through the participation in, and organisation of a number of key events across the continent, including: - Participation in AU stakeholder dialogue on the AfCFTA, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia- Training for the Pan-African Parliament&apos;s Womens caucus on the AfCFTA- Tralac represented at AU Summit, Niamey, Niger- Launch of women in trade governance, Nairobi, Kenya and first Women in Trade Governance Residential programme presented in Cape Town, SA- First regional roundtable for the private sector presented in Cape Town, SA- Hosting of tralac&apos;s Annual conference in East Africa for the first time, Nairobi, Kenya Towards the end of the reporting period preparations were made to move several activites online due to the Covid-19 situation and lockdown in South Africa.&#xA0; The infographics below point to the possible impact the organisation is having on trade policy and trade law in Southern Africa and further afield as regards the AfCFTA.&#xA0;  Reach and Social Media engagement We have previously been a bit concerned that tralac&apos;s audience to a fair degree consists of donor representatives and trade experts from countries such as the US, the UK and Germany. The list of top 25 users by country below allays this fear by showing a greater diversity than in previous years and a sizeable increased reach across Africa. &#xA0;&#xA0;  Financial reporting Tralac has a Financial Officer and a part-time contracted internal auditor. Budgets are detailed and follow-up is easy.&#xA0; Over the years the reporting has developed and tralac and the Embassy has agreed on a &quot;budget vs actuals&quot; format with a column for deviations and cause for deviations. &#xA0; The Executive Financial Summary and the Budget vs Actuals provide a good picture of the expenditures during the 2019/2020 financial year and the entire five-year programme period.&#xA0; For 2019/2020 a total of ZAR12 551 042 had been approved, which included disbursed unused funds and accumulated interest. A total of ZAR7 524 002 was disbursed (SEK5m) and the actual amount spent was ZAR8 939 092, meaning that ZAR1 415 090 of previously disbursed unused funds were used. The difference between approved budget and actual was ZAR3 611 950, or about 30%. As mentioned above regardless of the fairly low budget utilisation all activities and targets in the 2019-20 log frame were reached.&#xA0; Reasons for the costs savings include a higher degree of utilisation of in-house staff and volunteers as opposed to associates and consultants, co-funding with USAID and GIZ of some budgetlines, contribution by the Australian Volunteer Programme, savings on printing costs etc. &#xA0; For the five-year period a total of ZAR48,959,752 had been received by tralac (SEK32m), in addition interest of ZAR999,470 had been generated and a total of ZAR46,138,707 had been spent. This left an unspent amount of ZAR2 821 045 + interest ZAR999 470= ZAR3,820,514. A five-year reconciliation shows in detail how the funds have been spent during the agreement period.&#xA0; The agreement states that: &#xA0;  In the 2018 September Annual Review Meeting a discussion was held about when the interest could be utilised. After consultation with Sandra Lima at JUR it was agreed that the interest could be used during the activiy period, hence it was approved for utilisation in 2019/20. The possibility for tralac to request a no-cost extension, should funds remain at the end of the activiy period 29.2.2020 was discussed in 2018.&#xA0; The financial year 2019/2020 was the last year under this funding cycle, but as some funds remained towards the end of the activity period tralac asked for a no-cost extension until 31.7.2020, which was granted. According to the financial report an amount of ZAR3 820 514, including interest remained. The budget for the no-cost extension amounted to ZAR3.1m. In June 2020 tralac requested a second no-cost extension amounting to ZAR1.2m, which includes use of the accumulated interest of ZAR999 470. Partnership Sida/the Embassy and tralac In the Annual Report tralac states that it is grateful towards Sida which has allowed them to develop innovative training programmes, to have flexibility to add to their research agenda as unexpected events have unfolded and has prompted tralac to refine their organisation and and financial management processes and policies. On our part we are proud to be associated with tralac as we know first-hand that their products are relevant and of high quality. Several Sida staff members are subscribers to, and use tralac&apos;s reports and newsletters. Evaluation During 2019/20 an evaluation took place covering the entire programme period March 2015-Feb 2020. The services were procured by tralac and the evaluation was carried out by Sanaa Consulting who also did the previous Mid-Term Review.&#xA0; The evaluation team concluded that &quot;findings from both the surveys and interviews show that tralac&apos;s activities have been highly relevant for beneficiaries and tralac&apos;s partners and that tralac has been able to make an impact by positively influencing the work of national policy makers and individuals, and to some extent influenced the work of actual organisations, including trade ministries, regional economoic communities and the African Union.&quot; Key recommendations include: 1. Phased scaling up of tralac&#x2019;s core team: The new strategy should seek options on how to grow the core team to cover up to 2 additional researchers across different levels of seniority and allowing for the interns to extend their tenure to up to 12 months at a time. tralac should aim to fund this by increasing contributions from existing donors and actively engaging with new donors to ensure that it has the funding commitments in place to scale-up the team. 2. Expansion via defined institutional partnerships: tralac should finalise the formal Memorandum of Understanding with the African Union Commission and aim to develop and lead a loose network of research and capacity building organisations on trade. 3. Further leverage the network model: tralac should consider its community of practice/alumni network as a system and how it can best service the system, for example, by providing professional support services for the enhancement of the careers of alumni within trade related organisations. 4. Secure and manage access to private sector: tralac should ensure that engagement with the private sector remains a core part of its future strategy. 5. Further exploring new issues and delivery methods: new thematic issues should continue be addressed in the new strategy, ideally through a scaled-up in-house team, associate network and institutional partnerships. 6. Consolidating and coordinating donor interest and investment: With support from tralac, Sida should convene a donor coordination mechanism that is able to address emerging themes and issues proactively. The Embassy made comments on the first draft of the evaluation.&#xA0; The impression was that the evaluation was a bit thin in terms of new contacts and research and relied too much on the previous evaluation, stressing the need for those recommendations to be implemented (such as an expansion to West Africa), regardless of what tralac thought. The final version was better and more useful.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51050073" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
