<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5105006501-RSS-33120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">World Customs Organisation (WCO), 2014-2018, fas II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Customs Organisation (WCO), 2014-2018, phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till World Customs Organization(WCO) fas II, 2014-2018, med      syfte att fr&#xE4;mja regional ekonomisk utveckling och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet i     Sub-Sahara Afrika mot f&#xF6;rverkligandet av regionala tullunioner, samt  uppr&#xE4;ttandet av effektiva tullmyndigheter och d&#xE4;rmed minskade         handelshinder.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to World Customs Organzation (WCP) Phase II, 2014-2018 with   the aim at promoting regional economic development and gender         equality in Sub-Saharan Africa, supporting the regions&apos; specific      goals towards the realization of regional customs unions, and the     establishment of effective customs administrations, thereby reducing  trade barriers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The WCO and Sida have been working in partnership since 2008 to enhance the capacity of customs administrations to meet several developmental goals. The most recent Programme of cooperation between the WCO and Sida was the WCO-Sweden Sub-Saharan Africa Customs Modernization Programme (2014-2018) which had a regional approach, focusing&#xA0;on EAC&#xA0;(East African Community), ECOWAS (Economic Community Of Western African States) and SACU (Southern African Customs Union), and delivered a wide range of positive outcomes for 21 beneficiary countries within the regions.&#xA0;
The overall objectives of the programme was to&#xA0;contribute to poverty reduction efforts in beneficiary regions by fostering regional economic development through sustainable and improved trade while addressing the illegal flow of goods and related integrity issues; and promoting sustainable development and gender equity.&#xA0;Each&#xA0;regional project had its own specific objectives and results based on the overall objective, previous work and the demand and needs from the region.&#xA0;
In EAC&#xA0;the expected&#xA0;results&#xA0;were to assist in the roll-out of the full scale regional Authorized Economic Operators (AEO) scheme through capacity building in risk management, verification, post clearance audits and implementation of appropriate governance structures; contribute to information and communication technology with assistance in development of tools for post clearance audit, risk management, risk profiling and regional information exchange; risk&#xA0;management and enforcement&#xA0;through diagnostic studies in enhancement of capacities relating to risk management and front-line enforcement operations; mutual&#xA0;recognitionwith assistance in development of compliance and security programs for all parts of the supply chain and the export procedures to allow the EAC to enter agreements with other trading partners on facilitated management between the agreeing parties.
The ECOWAS&#xA0;project focused on strategic&#xA0;management where both the ECOWAS&#xA0;customs directorate and supported customs administrations have improved specific strategic management capacities;&#xA0;Human Resource Management to support&#xA0;customs administrations to improve their capacities in specific HRM fields; strengthened stakeholder&#xA0;relations to improve&#xA0;customs&#xA0;management of their relations with specific key stakeholders
The&#xA0;SACU project&#xA0;focused on&#xA0;IT connectivity in the region to enable regional integration and facilitate trade; create trade partnerships to improve&#xA0;the relationship between customs&#xA0;and the private sector and to initiate a Preferred Trader Programme that will meet the requirements and expectations of both the national authorities and the trade community. The SACU Preferred Trader Programme is an initial step for the region towards fully fledged Authorized Economic Operators (AEO). Morover,&#xA0;enhancing the risk management and enforcement capacities in the region and the&#xA0;need for a SACU regional framework for risk management and enforcement has been on the agenda for a while; focus on legislative reform of the WCO SACU Connect project is considered to be critical to the success of the project as a whole; focus on Post Clearance Audit (PCA) improved PCA&#xA0;systems and operations.&#xA0;
Part of the Sweden-WCO Agreement was also the&#xA0;WCO-INAMA-project that was a broader multi-donor program&#xA0;focuses on strengthening the enforcement capacity of targeted customs in Sub-Saharan Africa and Asia. INAMA focused&#xA0;on the illegal trade in wildlife (fauna and flora) and in particular CITES listed species.&#xA0;The overall objective was that customs administrations should have enhanced enforcement capabilities as well as capacity at all necessary organisational levels, including good governance and integrity.
The expected&#xA0;outcomes were&#xA0;the following:&#xA0;enforcement capabilities of customs officers at border crossing points have increased; cooperation between customs officers and field officers from other authorities has been strengthened; cooperation between customs officers in supply countries and destination countries has been strengthened; good governance and integrity principles are further embedded in the &#x201C;corporate culture and operations&#x201D; in supply and destination countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47139" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCO CCF/World Customs Organization Customs Cooperation Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47139" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCO CCF/World Customs Organization Customs Cooperation Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade facilitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">932958.2063878482</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1294047.6670660672</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1124905.393560451</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">932958.2063878484</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1294047.667066067</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1124905.3935604512</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3926175.162903</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-28">932958.2063878482</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-28">1294047.6670660672</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">1124905.3935604512</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The WCO-EAC-CREATe project focused on designing and rolling-out a regional Authorized Economic Operators (AEO) Programme in the East African Community (EAC). The Programme counted over 100 regional AEOs that represent over $USD 3 billion in annual regional trade, 10% of regional trade and 10% of revenue collected in the region. Benefits provided to the regional AEOs range from reduced documentary requirements, faster clearance, and self-management of bonded warehouse to dedicated client relationship managers.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Accredited AEOs in the region have, hence, been able to reduce their costs of doing business. For example, a Tanzanian transporter has communicated that he saves an average of $USD1.8 Million since he joined the regional AEO Programme while AEOs in Burundi save in average $USD89, 950 per year since becoming AEOs. AEOs also have benefited from faster clearance time than non-AEOs at major ports in the region as confirmed in Mombasa where AEO cargoes are cleared in three days and seven hours, compare to non-AEO consignments that were being cleared on average five days and two hours.
WCO WACAM project in West Africa aimed to support the priority organisational development areas identified in the Regional Strategic Plan. The project supported five ECOWAS countries with the implementation of different WTO TFA Articles related to i.e. advanced rulings, publication of average time release study and establishment of national committee on trade facilitation. The project&#xA0;supported customs administrations in Burkina Faso, Gambia, Liberia, Mali, Niger and Senegal to establish competency based HRM system aligned with best practices and WCO standards. Burkina&#xA0;Faso, Cap Verde and Gambia adopted WCO organisational project management tools such as strategic dashboard and management&#xA0;reporting system. Also, Guinea was assisted to better engage with other border agencies in the area of enforcement and two inter-agency enforcement&#xA0;operations to seizures&#xA0;of arms, drugs, endangered species and fake medication.&#xA0;&#xA0;
The WCO-SACU Connect Project contributed to enhancing regional integration and trade facilitation through regional collaboration on customs modernisation. The project facilitated the ratification of SACU Annex E by all member countries. This led to the development of the SACU Regional IT Connectivity Blueprint/Roadmap and frameworks that now allows for live data exchange between South Africa and Eswatini. In building this platform, it was necessary to initiate a Customs-Trade Partnership through a regional Customs-Trade Forum and the concept of a Regional Preferred Trader Programme. A Lesotho Preferred Trader reported how their perishable imports now go straight to their store rather than being held up at the border resulting in reduced wastage rates and increased sales.
The risk management component of the project, through three regional enforcement operations, contributed to the detection of illicit trade transactions with a combined revenue recovery of over $USD 22 million, imported goods undervaluation from 266 transactions, 71 false import declarations, 14 arrests for smuggling cigarettes and tobacco, and seizures of 9 400 cigarette and 40 000 litres of un-denatured alcohol. &#xA0;
The&#xA0;WCO-INAMA&#xA0;project (2014-2018) was expected&#xA0;to result in&#xA0;targeted customs administrations to have improved: enforcement capacity related to CITES (the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora); capacity to collect, process and disseminate intelligence on CITES; awareness, knowledge and competencies on enforcement of CITES.&#xA0;
The most important achievements were the development of the Institutional Assessment Tool, as it will remain a powerful tool for administrations to continuously assess their CITES enforcement capacity. Moreover, the Basic and Advanced Intelligence trainings developed with the support of the project are also part of its most sustainable achievements. The seven diagnostic reports with detailed recommendations on action to strengthen enforcement, prepared with the support of Sweden in Burkina Faso, Cameroon, Kenya, Mozambique, Tanzania was also a good result as well as CITES training modules and experts accreditation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51050065" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
