<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5105007301-RSS-33181</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Tralac 2015-2020, fas II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tralac 2015-2020, phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida provided a mix of core and project support to tralac 2015-2020. Hence the objectives conincided with those of tralac as an organisation:
&quot;The Trade Law Centre NPC (tralac) is a regional capacity building think tank based in in the Western Cape region of South Africa. Established in 2001, tralac is a not-for-profit organisation, building trade-related capacity in Africa. We assist countries, especially in east and southern Africa, to improve their trade policy and governance so that trade can contribute to sustainable development outcomes in Africa.
OUR MISSION
Our mission is to &#x2018;build capacity for Africa to trade better.&#x2019; We build technical expertise and support institutional capacity for trade governance &#x2013; specifically international trade law and policy development across Africa; and are committed to the principles of rules-based governance at the national, regional and international levels.
OUR GOALS
Understanding that regional integration and trade are means, rather than ends, tralac&#x2019;s core goals are:
? to support rules-based governance committed to transparency and accountability and;? to support inclusive growth and sustainable development by building knowledge and capacity through the provision of quality research and analysis, building technical expertise and supporting policy dialogue.&#xA0;
WHAT WE DO
To support better, rules-based trade governance tralac works across three interconnected &#x2018;impact&#x2019; pillars which &#x2018;Inform, Capacitate and Empower&#x2019; key stakeholders in trade governance in Africa.
? Pillar I: Inform: We inform key stakeholders by producing and disseminating essential analysis on local, regional and international trade and integration developments.
? Pillar II: Capacitate: We capacitate key stakeholders by providing a wide range of training programmes to develop skills on policy analysis and development.
? Pillar III: Empower: We empower key stakeholders by facilitating and supporting stakeholder engagement. We host dialogue forums for discussion and debate on current trade and regional integration developments relevant to the African region.&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Trade Law Centre NPC (Tralac) &#xE4;r en icke-vinstdrivande organisation baserad i Sydafrika som utvecklar handelspolitisk och handelsr&#xE4;ttslig kapacitet i s&#xF6;dra och &#xF6;stra Afrika. Tralac bedriver kapacitetsbyggnad i regionen genom bevakning och analys av handelsfr&#xE5;gor, utbildnings-/tr&#xE4;ningsverksamhet, policydialog och delgivning av handelsrelaterade kunskaps- och analysprodukter till intressenter ber&#xF6;rda av handelspolitiska  processer i regionen.

Tralacs verksamhet syftar till att utveckla kapaciteten i s&#xF6;dra och &#xF6;stra Afrika s&#xE5; att denna region ska kunna tillhandah&#xE5;lla de positiva utvecklinseffekter internationell handel kan medf&#xF6;ra.

Organisationens verksamhet v&#xE4;gleds av ett strategiskt ramverk som str&#xE4;cker sig &#xF6;ver perioden 2015-2019 (sydafrikanskt budget&#xE5;r). Det strategiska ramverket inneh&#xE5;ller tre huvudpelare inom vilka programverksamheten sker: i) handelspolitisk bevakning och analys, ii) utbildning, iii) policydialog.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tralac develops trade law and trade policy capacity in Eastern and Southern Africa. Tralac is a not-for-profit registered Company in South Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TRALAC/Trade Law Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">949070.5040750715</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467480.8625021913</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">949070.5040750715</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">467480.8625021916</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-03-01">1423605.756112</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">949070.5040750715</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">467480.8625021913</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The data below provides a picture of how tralac has developed and grown during the agreement period. Sweden has been the main funder, complemented by USAID and GIZ.&#xA0;
Over the years tralac has had to learn and continuously adapt to the changes in the trade governance landscape, and the changing needs of various beneficiaries. This&#xA0;includes:? The use of different formats for publications to target various beneficiaries with different needs e.g., by introducing the use of infographics and mini policy guides; ? The introduction of new training programmes to address current skills shortages for trade policy officials including a tralac certificate programme, and the data science short course. Introductory courses&#xA0;to build capacity for key stakeholders often marginalised in trade governance, including the Women in Trade Governance programme; and the training of journalists to support accurate and informed trade reporting in the region.? The inclusion of a diverse profile of key stakeholders in the dialogue fora by facilitating events such as the tralac Annual Conference in different countries in Southern and Eastern Africa.
Unexpected results
The development of the AfCFTA has provided an opportunity for tralac to widen its scope of analysis both geographically and to a continent-wide trade agreement. Hence, its stakeholders and audience has grown. Tralac has been consulted by the AUC as an adviser and technical expert in the process.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Secondly, Covid necessitated further adaptation of work and delivery methods. Tralac turned the challenge into an opportunity to increase its outreach by delivering a number of online webinars on topical issues such as the AfCFTA. The popular Annual Conference also reached a larger public than before as it was held digitally, with recorded sessions.&#xA0;&#xA0;
As a result of these activities and interventions the awareness of tralac&apos;s work and participation across Africa and beyond has increased substantially. As can be seen below, their performance has improved throughout the funding period.


&#xA0;
Lastly a few words on tralac&apos;s contribution to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG)Tralac welcomed the adoption of the 2030 Agenda for sustainable development in September 2015. By advocating for regional integration and enhanced trade governance in Africa, they see their goals and core activities being closely aligned to the sustainable development agenda. The ethos of good (transparent and accountable) trade governance and strong institutions, articulated in Goal 16, lies at the heart of the work they do, and is essential for the realisation of sustainable outcomes through increased trade, economic growth and ultimately poverty alleviation.
Over the years the work has also focused on other areas recognised as markers for development in Africa such as youth, gender, climate change and the environment, increasingly featuring as important policy priorities on the continent.
#1: NO POVERTYThe African Continental Free Trade Agreement aims to boost intra &#x2013; Africa trade by facilitating trade through improved governance and improved trade facilitation. As such, a significant proportion of tralac&#x2019;s work focuses on the AfCFTA and the potential, if implemented, for unlocking growth and realising sustainable development outcomes in Africa.Tralac has also made available a collection of resources including the legal text, status of ratifications and negotiations on its website.#5: GENDER EQUALITYTralac continues to work towards the inclusion of women across all activities. Over the years tralac published several publications focusing on trade and gender &#x2013; including a mini policy guide titled &#x2018;Women and Trade: Towards gender equality in the AfCFTA&#x2019;; A gender responsive African Continental Free Trade Area (AfCFTA); and Women in Services Trade: Participation and Ownership, A Sub-Saharan African Focus to list a few. Tralac also launched the Women in Trade Governance Network in March 2019 (now the SheGovernsTrade development Programme) to ramp up efforts to support women inclusion in trade governance. The first residential programme for the Women in trade Governance was presented in July 2019.
#8: DECENT WORK AND ECONOMIC GROWTHEconomic growth is critical for the creation of employment for Africa&#x2019;s youth. Recognising that the youth are the future of Africa, tralac continues to support Africa&#x2019;s youth through the internship programme. Fifteen interns from various countries in Africa have taken part in the internship programme since 2015. On the research front, trade in services and the digital economy have long been identified as important drivers for economic growth in Africa. Along with several publications focusing on trade in services, tralac recently published a digital book on Trade in the digital economy, providing a collection of tralac&#x2019;s work over the past five years (updated where necessary) on the digital economy, e-commerce, information communication technology and related developments.
#9: INDUSTRY AND INFRASTRUCTUREGood trade governance needs good trade infrastructure. One of tralac&#x2019;s core research themes is trade facilitation, focusing particularly on the trade and transport facilitation needs of developing countries and LDCs in the region. Over the years tralac has published a selection of publications focusing on infrastructure, industrial development and the importance of trade facilitation including updates on the WTO Trade Facilitation Agreement and African countries and challenges in Southern Africa.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51050073" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
