<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-6105002401-RSS-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MDG4/5 Africa H4+</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">MDG4/5 Africa H4+</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till H4+ (UNICEF, UNFPA, WHO, UNAIDS, UN Women och V&#xE4;rldsbanken) f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; MDG 4 och 5 p&#xE5; landniv&#xE5; i sex l&#xE4;nder: Elfenbenskusten,  Etiopien, Guinea-Bissau, Kamerun, Liberia och Zimbabwe. Avtalspart &#xE4;r UNFPA som utsedd administrativ agent f&#xF6;r H4+-samarbetet. St&#xF6;det g&#xE5;r   f&#xF6;retr&#xE4;desvis till att implementera l&#xE4;ndernas nationella planer f&#xF6;r   m&#xF6;dra- och barnh&#xE4;lsa f&#xF6;r perioden 2012-2015.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to H4+ to achieve MDG 4 and 5 on country level in six         countries (above). Support is targeting service delivery in           accordance with the national plans for maternal, newborn and child    health for the period 2012-2015.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the H6 Joint Programme is to provide catalytic and strategic support to national health systems to address the root causes of poor maternal and child health outcomes in 10 countries: Burkina Faso, Cameroon, C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Ethiopia, Guinea-Bissau, Liberia, Sierra Leone, Zambia and Zimbabwe, along with global-level activities.
The programme implemented by the H6 Partnership (UNAIDS, UNFPA, UNICEF, UN Women, WHO and World Bank), has received support from Canada and the Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (Sida) for a total of $99.76 million during the period 2012 - 2018. Collaboration with Canada started in 2012 and ended in 2016, whereas collaboration with Sida covers 2013 to 2018. Therefore, this report reviews progress for 2017 for Sida support only.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Agency, Fund or Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 - By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.1 - Till 2030 minska m&#xF6;drad&#xF6;dligheten i v&#xE4;rlden till mindre &#xE4;n 70 d&#xF6;dsfall per 100 000 f&#xF6;rlossningar med levande barn.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B031" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">51707072.05011154</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">51707072.05011154</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-83921.5800580629</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-01">51707072.050111</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-28">51707072.05011154</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">-83921.54974408</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period, four of the H6 Joint Programme countries (Cameroon, Ethiopia, Guinea-Bissau and Liberia) received no-cost extensions for 2017 to complete planned activities. These were confined to evidence-informed upstream work to strengthen national strategies and plans. This improved the service environment of intervention facilities and enhanced skills for 1,227 individuals, to strengthen human resources for health.
In 2017, key results at the policy level included the following:? Cameroon disseminated the national policy on community health;? Ethiopia&#x2019;s accomplishments included the development of a national strategy to eliminate mother-to-child transmission of HIV, national guidelines on prevention of mother-to-child transmission of HIV (PMTCT) and congenital syphilis, a national roadmap for MNCH quality of care and a plan of action to eliminate preventable obstetric haemorrhagedeaths.? Guinea-Bissau reported the development of its National Every Newborn Action Plan &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0; (ENAP); national guidelines for the evaluation of the quality of maternal, child andnewborn care; and the assessment of equity in immunization in three regions (Gabu,Tombali and SAB) along with recommendations to improve coverage. The Health Sector Coordination Committee at the national level and regional level also received support tofunction effectively; the committees are under the leadership of senior politicalrepresentatives (governors and regional secretaries).
In Liberia, the National RMNCAH 2015&#x2013;2016 operational plan was reviewed and the 2017&#x2013;18 plan was then developed.
In 2017, progress for an improved service environment included the following:? Blood transfusion bags (10,000) were purchased for use in 30 districts, including support to collection of donor blood and quality assurance in C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire; In Cameroon, newborn resuscitation kits were distributed to the 91 intervention facilities in the far north region; Autoclaves were installed and made operational to ensure the quality of maternal and newborn services in 19 maternity health facilities of Ethiopia; Guinea-Bissau reported procurement and distribution of essential drugs, instruments, and medical consumables to 75 health facilities in seven intervention health regions for the provision of quality mother and child health services; Efforts to revive maternal and newborn care in six counties of Liberia continued in 2017, where installation of medical equipment finalized in 18 intervention health facilities and a need-based running water supply facility was established at seven intervention health facilities. In six intervention counties, 25 health facilities were made functional for the provision of RMNCAH services, contributing to the Ebola recovery phase of the national health system.
In 2017, key results in human resources for health included the following:? During 2017, about 1,227 health functionaries received training in a wide range of skills in the areas of emergency obstetric and newborn care (EmONC), Integrated Management of Newborn and Childhood Illnesses (IMNCI), family planning, PMTCT, newborn care, community awareness and pre-service training. This includes enhancing quality and capacities of the training institutions and trainers.
In 2017, results in health service delivery included the following:? Cameroon focused on facilities in an area facing insecurity through community-basedinterventions and outreach services.? C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire successfully integrated family planning, voluntary HIV testing and cervical cancer screening with RMNCAH programme priorities.? Ethiopia reported that 105 patients with obstetric fistula were repaired during 2017 at health facilities in Jimma and Arsi University. Transport was provided for the patients and their guardians to enable them to travel to the health facility and back home after the repair. This has restored the women&#x2019;s good health, and most are now advocates providing information to other women in the community.? Guinea-Bissau&#x2019;s national healthcare system continued to face many challenges in 2017 due to a dynamic external environment. With H6 support, the country strengthened health facilities to provide services and ensure improved health outcomes and strengthened referral linkages. Nine international experts for obstetric, pediatric and anesthesiology specialists were brought in to build the capacity of national health care providers and improve services for maternal, newborn and child health care. During 2017, the pending refurbishment of intervention facilities was completed in five health facilities, including construction of a maternity waiting home in Buba and in Catio; one surgery room in Buba; and one health centre and a residence for health care providers in G&#xE2;-Para. In addition, a mechanism to conduct client satisfaction assessment was established in Sim&#xE3;o Mendes National Hospital, aimed at measuring the level of satisfaction of users (especially women). The results of the assessment were used to inform policymakers about the adverse effect of the user fees for pregnant women, women affected by HIV, and survivors of sexual and gender-based violence.? In Liberia, the programme supported Ministry of Health officials to conduct supportive supervision, coaching and mentoring of skilled providers as well as community cadres. The objective was to ensure that RMNCAH service delivery at the intervention facilities conforms to the quality standards. As a result, the intervention facilities reported a significant upward trend in institutional deliveries attended by skilled providers, from 2,953 in the first quarter of 2017 to 4,642 in the second quarter.
At the global level in 2017, the H6 continued to mobilize political support for the Every Woman Every Child movement and for the health targets of the Sustainable Development Goals. Advocacy continued among national governments across the H6 Partnership&#x2019;s 75 focus countries. The end line evaluation findings were effectively disseminated, reaching a variety of stakeholders including development partners and the donor community at the global level, as well as national-level partners in the ministries of health, academia, NGOs and implementing partners, among others. The resource mobilization efforts and discussions were initiated with potential donors for future collaboration.
The H6 Partnership contributed to the implementation of several new global efforts. These included global strategies like the Global Strategy for Women&#x2019;s, Children&#x2019;s and Adolescents&#x2019; Health; Global Financing Facility (GFF); Every Newborn Action Plan (ENAP) and Ending Preventable Maternal Mortality (EPMM). H6 further received a five-year extension of collaborative funding from the French Muskoka Initiative for countries of West and Central Africa. Ten million Euros have been allocated for the first year, with budgets for the following years to be decided on an annual basis.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="61050024" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
