<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100009802-RSS-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">SAIIA,  South Africa Institute of International   Affairs, K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d 2013-2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAIIA, South Africa Institute of International Affairs, Core support 2013-2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAIIA&#x2019;s 2013-2017 strategic plan was significantly shaped by the external evaluation that was conducted by SIDA in 2011 to assess the impact of core support on the achievement of its programmatic goal &#x2018;a well-governed, peaceful, economically sustainable and globally engaged Africa&#x2019;. The 2011 external evaluation flagged several areas related to SAIIA&#x2019;s internal structuring and external positioning and profile that required strengthening &#x2013; in particular its online representation, the mainstreaming of M&amp;E in all its programmatic activities, the development of closer links with universities, specifically the University of the Witwatersrand, and its financial sustainability strategy. As noted earlier, SAIIA&#x2019;s 2013-2017 Strategy was organised on the basis of 7 thematic areas and strategic pillars, namely: ?
Pillar 1: Research Agenda and Programme: Strategic Objective 1 To ensure that SAIIA remains a leading research think tank on policy issues related to Africa&#x2019;s governance, economic development, stability and voice in international Affairs ?
Pillar 2: Strategic Dissemination: Strategic Objective 2: To enhance SAIIA&#x2019;s impact on policy issues through a targeted dissemination strategy ?
Pillar 3: Public Benefit: Strategic Objective 3: To fulfil SAIIA&#x2019;s mandate as a public benefit organisation and enhance public education, including youth education, on international affairs ?
Pillar 4: Human Resources: Strategic Objective 4: To strengthen SAIIA&#x2019;s organisational capacity, particularly in relation to its management and the attraction, retention, development and motivation of its chief intellectual capital &#x2013; its staff ?
Pillar 5: Monitoring and Evaluation: Strategic Objective 5: To build SAIIA as a learning organisation that works within a results-based management framework ?
Pillar 6: Financial Sustainability: Strategic Objective 6: To advance organisational financial stability through continuous improvement of its financial systems and through the growth of SAIIA&#x2019;s income base and the diversification of its funding ?
Pillar 7: Information Technology: Strategic Objective 7: To improve the effectiveness and efficiency of SAIIA through appropriate use of information technology</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Institute of International Affairs (SAIIA) is an        African regional organisation active within the area of peace and     security, with special focus on policy analysis and research. SAIIA   receives core support totalling SEK 14 000 000 from Sida for the      period May 2013-June 2016.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">South African Institute of International Affairs (SAIIA) &#xE4;r en        afrikansk regional organisation verksam inom omr&#xE5;det fred och         s&#xE4;kerhet, med s&#xE4;rskild fokus p&#xE5; policyanalys och forskning. SAIIA f&#xE5;r k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d om totalt SEK 14 000 000 av Sida f&#xF6;r perioden maj 2013-juni  2016.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAIIA/South African Institute of International Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAIIA/South African Institute of International Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-01">460603.082969</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-28">351000.351000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAIIA works towards the overall goal by generating African-based policy analysis relevant to a rapidly changing global setting that supports accountable and good governance and an economically vibrant and stable Africa. SAIIA&apos;s research on governance and democracy, economic diplomacy, the engagement of global powers in Africa, South African foreign policy and key African drivers, and lastly, global governance and sustainable development support this goal. This has translated into the production of 273 formal, peer-reviewed written publications by the institute of the implementation period, broken down as follows: 97 Policy Briefings, 118 Occasional Papers, 46 Policy Insights and 12 Research Reports which were disseminated in 2013 through 51 events, in 2014 through 72 events, in 2015 through 61 events, in 2016 through 57 events and in the first semester of 2017 through 17 events. The events included a mix of international conferences, closed workshops, policy dialogues, members briefings, careers evenings, youth events and media briefings.
From a programmatic perspective SAIIA has established two African networks that support the engagement of its Resource Governance programme and the work of its Economic diplomacy programme. The Governance of Africa&#x2019;s Resources Research Network (GARN) was established in 2010, and consists of a network of 12 research institutes from across the African continent that share an interest in promoting the responsible, equitable and sustainable exploitation of Africa&#x2019;s vast natural resources.
SAIIA&#x2019;s foreign policy work focuses on the nexus between foreign policy and development in Africa and the degree to which a new African foreign policy system is emerging that encourages these conditions. Specifically, the programme seeks to produce a body of work that assists policymakers, the business community and civil society in South Africa and Africa in identifying avenues for cooperation to advance regional peace and security, development and economic growth.
SAIIA&#x2019;s work on Governance and the African Peer Review Mechanism (APRM) has been conducted jointly with the Electoral Institute for Sustainable Democracy in Africa (EISA) since 2012. The aim of SAIIA&#x2019;s intervention strategy is to improve the ability of APRM to contribute to governance reforms, institutions and processes in Africa. SAIIA is broadly acknowledged as a leading independent authority on the APRM, having worked in over 20 African countries since 2002 to help CSOs, governments and researchers understand and maximise the opportunities that the APRM presents and to open up a national debate on the key governance challenges across four sectors, political, economic, socioeconomic and corporate governance. SAIIA has used the APRM as a prism through which to analyse critical emerging governance issues.
SAIIA&#x2019;s resource governance programme seeks to strengthen natural resource governance and climate change policy responses to ensure inclusive, sustainable and equitable development in Africa. Overarching research themes are: mining and development; Africa&#x2019;s energy mix and the green economy; and integrated governance of the commons. Within these broad themes, the programme addresses specific resource sectors including mining, energy, forestry, fisheries and wildlife. The programme focuses primarily on the countries of SADC, but has also conducted work in Ghana, Ethiopia, Uganda and Kenya. The programme engages with a range of national, regional and global stakeholders, for example the African Mineral Development Centre, the SADC Secretariat, the African Union Commission, and the Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative, among others.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000098" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
