<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100014302-RSS-16064</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIDS and Rights Alliance for Southern Africa      (ARASA) 2013-2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AIDS and Rights Alliance for Southern Africa      (ARASA) 2013-2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till AIDS &amp; Rights Alliance f&#xF6;r s&#xF6;dra Afrika &#xE4;r att t&#xE4;cka &#xE5;ren   2013-2017. Verksamheten kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras i SADC-regionen med     Arasa s 89 partnerorganisationer. Dessa aktiviteter kommer att        fokusera p&#xE5; kapacitetsuppbyggnad och opinionsbildning f&#xF6;r en          m&#xE4;nniskor&#xE4;ttsbaserad strategi f&#xF6;r TB, HIV, h&#xE4;lsa och SRHR.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to the AIDS &amp; Rights Alliance for Southern Africa is to cover the years 2013-2017. The activities will be implemented in SADC       region with ARASA&apos;s 89 partner organisations. These activities will   focus on capacity building and advocacy for a human rights based      approach to TB, HIV, health and SRHR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To ensure that&#xA0; legal,&#xA0; policy and social environments exist in 18 countries of Southern and Eastern Africa in which people living with HIV and TB and key populations most at risk, &#xA0; access acceptable, affordable and quality SRHR, HIV, TB prevention treatment and care services.
Civil society organisations in Southern and Eastern Africa effectively advocate for a conducive policy and legal environment, and
Service providers and policy makers respond to&#xA0; human rights abuses and violations (SRHR, HIV and TB) at national, regional and global levels - with&#xA0; particular focus on people living with HIV and TB and key populations at higher risk of contracting HIV and TB.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARASA/Aids &amp; Rights Alliance for Southern Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARASA/Aids &amp; Rights Alliance for Southern Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3 - By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.3 - Senast 2030 utrota epidemierna av aids, tuberkulos, malaria och f&#xF6;rsummade tropiska sjukdomar samt bek&#xE4;mpa hepatit, vattenburna sjukdomar och andra smittsamma sjukdomar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">12569.7167597195</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">12569.7167597195</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-4081.566174794</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-01">13238.807345</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-28">12569.7167597195</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">-4081.566174794</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results reported in this memo are drawn mainly from the Evaluation of the Strategic Plan 2013 - 2017,&#xA0; Annual Reports, meetings&#xA0; and Internal ARASA studies.&#xA0;
Capacity for policy makers and CSOs was enhanced which in turn contributed to influencing policies through legal reforms, policy shifts&#xA0; and social change in communities. In Angola ARASA contributed to the revision of the Penal Code. This was achieved through collaborative efforts with&#xA0; SADC-PF&#xA0; and other partners.
The co-hosting of&#xA0; the SADC-PF Regional Standing Committees by ARASA and SADC PF in May 2016 contributed to additional capacity strengthening for SADC Standing Committees. &#xA0;
ARASA&#xA0; was a critical partner in the process of providing technical assistance during the development of&#xA0; Minimum Standards&#xA0; adopted at the 44th Plenary Assembly Session of the SADC Parliamentary Forum in Maputo in December 2018.
In collaboration with UNDP, ARASA undertook the Legal Environment Assessment (LEA)&#xA0; which&#xA0; highlighted the existence of punitive laws criminalizing&#xA0; same sex relationships in the region. The LEA was key in informing the strategy towards advocacy for law reform and the development of&#xA0; enabling legal and regulatory frameworks for national responses to addressing Sexual Reproductive Health and Rights(SRHR).&#xA0;
Along with&#xA0;Human Rights Institutions, parliamentarians and judges, UNDP and SADC-PF,&#xA0; ARASA advocated for removal of legal barriers,&#xA0; repeal and reform of punitive and discriminatory laws. Duty bearers and parliamentarians were specifically targeted by ARASA and Section 27 through SADC-PF on the domestication and implementation of internationally agreed protocols regarding&#xA0; respect for Human rights.&#xA0;
ARASA Aggressively advocated for the rights to health services for LGBTI people and other key populations. Together with partner CSOs, ARASA&#xA0; provided background material &#xA0; in court proceedings in Botswana &#xA0; where the High Court &#xA0;ultimately ruled in favour of the LGBTI community. &#xA0; In Tanzania, ARASA worked with CSOs and UNAIDS to protect rights defenders.&#xA0;
Contributed to greater realisation of health rights for key populations and improvement in service delivery in countries where ARASA had country programmes (Kenya and Uganda). In these countries, ARASA pushed for law reforms to protect the rights of key and vulnerable populations and increased access to justice. In Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania however, the environment for key populations still remains hostile because of deep rooted hostility and prejudice against this group.&#xA0;
Working with MPs and Speakers of various Parliaments in the region and&#xA0; in collaboration with SADC-PF and other partners, ARASA &#xA0; strengthened the capacity of civil society organisations in Angola on issues around key populations and access to SRHR services. Following a series of training of 22 CSO partners in Angola,&#xA0; &#xA0;partners&#xA0; became key&#xA0; advocates for&#xA0; the rights of key populations which ultimately contributed to the adoption of the new Penal Code.
Contributed to the&#xA0; the passage of Resolution 275 by the African Commission for Human and People&#x2019;s Rights (ACHPR) in Luanda, Angola&#xA0; on the Protection against Violence and other Human Rights Violations against Persons on the basis of their real or imputed Sexual Orientation or Gender Identity.&#xA0;
Increased monitoring of government actions to ensure the protection, respect and upholding of&#xA0; human rights in the context of national responses to HIV. &#xA0;
Challenged Intellectual Property Laws&#xA0; and urged the&#xA0; South African government&#xA0; &#xA0;to address barriers related to&#xA0; high costs of&#xA0; accessing patented drugs for HIV&#xA0; treatment.&#xA0;
Introduced and tackled&#xA0; difficulty&#xA0; topics (sensitive conversations) through&#xA0; Community Health Advocates (CHAs) who interacted directly&#xA0; with communities. Lessons harvested from community conversations formed the basis for advocacy at national and regional levels. Through CHAs,&#xA0;ARASA reached more than 1000 community members - in Zimbabwe, Botswana, DRC, South Africa, Mozambique and Kenya.&#xA0;Country Programme Coordinators and&#xA0; CHAs reported enhanced health and human rights literacy, thereby increasing&#xA0; monitoring of access to health services by communities. &#xA0;
Actively participated in the collection of evidence adduced in cases involving LGBTI people and their denial to&#xA0; access&#xA0; treatment.&#xA0; &#xA0; In&#xA0; collaboration with UNAIDS, ARASA actively participated in litigations in Tanzania for violation of human rights for LGBTI communities&#xA0; who were persecuted and prosecuted&#xA0; on account of their sexual orientation.&#xA0;
Between 2013 and 2019, programmes in Malawi, Mauritius, Mozambique, Kenya, Tanzania, Uganda, Zambia and Zimbabwe were supported financially, in building advocacy skills and capacity for their national CSOs&#xA0; which resulted in increased numbers of&#xA0; knowledgeable civil&#xA0; society leaders across the region. Trained leaders became advocates for human rights and this formed the basis for&#xA0; a broader social mobilisation and push for the right to health.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000143" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061702" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3700000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional SRHR 2015-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt SRHR 2015-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
