<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5103008101-RSS-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET phase II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FEMNET phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening African women&apos;s rights with focus on the right to safe and legal abortion, abandonment of child marriages and abandonment of Femal Genital Mutilation (FGM/C). This will be done through strategic policy incluence in collaboration with the African women&apos;s rights network FEMNET and through capacity building of its&apos; members of women&apos;s rights organisations on the African continent.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka afrikanska kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter med fokus p&#xE5; r&#xE4;tten till s&#xE4;ker och laglig abort, avskaffande av barn&#xE4;ktenskap och avskaffande av kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning. Detta genom strategiskt p&#xE5;verkansarbete och policyutveckling i samarbete med det afrikanska kvinnor&#xE4;ttsn&#xE4;tverket FEMNET, samt genom kapacitetsuppbyggnad av dess medlemmar av kvinnor&#xE4;ttsorganisationer p&#xE5; den afrikanska kontinenten med fokus p&#xE5; sex l&#xE4;nder (Zambia, Mozambique, Rwanda, Guinea Conakry, Liberia och Tanzania).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET/The African Women&#x2019;s Development and Communication Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South of Sahara, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.3 - Avskaffa alla skadliga sedv&#xE4;njor, s&#xE5;som barn&#xE4;ktenskap, tidiga &#xE4;ktenskap och tv&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ktenskap samt kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.3 - Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.5098959771</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1797819.3508814604</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">868649.358828192</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.1700011697</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">575347.5098959792</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1797819.3508814592</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211435</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">868649.3588281921</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-01">5382005.382005</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">1170001.17000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">575347.5098959771</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">951786.7151725378</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">846032.6357089225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">651487.0191211441</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">868649.358828192</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51030081_51030081_51030081-GrantAgreement-FEMNETPhaseII.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51030081_51030081_51030081-DecisiononContribution-FEMNETPhaseII.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET led and coordinated the Africa Civil Society 25-year Review of the Beijing Declaration and Platform for Action. FEMNET as a lead continental CSOs convener, invested in ensuring African women and girls are informed on the process and are equitably engaged in the national review processes, which in many countries has minimal participation of the CSOs in the government review processes. During the continental review in October 2019, FEMNET convened more than 400 women to engage with their governments as they consolidate the continental Beijing +25 report. Critically, FEMNET on behalf of African CSOs, was part of the Beijing+25 technical drafting team charged with refining the African governments political declaration, key messages and priority actions on the B+25 review. FEMNET received over 500 requests to attend the African Beijing+25 CSOs Forum in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia and mobilized and coordinated the registration of over 200 gender advocates, women&#x2019;s rights activists and feminists. Close to 70% of the people were in the space for the first time, including young women, veterans/elderly women, sex workers, LBTIQ, women from informal settlements, women with disabilities, media, representatives of trade unions, grassroots, faith groups, cultural and religious leaders, politicians and feminists. Also of note is that only 3 countries (Tunisia, Cameroon and Senegal) compiled national CSOs parallel reports for the Beijing+25 review which were submitted to FEMNET. In comparison, during the Beijing+20 and Beijin+15 reviews, there were 6 national and 13 national shadows reported produced, respectively. FEMNET learned in 2019 that the national reviews fall short in creating national political momentum to inspire shadow reporting. The reporting processes in most countries were by and large led by governments, supported by UN Women with CSOs &#x2018;consulted&#x2019; and not treated as integral part of the review, which meant, the tripartite nature of the engagement (Governments, Development Partners and CSOs) was recorded to be weak. In the July 2019 AU Summit held in Niger, which was also the first AU summit to be coordinated by regional commissions following AU reforms, FEMNET through GIMAC platform, called for the SRHR of refugees, returnees and internally displaced people in their diversity. To ensure outcome documents captured in detail SRHR issues, FEMNET volunteered to seat in the outcome document drafting team. Out of 19 outcome statements, 3 focus on SRHR. &#xA0; FEMNET in close collaboration with the Solidarity of African Women&#x2019;s Rights, (SOAWR), continue to push for the universal ratification of the Maputo Protocol. By 2020, 11 countries had yet to ratify the Protocol. In December 2019, FEMNET and SOAWR members partnered with the African Union Women, Gender and Development Directorate (WGDD) to organize two High level advocacy missions in Sudan and Madagascar and held discussions with the chair of the Botswana Women&#x2019;s Parliamentary Caucus. The missions yielded successful results with all the countries committing to work on the process of ratification. In Sudan a multi stakeholder approach training outlined the major hinderances to ratification that both the Ministry and civil society need to work on. In Madagascar the civil society actors are eager to support the government but will need additional support and capacity to push for ratification. Similarly, with Botswana the new government &#x2018;promised&#x2019; to ratify a High level mission and training of the Women&#x2019;s Parliamentary Caucus and Civil society is being planned. Collective efforts will be intensified, including to strengthen and create awareness on the role of the African Human Rights System.SRHR-services &#xA0; FEMNET has been supporting religious and cultural leaders in undertaking community level advocacy in 3 countries including Kenya, Guinea and Malawi as part of the efforts to ending harmful cultural practices such as female genital mutilation and child marriage. In order to build strong understanding of SRHR among religious and cultural leaders and strengthen their engagement with sexual minority groups, FEMNET organized in 2019, the first Kenya National SRHR Dialogue in Nairobi - where religious and cultural leaders met with representatives of LGBTIQ community, sex workers and safe abortion activists. Religious and cultural leaders had an opportunity to learn about the challenges sexual minorities face, especially the stigma by religious and cultural leaders. The safe abortion advocates were able to bring the reality of unsafe abortion and its effects on girls and women. Sex workers on their part advised religious and cultural leaders not to treat them as outcasts. They reiterated that religious and cultural leaders are also consumers of their services but are always at the forefront in condemning them in public. Participants in their diversities agreed that sexual and reproductive health and rights are diverse and they need to be respected and promoted, and that religious and cultural leaders must strengthen their understanding of the SRHR in its totality from a human rights stand point and not base it on religious dogma or cultural beliefs. &#x201C;I didn&#x2019;t know that LGBTIQ people look like any other person you meet in your daily routine. I could not distinguish them from other human being of the community&#x201D; &#x2013; Reverend Samuel Kirigia, Chuka ACK Parish, Meru-Kenya. In 2019, FEMNET also organized a learning/exchange visit to Kenya for BAI implementing partners to have a first-hand experiences on how religious and cultural leaders can be engaged in promoting SRHR for women and girls in Kenya. At least 9 WROs from Kenya, Uganda, Malawi, Zambia, Mozambique, Guinea, Liberia, Tunisia and Tanzania reported improved skills in engaging with religious and cultural leaders and men and boys in promoting SRHR for women and girls. Religious and cultural leaders from Kenya had an opportunity to also learn the role played by religious and cultural leaders in other countries. Participants reflected on the engagement of men to men in the broader women&#x2019;s movement, for example currently there are very few known platforms that bring together initiatives that work with men and boys in collaboration with women&#x2019;s rights organizations to promote SRHR in Africa. Participants requested FEMNET to continue to address capacity needs for organizations working with men and boys and exploring practical ways to sustainably engage men in the SRHR movement A practical yet ambitious follow-up plan was created and agreed to strengthen the engagement of men and boys in SRHR movement. In May 2019, FEMNET convened a Media Training on Sexual Reproductive and Health Rights (SRHR) with 45 journalists from across Africa. The participants also included 6 FEMNET partner organizations who are implementing the SRHR programmes on various issues such as ending early and forced child marriage, ending female genital mutilation, advocating for safe abortion among others. The primary aim of the training was to &#x201C;Support the media in Africa to co-create SRHR narratives&#x201D;. A specific journalists network within the six supported countries (Rwanda, Zambia, Tanzania, Liberia, Guinea and Mozambique) for sustained media SRHR focus has been launched. The FEMNET SRHR media Network of the&#xA0;six BAI implementing partners is currently unpacking and making use of the FEMNET&#xA0;SRHR Media Manual a critical point of reference in media reporting. Having a basis to&#xA0;guide SRHR media networks has the potential to galvanize significant impact in the way&#xA0;African Media present and report on SRHR.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51030081" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061702" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3240000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional SRHR 2015-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt SRHR 2015-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
