<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-18/3420/RA1-2018/Health/NGO/9564</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparedness response project in Far Al Udayn district of Ibb governorate and Shara&apos;b Ar Rawna district of Taiz governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGO&#x2019;s (YDN) is proposing to implement a 6-month project that aims to response and increase the access of vulnerable persons in both IDP and host communities to Health services through coordination with Taizamp Ibb GHO&#x2019;s to response of preparedness&#x2019; plan of Health cluster in Sharab Ar Wana district in Taiz governorate, and Fara&#x2019; Al-Udayn in Ibb governorate.
The project rationale is based on facts that target governorates are well prepared to manage timely and coordinated humanitarian response to the IDPs which may flee because of conflict and ensure the national sub clusters in Ibb hub with covers the humanitarian response to all districts under Ibb UN hub. 
The project also is built on the assumption that women and girls in both IDPs and host communities fall under more heavier burden of poverty and other forms of vulnerability and takes for granted that they have very low status more as IDPs and thus either unaware or unable to access Health services with assumes that there is still need for local level details need assessment on medicines vulnerability and types of health services needed in Sharab Ar Wana district in Taiz governorate, and Fara&#x2019; Al-Udayn in Ibb governorate.
 
Working with the conceptual framework of PHC referral systems at national level for several years, YDN has been putting into ongoing food, Health amp Nutrition project in Sharab Ar Wana district in Taiz governorate, and Fara&#x2019; Al-Udayn in Ibb governorate innovative approach to community based a control mechanism which heavily relies on community mobilization in support of identified and access of  need health services. 
YDN through pioneering experience of  manage or submitted Health services via implemented various projects in targeted districts and  has strong capacity to implement the main following activities:
1)	Procurement and pre-positioning of stocks of medication and medical supplies at central and hub levels with focus on the Governorates with conflict and cholera cases.
2)	Conducting in-service refresher training for the health staff on surveillance, case management, first aid, trauma care etc.
YDN through coordination with various health stakeholders and partners in targeted districts,  will manage and implement the main mentioned activities in collaboration with health sub-cluster in Ibb will provide the most needed lifesaving assistance to displaced people based on DTM provided weekly updates on IDPs movements (figures, trends) to guide the Ibb humanitarian partners. 
YDN through OCHA coordination with local authority in both Taiz and Ibb Governorates, will ensure the facilitation to Humanitarian partners to carry out timely response which it&#x2019;s expected that, most districts which may receive IDPs continue to be accessible by humanitarian actors.  
In terms of experience, most of YDN projects during the last 10 years included large-scale procurement procedures that enabled YDN&apos;s team to experience all the procedures of tenders and other types of procurement activities and to deal with various local/international vendors of different fields of work varied from food items to medicines/medical supplies and equipment.
Since 2017, YDN managed procurement processes with a total cost of 1,278,499 $ among which, 1,182,586 $ was through public tendering processes. Previously, YDN has implemented a technical training centers project funded by MTN telecoms that included processes of procurement with a total of 1 Million $ and was done through contracting with international vendors.
Through the implementation of its various projects funded by HFU or other donors, YDN have managed to develop an adequate procurement capacity based on a sound public procurement system. Such system includes: 
1) Procurement rules and procedures that are simple, clear and efficient 
2) Effective procurement/logistics staff to conduct procurement plans and procedures 
3) Competent contracts management</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khaled Mutahar Anka&apos;a</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Branches Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>770907150</telephone>
   <email>kh.anqaa@ydnorg.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.05521633 44.26319019</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-10">499997.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-9564">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-10">499997.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303449874">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-20">249998.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303729724">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-18">249998.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1105878210">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-24">37553.22</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Development Network for NGOs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
