<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-18/3420/RA1-2018/FSAC/UN/9557</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency support for agriculture-based livelihoods through preservation of livestock assets</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the conflict began in mid-March 2015, the food security situation has rapidly deteriorated. The food insecurity levels continue their upward trend with approximately 17.8 million Yemenis (61% of the population). This dire situation represents 5% increase in needs compared to the needs in 2017. The significant level of needs is attributed to the depreciation of the Yemeni currency, severe disruption and loss of livelihoods and income (including suspension of public servants&#x2019; salaries since September 2016). The precarious situation has been further exacerbated by large IDP caseloads that have virtually stretched the coping mechanisms of the internally displaced households and host families to the brink of exhaustion, leading to extreme and elevated hunger conditions across the country. Moreover, livelihoods of a significant segment of the population dependent on agriculture has been disrupted. Local food production has been severely compromised with indications that the Oct-Nov harvest will most likely not offset the local cereal production deficit. According to FAO, the cultivated land under rain fed condition decreased by 11 percent, irrigated land under cereals decreased by 40 percent, while production of small ruminants has reduced by 25 percent for both sheep and goats compared with pre - crisis period. The livestock mortality rate increased by 20 percent compared to pre-crisis. This was due to the absence of public services in particular the disease control campaigns including disease surveillance and vaccination and destruction of infrastructure of veterinary services.
This intervention is designed to reduce food insecurity of the most vulnerable households and at risk groups by providing emergency livelihoods assistance aimed at supporting livestock production by supplying animal feed (Hodeidah and Raymah governorates) and vaccination of small ruminants (Hodeidah, Raymah, Al-Maharah and Hajjah governorates).
The project intends to target a total of 60,300 internally-displaced households (HHs) and host communities in four governorates, including 4,000 HHs in Hodeidah and Raymah governorates to be supported with animal feed. In total, 422,100 people will have a direct benefit from this project.  
FAO and other international organizations such as IMC and ICRC started to prepare and implement preventive immunization programs for the main animal epidemics which are peste des petits ruminants (PPR) and sheep and goat pox (SGP) to reduce the effects of the spread of epidemic diseases which affect the animal health and production and thus reflected on farmer&#x2019;s income. Although vaccination campaigns which were carried out in some governorates and still ongoing in some governorates by various organizations, but they were able to cover only about 70% of the country&apos;s livestock population. Therefore, the project proposes to support animal health through implementing complementary preventive vaccinations campaigns against major diseases of small ruminants in line with the government strategy for vaccination against PPR, sheep and goat pox as well as treatment of animals against internal and external parasites. The total numbers of animals expected to be covered by these campaigns is 1,125,900 (each animal will receive all three types of treatment). With an average livestock ownership of 20 heads per household, the campaigns are expected to benefit approximately 56,300 livestock farmers. 
Addressing animal health and feeding issues will have a direct impact on the livelihoods of livestock-dependent vulnerable households across the project areas. The intervention will improve livestock health and fertility, which will increase milk and meat production, hence, promoting income generation. 
Supply of animal feed and vaccination campaign will be supplemented by awareness raising sessions on improved animal feeding techniques, prevention of animal diseases and treatment practices to maximize the effect of the project results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate General of Animal Health and Veterinary Quarantine (DGAHVQ) under the MAI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rawabi AL-Nahdah Developmental Foundation ( RADF )</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SENIOR LIVESTOCK DEVELOPMENT OFFICER FAORNE</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>friederike.mayen@fao.org</telephone>
   <email>Friederike (FAORNE)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SALAH HAJJ HASSAN</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO Representative in Yemen</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+967) 736 600 955</telephone>
   <email>Salah.ElHajjHassan@fao.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="28">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Maharah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.59344354 51.59013758</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="31">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raymah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.59985617 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-13">1050000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400286890">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-21">141321.7</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-9557">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-13">1050000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303458304">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-24">1050000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
