<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-18/3420/RA1-2018/Health/NGO/9561</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancement of Taizz  Governorate Health Preparedness Capacity in Maqbanah, Al Mukha, Al Wazi&apos;iyah , Jabal Habashy, Shara&apos;b Ar Rawnah, Mawza and At Tazya&apos;ah districts.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be prioritized to support Health Cluster preparedness plan 2018 to address the most critical lifesaving activities in targeted locations of Maqbanah, Al Mukha, Al Wazi&apos;iyah , Jabal Habashy, Shara&apos;b Ar Rawnah, Mawza and At Tazya&apos;ah districts in Taizz governorate. Outbreak response and Strategic distribution of essential medicines and medical supplies ( ORS, beds, IV fluids and equipment for rehydration, antibiotics and other medicines for cholera case-management ) is a top priority in the Health Cluster, in order to stop the current epidemic and prevent further waves of cholera epidemic so as to reduce morbidity and mortality by way of advancing epidemic preparedness, early detection of an outbreak and to ensure boys, girls, women, men and elders among vulnerable populations (IDPs, and the host population) have access to Humanitarian basic health services through effective preparedness and timely response and strengthening the control and prevention of the cholera outbreak in particular hard to reach areas of the 7 target districts. The planned interventions aim to mitigate impact of essential medicines and supplies stock out through the core pipeline target the highest risk districts affected by the ongoing cholera outbreaks. 
Under the leading of National and Sub-National Health Cluster, this project will enhance the technical aspect of IYCY response to the current acute emergency with focus on cholera outbreaks response through set up cholera emergency contingency stock of medicines and medical supplies as well as enhance health system capacity to adequately respond to outbreaks through refresher training for the health staff on surveillance, case management and will further support the health cluster to perform its role. Key focus will be to rapidly Procurement of the medical supplies to respond to acute emergencies, support outbreak response and disease surveillance in identified areas in Taizz, In addition the project will support the distribution of the lifesaving health supplies and ensure strategic pre-positioning of the much needed drugs in key locations reporting the high needs of health and critical gaps.
In addition to direct implementation of the project detailed above, and with the aim to improve the effectiveness of this project as well as the humanitarian community&#x2019;s understanding of needs in hard to reach areas, IYCY proposes project  will focus on districts in Taiz with conflict and cholera cases in both sites of conflict parties between Al-Shari&apos;a and Ansar Allah, from Al-Shari&apos;a sites IYCY has already warehouses in Taiz City that will allow IYCY to directly reach vulnerable populations (IDPs, and the host population) in districts under control of Al-Shari&apos;a and to the areas difficult to reach from other districts as well as IYCY has warehouses in Al-Houban and Shara&apos;b Ar Rawnah districts which will also allow IYCY to directly reach vulnerable populations in districts under control of Ansar Allah and to the areas difficult to reach from other districts. Therefore, due to security constraints on the main road this makes it challenging to mobilize resources on time when urgently needed. Finally, by engaging existing community networks, a variety of stakeholders from different political and ideological backgrounds, and the existing aid and government structures in place, in close coordination with National and Sub-national health cluster, IYCY will develop an extensive risk register to include also a context assessment, actor mapping, and thorough investigation of conflict dynamics to inform a comprehensive access strategy that allows IYCY to directly reach vulnerable populations in Taiz. Interrelated response is taking place for alleviation the outbreak conduct the activities based on the IYCY polices and implementation guidelines accompanied with great commitment OCHA operational and financial policies and regulations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abduljabbar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967772636531</telephone>
   <email>abduljabbar.hassan@iycy.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-09">497755.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-9561">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-09">497755.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303445282">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-17">248877.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303688805">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-27">248877.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
