<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-18/3420/SA1/FSAC/NGO/10350</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Lifesaving Food Assistance to 2000 HHs Severely Food Insecure  Men, Women, Boys and Girls in Ma&#x2019;ain and As Sabain Districts in Amanat Al Asimah Governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YLDF proposes this project that aims to improve the access to emergency life-saving food assistance to reduce severe hunger among highly vulnerable families through providing food baskets adhering to FSAC minimum standards to severely food insecure families, newly displaced and host families in high priority areas 2000 HHs (2744 men, 2856 women, 4116 boys, 4284 girls) in Ma&#x2019;ain and As Sabian Districts in Amant Al Asimah. It is also contributes to:
	Response to the first standard allocation first priority which help to cover first-line responses gaps.
	Cluster Strategic Objective 1 - Increase access to food for highly vulnerable families 2000 HHs (2744 men, 2856 women, 4116 boys, 4284 girls)  in Ma&#x2019;ain and As Sabian Districts in Amant Al Asimah  
	SO1: provide life-saving food assistance to of most vulnerable people in Yemen through an effective, targeted response, through unconditional voucher transfer by 12000 food baskets confirming to FSAC minimum food baskets to severely food insecure families, newly displaced and host families in high priority areas 2000 HHs (2744 men, 2856 women, 4116 boys, 4284 girls) in Ma&#x2019;ain and As Sabian Districts in Amant Al Asimah  
This project is designed in coordination with FSAC-Sana&#x2019;a and National Cluster to identify the gaps in the targeted districts. It is designed in line with AAP, gender mainstreaming and protection commitments endorsed by FSAC-Yemen. The engagement of targeted communities/beneficiaries is strongly through all phases of the project. In the basic needs assessments, Focus Group Discussion and interview # of HHs and IDPs men, women, boys, girls, the elderly, and disabled people were consulted to understand their needs and preferences for location, design, and assistance modality. Beneficiaries participation will continue throughout planning and implementation ensuring that beneficiaries know they have a right to equitable and safe assistance, where and how to obtain it with clear instruction and directions. Direct discussion with community representatives to be conducted to identify the adaptions needed for the most vulnerable. Beneficiaries amp other stakeholders&#x2019; involvement in monitoring process through community food management committees. A complaints feedback mechanism is established aiming to improving programming, assisting in understanding beneficiary and community perceptions, promoting beneficiary empowerment and assisting in the early detection of problems such as targeting, misconduct e.g. Sexual exploitation and abuse, food diversion and fraud. During execution, regular progress updates on project indicators to be achieved challenges/how the challenges are dealt with, result of BCFM and how they were handled, levels of achievement will be shared with the stakeholders with desegregated data for beneficiaries on sex and age where applicable. Local authorities and stakeholders (including women and men) will be informed of humanitarian principles, lows, standards &#x2026;etc. through informative session. Selection of beneficiaries is nondiscriminatory based on clear beneficiaries&#x2019; HHS vulnerability selection criteria endorsed by FSAC prioritizing the most vulnerable of women, men, boys and girls

The selected beneficiaries are 2000 HHs of severely food insecure families and newly displaced and host families affected by the conflict in Ma&#x2019;ain and As Sabain Districts in Amant Al Asimah Governorate  (2744 men, 2856 women, 4116 boys, 4284 girls). Beneficiaries are located in the targeted districts and are selected based on the FSAC endorsed household vulnerability and targeting criteria. They will have equitable access to food confirming to FSAC minimum basket 6 times through unconditional voucher transfer while considering associated protections, gender, risks and other considerations.

YLDF will consier the HHs in its livelihoods projects that are being implmented in the same targeted areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Al-Maznai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sr. Emergency Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>736777938</telephone>
   <email>aalmaznai@yldf.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nawal Dubais</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>735790177</telephone>
   <email>ndobais@yldf.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amanat Al Asimah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.36598719 44.20206450</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-11">180167.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-11">819763.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-10350">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-11">999931.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303624142/45">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-26">299979.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304009111">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-24">299979.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304114968">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-26">399972.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
