<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="www.imd.org.mz" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>MZ-MOJ-100717344-MOZ-POD-21</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="MZ-MOJ-100717344" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto para Democracia Multipartid&#xE1;ria (IMD Mo&#xE7;ambique)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Power of Dialogue</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political parties;
National Parliament;
Provincial Assemblies ;
Civil Society Organisations ;
The diplomatic community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ultimate goal of the PoD Programme is to promote peaceful democratic space and inclusive, responsive and representative political decision-making at all levels. IMD and NIMD have been doing this for years in Mozambique and will continue to do so under this programme through the strategic Programme objective to aim for Political and civic actors to collaborate, influence and participate in legitimate, transparent and accountable political processes. We have contextualized this objective to the Mozambican context and to fit the IMD and NIMD joint programme portfolio.  We have chosen to specifically focus on promoting women in politics which leads to the following strategic programme objective: Political and civic actors collaborate, participate and influence the position and engagement of women in political processes in Mozambique.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s rights and gender equality are a cross-cutting issue in addressing many social, political and economic issues. In the Power of Voices programme, it is intended that matters sensitive to women&apos;s civil and political rights are not a cross-cutting issue but the focus of the programme.
In Mozambique, the struggle for women&apos;s civil and political rights has progressively evolved, and it can be seen from the increase in women&apos;s political participation in decision-making bodies such as ministries, state departments, governors as well as institutions democratic institutions such as the Assembly of the Republic and the Provincial Assemblies. The repeated and selfless struggle for equal rights and opportunities between men and women is a sign that women, being a vulnerable group, have not always had equal benefits and inclusion in the country&apos;s social, economic and political life, which demands a need for promotion of spaces where women can have a voice to defend and influence for a gender and more inclusive agenda.
In the Mozambican context, no one can speak or advocate for development if there is no equal social, political and economic inclusion between women and men and in an environment where everyone can have freedom to express themselves and influence political and decision-making processes in the face of political actors and institutions. Thus, in order to exercise this influence, society&apos;s stakeholders, especially women, must be equipped with sufficient tools and capacities to exercise their constitutional rights and freedoms without fear and in an environment in which differences are accepted, regardless only sex, religion, place of birth, age, social position or level of education, physical characteristics or other form of discrimination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="POD MOZ" crs-channel-code="21000" ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Institute for Multiparty Democracy (NIMD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is planed to end on 31 December 2021</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is planed to start on 01 January 2021</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total budget for all POD Project countries is &#x20AC;32,677,156 of which Mozambique will execute &#x20AC;2,059,186</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="www.imd.org">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IMD prepares and disseminates the program report</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-31">411000</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-28">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="MOZ-POD-21" ref="NIMD - Netherlands Institute for Multiparty Democracy" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a consortium led by NIMD.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="IMD-Mozambique" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-31">211000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="MOZ-POD-21" ref="NIMD - Netherlands Institute for Multiparty Democracy" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="IMD-Mozambique" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
