<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="www.imd.org.mz" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>MZ-MOJ-100717344-Good Governance and Elections with Integrity</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="MZ-MOJ-100717344" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto para Democracia Multipartid&#xE1;ria (IMD Mo&#xE7;ambique)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Good Governance and Elections with Integrity</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the electoral component 1. In the electoral component, IMD&apos;s intervention allowed the creation of a more comprehensive electoral observation environment through the operationalization of the Peace Room, combined with the improvement of the quality of observation and reporting of electoral incidences and the use of innovative digital platforms for the provision of electoral information. It should be noted that the Sala da Paz was the first electoral observation platform to publicize the trend in electoral results, 24 hours after the elections. 2. Ultimately, these interventions contributed to building an environment, that somehow, through the powerful intervention of the Peace Room prevented Mozambique from experiencing moments of tension and conflict resulting from non-compliance with electoral legislation and rejection of electoral results. So there were no armed conflicts resulting from the electoral process. In the strengthening of the role of the Provincial Assemblies component 1. Creation of a dialogue platform between the different MAP, MAEFP, civil society in which the lessons and challenges of the implementation and functioning of the PA are reflected on; 2. Provincial Assemblies fortified in terms of relevant tools and instruments to guide the functioning of PAs. 3. Leaders of the Provincial Assemblies trained in the exercise of their functions of regulation and oversight of local government action</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the transition to multiparty democracy materialized by the holding of the first general elections of 1994, the country has cyclically organized electoral elections. Experience in conducting electoral processes over the years shows that there are progresses, learnings and challenges for the institutionalization of Mozambican democracy. However, despite the regular conduct of electoral processes, major challenges remain for the credibility of democratic processes. That is, the holding of the elections per se has not been sufficient for the consolidation of electoral democracy. Almost every election has been harshly questioned, whether in the preparatory phase, during and especially in the post-election period. In some cases, conditions for holding elections excite for conflicts that take on military dimensions. Integrity, transparency and fairness in electoral processes are some of the elements that despite efforts remain critical and make the real transition to a consolidated multiparty democracy difficult.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">to contribute to increase the confidence and integrity of Mozambican electoral democracy, promoting transparency and effective electoral justice; and &#x2022; to strengthen the role of provincial assemblies ensuring the consolidation and dissemination of experiences and good practices, taking into account the new operational layout of Provincial Assemblies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Ireland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities started on the agreed date, however the disbursement was slightly delayed.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Even though there were delays, IMD was able to carry out activities on schedule.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities were planned to start in April 2019 and end in April 2020.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The budget was entirely for Mozambique, and implemented by IMD.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11150" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="www.imd.org.mz">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IMD presents the details of the activities and the respective expenses, for the implementation of the project.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">36262</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-27">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="Good Governance and Elections with Integrity" ref="Embassy of Ireland" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unique Tranche</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="Good Governance and Elections with Integrity" ref="IMD Mo&#xE7;ambique" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Only tranche, however received after the start of the activities that were supported by the internal funds of the IMD.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/FINAL-REPORT-IMD-_IRISH-20200907120921.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NARRATIVE FINAL REPORT</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FINAL ACTIVITY REPORT</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
