<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>MZ-MOJ-100717344-MD Against Xenophobia</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="MZ-MOJ-100717344" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto para Democracia Multipartid&#xE1;ria (IMD Mo&#xE7;ambique)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recurrence of Acts of Xenophobic Violence in the Republic of South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected results Understanding of the ongoing violent phenomenon in the RSA; Identification of the causes of violent attacks against foreigners; Description of the moral and material authors of the attacks; Enumeration of attacking methods of action; Analysis of the implications of the attacks on Mozambique; Discussion of response models of Mozambican society to these phenomenon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life in society has almost always been characterized by the co-presence of different cultures and &#x201C;manifestations of tolerance yet xenophobia have been, since antiquity, a constant mark of interethnic relationship&#x201D; (Soares, 2001: 34). Thus, perceiving the receptivity or repulsion of the people before the presence of foreigners is not a new interest, as Herodotus had already done in the 5th century BC. Cases of xenophobia are not necessarily new in South Africa. According to Landau, Ramjathan-Keogh and Singh (2005), South Africa&apos;s domestic policies have always been a source of emigration, starting with Mfecane, going through colonialism, segregationism and the apartheid period, when many left the country - mainly towards neighboring countries - in search of freedom, opportunities or a base of organization in exchange for South Africa. Thus, it can be assumed that the post-apartheid project or the homeland created by Nelson Mandela, the &quot;Rainbow Nation&quot;, is a project still far from its success. Although there has been a transition from authoritarianism to democracy, hatred and violence continue to characterize contemporary South Africa (Harris, 2002). The South African people are considered violent in nature. Harris, based on the analysis of various studies, concluded that South African relations and interactions are governed through violence rather than any other peaceful means (ibid .: 11). It is within this context that the Institute for Multiparty Democracy (IMD) in partnership with Joaquim Chissano University (UJC) intends to facilitate the holding of the Symposium to discuss the roots, consequences and proposed responses by the Mozambican State in relation to the acts of violence committed by some South Africans against certain foreigners, particularly Mozambicans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Audience The meeting will be attended by the following actors: Academics; Politicians; Civil Society Organizations; Journalists; Representatives of the Diplomatic Corps; Private Sector (CTA); General public</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The general objective of the symposium is to discuss the causes, implications and perspectives or models of response by Mozambican society regarding the recurrence of acts of xenophobic violence in the Republic of South Africa (RSA). Specific Objectives: Define the phenomenon that is occurring in the RSA; Identify the causes of violent attacks against foreigners; Describe the moral and material authors of the attacks; List the attacking methods of action; Analyze the implications of the attacks on Mozambique; Discuss models of response of Mozambican society to these phenomenon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="IMD" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="XI-IATI-MZ-MOJ-100717344" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto para Democracia Multipartid&#xE1;ria (IMD Mo&#xE7;ambique)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XI-IATI-MZ-MOJ-100717344-IMD-PelaDemocraciaMultipartidaria" crs-channel-code="90000" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Institute for Multiparty Democracy -NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-19" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.imd.org.mz/"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">3247</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
