<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="3" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-NL-KVK-41048542-20WECU-8608</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing a clear strategic plan for Wassa-East District Cooperative Cocoa Farmers and Marketing Union</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;p&gt;The goal is to develop a strategic business plan and update membership registration for all the 57 primary cooperatives&lt;/p&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;p&gt;This is the introduction year of the collaboration between Agriterra and WECU. For this year  the focus will be developing a BHAG and a clear strategic business plan in consultation with the 57 primary cooperatives of the union. As part of professionalizing the cooperative union  an accountant will be hired to oversee the financials of the union  there will be proper documentation of constitutions  sustainable workshop will be give and basic financial&amp;nbsp;management training as well.&lt;/p&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;p&gt;Wassa-East District Cocoa Cooperative Farmers and Marketing Union was established in 2011 and is into the production of certified cocoa beans. The Union is made of 2875 members and have 57 primary cooperatives. Their production volumes has been about 2348MT-2052MT in the last two seasons. The cooperative has plans of becoming the best producer of cocoa beans in therms of quality and quantity  to provide adequate extension services to members  to establish a commerical business aside cocoa production and to become a Licensed Cocoa Buying Company in the long-term but currently the cooperative union does not have a clear strategy towards achieving these. The cooperative union wants to collaborate with Agriterra to assist them in strengthening their cooperative union thus this first year  they would like to develop a strategic plan to serve as a guide. Aside this  there is a need for strengthening financials and membership information of the union. The union currently does not have an accountant and updated production volumes and member information. WECU would like to hire a qualified accountant and update the database of members.&lt;/p&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="WECU" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wassa East Cooperative Cocoa farmers and marketing Union limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>31264455445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
   <website>https://agriterra.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willemsplein 42 6811 KD Arnhem  Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
