<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-NL-KVK-41048542-19LNAM-8516</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve Rice Production and Youth Involvement</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:42.55pt;text-indent:0in;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(65  65  65); font-family: sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: pre-wrap; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: rgb(255  255  255); text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; display: inline !important; float: none;&quot;&gt;There are a lot of ideas for the coming years but they need to have proper strategy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt; But the cooperative has ideas how to improve the business by modernising the machinery and the use of new farming technology. Because the cooperative has around 650 acres of land they are able to get long term loans from the government (only possible when you own at least 100 acres of land). The cooperative expects that in 2 till 3 years they are allowed to sell land. At this moment one acre of land is worth around $ 3.000. By selling some acres of land (small part) it must be possible to get more loans to invest in the cooperative. The cooperative is sustainable because of the fact that they own around 650 acres of land. The plans of the cooperative are realistic because they own a lot of land  so their own equity is very high (only land is worth around 2 million dollar). The biggest challenge for the cooperative to use the equipment and machinery efficiently to get the maximum profit.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:42.55pt;text-indent:0in;&quot;&gt;The cooperative wants more youth involvement in the board. They also wants to invest in new machinery and equipment. These plans are feasible  however a more efficient use of the machinery is needed in order to get the maximum profit. For rice milling &amp;nbsp;the over capacity in Pyu is a risk. To mitigate these risks more members are needed (or more clients). What they need is an overall (strategic) plan for the future. This plan must be made with the collaboration of the youth and Agriterra as it is their future.&lt;/p&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;p&gt;Lu Nge Ah Man cooperative is a primary cooperative and was established in 1976. The cooperative owns around 550 acres of land which they rent to members and partly (150 acres) used by themselves. The land has been given to the cooperative in 1976. The cooperative consist of 56 members. Membership is stable since the start. Besides the land the cooperative owns a rice mill (including drying machines)  machinery  trucks  combines. Besides the board members there are 16 staff members. &amp;nbsp; The added value for members is the use of the mill and the machinery  sharing knowledge about modern farming  credit service and trade (beans).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cooperative Scoping was done on 4th July 2019 and cooperative assessment was recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;p&gt;The cooperative wants support on how to involve youth in the board and also modernize the organization (supervisory board etc.). They also needs support on the (internal) capitalization of the cooperative for investments in modernising the equipment. Following points will be main focus for the first year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. &amp;nbsp;Introduction of youth and how to achieve cooperation with other parties in agri business (farmers  millers tec.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Strategic plan  business plan for investments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Finance  procedures must be there and followed  budget planning and cash flow forecast on BU level and total versus realization&lt;/p&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Myanmar</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="LuNgeAhManAPC" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lu Nge Ah Man Agriculture Primary Cooperative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0031264455445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
   <website>https://agriterra.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willemsplein 42 6811 KD Arnhem  Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
