<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13570A0103-BIH-15112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIPLS Improving Performance of Local Services, UNDP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PIPLS Improving Performance of Local Services, UNDP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project aim is to improve access to critical public services through better governance and greater investment in local infrastructure, with the former effectively and sustainably enabling the latter. This outcome will be pursued through three interlinked and mutually reinforcing results taking place across 15 local and 2 cantonal governments. Under Result 1, the Project will help local governments establish a system for the strategic management of public assets held by municipal authorities, to include creating clear lines of responsibility for asset management within each institution; establishing and regularly updating a register of assets with a transparent record of all purchases, sales or disposition of assets; development of asset management plans to help ensure efficiency and effectiveness in asset utilization; building the necessary staff skills to effectively manage the system and its components; and creating the requisite policy framework for effective asset management at local government level. In addition to ensuring that public assets are managed in a way to ensure the optimal level of service is provided to residents, the system will also ensure the requisite level of transparency and accountability in managing publicly owned goods by local government officials and leaders alike. In order to ensure sustainability of results and create a better enabling environment beyond the immediate stakeholder community, the Project will, in parallel, engage with decision makers at higher levels of government to influence the relevant policy framework for asset management. Under Result 2, the Project will work with partner local authorities to optimize public spending and generate funding for capital investments in critical service areas as identified by relevant local development strategy documents. Activities under this result will work towards introducing and internalizing a rigorous process of disciplined expenditure management aimed at establishing a conservative level of operational spending. In addition, the Project will work to strengthen internal control systems to curb unlawful spending and introduce a new level of scrutiny to the local government&#x2019;s financial management practices. Considering the largely inefficient and ineffective public procurement practices, and their detrimental impact on service delivery, the Project will also pursue enhancements in procurement policies and procedures across all partner local governments. As with Result 1, the Project will pursue willing policy partners at higher levels of government to effect practice-based changes in the regulatory environment. Under Result 3, the Project will clearly and immediately demonstrate the benefits of improved governance practices and arrangements, created under Results 1 and 2, to mobilize newly available funding in implementing critical public service priorities. In practical terms, local governments that have performed the best, or have saved and generated the most money, will be rewarded with a &#x201C;top-up grant&#x201D; through the Project grant facility thus enabling the implementation of their priority interventions already called for under their local development strategies. Competing local governments will be evaluated against targets established based on an in-depth external review of their financial situation at project inception. In addition, to be eligible, priority infrastructure interventions for best performing municipalities/canton will need to be i) linked to their development strategy; ii) co-financed with at least 60% of the total amount by the local authority; and iii) operate on a fully sustainable basis once completed. The selection process will also be guided by SDG financing considerations with funding channelled to meet the implementation of prioritized goals across all partner communities. In essence, Result 3 will represent an incentive for participating local and cantonal governments to maximize their commitment to good governance practices outlined under the first two project results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FNs utvecklingsprogram (UNDP) har ans&#xF6;kt om SEK 16 miljoner i st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra Project for Improving Performance of Local Services (PIPLS), I Bosnien och Hercegovina (BiH) under perioden 2020-2023.
Projektet kommer att sp&#xE4;nna &#xF6;ver tre olika pelare f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra de lokala myndigheternas effektivitet n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller att tillhandah&#xE5;lla kritiska tj&#xE4;nster till allm&#xE4;nheten. Den f&#xF6;rsta pelaren kommer att str&#xE4;va efter att mobilisera ytterligare inkomstk&#xE4;llor f&#xF6;r partnerkommuner, den andra kommer att se till att alla utgifter f&#xF6;rvaltas effektivt och i linje med uppst&#xE4;llda prioriteringar f&#xF6;r tj&#xE4;nsteleverans, medan den tredje pelaren kommer att ge omedelbara f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttringar av den offentliga serviceinfrastrukturen i partnerkommuner, till stor del finansierade via nya genererade int&#xE4;kter och besparingar. 
Projektets totala budget &#xE4;r 21,7 MSEK (USD 2 444 710). Den svenska insatsen &#xE4;r MSEK 16 (USD 1 796 890) medan UNDP bidrar med 1 MSEK (USD 113 400), sammantaget 17 MSEK (USD 1 910 290). D&#xE4;rtill kommer kommunerna och kantonerna att bidra med circa MSEK 4,7 (USD 534 420) (dessa resurser kommer att hanteras inom projektet eller parallellt av kommunerna baserat p&#xE5; respektive kommuns &#xF6;nskem&#xE5;l).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP has applied to Sweden for funding of 16 million SEK to carry out the Project for Improving Performance of Local Services (PIPLS) in Bosnia and Herzegovina during the period 2020-2023.
The project will work across three different pillars to improve the effectiveness of local authorities in providing critical services to the public. The first pillar will aim to mobilize additional sources of revenue for partner local governments, the second will ensure that all expenditures are managed effectively, and in line with service delivery priorities, while the third pillar will deliver immediate improvements to public service infrastructure in partner localities funded, in large part, via newly generated revenues and savings.
The total project budget is 21,7 MSEK (USD 2,444,710). The contribution by the Government of Sweden is 16 MSEK (USD 1,796,890) and by UNDP 1 MSEK(USD 113,400) in total 17 MSEK ( USD 1,910,290).
In addition, local governments and cantons are expected to participate with USD 534,420 (app. 4,7 MSEK) over the project implementation lifetime (these contributions are to be managed in parallel or directly depending on government preferences).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and support to subnational government</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">874441.8146416537</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">291480.6048805512</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">874441.8146416537</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">291480.6048805513</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-30">1085811.698535</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bosnia-and-herzegovina/13570_FAGoSwedenandUNDP-PIPLSSEK16mil27Nov2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bosnia-and-herzegovina/13570_Amendment1TAFsigned.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment No 1 to the Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the first year of implementation, Project has developed and administered an in-depth survey of asset management practices with the purpose to examine in detail both the current operational practices in place, as well as the relevant policy framework governing asset management in local government. The survey process encompasses a document review process, examining all available registry information, protocols governing public asset management, classification policies, plans and any other available written information, as well as structured interviews with both practitioners and senior organisational leadership. The Project was able to produce a series of  analytical studies in each of the 18 local governments. With the results of the survey  the Project is presently organising three workshops with policy makers, practitioners, and local government officials, in cooperation with the two local government associations. The workshops are aimed at vetting the findings of the surveys and formulating policy action that needs to be taken in order to create a more enabling legal framework for better asset management. Following the recommendations from the survey, the Project Team has drafted the terms of reference for a service provider that will be providing on-site support across all 18 partner authorities. In addition the Project Team is preparing the training material for a capacity building program to complement the implementation of recommendations. The training program will target municipal practitioners as well as senior staff in order to create an enabling environment for the introduction of the strategic asset management framework. 

Futrhermore, the Project assists partner local governments and cantons review their revenue streams, both revenues and expenditures, especially in light of the current challenges brought about by COVID-19. Within the review process for municipal budgets the Project has produced a set of short, mid, and long-term recommendations aimed at maximising the impact of available financial resources across all 18 local governments. Overall, and across all participating local governments, this process has yielded commitments to generate over 11 million KM in additional development funding. The savings, as well as additional revenues generated through better use of available resources, will be channelled into critical development projects that otherwise would not have been funded due to scarcity of resources. A comprehensive review and reinforcement of the internal control environment in participating local governments and cantons will be carried out to enable better responsibility and transparency in the management of public funds. In cooperation with the State Public Procurement Authority, and based on inputs from local partners, the Project has initiated the development of a training program focused on practical scenarios most commonly encountered by municipal officers implementing provisions of public procurement legislation. 

In February 2021, the Project Team issued a call for expression of interest to all eligible newly elected mayors in the country, inviting applications for the provision of technical support across the following four thematic areas: digital governance, service delivery, financial management, and local economic development. A total of 17 applications were received, nominating a total of 33 projects. After evaluation of the received applications, it was noted that the local governments were mostly interested in digital governance, local economic development, and service delivery and infrastructure.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13570" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
