<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5500002401-BIH-15112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strenghtening Local Communities in BiH (EMZED)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Strenghtening Local Communities in BiH (EMZED)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet &#x201D;Strengthening Local Communities in BiH (MZs)&#x201D; &#xE4;r ett gemensamt initiativ mellan den schweiziska och svenska regeringen, vilket kommer genomf&#xF6;ras av FNs utvecklingsprogram (UNDP) i Bosnien och Hercegovina (BiH). 

Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med projektet &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra livskvaliten f&#xF6;r medborgarna i BiH, genom att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka lokal infrastruktur och tj&#xE4;nster samt &#xF6;ka den demokratiska ansvarsskyldigheten och den sociala integrationen. 

De utvalda medlen f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; dessa m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att uppmuntra kommunalt ledd lokal utveckling och vitalisering av den lokala f&#xF6;rvaltningen d&#xE4;r MZs fungerar som platser d&#xE4;r de styrande har f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar att komma n&#xE4;ra landets medborgare och d&#xE4;r de, genom lokala gr&#xE4;srotsorganisationer som verkar i samh&#xE4;llet med cirka 1000 personer, skapar f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r verkligt deltagande och gemensamma &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder.

Som ett resultat av det &#xF6;vergripande projektm&#xE5;let har tre effektm&#xE5;l uppr&#xE4;ttats:
Effektm&#xE5;l 1: Relevanta intressenter delar och innehar en modern/nutida vision f&#xF6;r den lokala f&#xF6;rvaltningen;
Effektm&#xE5;l 2: En effektiv, legitim och ansvarig lokal f&#xF6;rvaltning ;
Effektm&#xE5;l 3: M&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;randet av ett reglerande regelverk hos den lokala f&#xF6;rvaltningen.

Den totala projektbudgeten &#xE4;r 80 MSEK, som finansieras likv&#xE4;rdigt av Sverige och Schweiz (40 MSEK vardera).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project&quot; Strenghtening Local Communities in BiH (MZs)&quot;  is a joint initiative of the Government of Switzerland and the Government of Sweden, implemented by the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH).
 The overall project objective is to improve the quality of life of the citizens of BiH, through enhancing local infrastructure and services and increasing democratic accountability and social inclusion.
The chosen means to achieve this goal is through encouraging community-led local development and revitalising community government by MZs, as the places where government comes closest to the people and as grass-roots organisations that serve communities of around 1,000 people, with the possibility for real participation and joint action.
Against the overall project goal, three project outcomes have been set, as follows:
?	Outcome 1: Relevant stakeholders share and own a modern/contemporary vision for community government;
?	Outcome 2: Effective, legitimate and accountable community governance;
?	Outcome 3: Enabling regulatory framework for community government.
Total budget of the programme is 80 MSEK equally financed by Sweden and Swiss (40 MSEK each) during the period 2015-2019.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall project objective is to improve the quality of life of the citizens of BiH, through enhancing local infrastructure and services and increasing democratic accountability and social inclusion.The chosen means to achieve this goal is through encouraging community-led local development and revitalising community government by MZs, as the places where government comes closest to the people and as grass-roots organisations that serve communities of around 1,000 people, with the possibility for real participation and joint action.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEZA/Direktion fur Entwicklung und Zusammenarbeit</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and support to subnational government</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1236997.1462763508</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-245718.2665065466</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1236997.1462763508</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-245718.2665065466</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-01">4584307.000581</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">1170001.17000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">1150695.0197919542</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">86302.1264843966</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-28">-245718.2968205295</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Phase 1 of the project &#x2018;Strengthening the Role of Local Communities (Mjesne Zajednice)&#x2019; has achieved its planned outcomes to a broad extent and in some areas greatly surpassed expectations. The project has encouraged community led local development and begun to revitalise Mjesne Zajednice (MZ) as important players in local development. It has stimulated active citizens, facilitated stronger engagement of communities in matters of governance, improved citizen centred public service delivery and advanced MZ/local community capacities in 24 local governments (18% of all local governments) and 136 MZs (6% of all MZs in the country). This has helped restore trust among citizens in local government and affirmed the belief that change is possible in their communities. Outcome 1. Citizens and governments are committed to realise the jointly agreed upon new inclusive and gender sensitive vision of MZs in Bosnia and Herzegovina. The central project achievement is the development of the MZs vision, which provides a legitimate foundation for potential reform aimed at stronger local communities and can acts as a springboard for future systemic change in the area of community governance. The MZ vision set the following four main MZ functions: (i) MZ as an advocate of community interests, (ii) MZ as a venue for service facilitation or service delivery, (iii) MZ as socio-cultural community centre and (iv) MZ as a venue for citizen participation. Having in mind the specifics of each locality, in reality MZs take on more of these roles at the same time and serve at all times as a democratic space for citizens.
The MZ vision was developed countrywide as a highly participatory and inclusive process incorporating input from 1,800 representatives from 166 MZs and 84 local governments. At the national event, the MZ vision was verified and formally endorsed by the Ministry of Human Rights and Refugees of Bosnia and Herzegovina, the Ministry of Local Self-Governance of Republika Srpska, the Ministry of Justice of the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina, Brcko District and the entity associations of cities and municipalities.The MZ vision models were piloted whereby more than 6,000 citizens benefited from those project activities through increased decision-making processes, municipal communal services.
Furthermore, proactive capacitated and interconnected MZs have contributed to the downward responsiveness of municipal governments and improved service delivery.The project has achieved significant progress in setting the foundation for more active, capacitated and interconnected MZs and local governments It has created an enabling environment for citizen engagement and collaboration between MZs, CSOs and local governments. The project invested in people by sustaining long-term change through targeted interventions including citizen consultations for priority setting, small grants schemes to support community priorities set by citizens, civic engagement as well as securing a continuous knowledge, innovation, ideas and capacity building and networking to make it all possible. Forum officially and formally instituted as a public decision making process for citizen engagmenet. Investment in services was an important pillar. Project support in partnership with local government improved public services in the area of communal infrastructure: local roads (23% of the total investment), MZ facilities (26% of the total investment), water supply/sewage/sanitation (7.5% of the total investment), public lighting (9.5% of the total investment), playgrounds/fields (23% of the total investment) and procurement/other (11% of the total investment). The increased number of women and young people in MZ councils in the project localities is evidence of the strengthening of women as drivers of change and youth empowerment at the community level. Membership of women in MZ councils has increased by nearly 50 %, while the number of young people involved has increased by 180.7 % compared to the last countrywide MZ council elections. MZs are more accessible and modernised and provide a free public space (24 Community Hubs) open to all citizens, MZs, CSOs, LGs, and the private sector aimed at the betterment of communities. The project established a countrywide MZ Network that brings together over 100 LG and aims to share best practice in the area of community governance as well as play an advocacy role in policy processes, give a voice to MZs, provide a platform for the articulation of joint challenges and for the synchronised dissemination of good practice and ensuring sustainability.
A new regulatory framework for functional MZs developed by governments will enable more inclusive gender sensitive and accountable local governance in Bosnia and Herzegovina.The project induced the process of change of normative frameworks related to local self-governance. Entity parliamentary commissions and Brcko District authorities represented by the highest levels of government have begun to consider potential changes to the existing regulatory frameworks in order to ensure that these are conducive to transforming the vision into practice. As a result, amendments to the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina Law on Principles of Local Self-Governance were drafted and recommendations for legal improvements were defined in Republika Srpska. The Three Project Commissions, after establishment, prepared recommendations for legislative amendments within the existing legislative framework and held a series of consultative meetings led to consensus of amendments to the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina Law on Principles of Local Self-Governance were drafted and recommendations for legal improvements were defined in Republika Srpska.?</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55000024" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
