<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11330A0101-BIH-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BUKA, independent web portal for investigative journalism</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">BUKA, oberoende web portal f&#xF6;r unders&#xF6;kande journalistik</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CID was established as a civil society organisation already in 2000. They have by now more than 16 years of experience in designing and implementing Projects aimed at the democratisation of Bosnia and Herzegovina, They have according to Norway whom have supported their efforts since 2011 as well as OSCE an excellent track record and an extensive outreach across many communities in Bosnia and Herzegovina. CID is recognised for using media platforms as a tool for democratisation, and is closely linked to its BUKA web Magazine which has been duly described by OSCE recently as one of only four non-for profit media which is a positive example of good practise and media integrity. Hence CID/BUKA is one a very few existing media organisations in the country that have been able, and indeed with a long good track record, to protect and promote public service values in journalism. A dire and much needed competency in a country such as in Bosnia and Herzegovina. Furthermore BUKA has a TV show. The BUKA web magazine is the the most visited portal dealing with political issues in BiH. On average they have some 60-80 000 visits per day and its Facebook Group Counts over 260 000 members. hence they stand out as a unique and influential initiative throughout the country. Even though they are known to be a critical platform and do touch sensitive matters they still manage to get a limited number of commercial adds, which shows their potential strength. They are at the same time a watch dog which voices critical observations such as corrupt practise of politicians etc. but they are still commercially strong and interesting. In itself a unique and somewhat uncommon combination. Given the above their is not many other established media platforms in the country which compare CID/BUKA with. They do have a comparative advantage which its outreach and popularity which can not be matched by any other similar well established organisation which do not already receive funding. In a very recent statement issues by the Council of Europe (November 2017), it is stated that Bosnia and Herzegovina authorities should spare no effort to build a truly cohesive society and effectively protect media freedom. Given the role that CID/BUKA is shouldering, and has been for a number of years, which is to improve media freedom and freedom of expression this is just further adding to the necessity to strengthen an organisation such as CID/BUKA.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CID/BUKA &#xE4;r en media organisation som &#xE4;r sprungen ur en organisation med fokus p&#xE5; ungdomar och som startade sin verksamhet i Bosnien-Hercegovina &#xE5;r 2000. De &#xE4;r en civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisation som verkar f&#xF6;r landets l&#xE5;ngsiktiga demokratisering och d&#xE5; genom att anv&#xE4;nda sin media plattform f&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; ut p&#xE5; maximalt s&#xE4;tt till allm&#xE4;nheten i landet. Dels har BUKA ett webmagasin (tidning), samt d&#xE4;rut&#xF6;ver &#xE4;r man verksamt i sociala media (facebook) med 250 000 medlemmar och med BUKA TV och radio. Man vill med sin verksamhet utg&#xF6;ra en Watch dog organisation och d&#xE4;r man kritiskt granskar makten i hela landet s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l i Republika Srpska som i Federationen. Granskningen handlar inte bara om den politiska sf&#xE4;ren utan &#xE4;ven hur privata sektorn fungerar etc. Man har &#xF6;ver &#xE5;ren etablerat sig som en stark och trov&#xE4;rdig akt&#xF6;r, d&#xE4;r man utg&#xF6;r en av relativt f&#xE5; professionella och objektiva nyhetsf&#xF6;rmedlare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centar za Information Dekontaminaciju Mladih - BUKA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">175500.1755001755</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">158631.119195423</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">162871.754780286</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">175500.1755001755</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">158631.1191954229</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">162871.754780286</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">526500.5265</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">175500.1755001755</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">158631.119195423</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">162871.754780286</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/11330-grant-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/11330_AmendmenttotheAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment No 1 to the Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/beslut-om-insats-11330.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats 11330</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative Report from CID/BUKA for 2019 The report covers all activities undertaken during 2019. BUKA concludes that though the continued to cover many of the same areas of interest like the year before the situation has deteriorated in BiH; poor economic situation, high unemployment, political instability,&#xA0; ethnic tensions, alarming number of people leaving the country for a better life in EU. Environmental issues and alarming air pollution are factors also driving this negative trend.  Investigative journalism are followed by threats and intimidation. Thought this harsh realities BUKA has continued to publish its stories and with critical voices from different parts and walks of life. One of themes covered in 2019 has been the migration crises. BUKA reporting about poor living conditions for these people. Also, in 2019 there were a number of environmental incidents, such as the case of pyrroline contamination in the industrial zone INCEL in Banja Luka. Citizens in RS very deeply concerned about this event. BUKA worked a lot on stories related to poor air quality. The reports published by BUKA were perceived as credible by the audience, environmental activists used the information for their actions, and several members of Banja Luka City Council initiated discussion about the problem of air pollution and the lack of monitoring in RS. In general, BUKA seem to focus their interest and articles on highly relevant topics, and of interest to the general public. Much of the stories have a close relationship to RS and Serbia, seemingly less to the Federation. However, their viewers come from all over BiH. One other interesting piece of work done was their investigative article about how big advertisers control media in the country. A story about largest telecommunication company in the region Mtel. BUKA reported about LGBTI rights, in particular about the first Pride in BiH which was organized in September 2019. BUKA was the only media in the RS that reported live from the Pride. Producing and airing 7 TV shows was only partially implemented, 2 TV shows produced and aired. Remaining five planned for actions in 2020. BUKA leaves us without clear indications why so few TV shows were produced during 2019, and where they inform that they did more TV shows but with other funding sources behind. An issue for us to pick up no doubt. Producing administering and publishing web media content which gives voice to alternative voices (CSOs etc.) were fully and successfully implemented. A total number exceeded the planned outcome of 50 pieces. E.g. BUKA continued reporting about the movement &quot;Justice for David&quot;. &#xA0; BUKA has as part of its regular narrative report also enclosed its web statistics for last year. The web statistical chart shows that BUKA (6yka.com) has over 9 Million users, new users are many. There were 63.3 Million page views and 43.4 Million sessions&#xA0; held during 2019. New visitors is 29.5% whereas the remaining 70% are returning viewers. BUKA&apos;s Facebook group grew to almost 300.000 followers in 2019.  In the web page presented there is an interesting breakdown in use of language when entering the web page and its contents. 21% or close to 2 Million viewers in 2019 used &quot;Croatian&quot; lingo, whereas 1.8 Million English, 1.7 Million Serbian and Bosnian language a mere 0.5 Million. The whole breakdown in language raises some interesting questions. Why do they have this breakdown, how important are the distinction in language and how much resources are placed on language translation. Why is this important and finally noting that a lesser part of viewers seem to use &quot;Bosanska&quot;, what does this imply. That BUKA is not as national wide in its coverage and interest than we have thought? &#xA0;&#xA0; In terms of staff capacity BUKA enlarged its editorial team by employing one journalist, but there are currently three vacancies for different positions in the organization, as they want to build and strengthen the organization. An issue for discussion at annual meeting(s). Threats and cyber-attacks are common. For years they have received messages of that kind. Editor in Chief received death threats twice in 2019. BUKA has by some been branded as &quot;enemies of the RS&quot;. In 2019 BUKA came under cyber-attack (discussion point it too). Some pictures relating to articles were destroyed etc. Press freedom in BiH is hampered and under threat in BiH. Investigative journalism is&#xA0; barely present in BiH.&#xA0; Although there are existing laws and provisions and defined ethical codes etc., ethical codes are massively violated so hate speech and political are common in online media. The decline in the quality of media content is particularly noticeable in online media, with a large number of fake portals. The professionalism of media in BiH has been steadily declining. The state of the media in BiH is worse than last year. &#xA0;&#xA0; Financial Report for FY 2019 (CID/BUKA) Total budget for the period 1 December 2017 until the end of the agreement period in late December 2010 is planned outlays of 449.485 EUR (4.5 MSEK). Thus far and until the 31th December 2019 BUKA has spent 206.344 EUR (or nearly 46% of its Swedish funded resources). This indicate a relative low usage of Swedish funding when 2/3 of the total agreement period has elapsed. Thus far BUKA has not approached Sida and suggested any extension of the present agreement period. Either that needs to be a more viable solution; or BUKA will be able to speed up its activities to consume more than 50% of funding in the year of 2020 or not use all funds.&#xA0;  Using the balance funds in 2020 seems a very unlikely outcome given the problems CID/BUKA are faced with, not just linked to COVID 19 and its wider implications, but also given the shrinking space and reduced access to information (adding to which more difficulties to work with independent media and journalism in RS) which hamper work and planned implementation of activities. &#xA0; Audit Report BUKA 2019  The audit report duly submitted but delayed, partly due to COVID 19 realities on the ground. Standard ISRS 4400. Added to which following RS local laws stipulations for audits. Firm RS based BGD. All statistics comply with financial plan/reporting and numbers add up. BUKA received approx. 287.000 KM during FY 2019 and utilized 171.000 KM. There is a major balance of funds with BUKA entering into FY 2020. Out of the total planned spending of 4.5 MSEK for the full period thus far (end of 2019) a mere 45% of funds had been used. See below for Budgetary plan for 2020.  There is no traditional Opinion stated by the audit firm which confuses me. However, given all information provided and scrutiny done by audit firm this is to the best of my understanding an unqualified audit with no any substantive recommendations. It contains some observations mostly linked to overall performance of activities done. Annual plan and budget for 2020 (CID/BUKA) The work plan is short but focused continuing the needy work and plans part of the overall strategy guiding them from 2017 and until now. No any surprises visible, more of the same and continued focus on producing quality media content and staying with more articles of interest to the general public. Only concerned noticed is the plan to have 12 TV shows produced in 2020. That given last year&apos;s target were to produce 7 shows and only 2 done. So, realism in this part need to be further explored and discussed. The budget for FY 2020 is short concise and clear. It stipulated that given the final allocation of 1.5 MSEK from Sida, they plan to conduct all activities in the year and with a then usage of 2.4 MSEK or 55% of the remaining budgets. The realism in such a plan, and with no cost extension could and should be discussed with BUKA during the annual meeting to be held. &#xA0; Comments and issues to raise during the Annual meeting 3rd June 2020  More general/generic questions to pose to BUKA -General questions how has COVID 19/Corona affected you as an organization, the way you work and in relation to others? Delay and challenges. NEED to consider a No-Cost extension? -Political situation in 2020 and onwards. Landscape, media freedom and not. Shrinking space and strategies to combat this &#x2013; nationally and/or with help from external forces (EU, UN et al)? RISKs and threats facing CID/BUKA.  -What about your own funding situation, different donors. Norway/Sweden/USAID etc.? Outlook 2020 and onwards. (Assumption: BUKA will ask us for continued support from 2021. Based on what strategies and documentations. Is core funding a possibility for BUKA. I think this is premature. Sweden should also in this case act in close discussion and collaboration with Norway, given their funding plans and long-term thinking of support to BUKA. Long-term plans for SUSTAINABILITY.  -A problem all along in our joint cooperation and collaboration has been linked to late reporting, delays and reminders which feels un-necessary and irritating. It seems that you might not have the right capacity to shoulder this responsibility. Your comments to this fact and plans to solve it. It is an issue of credibility.  Financial and audit comments from Ina H:  -Very low expenditure last year and compared to the previous year. All in all, 46% of all funds utilized from Dec 2017 until Dec 2019. But then according to Plan for FY 2020 BUKA plan to spend all of the remaining funds in 2020 (54%) during this last year (money now released in June 2020). Realism in that plan and given all of COVID realities on the ground.    Narrative Report from CID/BUKA for 2019 The report covers all activities undertaken during 2019. BUKA concludes that though the continued to cover many of the same areas of interest like the year before the situation has deteriorated in BiH; poor economic situation, high unemployment, political instability,&#xA0; ethnic tensions, alarming number of people leaving the country for a better life in EU. Environmental issues and alarming air pollution are factors also driving this negative trend.  Investigative journalism are followed by threats and intimidation. Thought this harsh realities BUKA has continued to publish its stories and with critical voices from different parts and walks of life. One of themes covered in 2019 has been the migration crises. BUKA reporting about poor living conditions for these people. Also, in 2019 there were a number of environmental incidents, such as the case of pyrroline contamination in the industrial zone INCEL in Banja Luka. Citizens in RS very deeply concerned about this event. BUKA worked a lot on stories related to poor air quality. The reports published by BUKA were perceived as credible by the audience, environmental activists used the information for their actions, and several members of Banja Luka City Council initiated discussion about the problem of air pollution and the lack of monitoring in RS. In general, BUKA seem to focus their interest and articles on highly relevant topics, and of interest to the general public. Much of the stories have a close relationship to RS and Serbia, seemingly less to the Federation. However, their viewers come from all over BiH. One other interesting piece of work done was their investigative article about how big advertisers control media in the country. A story about largest telecommunication company in the region Mtel. BUKA reported about LGBTI rights, in particular about the first Pride in BiH which was organized in September 2019. BUKA was the only media in the RS that reported live from the Pride. Producing and airing 7 TV shows was only partially implemented, 2 TV shows produced and aired. Remaining five planned for actions in 2020. BUKA leaves us without clear indications why so few TV shows were produced during 2019, and where they inform that they did more TV shows but with other funding sources behind. An issue for us to pick up no doubt. Producing administering and publishing web media content which gives voice to alternative voices (CSOs etc.) were fully and successfully implemented. A total number exceeded the planned outcome of 50 pieces. E.g. BUKA continued reporting about the movement &quot;Justice for David&quot;. &#xA0; BUKA has as part of its regular narrative report also enclosed its web statistics for last year. The web statistical chart shows that BUKA (6yka.com) has over 9 Million users, new users are many. There were 63.3 Million page views and 43.4 Million sessions&#xA0; held during 2019. New visitors is 29.5% whereas the remaining 70% are returning viewers. BUKA&apos;s Facebook group grew to almost 300.000 followers in 2019.  In the web page presented there is an interesting breakdown in use of language when entering the web page and its contents. 21% or close to 2 Million viewers in 2019 used &quot;Croatian&quot; lingo, whereas 1.8 Million English, 1.7 Million Serbian and Bosnian language a mere 0.5 Million. The whole breakdown in language raises some interesting questions. Why do they have this breakdown, how important are the distinction in language and how much resources are placed on language translation. Why is this important and finally noting that a lesser part of viewers seem to use &quot;Bosanska&quot;, what does this imply. That BUKA is not as national wide in its coverage and interest than we have thought? &#xA0;&#xA0; In terms of staff capacity BUKA enlarged its editorial team by employing one journalist, but there are currently three vacancies for different positions in the organization, as they want to build and strengthen the organization. An issue for discussion at annual meeting(s). Threats and cyber-attacks are common. For years they have received messages of that kind. Editor in Chief received death threats twice in 2019. BUKA has by some been branded as &quot;enemies of the RS&quot;. In 2019 BUKA came under cyber-attack (discussion point it too). Some pictures relating to articles were destroyed etc. Press freedom in BiH is hampered and under threat in BiH. Investigative journalism is&#xA0; barely present in BiH.&#xA0; Although there are existing laws and provisions and defined ethical codes etc., ethical codes are massively violated so hate speech and political are common in online media. The decline in the quality of media content is particularly noticeable in online media, with a large number of fake portals. The professionalism of media in BiH has been steadily declining. The state of the media in BiH is worse than last year. &#xA0;&#xA0; Financial Report for FY 2019 (CID/BUKA) Total budget for the period 1 December 2017 until the end of the agreement period in late December 2010 is planned outlays of 449.485 EUR (4.5 MSEK). Thus far and until the 31th December 2019 BUKA has spent 206.344 EUR (or nearly 46% of its Swedish funded resources). This indicate a relative low usage of Swedish funding when 2/3 of the total agreement period has elapsed. Thus far BUKA has not approached Sida and suggested any extension of the present agreement period. Either that needs to be a more viable solution; or BUKA will be able to speed up its activities to consume more than 50% of funding in the year of 2020 or not use all funds.&#xA0;  Using the balance funds in 2020 seems a very unlikely outcome given the problems CID/BUKA are faced with, not just linked to COVID 19 and its wider implications, but also given the shrinking space and reduced access to information (adding to which more difficulties to work with independent media and journalism in RS) which hamper work and planned implementation of activities. &#xA0; Audit Report BUKA 2019  The audit report duly submitted but delayed, partly due to COVID 19 realities on the ground. Standard ISRS 4400. Added to which following RS local laws stipulations for audits. Firm RS based BGD. All statistics comply with financial plan/reporting and numbers add up. BUKA received approx. 287.000 KM during FY 2019 and utilized 171.000 KM. There is a major balance of funds with BUKA entering into FY 2020. Out of the total planned spending of 4.5 MSEK for the full period thus far (end of 2019) a mere 45% of funds had been used. See below for Budgetary plan for 2020.  There is no traditional Opinion stated by the audit firm which confuses me. However, given all information provided and scrutiny done by audit firm this is to the best of my understanding an unqualified audit with no any substantive recommendations. It contains some observations mostly linked to overall performance of activities done. Annual plan and budget for 2020 (CID/BUKA) The work plan is short but focused continuing the needy work and plans part of the overall strategy guiding them from 2017 and until now. No any surprises visible, more of the same and continued focus on producing quality media content and staying with more articles of interest to the general public. Only concerned noticed is the plan to have 12 TV shows produced in 2020. That given last year&apos;s target were to produce 7 shows and only 2 done. So, realism in this part need to be further explored and discussed. The budget for FY 2020 is short concise and clear. It stipulated that given the final allocation of 1.5 MSEK from Sida, they plan to conduct all activities in the year and with a then usage of 2.4 MSEK or 55% of the remaining budgets. The realism in such a plan, and with no cost extension could and should be discussed with BUKA during the annual meeting to be held. &#xA0; Comments and issues to raise during the Annual meeting 3rd June 2020  More general/generic questions to pose to BUKA -General questions how has COVID 19/Corona affected you as an organization, the way you work and in relation to others? Delay and challenges. NEED to consider a No-Cost extension? -Political situation in 2020 and onwards. Landscape, media freedom and not. Shrinking space and strategies to combat this &#x2013; nationally and/or with help from external forces (EU, UN et al)? RISKs and threats facing CID/BUKA.  -What about your own funding situation, different donors. Norway/Sweden/USAID etc.? Outlook 2020 and onwards. (Assumption: BUKA will ask us for continued support from 2021. Based on what strategies and documentations. Is core funding a possibility for BUKA. I think this is premature. Sweden should also in this case act in close discussion and collaboration with Norway, given their funding plans and long-term thinking of support to BUKA. Long-term plans for SUSTAINABILITY.  -A problem all along in our joint cooperation and collaboration has been linked to late reporting, delays and reminders which feels un-necessary and irritating. It seems that you might not have the right capacity to shoulder this responsibility. Your comments to this fact and plans to solve it. It is an issue of credibility.  Financial and audit comments  -Very low expenditure last year and compared to the previous year. All in all, 46% of all funds utilized from Dec 2017 until Dec 2019. But then according to Plan for FY 2020 BUKA plan to spend all of the remaining funds in 2020 (54%) during this last year (money now released in June 2020). Realism in that plan and given all of COVID realities on the ground.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11330" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
