<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5506003501-BIH-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Investigative Reporting, CIN 2016-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Centre for Investigative Reporting, CIN 2016-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Budgetst&#xF6;d till Centre for Investigative Reporting, CIN, en nyhetsbyr&#xE5; i BiH som arbetar med unders&#xF6;kande journalistik. Insatsen bidrar till att bek&#xE4;mpa korruption i BiH genom unders&#xF6;kande reportage, som i vissa fall leder till utredningar av Myndigheten mot korruption eller av polis och &#xE5;klagare. Reportagen &#xE5;terpubliceras ocks&#xE5; i m&#xE5;nga medier.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support to Centre for Investigative reporting, CIN,  a news agency for investigative journalism. The contribution enables an institutional development of CIN for a further efficient delivery of investigative journalism. CINs reports contributes to combating corruption i BiH through its reporting which in some cases lead to investigations by BiH anti-corruption Agency or police /prosecutors. The reports are also republished in many of the mainstream media in the region.
 
.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The core support is aimed at institutional development of CIN to enable a high quality investigative journalism. CIN is one of the few organisations in Bosnia and Herzegvoina (BiH) which is doing this kind of reporting and with seemingly a very high degree of quality. This statement is confirmed not just by their own reporting submitted, and by our own assessment but from other independent parties and sources in the country. &#xA0;&#xA0;The outcome level relates to improvement of institutional capacities in order to reach investigative reporting at international standards that can have an impact on advocacy efforts for legislative changes or judicial actions taken upon CIN&apos;s stores and products. Over the years CIN has further improved its ability to hire staff of a good quality and to become even better in fact scrutiny in order to secure accuracy in their reporting. Hence they have been able to build trust and reliability as a source of information to a wider audience, internally as well as externally.&#xA0;Expected outcome is also described in terms of young reporters capacitated for investigative reporting and reaching a higher degree of budget secured through commercial income.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIN/Centar za Istrazivacko Novinarstvo Udruzenje</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIN/Centar za Istrazivacko Novinarstvo Udruzenje</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">58435.1078127739</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">115069.5019791954</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">105754.0794636153</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">58435.107812774</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">115069.5019791954</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">105754.0794636153</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-01">409045.754689</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">58435.1078127739</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-28">117000.117000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">115069.5019791954</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">105754.0794636153</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIN Report on actvities on Core Support grant 2016-2019
This constitutes the last year of reporting for CIN during the Strategic Period 2016-2019. CIN has strongly continued its anti-corruption work. Sida&apos;s core funding has managed CIN to stay strong in its watchdog function not just in BiH but also in the Western Balkans region. They press and manage to hold the government(s) accountable to the people. Exposing organized crime and politicians is however not an easy task. As can easily be followed down below when reading the CIN RAF many results are there in 2019 and achievements made during the full period 2016-19. However at the same time CIN has faced threats and obstacles presented upon independent journalism. Information provided by CIN and its journalists are based on credible sources and facts and supported by official documents. Process of research is clearly defined with adequate control mechanisms. CIN holds a number of essential data basis which are open sources. CIN is attracting citizens to report and hence they received 150 tips during last years which were followed up on. CIN has also continued its efforts in improving Freedom of Information Act (FOI), along a group of NGOs/CSOs; TI-BiH, Media Centre, Infohouse, OS BiH, ACCOUNT etc. &#xA0;&#xA0;
CIN Results Assessment Framework (2016-2019)
In terms of CIN being able to respond to number of project proposals linked to markets demands it was planned target to have 10 of those in 2019 whereas the result was one. New approaches and all staff focusing attention to the New Strategic Plan 2020-23 resulted in less productivity of outcome 1.1 (administrative capacity). A number of internal training programs were conducted by CIN in 2019, in order to advance internal capacities. Two reporters participated in global trainings&#xA0; which was provided by OCCRP. Furthermore training in Multi-Media production using new technology was conducted, incl. mobile video production. In 2019 CIN produced 15 videos, one documentary and 116 infographics and or animated graphics in support of each story they published.Outcome area 2 (BiH authorities have increased responsiveness to anti-corruption issues raised in media articles) CIN produced a total of 62 investigative stories and 36 follow up/short stories in 2019. Target set for 2019 was 35 stories. Themes covered; public administration, employment procedures, public finance, judiciary, asset declarations for judges/prosecutors, Arab investments in BiH, public procurements etc. Any stories covering organised crime. In terms of re-prints in media outlets in BiH and the region (WB) they planned for 30 during 2019 and achieved over 1200 times in various media outlets. CIN stories have a vast outreach, wider audiences are now touched. CIN work closely with other civil society organisations such as with TI-BiH (covering HJPC story). Based on CIN stories 13 court decisions were issued including imprisonment sanction for one one person they wrote about. 11 legislative changes were registered during 2019.
CIN received about 150 tips (Whistle blower information) through direct contacts. In 2019 six of this information received resulted in CIN publishing their stories, focusing on anti-corruption measures. Working with the commercialization of CIN more or less failed. No any commercial products were issued. However as regards CIN&apos;s recognition of its hallmark and its brand; during the period 2016-2019 CIN have had an increase about 60% of unique visitors while video views more than doubled from 330.000 to 740.000 visitors. &#xA0;&#xA0;
CIN -Financial Report for 2019
The financial report 2019 shows a total Sida spending amounting to 378.926 BAM, which is a total of the allocation received in FY 2019 (1 MSEK) plus balance funds deferred from the previous year FY 2018. However it is visible that the planned Sida budget for 2019 was indicative 316.046 BAM. Hence two questions arises from reading th financial chart; i) why was there such a substantive increase from the planned 316&apos; BAM to 378&apos; BAM in 2019? ii) second questions relates to the fact that in nearly every budget line presented there are shifts up- and downwards. Which might not be so surprising given the overall increased usage of funds. But why for ex. is Sida spending so much increased for the Director (quoting just one example), another one being that for the finance manager Sida spent more than 500% more than planned for his/her position. Given there is no any explanatory budgetary notes these questions do come up.CIN - Annual financial statements and Independent Auditor&apos;s Report 2019 &amp; Management Statement 2019
The Independent auditor&apos;s report 2019 is an unqualified audit, hence no any deviations detected. All financial matters are in accordance with international reporting standards on Auditing(ISAs). According to the financial chart presented (Notes to financial statements) Sweden was the individually largest contributor to CIN during 2019 with its core support provided. A total of 378.887 KM was made available to CIN then. However of this amount used in 2019 a sum of approx. 194.000 KM was deferred to from the previous year 2018. Swedish released allocation for FY 2019 was a mere 1 MSEK. This year was the final year of the previous agreement.&#xA0;
The management statement from CIN confirms adherence to all regulations that are to apply for an organisation such as they. No any observations due to the fact no deviations visualized during 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55060035" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
