<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12914A0101-BIH-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International, core support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Transparency International, core support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">TI BiH har l&#xE4;mnat in en ans&#xF6;kan, tillsammans med budget och m&#xE5;l, avseende k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till k&#xE4;rnverksamhet, till Sida. Sida har beslutat att bevilja st&#xF6;d som exklusivt f&#xE5;r anv&#xE4;ndas f&#xF6;r implementering av TI:s k&#xE4;rnaktiviteter baserat p&#xE5; de v&#xE4;sentliga strategiska prioriteringarna fastlagda i TI:s strategiska plan f&#xF6;r 2015&#x2013;2020. Dessa prioriteringar &#xE4;r: 
Etablera ett starkt och produktivt samarbete med medborgare och institutioner, med ytterligare fokus p&#xE5; identifiering av f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsmedel inom institutionerna; 
Anta och &#xF6;vervaka inf&#xF6;randet och verkst&#xE4;lligheten av anti-korruptionsstandarder och policys p&#xE5; alla politiska niv&#xE5;er i landet, och kampen mot social r&#xE4;ttvisa; 
F&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka kapaciteten och bilden av TI BiH och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra organisationens position p&#xE5; global niv&#xE5;;
Efterstr&#xE4;vansv&#xE4;rda resultat i slutet av projektet &#xE4;r:
&#x2022; &#xD6;kad beslutsamhet hos individer och partners att vidta &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder mot korruption och delta i beslutsprocessen
&#x2022; Etablerade och f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkta koalitioner och partnerskap med relevanta intressenter
&#x2022; F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad och f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkt lagstiftning mot korruption baserad p&#xE5; relevanta internationella standarder och rekommendationer
&#x2022; Effektivare till&#xE4;mpning av lagar och normer och minskad straffrihet f&#xF6;r korrupta handlingar
&#x2022; F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrat genomf&#xF6;rande av strategier och planer mot korruption hos ledande institutioner
&#x2022; H&#xF6;gre niv&#xE5; av integritet hos organisationer och individer
&#x2022; F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad mottaglighet, n&#xE4;rvaro, p&#xE5;verkan av, och prestationsf&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga hos, TI BiH p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TI BiH has submitted an application, including budget and objectives to Sida for core financial support to its core activities. Sida has decided to award a grant to be used exclusively for the implementation of the TI&apos;s core activities based on the main strategic priorities defined by its Strategic plan 2015&#x2013;2020 which are:
Establishing a strong and productive cooperation with citizens and institutions, with additional focus on agents of change identified within institutions;
The adoption and monitoring the introduction and enforcement of anticorruption standards and policies at all levels of government in the country, and the fight for social justice; 
Enhancing the capacities and image of Transparency International BiH and improving the organisation&#x2019;s position in the global network  
Desired outcomes  identified by the end of the intervention are:
&#x2022; Increased empowerment of people and partners to take action against corruption and participate in decision-making process
&#x2022; Established and strengthened coalitions and partnerships with all relevant stakeholders
&#x2022; Improved and strengthened anti-corruption legislation based on relevant international standards and recommendations
&#x2022; More effective enforcement of laws and standards and reduced impunity for corrupt acts
&#x2022; Improved implementation of anti-corruption strategies and plans in leading institutions
&#x2022; Higher levels of integrity demonstrated by organisations and people
&#x2022; Enhanced responsiveness, presence, performance and impact of TI BiH at all levels</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TI BiH has submitted an application, including budget and objectives to Sida for core financial support to its core activities. Sida has decided to award a grant to be used exclusively for the implementation of the TI&apos;s core activities based on the&#xA0;main strategic priorities defined by its Strategic plan 2015&#x2013;2020 which are:
Establishing a strong and productive cooperation with citizens and institutions, with additional focus on agents of change identified within institutions;
The adoption and monitoring the introduction and enforcement of anticorruption standards and policies at all levels of government in the country, and the fight for social justice; 
Enhancing the capacities and image of Transparency International BiH and improving the organisation&#x2019;s position in the global network &#xA0;
Desired outcomes&#xA0; identified by the end of the intervention are:
&#x2022; Increased empowerment of people and partners to take action against corruption and participate in decision-making process&#x2022; Established and strengthened coalitions and partnerships with all relevant stakeholders &#x2022; Improved and strengthened anti-corruption legislation based on relevant international standards and recommendations&#x2022; More effective enforcement of laws and standards and reduced impunity for corrupt acts&#x2022; Improved implementation of anti-corruption strategies and plans in leading institutions&#x2022; Higher levels of integrity demonstrated by organisations and people
&#x2022; Enhanced responsiveness, presence, performance and impact of TI BiH at all levels</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TI BIH/Transparency International in Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">423016.3178544613</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">105779.6670901332</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">303139.8290757733</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">423016.3178544613</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">105779.6670901332</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">303139.8290757733</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-01">801002.442919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">105779.6974928608</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">303139.8290757733</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bosnia-and-herzegovina/agreement-signed-ti-core-support.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bosnia-and-herzegovina/decision-tibih-core-support.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Significant results have been achieved in the Strategic priority 1: Establishing a strong&#xA0;and productive cooperation with citizens and institutions, with additional focus on agents&#xA0;of change identified within institutions. Legal Aid Center (ALAC) acted in 240 new&#xA0;cases.Increased number of cases in 2020 can be partly accounted for by the pandemic,&#xA0;which affected all spheres of life, including trends in corruption reporting. Citizens were&#xA0;more likely to seek legal protection for infringement of their labour and employment&#xA0;rights, and a large number of enquiries concerned citizens&#x2019; suspicions that they were&#xA0;prevented from enjoying fundamental human rights and freedoms under the pretext of a&#xA0;state of emergency and/or circumstances brought about by the pandemic. Despite the&#xA0;fact that 2020 was marked by an unprecedented health crisis, citizens were still ready to&#xA0;report corruption in their immediate environment.As in previous years, the largest number of reports in 2020, a total of 100, concerned the&#xA0;public administration sector. This includes complaints against all institutions in BiH at all&#xA0;levels of government (state, entity, local) as well as those related to state-owned&#xA0;enterprises and public institutions. A large number of reports concerned irregularities in&#xA0;the recruitment of civil servants at all levels of government, recruitments in state-owned&#xA0;enterprises and public institutions, failure of inspection authorities to act on citizens&#x2019;&#xA0;complaints, violation of regulations on personal data protection, etc. A large number of&#xA0;reports concerned irregularities in the recruitment of civil servants at all levels of&#xA0;government, recruitments in public enterprises and public institutions, failure of&#xA0;inspection authorities to act on citizens&#x2019; complaints, violation of personal data protection&#xA0;regulations, etc.&#xA0;During the reporting period TI BiH has completed its first generation of Integrity School&#xA0;with two remaining modules and organized two modules of the new generation of the&#xA0;Integrity School.&#xA0;During reporting period TI BiH continued with building coalitions with governmental,non-governmental and international organizations by involving various stakeholders in&#xA0;the process of anti-corruption reforms. The aim of those activities was finding quality&#xA0;solutions and enabling more effective implementation of the reforms. TI BiH continued&#xA0;to cooperate with the Agency for prevention of corruption and coordination of the fight&#xA0;against corruption (APIK) in process of finalization of the Strategy for the fight against&#xA0;corruption BiH and advocating for adoption of the Strategy by the Council of the&#xA0;Ministers. TI BiH carried out and published the overall analysis/evaluation of the&#xA0;implementation of Anti-Corruption Strategy and Action Plan of BiH 2015-2019, with&#xA0;focus on overall effects of its implementation.&#xA0;During the reporting period TI BiH focused its activities on monitoring of the challenges&#xA0;and risks resulting from the COVID 19 pandemic, especially in the terms of distribution&#xA0;of the funds intended for alleviating the consequences of the pandemic, transparency andadequate distribution of the funds, but also monitoring of general implementation ofprescribed measures.&#xA0;During the reporting period TI BiH started with implementation of the activity related to&#xA0;the implementation of the methodology for assessing procurement system (MAPS) &#x2013; a&#xA0;universal tool that aims to catalyze and accelerate the implementation of modern,&#xA0;efficient, sustainable, and more inclusive public procurement systems. MAPS assessment&#xA0;highlight where reforms are most needed and indicate how reforms can be best carried&#xA0;out. TI BiH developed a methodology for monitoring of concessions in BiH, as well as&#xA0;collected publicly available data, and started with the process of data collection by&#xA0;sending a request to the institutions in charge of awarding concessions by freedom of&#xA0;access to information act.&#xA0;In order to increase the transparency and make the information on functioning of StateOwned Enterprises (SOEs) available to the public, TI BIH updated its SOEs databasewith relevant information and financial/audit reports of more than 300 state-ownedenterprises for 2019. TI BiH undertook an analysis of the organizational structure ofpublic administration in BiH, identified major problems and provided recommendations&#xA0;for reforms, with special focus on decreasing the complexity of the administrative set-up,&#xA0;enhancing its functionality and identification of opportunities for decreasing the cost of&#xA0;public administration. TI BiH continued with its regular monitoring of the work of&#xA0;judiciary, with the focus on monitoring of prosecution of corruption cases, as well as&#xA0;accountability of the judiciary.During reporting period TI BiH prepared and published paper called &#x201C;The Rule ofCartel&#x201D; which discusses the political and institutional development of the post-conflictBiH, which remains a country that is still undergoing transition, based on the theoretical&#xA0;assumptions of the phenomena of the hybrid regimes, state capture and cartelization of&#xA0;politics. Moreover, publication &#x201C;Gender and Corruption in Failed Democracies &#x2013; Case&#xA0;study Bosnia and Herzegovina&#x201D; was published.&#xA0;Considering the effects of COVID-19 pandemic, TI BiH invested additional efforts for&#xA0;development and upgrade of online tools for public events, as well as to purchase&#xA0;additional equipment for the needs of organization of public events via online platform&#xA0;or in hybrid format with panelist in the room and other participants online.&#xA0;TI BiH Strategy 2021-2030 accompanied with the Action Plan adopted by the TI BiH&#xA0;Assembly. TI BiH put additional focus on strengthening the capacities of its staff.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12914" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
