<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12030A0101-BIH-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sarajevo Open Centers strategiska plan 2018-2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarajevo Open Centre Strategic Plan 2018-20</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen utg&#xF6;r ett fortsatt budgetst&#xF6;d till Sarajevo Open Centres och till dess Strategiska plan f&#xF6;r perioden 2018-2020. SOC har under de senaste tre &#xE5;ren 2014-2017 lagt en &#xE4;n starkare grund f&#xF6;r sitt arbete och en ledande roll i kampen f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i Bosnien-Hercegovina, med s&#xE4;rskild inriktning p&#xE5; LGBTI gruppens r&#xE4;ttigheter men &#xE4;ven p&#xE5; kvinnors m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i samh&#xE4;llet. Organisationen arbetar brett med medvetandeg&#xF6;rande insatser (advocacy) och lobby f&#xF6;r att skapa och f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndra lagstiftning och policies i en riktning som tillvaratar dessa gruppers r&#xE4;ttigheter. Man arbetar aktivt med uppf&#xF6;ljning och dokumentation av &#xF6;vergrepp, tar fram &#xE5;rsrapporter om kvinnor situation i landet. Man medverkar och samverkar p&#xE5; olika s&#xE4;tt med regeringen (government) och med institutioner i b&#xE5;da entiteterna och med partier och parliament f&#xF6;r att p&#xE5;verka situation f&#xF6;r LGBTI och kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter i en positiv riktning. Man utbildar tj&#xE4;nstem&#xE4;n och i den medvetandeg&#xF6;rande verksamheten finns stort fokus p&#xE5; juridsk r&#xE5;dgvning, social mobilisering av det civila samh&#xE4;llet samt organisationsutveckling och n&#xE4;tverksbyggande.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The initiative represents a continued budgetary support (core support) for the Sarajevo Open Centers and its Strategic Plan for the period 2018-2020. In the last three years 2014-2017, SOC has laid an even stronger foundation for its work and its unique role as a leading organization in the fight for human rights in Bosnia and Herzegovina, with a particular focus on the rights of the LGBTI group, but also on women&apos;s human rights in society. The organization works widely with advocacy efforts and lobbying to create and change legislation and policies in a direction that safeguards the rights of these groups. One actively works with follow-up and documentation of abuse, presents annual reports on women&apos;s situation in the country. Participating and interacting in various ways with government authorities and with institutions in both entities, as well as with parties and parliament to influence the situation of LGBTI and women&apos;s rights in a positive direction. SOC is training staff and in the awareness-raising business, and where there is a great deal of focus on legal advice, social mobilization of civil society and organizational development and networking.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarajevo Open Centre/Sarajevski Otvoreni Centar</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">184111.2031667127</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">169206.5271417845</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">173729.8717656384</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">184111.2031667127</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">169206.5271417845</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">173729.8717656384</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">552333.6095</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">184111.2031667127</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-28">169206.5271417845</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">173729.8717656384</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/finalagreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/socaddagreement2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to the Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/beslut-om-insats-12030.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats 12030</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/bosnia-and-herzegovina/beslutsoc2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on amendment</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarajevo Open Center - Narrative Report 2019 SOC has presented its annual narrative report closely connected to its Results Assessment Framework (Annex I) of its full reporting for FY 2019. This report is very comprehensive, information rich and easy to follow in terms of results made and in close collaboration to the existing original RFA/LFA, part of the agreement set up and the core funding mechanism and SOCs&apos; strategic plan 2018-2020. Apart from a good narration all indicators are easy to follow and where base lines exists in most cases which can then be followed in the target sections and results. Means of verification is stringently presented as well as comments to achievements or challenges existing.&#xA0;  Main comments to the reporting done; highlights. One striking feature of SOC work with the wider LGBTI community is the work laid down with activities involving also families and including parents to enhance the understanding and acceptance of the LGBTI group. A multitude of meetings was arranged, which has resulted in parents forming their own informal supportive groups and a platform through which&#xA0; they communicate and reach out to other parents. The first ever held Pride march was then done and conducted in Sarajevo on 8th of September 2019, with more than 2000 participants. The March was done without any violence and no one getting hurt. A major success for the Sarajevo Canton and for the full LGBTI community of BiH and the organizing committee. They had worked for nearly a full year to make this a success. &#xA0;  Information sharing is a crucial and important part of SOC work; identifying rights based related issues. Information is a vital element for the empowerment of the LGBTI community in BiH. During 2019 there were 146.907 individual visits to www.lgbti.ba. During the year peer giving advice is given to seekers. During 2019 48 LGBTI persons contacted for such peer to peer advice at SOC. Legal assistance has also been provided and 32 such assistance ere provided during the year. Same-sex partnership was one of the reasons behind seeking legal advice but other reasons too. litigations cases has been there, seeking protecting for their human rights. In 2019 four new cases started against discriminatory actions taken against LGBTI persons. In one of the cases for hate crimes one person was convicted and sentenced to pay a fine. &#xA0; &#xA0; Sarajevo Open Centre conducted training of police officers of Canton Sarajevo in 2019. Furthermore, a similar training of judges and lawyers were also done - leading to greater understanding of the rights of LGBTI persons, discriminations they face and hate crimes based on sexual orientation and gender identity. The first Pride March described above was supported by four political parties of BiH. &#xA0; Sarajevo Open Center - Financial Report 2019 In terms of funding (FY 2019) a total of 98.3% of the association&apos; operation in 2019 relates to the external funding for particular projects, while remaining 1.7% is the associations&apos; generated own revenue. Total funding amounted to 1,470,118 BAM whereas Sida&apos;s core support constituted 37,3 % or 539.000 BAM. At the end of the year a balance of 277,533 BAM remained and was transferred to FY 2020.&#xA0; One reason behind the relatively high balance (Swedish) is due to the fact that SOC obtained late in the year and additional 198.191 KM (1.1 MSEK, Democracy drive) funding and where more or less the main bulk of that money will be spent during FY 2020. In 2019 SOC had a total of 16 different funding sources.  In detail review of the financial reporting of FY 2019 (Core funding): Staff costs amounted to 94% of planned outlay in no any case did staff costs exceed 100% of what was initially planned for. In regards of office costs total amounted used 69%, one item exceeded original planned budget - vehicle cost 110%. Has probably to do with increased fuel costs. No substantive increase. Sida funds rolled over from FY 2018 was 51557 BAM added to which 2019 years&apos; allocation (1.6 MSEK) was released in March 2019 (289350 BAM). In total 340.907 BAM whereas a balance remaining (from the original core funding) amounting to 86.854 BAM.   In detail review of the additional funding provided by Sida &quot;Democracy drive&quot; - money released 17th June 2019 &#xA0;&#xA0;  As described above this additional fund was only made available to SOC in mid-June 2019. Due to other pressing commitments by SOC and including planning and execution of the first Pride March ever in BiH (8th September) they were not able to start using the special funds until period October-December 2019. Only a mere 7.513 BAM was spent then, and the balance 190.677 BAM will be duly spent during FY 2020. Sarajevo Open Center - Audit Report 2019&#xA0; The Auditor&apos;s opinion for the financial period 1.1 2019 until 31.12 2019 and of the core support provided is an unqualified verdict. And that in all material aspects the financing reporting standards are upheld. Furthermore, nothing else (other matters) pertaining to the audit has been discovered.  The adjoining management letter issues by the auditor (Intercons d.o.o) has in all five areas of observations resulted in full compliance by Sarajevo Open Centre.  Final comments &amp;amp; Issues to raise with SOC during Annual meeting Your outlook for the remaining part of 2020 &#x2013; given implications from COVID and the Corona (now and near future) What about the next Pride March 2020, and other planned event(s) Potential openings but also challenge, in terms of political and practical work for SOC in strengthening the LGBTI work Your plans for the future; given from experience from 2019 and 2020. What is the main take away from the recent evaluation you conducted? Changes in future strategic plans 2021- an onwards Your and partners capacities, staff situation? Your views on us donors (more widely), the need for support (in what form and way). Donor and SOC coordination efforts?</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="12030" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
