<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10653A0101-BIH-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Feasibility Studie f&#xF6;r vatten och avloppsvatten i Brcko Distrikt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feasibilty study for water&amp;waste water in Brcko District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) has applied to Embassy of Sweden for funding of 2 547 500 SEK needed to carry out the Feasibility study for water and waste water in Brcko District, Bosnia and Herzegovina (BIH) in 2017.

The intervention aims at preparation of comprehensive feasibility study for Brcko District, which will help to determine a priority investment programme and evaluate its benefits, including assessing its environmental and social feasibility. The feasibility study will also provide an overview of the Comunal Company&apos;s procedures and technical, operational, environmental, social, and financial performance, and should form the basis for agreeing on the Company&apos;s restructuring objectives (e.g. reduction in water losses, improvements in tariff collections, standards of treatment, etc.)

Overall, EBRD will use the Feasibilty study to appraise the water&amp;waste water project in Brcko and take a decision on the prospective financing. This will also open oportunity for Sweden to consider possibility of co-financing the waste water treatment plant in Brcko in the future.

Feasibility study will be prepared by independent consultant, which will be procured and monitored by EBRD. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 2 547 500 SEK, planned to be transferred to EBRD in one upfront tranche in 2016. All activities will be finalized in 2017.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Europeiska banken f&#xF6;r &#xE5;teruppbyggnad och utveckling (EBRD) har ans&#xF6;kt om 2 547 500 kronor fr&#xE5;n Sveriges ambassad i Sarajevo f&#xF6;r att utf&#xF6;ra Feasibility Studie f&#xF6;r vatten och avloppsvatten i Brcko Distrikt, Bosnien och Hercegovina (BIH) i 2017.

Interventionen syftar till en beredning av omfattande Feasibility studie f&#xF6;r Brcko Distrikt, som vill hj&#xE4;lpa till att best&#xE4;mma prioriterad investering program och utv&#xE4;rdera f&#xF6;rdelar, bland annat att bed&#xF6;ma milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssiga och sociala genomf&#xF6;rbarhet. Feasibility Studie kommer ocks&#xE5; att ge en &#xF6;versikt &#xF6;ver Kommunala f&#xF6;retagets rutiner och teknisk, operativ, milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssiga, sociala och ekonomiska resultat, och b&#xF6;r ligga till grund f&#xF6;r att komma &#xF6;verens om omstrukturerings m&#xE5;l (t.ex. minskning av h&#xF6;ga vattenf&#xF6;rluster, f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttringar i tull samlingar, normer f&#xF6;r behandling, etc.)

EBRD kommer att anv&#xE4;nda Feasibility studie f&#xF6;r att bed&#xF6;ma vatten och avfallsvattenprojekt i Brcko och fatta beslutet om framtida finansieringen. Detta kommer ocks&#xE5; att &#xF6;ppna m&#xF6;jligheter f&#xF6;r Sverige att m&#xF6;jligen samfinansiera avloppvattenreningsverk i Brcko inom framtiden.

Feasibility studie kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras av oberoende konsult, som kommer att upphandlas och kontrolleras av EBRD.

Total budget av insatserna &#xE4;r 2 547 500 kronor, planerade att &#xF6;verf&#xF6;ras till EBRD i delkvoten i 2016. All verksamhet kommer att slutf&#xF6;ras under 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific objective of intervention is to confirm the need for investment in water&amp;waste water in Brcko, but also to assess technical and financial feasibility of the proposed investments as well as to define priority investment programme and its implementation strategy.The intervention is instrumental to effectively identify and assess possibilities for financing in water&amp;waste water sector in Brcko district.  Objectives of intervention are well-defined and possible to monitor. The intervention logic is clear and realistic. The result matrix is assessed clear and logical, containing the baseline values and measurable indicators against. Critical assumptions for the achievement of the objectives are also assessed and presented.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="46015" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EBRD/European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="46015" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">297726.8743060831</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">297726.8743060831</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-01">297726.874306</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">297726.8743060831</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) acts as implementing partner holding the full responsibility for the project implementation. The consultants hired by EBRD prepared the priority investment programme for Bank financing, based on which the feasibility study was successfully completed. In addition to consultants, the EBRD experts were involved during the preparation of the study, whilst the prepared Final Report documents were duly reviewed and approved by EBRD experts. During the project implementation the Consultant maintained a continuous dialogue with the EBRD, the Company, the Brcko District and other stakeholders. As the exchange of information and aligning the interests of concerned stakeholder took longer than expected, the assignment was completed with four months delay. Instead of completing it by 30 June 2017, the final draft document has been presented at the Brcko District Assembly on 27 September 2017.The key findings of the Feasibility Study are presented below:Priority Investment Programme (PIP)Water supply projects:1. Main Transmission Pipeline (GTC)2. Branch for water supply of Brod settlement3. Branch 1 for water supply of east side of BD4. Branch 2 for water supply of east side of BD5. Branch for water supply of west side of BD6. Reconstruction of existing water supply network7. Purchase of metering equipment and vehiclesWastewater projects: 1. Reconstruction of concrete sewage system2. Construction of new main sewage collectors 3. Construction of WWTP for urban area
Financial Analysis The financial analysis of the Project included the following: &#x2022; affordability analysis for W&amp;WW tariffs&#x2022; analysis of the historical financials of the Company and specifically WSS; &#x2022; financial projections for the WSS for the period from 2017 to 2036; &#x2022; analysis of the financial information of the BD and its capacity to repay new loans;&#x2022; incremental revenues and expenses resulting from the Project, along with financial internal rate of return (&#x201C;IRR&#x201D;) and the economic rate of return on the investment (&#x201C;EIRR&#x201D;).
Environmental and Social AnalysisThe Project will have a significant positive impact, including:&#x2022; Stabilization of water supply through pressure regulation of the system. &#x2022; Construction and operation of the WWTP will significantly reduce wastewater discharges, greatly improving the ecosystem of the recipient rivers and improve the quality of aquatic environment. In addition, public health risks associated with discharges of untreated wastewater will be minimised.&#x2022; Improved living conditions and hygienic conditions.&#x2022; Employment opportunities, and thereby increased incomes, and human resource development in a form of staff training by suppliers of equipment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10653" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
