<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10496A0101-BIH-32130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small Business Act, EDA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sm&#xE5;f&#xF6;retagslagen, EDA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
EDA, Local Development Agency (Lokala Utvecklingsbyr&#xE5;) i Bosnien och Hercegovina, har l&#xE4;mnat in projektans&#xF6;kan till Sveriges ambassad f&#xF6;r finansiering med 17,5 MSEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet f&#xF6;r &quot;Small Business Act&quot; (SBA) i Bosnien och Hercegovina under perioden 2017-2020.

Interventionen syftar till att harmonisera strategiska och politiska ramar f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag i Bosnien och Hercegovina. Detta kommer att ske genom st&#xF6;d till institutioner f&#xF6;r att accelerera den ekonomiska integrationen med EU n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller strategiska och politiska ramar f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat &#xE4;r harmoniserad juridisk, strategisk och politiskt ramverk f&#xF6;r sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag i Bosnien och Hercegovina baserat p&#xE5; SBA.

Projekts totala budget &#xE4;r 17,5 MSEK, varav 17 MSEK &#xE4;r f&#xF6;r organisation, resterande belopp &#xE4;r f&#xF6;r senare utv&#xE4;rdering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
EDA, Local Development Agency from BiH, has applied to Embassy of Sweden in BiH for funding of 17,5 million SEK to carry out the &quot;Small Business Act Strategic Framework&quot; in Bosnia and Herzegovina during the period 2017-2020. 

The intervention aims at harmonizing of SME strategic and Policy Framework in BiH, to be in line with SBA. This will be done through supporting institutions to accelerate economic integration with the EU in the field of SME strategic and policy framework. Expected result is harmonized legal, strategic and policy framework for SMEs in BiH based on SBA. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 17,5 million SEK, out of which 16,7 MSEK is for organization and the remaining amount is for evaluation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the Small Business Act project is to support institutions in Bosnia and Hercegovina to accelerate economic integration with the EU in the area of SMEs. The project also aims to harmonize the national legal, strategic and policy framework for SME development internally - between different administrative levels in the country  and to interlink internal harmonization with the external EU SME framework. In order to use and adapt Small Business Act as a common methodological framework to harmonize legal, strategic and policy framework for SMEs in Bosnia and Hercegovina, the project encompasses all stages of policy development (planning, implementation, M&amp;E, revision) and facilitating interactions of key stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EDA/Enterprise Development Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EDA/Enterprise Development Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small and medium-sized enterprises (SME) development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">234000.234000234</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">634524.4767816919</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">234000.234000234</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">634524.4767816919</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-24">1989001.989001</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">234000.234000234</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">1035625.5178127589</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">634524.4767816919</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall project was structured around 8 expected results as follows: 
ER 1: SME Laws in the country changed and adopted in accordance to , SBAER 2: Improved implementation of SBA based parts of existing SME strategies and plans in the country, ER 3: A common methodology for preparation, implementation, M&amp;E of SME strategies prepared and agreed between key stakeholders in the country, ER 4: Existing SME strategies and plans revised in accordance with common methodology based on , SBAER 5: Harmonized SME policies, ER 6: New SME strategies and plans for the period after 2020 developed in accordance with common methodology and adopted by relevant authorities, ER 7: Fully functional harmonized institutional set-up for SME development, ER 8: Harmonized SME policies and practices promoted to local and international stakeholders supporting SME development
The project during its implementation measured progress across all mentioned results. With this said, it would be important to note that project operated in a difficult political context and complex administrative structure. To meet the requirements, wide range of stakeholders needed to be engaged in the process, achieve consensus and apply harmonized and even approach across the country. Regarding harmonization of SME policies and practices, three ways of harmonization are successfully tested and applied:
Harmonization of laws and strategies in the country with SBA as corresponding EU framework and mutually between different administrative levels in the country (harmonization of the laws on small and medium enterprises; harmonization of SME development strategies); after reflection this type of harmonization is named indirect harmonization;

Top-down harmonization  tested and applied for those policies where the state level has appropriate competencies, in the field of quality infrastructure (five harmonized measures for progress in terms of standards and technical regulations) and in the field of internationalization (three measures to strengthen the competitiveness of export-oriented SMEs in global value chains); two harmonized policy instruments are fully developed, one for supporting SMEs to introduce technical standards and one for supporting internationalization of SMEs (export-promotion), and promoted by publications; similarly a harmonized approach to state-aid in regard to SME support is elaborated, embedded into Strategic Guidelines and promoted by a publication;

Bottom-up harmonisation - tested and applied for those policies when the competencies are at the level of entities and Brko District, as in the case of harmonized development and adoption of action plans for SME innovation (adopted three action plans with the same structure and a set of four main measures), as well as in the case of piloting SME energy transition support policies and practices; promoted by three publications  

The project measured progress across all expected results and managed to established solid grounds for completing the harmonization of the legal and strategic framework as an irreversible process. Documents developed in support of the project are only pending formal adoption by respective governments and parliaments due to other political obstacles the country faces. In other words, once political issues that are not related to issues tackled by this project are resolved prepared documents  in the support of the project should not be subject to additional scrutiny, being already agreed between all relevant stakeholders.  Once the official adoption is completed of SME - related policies, laws and strategies developed in support of the project SBA alignment will most likely be institutionalized.

To provide some noteworthy examples of main outputs that project delivered directly contributing to overall objective and implementation of project results;

a) Draft BIH Strategic Guidelines for Harmonization of SME Support finalized prepared for adoption. It is being used as one of the key inputs for IPA III Programming

b) SME related ministries and departments at the state, entity and Brcko District (BD) levels adopted the same methodological guidelines in line with SBA. 

c) RS Law on Amendments to the Law on SME Developments adopted by RS National Assembly (2019) 

d) Draft Law on Stimulating Development of SMEs in BIH is adopted by the FBIH Government and both Houses of the Parliament and it is in its final stages of adoption 

e) Law on stimulating Economic Development in BD is in the adoption procedure. 

f)  FBIH Development Strategy (including key elements of SBA) is in its final stages of adoption while FBIH SME Development Strategy is under preparation. 

g) BD SME Development Strategy (including key elements of SBA) is adopted and BD SME Development Strategy is prepared, pending formal adoption. 

h) SME related public- private dialogue is fully functional on the state level, while on the other levels of governance progress is being made. 

i) Strategy Implementation Enabling Mechanism is successfully introduced and tested. 

When it comes to achievements that were not precisely planned are related to innovation in SMEs supported through the voucher program and setting up green economy and energy management in SMEs on the agenda of interventions in SMEs.

Project also provided assistance to the project partners in providing an evidence-based assessment and reporting during the OECDSME/SBAWBT preparation of SME Policy Index and BiHSBA Profile (2021, to be published in 2022). Technical assistance on demand was provided to BIH Ministry for Foreign Trade and Economic Relations in providing data for OECD questionnaires. As a result, all required questionnaires were timely filled in, completed and delivered to the OECD

Lastly,  SBAinBiH single portal is developed. All project partners expressed an interest to use it as an additional tool for monitoring implementation of SME related strategies and plans as well as a valuable resource for preparation of SME Policy Index and BiH SBA Profile in future (2024-2025).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10496" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
