<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10174A0101-BIH-15114</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Skattemyndigheter: kapacitetsutveckling, Skatteverket</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tax Administrations: capacity building, Swedish Tax Authority</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med projektet &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra skattemyndigheternas kapacitet och att bidra till en omvandling till moderna, mer transparenta och betrodda skattemyndigheter i Bosnien och Hercegovina.
De prioriterade omr&#xE5;dena &#xE4;r:
&#x2022; f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndra och utveckla tankes&#xE4;ttet runt skattehantering
&#x2022; service till skattebetalare
&#x2022; riskhantering inom skattemyndigheter
Skattemyndigheterna i Bosnien och Hercegovina ger fullt st&#xF6;d till projektet och kommer leda projektet tillsammans med &#x201D;Office for International Projects &#x201D; (OIP) i STA. STA kommer att anst&#xE4;lla en heltidsperson, planerat f&#xF6;r april 2017.
Den planerade projekttiden &#xE4;r fyra &#xE5;r (2017-2020). Totala budgeten f&#xF6;r projektet &#xE4;r cirka 26,5 miljoner kronor (26,5 MSEK) finansierats av Sverige-Sida. Rekommendationen &#xE4;r att finansiera &quot;Tax System reform i Bosnien och Hercegovina&quot; med 26 500 000 kronor (26,5 MSEK) under perioden 2017-2020.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective for the project is to improve the tax administrations capacity and contribute to a transformation for more modern, trustworthy and helpful tax administrations in the BiH.
The prioritized areas are:
&#x2022;Change the Mindset 
&#x2022;Taxpayer Service 
&#x2022;Compliance Risk Management 
The Tax Administrations in the BiH has committed full support to the project. The Tax Administrations in the BiH will lead the project together with the Office for International Projects (OIP) in the STA. A long term expert from STA will be recruited and is planned to be installed in April 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective for the project is to improve the tax administrations capacity and contribute to a transformation for more modern, trustworthy and helpful tax administrations in the BiH.
There are seven current components for the project, with more detailed objectives for each one of them.
1. Change the mindset
2. Taxpayer services
3. Pre-filling of tax returns
4. Compliance Risk Management
5. Tax Gap and improved analysis
6. BEPS and Global Forum Activities
7. Audit training and improved methods for inspectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skatteverket</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skatteverket</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15114" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Domestic revenue mobilisation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">656747.2797472797</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">823092.9531436987</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">723339.3965672225</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">748553.047330532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-216412.4567151302</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">656747.2797472797</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">823092.9531436987</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">723339.3965672227</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">748553.0473305321</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-216412.4567151302</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-01">2883333.567333</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">631800.6318006318</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">24946.6479466479</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">823092.9531436987</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">723339.3965672225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">748553.047330532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">-216412.4567151302</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On an overall level, the MTR concludes that the project has been relevant and largely met the needs and priorities of the tax administrations and the ministries of finance (with some minor exceptions in some components and in some administrations). The project components have been reasonably effective in achieving their objectives, albeit somehow slower in some administrations and some components than expected (partly also explained by covid-19). The project is set tp contribute to some significant positive and long-term effects in the area of building capacity, improving taxpayer services and communications, improved tax compliance throught better risk analysis and management and improved international cooperation in the area of tax avoidance. Project results are also considered to be sustainable, not least because much of the learning and progress is a result of interaction between the BiH tax administrations themselves. All in all, the MTR concludes that the project has made a significant contribution to its objective to improve the tax administrations capacity and contribute to a transformation for more modern, trustworthy and helpful tax administrations in BiH. and has laid som good foundations to be built upon in a possible second phase.&#xA0;
A positive side effect, that was not included as an objective, is the project&apos;s contribution to relationships of trust between the different participating tax administrations and ministries of finance. This has facilitated cooperation and learning between the organisations in several areas. The project&apos;s emphasis on joint workshops has made this possible.&#xA0;
Results in relation to each component are as follows:&#xA0;&#xA0;
1. Change the mindset: The component is relevant and consistent with participating institution&apos;s priorities. The project has contributed to significant changes in the mindset for those in contact with the project, increasing collaboration between tax administrations, building the capacity of staff to work with wider cultural change, and giving momentum to modernisation in other components. The work has laid good foundations for more progress in the long run. It is however challenging to give this work an overall structure or direction and to reach out to and engage more tax administration staff in this cultural change work. There need to be a clear strategic direction for each participating institution on what to achieve with the cultural change.&#xA0;&#xA0;
2. Taxpayer services: The participating administrations are committed to improve in this area. Progress in some parts of the component has been slow due to complex decision-making processes, notably in FBiH and BD. The component has contributed to improved taxpayer services in many areas outside the original scope of the project. The progress has been slower than originally expected in some administrations. All four tax administrations have developed external communication strategies. The component has also taken several steps towards establishing service centres for tax payers, some are already up and running. The project has, through STA, inspired developments in other areas too, for example regarding call centres and websites. These are good examples of the positive aspects of the methodology of peer-to-peer learning and exchange in this project.&#xA0;&#xA0;
3. Pre-filling of tax returns: Although progress vary among the tax administrations, capacity has been built in the area of pre-filling and hence laid the ground for further results and improvements. Progress is most evident in RS, who have now implemented and evaluated two successful pilots. For BD, it is somewhat unclear whether progress is due to the project or any other initiative. However, there has been significant progress in pre-filling of income tax returns and there is a new software developed to facilitate the work. In FBiH, the plan has been more ambitions and the work has been partly stalled due to a legislation process. Howerver, there is a solution on a technical level ready to be used.&#xA0;
4. Compliance Risk Management: The component has made significant progress. A challenge in this component has been that the four administrations came with different levels of experience and existing structures in the area of risk management, which has sometimes made i t difficult to find the right level for the missions. All participating organisations have made significant progress in this area both as a result of increased knowledge about the area but not least because of better coordination among the organizations, including learning exchanges. It is highly likely that the project will contribute to better risk management in all four administrations, which in turn will lead to improved tax compliance and efficiency.&#xA0;
5. Tax Gap and improved analysis: This is a large and complex area and the absorption capacity varies/is weak among the participation organisations. The administrations have developed a good understanding of tax gap analysis and begun to carry out and present some tax gap analysis in specific sectors. It is not yet possible to make conclusions on whether these results will lead to sustained impact.&#xA0;
6. BEPS and Global Forum Activities: This component is highly appreciated among the participating organisations, notably in RS and FBiH, and has contributed significantly to increased knowledge, capacity and prepardness. The role of STA is valued; work would not have happened without the STA support and STA has also had an important role as a bridge between the OECD BEPS Secretariat and the BiH administrations and helded BiH prepare for the peer review in 2021.&#xA0;
7. Audit training and improved methods for inspectors: Work within this component has not been up to speed yet. There is a need (sometimes acute because of aging staff) for improving knowledge and capcity within this area.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10174" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
