<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13162A0101-BIH-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women Strategic Note, UNW</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Womens Strategiska Plan, UNW</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till UN Women Strategiska Plan f&#xF6;r Bosnien-Hercegovina 2019-2022

Det f&#xF6;reslagna UN Women programmet och dess  &quot;concept note&quot; (konceptpapper) beg&#xE4;r st&#xF6;d till UN Women Strategiska Plan f&#xF6;r implementering i Bosnia och Hercegovina under perioden 2019-2022. Det f&#xF6;reslagna programmet inneh&#xE5;ller fem huvudsakliga resultatomr&#xE5;den vilka &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande: i) Styrande strukturer/regelverk samt sektorprioriteringar som reflekterar j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet mellan k&#xF6;nen, ii) Kvinnor har inkomsts&#xE4;kerhet, goda arbetsf&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden och ekonomisk autonomi, iii) Kvinnor och flickor kan leva ett liv utan v&#xE5;ld av olika former, iv) Fred och s&#xE4;kerhet och humanit&#xE4;ra &#xF6;verv&#xE4;ganden skapade av och f&#xF6;r kvinnor samt v) Att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra UN Systemet i syfte att bli mer effektivt och koordinerat (strategiska samarbeten).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to UN Women Strategic Note in Bosnia and Hercegovina 2019-2022

The proposed UN Women programme concept note requests support for support to UN Women Strategic Note Implementation in Bosnia and Hercegovina during 2019-2022. The proposed programme five main impact areas as follows: i) Governance structures and sector priorities reflect gender equality, ii) Women have income security, decent work and economic autonomy, iii) Women and girls live a life free of violence, iv) Peace and Security and humanitarian action shaped by women and v) To enhance UN System and become more effective and coordinated (strategic partnerships).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the intervention is to contribute to the implementation of UN Women Bosnia and Hercegovina Strategic Note for the period 2019-2022 (proposed to be extended until the end of 2023), which encompassess two strategic cycles; Strategic Note 2015-2020 and the Strategic Note 2021-2025.
The Strategic Note 2015-2020 included five so called impact areas:
Impact 1: Governance structures and sector priorities reflect gender equality&#xA0;concerns and committments. Impact 2: Women have income security, decent work and economic autonomy.Impact 3: Women and girls live a life free of violence.Impact 4: Peace and security and humanitarian action are shaped by women&#xA0;leadership and participation.Impact 5: To drive more effective and efficient UN System coordination and strategic&#xA0;partnership on gender equality and women&apos;s empowerment.In the new strategic note 2021-2025, there are three overarching impacts and connected outcomes, which are gathered under corresponding thematic areas. These are the same as in UN Women global strategic note as well as the UNSDCF. To each impact/outcome, there are several outputs which are more tied to the UN Women programme in BiH. Many of the outputs are about strengthened capacity among stakeholders in BiH.
Three thematic areas are included in the program:
1. Women&apos;s economic empowermentImpact: Women have income security, decent work and economic autonomyOutcome: By 2025, people benefit from resilient, inclusive and sustainable growth ensured by the convergence of economic development and management of environment and cultural resources
2. Gender based violenceImpact: All women and girls live a life free from all forms of violenceOutcome: People have access to better quality and inclusive health and social protection systems
3. Gender responsive governanceImpact: Women lead, participate in and benefit equally from governance systemsOutcome: By 2025, people contribute to, and benefit from more accountable and transparent governance systems that deliver quality public services, and ensure rule of law.
Women, peace and security will be mainstreamed throughout the programme, where women participation and inclusion in decision making processes will be targeted under all areas, notably under gender responsive governance.&#xA0;
Apart from the three programmatic areas and the cruss-cutting areas, UN Women have set objevtives for organisational effectiveness and efficiency, inluding their coordination role within the UN family, engagement of partners, communication, internal learning, and internal management and control.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bosnia and Herzegovina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">846032.6357089225</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1065478.203080367</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">846032.6357089225</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1065478.203080367</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-01">2870007.085523</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">846032.6357089225</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">816145.6936655435</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">249332.5094148235</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bosnia-and-herzegovina/finalagreementunw2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/bosnia-and-herzegovina/decisionunw2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s economic empowerment: This area is comparatively small and under development. So far, UN Women has commissioned to larger studies, with policy recommendations, about women&apos;s economic empowerment in BiH and resilience of women-owned businesses. In addition, a Rapid Gender Assessment during covid-19 has also informed UN Women&apos;s future programming.&#xA0; UN Women has&#xA0;also supported an NGO working directly with women entrepreneurs, which has resulted in developed and resilient businesses.&#xA0;

Ending Violence Against Women (EVAW): This area is where the bulk of Swedish funds go (as Sweden previously provided funding through project based support).

Under the UN Women SN 2015-2020 the work on EVAW was conceptualized around two results: improved services for survivors of VAWG in line with the provisions of Istanbul Convention and, active participation of different actors in prevention of VAW s at community and individual level.&#xA0;

Under UN Women SN 2021-2025 work on EVAW will be built on the results achieved and furthermore contribute to the three results. One, enhanced legal and institutional framework to incorporate the highest level of international standards on EVAW in laws, policies, and budgets will be continued; Two, community prevention work shall contribute to seven local communities are able to mobilize actors, resources, and capacities to create an environment for zero tolerance to violence; and third victim-centered services are accessible to women survivors in BIH.&#xA0;

UN Women has continued to contribute to improved quality of a multi-sectoral response to domestic violence on the local level, in selected cantons and municipalities.&#xA0;During 2019 and 2020 two entity Gender Centers were supported to work on improving services for survivors though policy development at entity and local level, establishing multisectoral teams and raising their capacities to provide coordinated response to domestic violence in three Cantons and 11 municipalities. Three CSOs and their partners organizations were supported to undertake assessments and develop advocacy recommendations for improved service provision for survivors of domestic violence and to develop a first in-depth analysis on sexual violence in BiH. Eight safe houses in BiH have been supported to strengthen capacities in providing specialized services for survivors of violence in times of pandemics. UN Women &#xA0;in cooperation with FBiH Ministry of Interior developed a policy and methodology for capacity building on standardized police response to cases of domestic violence in FBiH.

In prevention of VAW, during 2019 and 2020 UN Women worked on strengthening four local communities to develop and undertake prevention activities for zero tolerance to violence. UN Women established strategic partnership with the City of Banja Luka to work on safe and inclusive public spaces for women and girls. Efforts for strengthening the role of media in prevention of VAWG resulted in development of high-quality media content on VAW and improved cooperation between local newsrooms and multisectoral teams in 11 communities across BiH. Different forms of VAWG and influence of the Covid-19 pandemics to VAWG in BIH were placed in the center of the public discourse during November and December in 2019 and 2020 contributing to the increased awareness of the public.

Gender responsive governance: The area has expanded in the new SN from Gender responsive budgeting to governance. Since September 2020, the gender budget component is part of the Sida-funded regional project on gender budgeting. Before that, the intervention has contributed to increased capacity within targeted institutions, such as ministries of finance, gender institutional mechanisms, and other line ministries. Work has also been put in strengthening capacity of parliamentarians to overseepolicies and review state budgets from a gender perspective. So far, UN Women has seen two gender equality discussions rased by parliamentarians. It is not clear how UN Women&apos;s efforts have led to changed behaviours.&#xA0;

UN Women has also worked with the gender equality agency, gender centres and the directorate for EU integration to improve gender mainstreaming in the public sector and in the EU accession process, mainly through guidance and analyses in three policy sectors (agriculture and rural development, competitiveness and innovation, democracy and rule of law). It is unclear how these documents have been used and whether it has led to increased capacity or changed behaviours. This work has been continued under the Gender Equality Facility (GEF) project, funded by EU.&#xA0;

Covid 19: UN Women was active in the beginning of the pandemic through coordination of the UN responce to the pandemic. UN Women also issued studies and assessments of the situation, and has continued to analyse and make assessments of how different groups of women or sectors are affected by the pandemic, and to publish policy briefs with recommendations for different stakeholders. These and other more in-depth analyses are used to inform UN Women&apos;s and UN&apos;s further programming.&#xA0;

Coordination and communication: Apart from enabling a range of ongoing programmatic engagement, with results achieved and progress on track, Sweden&apos;s support has enabled UN Women to ensure a step change in Coordination and Communication to advance the gender equality and empowerment of women agenda in the country. Coordination is focused on four areas of engagement: gender equality institutional mechanisms, the UNCT, the international community and in cooperation with the civil society. The coordination is central to UN Women&apos;s effectiveness since UN Women can influence others more effectively. Communication goes hand in hand with coordination, and has seen a step change and significant increase in traditional and social media engagement and initiation of systemic efforts aimed at Strategic Communication, contributing to increased effectiveness and further outreach.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13162" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
