<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-16/DDA-3604/Call for Proposals/H/INGO/3226</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing Holistic Health Care Support for vulnerable Syrian refugees and Lebanese in Beirut, Mount Lebanon and North Governorates (PHCS Project)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International (RI) proposes the 12-month project &#x201C;Providing Holistic Health Care Support for vulnerable Syrian refugees and Lebanese in Beirut, Mount Lebanon and North Governorates (PHCS Project)&quot; to improve access to and quality of Primary Health Care (PHC) services for the most vulnerable Syrian refugees and Lebanese. RI&#x2019;s proposed intervention is built on the sector priorities, gaps, and needs, and several coordination meetings with the sector leads. Through the proposed project, RI will support 11 Primary Health Care Centres (PHCCs) to ensure proper utilization of the primary health care system by informing and educating target populations about services and subsidizing consultation fees. 
The Women 2 Women (W2W) outreach will inform, educate and encourage women to attend early Antenatal Care (ANC), utilize Family Planning (FP) methods, and Postnatal Care (PNC) follow-up. Care-givers will also be taught to recognize danger signs related to child health and to bring their children to the PHCC for early preventative care rather than waiting for treatment which may lead to hospitalization and higher out-of-pocket costs. RI will also work with the Ministry of Public Health (MOPH) to promote and facilitate routine vaccination of CU5 at the supported health facilities. 
As Reproductive Health (RH) is a main focus of this project, RI will be responsible of providing RH services for women in RI&#x2019;s supported PHCCs and support the W2W groups in their health concerns while leading focus group discussions. 
Access to Mental Health (MH) care has been identified as a gap in available services. 
RI will recruit 2 part time Psychologists to support the integration of the National Mental Health GAP (MhGAP) Program into the PHCCs with close coordination with World Health Organization (WHO) and the National Mental Health Department (NMHD) at MOPH. RI&#x2019;s part time Psychologists will endorse the implementation of the strategy in the selected PHCCs and will be responsible of the supervision of the activities which will include pharmaceuticals requests, patients follow up, reporting, and other technical support as needed. MhGAP implementation will be continually monitored through RI&#x2019;s MampE department in coordination with the part time Psychologists and shared with the NMHD and WHO to proactively address challenges and gaps.
To further integrate the Mental Health services and W2W outreach, W2W volunteers will be trained to discreetly and sensitively identify and refer survivors of Sexual and Gender Based Violence (SGBV) for medical and psycho-social services. Finally, to enhance awareness about availability of health services provided through MOPH PHCCs and accountability to the beneficiaries, RI will contract a production company to produce audio-visuals segments related to information on health services that can be accessed by all beneficiaries, which will be broadcast in RI&#x2019;s supported MOPH PHCCs and United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) Reception Centres. The content of the videos will be closely coordinated with the Communications Section of UNHCR and in turn the Health Sector before proceeding to production. RI already maintains experience working with a partner organization to produce audio-visual materials that are currently broadcast at the four UNHCR Registration Centres, which were developed through the consultative process with UNHCR Communications Section and relevant Sector Leads. RI will follow the same process to ensure new content related to MOPH PHCC Services and healthy practices is produced and broadcast.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-23" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valerie Rowles</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">County Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03114721</telephone>
   <email>valerie.rowles@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beirut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88690000 35.51310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN3">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mount Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.83330000 35.53330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN5">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.43330000 35.85000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-03">196153.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-10-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-03">853846.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-3226">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-03">1050000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302287269">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-14">630000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302899564">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-22">420000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
