<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-12wrf-5882</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Networking of family farmers&#x2019; organizations for improved Food Security governance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Rural Forum, a bask NGO with strong links and engagement in the rural world and with farmers&apos; organisations, has succesfully lobbied for the International Year of Family Farming. The UN declared 2014 to be this IYFF and instructed the FAO to implement the activities.

The WRF wants to benefit from the upswing the year might give to the cause of family farming to build more extensive interorganisational links among farmers&apos; organizations and to prepare in a particpatory way for a general framework that gives a common denominator on seven issues in order to enable farmers&apos; organisations to run their advocacy in their country. 

Agriterra is asked to engage for 1 million Euros in the process, funding three World Consultative Committee Meetings, two participatory thematic workshops per continent,and an International workshop along with the work of the WRF.

Within the framework of the International Year of Family Farming, that was announced by the UN respondi ng to a lobby initiated by the World Rural Forum, this bask NGO proposes a series of meetings to prepare for effective national lobbies taking advantage of the IYFF.

The following (many of those well know and clients of Agriterra) organizations are very actively committed to the process: 1 international federation (IFOAM), 8 continental or regional: AFA (Asia), COPA &#x2013;COGECA (Europe), COPROFAM (MERCOSUR), EAFF (East Africa), PAFO (Pan-African), PROPAC (Central Africa), ROPPA (West Africa), SACAU (South Africa) and 17 national or local family FFOs: AFDI (France), BWA (Belgium), CAOPA (Senegal), CCAE (Spain), CIFA (India), CIOEC (Bolivia), CONFRAS (El Salvador), CONVEAGRO (Peru), ENBA (Spain), FCAE (Spain), FEMUPROCAN (Nicaragua), UNAF (Chile), Jeunes Agriculteurs (France), SBV (Switzerland), UNAG (Nicaragua), UPA (Spain) and WAMTI (Indonesia).

With these organizations the WRF proposes to achieve the objectives listed in goals, being increased linkages among farmers&apos; organizations, and an agreed program for lobbying.

In the project with Agriterra, the WRF ains to attain the follwing result: 
Family farmers&apos; organizations elaborated a comprehensive framework for family farmers&apos; political demands at different levels

The envisaged activities are:
1.1. Consultation to identify/validate the most important issues for lobbying, at least the 7 thematic areas analyzed prior to and during the Family Farming World Conference. 
1.2. Systematization of the consultation process, preparation of working papers. 
1.3. Organize and hold three World Consultative Committee Meetings 
1.4. 2 participatory thematic workshops per continent, working on political strategies and proposals to be implemented during the International Year of Family Farming and a mechanism for the follow-up of the process. 
1.5. Dissemination of the outcomes of the regional workshops. 
1.6. International workshop to validate the information and the follow-up mechanism. 
1.7. Internal evaluation.

Next to the application to Agriterra, the WRF filed application to IFAD ($ 462.000) and the EC (unknown requested contribution). 

The FAO has been selected by the UN to formally implment the IYFF.

Increased linkage of family farmers&apos; organizations at regional and international level, contributing to the agreement on common demands for more coordinated advocacy in terms of Food Security and poverty reduction.. An agreed program for lobbying activities of family farmers&apos; organizations from five continents (Africa, America, Asia, Europe and Oceania) on common issues, taking advantage of the International Year of Family Farming in 2014 and its preparatory process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="2" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="WRF" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Rural Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-04-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31.26.44 55 445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xC1;lava</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basque country</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory policy formulation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
