<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-16iaki-6632</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategy development dairy processing activities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IAKIB is a dairy cooperative in the northern province of Rwanda, Gicumbi, with 684 members and approximately 10 million liters of milk annually. The cooperative is comparatively well organized and it aims to start milk processing in the near future. 

Currently IAKIB collects 30,000 liters of milk per day and sells it to Blessed Dairies, who hence sells 25,000 liters to Rwanda&#x2019;s market leading milk processor Inyange. Besides bulking, IAKIB has cow feed activities and provides minor financial services to its members. The first business case concerns starting with milk processing, the second concerns increasing the cow feed activities and the third concerns starting a SACCO (cooperative bank).

Agriterra&apos;s involvement is mainly focused on the processing activities of IAKIB. Its current buyer, Blessed Dairies, sells the majority of the milk as a middleman, but transforms approximately 5,000 liters per day into yoghurt, cheese and pasteurized milk. IAKIB is considering to start a joint venture with Blessed Dairies, to increase shareholder value with value added activities and benefit from the experience and knowledge of Blessed. The owner of Blessed is a member of IAKIB. IAKIB however is not sure whether this is the right way to go and also considers a sole venture. Agriterra aims to support IAKIB in 2016 with helping them find out the pro&apos;s and con&apos;s of each option and to define their strategy concerning the processing activities. The actions in 2016 include legal advice, an exchange visit to Meru Central Dairy in Kenya, a study visit on joint venture activities at UCORIBU in Rwanda and a Agriterra expert visit on strategic planning.

null

Clarify strategy for processing activities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="IAKIB" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ihuza Aborozi ba Kijyambere Bafatanyije</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="2" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31.26.44 55 445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Byumba</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Governance &amp; Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31191" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marketing &amp; Sales</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisational Structure</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
