<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-17at-7254</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contracting of Dairy Expert Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra has the ambition to expand its activities and client portfolio in Nepal. In order to realize this ambition, continuous scoping assignments are being enrolled in various parts of Nepal in order to identify ambitious and entrepreneurial farmer organizations with a reasonable business track record and good management potential. In its expansion activities Agriterra has identified potential for support of farmer cooperatives in three main sectors, which are 1) Dairy, 2) Tea, and 3) Vegetables. Currently Agriterra has a portfolio of 4 dairy clients (Annapurna Dairy Cooperative, Lalitpur Dairy Union, Kamdhenu Dairy Union, Dumarwana Dairy Cooperative) and it is expected that this portfolio will grow in the future. To provide specific support to these organizations, Agriterra decided to contract a Nepali Dairy Expert (Raju Sharma) as a consultant for various assignments specified in this ToR. Raju Sharma is a professional and advanced dairy farmer that owns a farm with 40 cows in Nepal. Raju worked for Agriterra before. He conducted 2 company assessments and joined a young farmers study tour to the Netherlands. Through his previous contract he also joined agripoolers and local business advisors for feed feasibility study, record keeping training and so on. 


null

The objectives of the learning trajectory would be threefold:
  
Identify, assess and understand key challenges faced by agri-businesses in providing effective and sustainable agricultural advisory services;
  Generate concrete areas and operational strategies for the improvement of such agricultural advisory services.
  Make main insights and general findings available for the wider agricultural development community;

Agriterra can specifically use this learning trajectory to :
- share best practises of farmer cooperatives
- improve its advisory services to support clients in making their extension services more effective and efficient, by developing one or several models and sharing the best practises (for example by improving its current product: workshop sustainable services )

-</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="2" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31.26.44 55 445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arnhem</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="31191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marketing &amp; Sales</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#87 Business plan to improve marketing</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic function / The FO has enhanced its profitable farmer-led rural enterprises with good potential for sustainability (to provide inputs, trade, storage, processing services or financial products to its members)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#87 Business plan to improve marketing</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0.0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
