<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-11nj-5769</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An entrepreneurial future ahead</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the last  years, NAJK worked with Agriterra on the project &quot;Grensverleggende Samenwerking&quot; (crossing borders together) performed at the provincial level where partnerships were made with young farmers in developing countries. There are a number of lessons learned from these collaborations:
1.	Mostly employees or national board members from the partner organizations were involved in the cooperation, while on behalf of NAJK local members participated. As a result, the true connection was missing. 
2.	The involved members were often connected to the project for too long. This wasn&#x2019;t a good stimulus for new members to start in the project, like NAJK and Agriterra wished for.
3.	The positive effect on the development of the foreign young farmers wasn&apos;t visible enough for the young Dutch farmers. The Dutch young farmers got demotivated.

This all indicates a need for more counselling services aimed at local and regional level, because this a) levels more with the knowledge that NAJK members have and b) the knowledge reaches the people who need it. This also better fits with the new mission and vision of Agriterra.
This project focuses principally on transfer of knowledge at the basis.
But: the level of advice offered will be according to the level of the advice asked by the foreign organization (local/regional/national).  

There is also a training program for the Dutch members (young people between 18 and 35 years), so they are better prepared for advising en consulting.

Activities
Prior to the mission
a.	The farmers&#x2019; organizations in developing countries formulate their needs for training/advice and make a list off people who need that training/advice, in cooperation with Agriterra. This list should include as many people as possible from the local level. NAJK could play a supportive role. The possible knowledge that could be needed is described in the paragraph: During the missions. It should be stressed that these are only ideas / examples of knowledge that NAJK can provide for. Very specific questions, such as in the field of membership administration or opinion formation and lobbying, can be met. NAJK will identify the knowledge within it&apos;s organization and it will seek for  potential trainers/coaches. These trainers/coaches come as much as possible from the regional / local level (if asked for also from national level). This has the extra advantage that young Dutch farmers and people around them are involved in international development and that they gain more knowledge and understanding of the situation in developing countries. This knowledge of developing countries will be taken into account when positions are taken. Since NAJK is a member of the European Council of Young Farmers (CEJA), it  will bring the knowledge on developing countries also to a European level. Most NAJK members are also a member of a cooperative organization where they display their views. Because NAJK members have been in contact with the situation of farmers in developing countries they will help the cooperative to do more about corporate social responsibility (CSR). The activities and achievements are intensively communicated to all the members of NAJK and others. BNDR-magazine, the NAJK-website, Facebook and Twitter are media being used.
b.	NAJK nominates candidates that are considered most eligible for the mission, to Agriterra. NAJK also accompanies them to the intake interview.
c.	The young people who are finally selected to be giving a training will have an intensive preparation course (a weekend) to better prepare them for their mission.  The training includes 4 sessions and consists of the following components:
&#x2022;	Explanation of goals, organizational matters
&#x2022;	Introduction to the host country / organization
&#x2022;	Intercultural Communication
The content of the training is designed by Agriterra (preparation package for Agripoolers), NAJK and an external organization experienced in intercultural communication such as Movisie or ICA Holland.
d.	NAJK helps the young farmer to find substantive information and it shares the knowledge on the subject of the mission witch is available within the organization. For example: The young farmer will be brought in contact with people who have considerable experience. Existing training programs will be adjusted where necessary by the NAJK employee and the young farmer. Depending on the assignment special courses can be developed.

&amp;#8195;
During the missions
e.	Provide training for young (potential) board members. This might include learning to manage an association, to trace the needs of young farmers in the area, to learn meeting and discussion techniques, lobbying and opinion formation. These courses can take place in both the Netherlands and the country of origin.
f.	Provide training for young farming entrepreneurs. Running a business is not so easy. Young people with their own businesses or people who want to start their own business follow this course. The trainings cover writing a business plan, accounting and negotiating with the bank. These trainings can be offered in both countries.
g.	Provide training for youth workers, like local employees who work with local youth. The courses are related to communication with young people, different working and activation methods.
h.	Providing technical advice in the areas of (dairy) farming, agriculture and horticulture. This advice can be about production, but also about storage or processing. The knowledge comes from NAJK members and / or from the people they know and it is aimed at local youth groups working in this field. This will increase the range of advice compared to 1 on 1 advice. This knowledge transfer takes place in the form of a practical training and / or internship.
i.	NAJK will function as a support desk during the mission. The young entrepreneur(s) doing the mission can pose his/her (their) questions, dilemmas or other advice to NAJK.  NAJK will have contact with the people from the mission actively to make sure that any needed advice can be delivered as soon as possible.

After the missions
j.	After the mission, NAJK will help the young member with writing the report.. Debriefings (within one month after the mission) between the young member,  Agriterra and NAJK will indicate how the mission can be followed up. The young member will discuss his experiences with other members of NAJK (at a local but also national level). Different action perspectives will deepen the follow up for which NAJK will give the required guidance and support: 
&#x2022;	Dragons&apos; Den, the young farmer develops with a young farmer from one of the countries an innovative business plan and asks his or her local association (AJK) for the fund raising. In this business plan an innovative program is key.
Dragons&apos; Den is a popular KRO program. The methodology is one of the action perspectives. The young entrepreneurs have set up a new idea and a plan to finance it. They can contact NAJK partners  for support and funding of the plan.
&#x2022;	Move the AJK to start a partnership with the visited PO. When prolonged support by a group of young Dutch farmers is needed, a schedule of activities and a year plan can be developed. There will be an evaluation after one year to see if the cooperation shall be prolonged. There is also room for other action perspectives brought up by the young farmers.
k.	The input provided by the young farmers leads to a specific analysis of the needs of the partner organization. As a result NAJK will develop customized training modules. Existing courses can be adapted to local conditions / needs or new courses can be developed. NAJK will suggest a (time)plan to implement this training. This may be in the partner country but can also in the Netherlands.

&amp;#8195;
Expected Results
1.	Five partner organizations have identified their first training needs with Agriterra and NAJK, the latest by the end of May 2012.
2.	Training needs have been translated into 5 specific assignments by Agriterra.
3.	NAJK has identified five young trainers and offers five appropriate trainings to the PO&apos;s.
The missions have the following results:
&#x2022;	Young (prospective) board members of the PO&apos;s are trained in management skills
&#x2022;	Within the PO&apos;s a clear youth policy is formulated
&#x2022;	Young entrepreneurs are trained in innovative entrepreneurial skills
&#x2022;	Youth workers are trained in working with young people.
4.	Each mission is followed by a clear follow-up. NAJK adjusts further training modules if necessary.
5.	NAJK&apos;s position papers show that the situation of young farmers in developing countries is taken into account.
6.	The evaluation shows that NAJK members have more knowledge of and support for international development.

Evaluation Process
The process evaluation will take place three times a year to discuss the progress, the project process and the communication. NAJK, together with Agriterra, will check if the objectives are met and if the planning is okay, what the experiences and learning effects are, and whether any changes to the project or the cooperation should be made.

Effect evaluation
An effect evaluation will be designed in collaboration with Agriterra. This will help to evaluate the effect of the given trainings and consults at the PO&apos;s. Based on this evaluation, the project may be adjusted if necessary.

NAJK carries out an impact evaluation with it&apos;s members by using sample interviews. AJK members that are involved in the project get a questionnaire. The answering of the questionnaire will show whether they are more involved in international development. With an open interview during provincial meetings it will become more clear if the provincial board thinks that the project contributed to improving the image and involvement of international development. Any improvements will be discussed.

Surveys are put on the NAJK website and Facebook page to measure if members got informed by the project.

This information is used in reports intended for Agriterra. After completion of this project year, a new project proposal will be presented. Evaluations of the first year will indicate whether the program as it is executed this year can be continued or whether it needs to be modified.

The main objective of this project is:
By and for young people: young Dutch farmers contribute to developing the skills of rural youth in developing countries so that they can defend their interests and that they can better exploit their possibilities. With this a focus on innovation and renewed entrepreneurship is key.

The secondary objective is:
Increasing public support from Dutch young farmers for development.

Sub goals
&#x2022;	Motivate young people to take place in the board of farmers&apos; organizations / cooperatives or to organize themselves at local level.
&#x2022;	Support and advise on the design of youth policy.
&#x2022;	Training of young board members.
&#x2022;	Increase technical knowledge of innovative agriculture (livestock, arable, horticulture, etc.);
&#x2022;	Training of youth workers.
&#x2022;	Encourage innovative entrepreneurship among young people and providing specific training (business plan writing, accounting, etc.) to these young people.
&#x2022;	Make sure the interests of rural youth from developing countries are taken into account at the (international) political advocacy.
&#x2022;	Increase support and involvement of Dutch young farmers for development and by that create a clearer growth model for Agriterra.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DGIS" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FFAAP" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Farmers Associations Andhra Pradesh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NAJK" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="2" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-09-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31.26.44 55 445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Utrecht</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diversity &amp; inclusiveness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">49764</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">78783.9</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">2481</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">1911.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Admin cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">4572.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Admin cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">1324.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise days. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">6080.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise days. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">2711.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise days. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">53840.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">24943</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment from Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">1324.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">23744.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">18021.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-12-31">-1670</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">15754</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">12407</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-12-31">31507</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">23145</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-12-31">-1670</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#39 Membership appraisal</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OSID / FO has systems in place, which facilitate member involvement in strategy setting and monitoring and in decisions (&#x2018;participation&#x2019;)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#39 Membership appraisal</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0.59" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.59"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0.59"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
