<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-11fm-5632</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raising the competitiveness of farmer&apos;s agri-businesses through sustaining its cooperation and diversification of its businesses</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project context
During the last years in agricultural sector of Moldova were made some significant and positive changes which marked the raising of Global Agricultural Product, were appeared a lot of advanced agricultural farms but the real potential of this sector still remains to be used at low level. A lot of hectares of land are not worked on thre on the other hand we have a huge quantity of imported agro-products. Also as result of created situation in rural area &#x2013; people migrates from rural area to urban.
So, starting with 2011 NFFM proposed to itself to implement a pragmatical approachment of initiation and development of agri-business in rural area, involving in this process the NFFM&#x2019;s capacities, State institutions &#x2013; decission makers. We will put the accent in finding concrete groups of farmers where the Federation will focus our technical assistance to provide to them not only the advisory services but to help them to develop businesses in better way using the modern technologies, applying efficient methods, elaborating the business-plans, obtaining subsidies from Govern and financial support from Govern and donor organizations.
One of the most important problems that farmers face on is poor capacities to sell  thier production. NFFM will pay a lot of attention in order to create at least minimal conditions to facilitate access of farmers to local market and maybe to create some oportunities to export its production. Also we will work in order to make farmers to understand that the cooperation or assciation will lead them to develop its professional, production and commercialization capacities, that is the reason of these objectives.
In order to sustain the initiation and development of farmers agri-businesses propose to continue the Program of Rural and Economical Development through financing the investment projects, providing technical assistence, sustain women and young farmers to start or develop economical initiatives in rural area, to promote ecological agro-production and agri-tourism.
For the next 2 years of this project NFFM set 4 major objectives or strategic goals which will be in the frame with NFFM&#x2019;s Strategic Plan 2011-2015, farmers demands Agriterra&#x2019;s new requirements and existent realities.
NFFM will focus in the next years according to new lines established by Agriterra:
a)farmer led agri-business
b)local economic initiatives 
c)specific looby and advocacy directed towards the former to themes.
As a result of these proposals and consultations with National and Regional Boards of NFFM, we set the following 4 strategic goals of this project
Project objectives
1. Development of private sector through sustaining and promoting farmers in the initiation and development of their agri-businesses in rural area;
2. Raising the competitivity of farmer&#x2019;s private households through promotion and sustaining of its cooperation and diversifying the businesses
3. Lobby and advocacy initiatives to Central and Local Public Authorities and other interested actors in order to sustain and develop the project&#x2019;s activities;
4. Institutional and organizational development of NFFM;
5.Development and strengthen the self-financing capacities of NFFM

Target group of the project
As a result of reorientation on NFFM&#x2019;s stretegic goals, the target group of this projects will be:
&#x2022; All members of NFFM &#x2013; farmers who are able to maintain and expand its agri-business and to provide qualitative products to the markets;
&#x2022; Farmers who would like to cooperate in product associations or cooperatives also farmers who already done this;
&#x2022; Cooperative and Product associations created by NFFM during the previous years;
&#x2022; Potential young farmers and women who wish to initiate and develop business in rural area, also moldovans who come from abroad to started agribusiness in native country. 
&#x2022; Farmers &#x2013; members who pay regular its memberships fees and are willing to pay for provided services;
&#x2022; Finally, all members and potential members who would like to develop its agri-business (private households, cooperatives, product associations and other)
The components of this target group will be the final beneficiaries of the proposed project and they are selected according to project&#x2019;s demands and necessities.

Expected results
Results for each activity is described in Logical Frame Matrix 
So, by the reaching the proposed objectives of the project through mentioned actvities directed to obtain the expected results, NFFM expects as tagible results and impact the following results:
&#x2022; To develop the farmers business abilities and to sustain them in extension or starting of its businesses
&#x2022;To make farmers to understand as a first step and to get farmers in cooperatives or product associations, also to set the cooperative marketing strategies
&#x2022; To build and strenghten the trade capacity of farmers or groups of farmers
&#x2022; To enhance the organizational and management abilities of created Farmers associations or cooperatives
&#x2022; Increase market power for farmers and also to simplify the access of farmers to internal or maybe external markets
&#x2022; Involve farmers in decission making process by lobby and advocacy activities 
&#x2022; To empower women and young farmers and create conditions for them to start new business in rural area
&#x2022;Diversification in agriculture, to promote biological agriculture and agro-tourism in Moldova
&#x2022; Enhancement of agricultural policies &#x2013; subsidies, banking and credit in agriculture, import and export regulations and other
This results since will be reach will ensure the sustainability of National Farmers Federation of Moldova and in the same time will lead to farmer&#x2019;s business development and finally to welfare of agricultural producers and development of Agricultura sector in Republic of Moldova.

NFFM&#x2019;s goal for this project and for the future is to be more focused and to work closer to farmers for economical development of the farmers households and associations, to raising the raising the competitivity of farmer&#x2019;s private households through promotion and sustaining of its cooperation and diversifying the businesses and to promote the specific lobby and advocacy activities in sustaining the proposed objectives. The activities related to reach these objectives are clear defined in the Logical Matrix of the project&#x2019;s activities also with attached outputs, outcomes and impact.
Main activities 
1.The enhancement of provided extension services by using applicative consultancy;
2.Attraction and integration of women and young farmers in entreprenorial activities from rural area;
3.Sustaining economical development of private farmers households through financing of investment projects without interests from Solidarity and Development Fund of NFFM;
4.Development of production and commercialization capacities through association and cooperation of farmers;
5.Promotion of ecological agriculture development in Moldova;
6.Diversifying the activities in rural area through promotion of agri-tourism;
7.Promotion af farmers products in the frames of internal or external exhibitions or fares;
8.Facilitation and sustain of projects activities through juridical and economical initiatives in order to promote farmers agri-business development;
9.Institutional and organizational development of NFFM.

Monitoring process
Monitoring and evaluation of project&apos;s implementation is made by: General Assembley, National Board, National and Regional staffs of NFFM also by the Control Commission of NFFM. We would Agriterra for the future to be the part who will directly be involved in the monitoring and evaluation of project implementation.

Implementation
The Implementation Management of the NFFM&#x2019;s project activities for 2011-2013 will be ensured by the elected and engaged personnel at local, regional and national level as well by its members, also NFFM invites Agriterra&#x2019;s expert to the implementation and monitoring process of this project.
Depending on the content, importance and the complexity degree of the planned activities the good implementation will be carried out with support of volunteer farmers, presidents of RO, members of the Board of National and Regional level, employed personnel from regional and national levels

Sustainability
The sustainability of the project will be secured by NFFM through all levels staffs. Given the fact that our main objective is to represent and defend the rights and interests of the farmers, through the activities of the proposed project Federation will continue with a better efficiency to implement its main objectives which aims to inrease the welfare of the farmers private households in Moldova. We strongly could mention that during our existence and according to our Statute and Strategic Plan, we permanently implement the activities which have as objective to solve the problems of the farmers and also we are permanently in a search of new effective solutions in order of economic recovery of agricultural producers especially from rural area.
In that order of ides we collaborate with similar organizations from abroad AGRITERRA, Agri Cord (Netherlands), Italian Agricultors Confederation, Argidius (Switzerland) also is the member of International Federation of Agricultural Producers. These organizations especially Agriterra who is the main our donor provide to us advisory services and technical assistance in order to sustain our activity.
It is important to mention that NFFM&apos;s activities undertaken in last time are fits very efficiently with the activities undertaken by Ministry of Agriculture, so, we are working together to solve the existent problems in agriculture, for example many activities which Federation entrprised during the last years are in accordance with the National Plan of Economical Recovery especially on agriculture issues (subsidies to agricultural producers, consolidation of lands, the establishments of model farms and cooperatives of production in all regions of Moldova, creation of processing chains and other relevant activities.
During the years we have organized these kind of activities in various issues related to agriculture and farmers, thats is the mean to continue these activities.

Promotion of oil seed production, value addition and marketing</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="APA" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federation of Agricultural Producers Associations Transilvania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="LAJK" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Limburgs Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NFFM" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NFFM - National Farmers Federation Moldova</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NAJK" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nederlands Agrarisch Jongeren Kontakt</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="2" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31.26.44 55 445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31191" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marketing &amp; Sales</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisational Structure</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory policy formulation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">103564.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">76278</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">7673.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Admin cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">11315.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise days. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">10557.03</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise mission. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">82246.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">21318</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment from NFFM - National Farmers Federation Moldova</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NFFM - National Farmers Federation Moldova</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">90541.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-12-31">28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">24177</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund from NFFM - National Farmers Federation Moldova</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NFFM - National Farmers Federation Moldova</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">79572.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-12-31">28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2011-12-31">5600.94</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peer to Peer. The value is summarized by year</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#53 Policy proposals developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lobby and advocacy / Joint advocacy of family farmers with relevant stakeholders</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#53 Policy proposals developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1.0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1.0"></target>
     <actual value="1.0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#65 Policy proposals integrated</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lobby and advocacy / Strengthened recognition and integration by relevant stakeholders of FO&#x2019;s role and position in specific public policies, and value chains</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#65 Policy proposals integrated</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0.0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2.0"></target>
     <actual value="2.0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#30 Local groups established</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OSID / FO has solid and representative local membership base (&#x2018;representativeness&#x2019;)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#30 Local groups established</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="8.0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11.0"></target>
     <actual value="19.0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#58 Participation in formal meetings on agricultural or food security issues</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OSID / FO has the capacity to participate formally and informally in external networks and partnerships (&#x2018;networking&#x2019;) and gains capacity for participatory policy formulation and representation</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#58 Participation in formal meetings on agricultural or food security issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2011-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7.0"></target>
     <actual value="12.0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
