<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-18SLC-8066</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sinthe Coop - Dairy Business</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sinthe Livestock Cooperative is located in Sinthe village, a village in the area of Sagaing township, just Southwest of Mandalay in the Central Dry Zone of Myanmar. The Dry Zone covers more than 54,000km, encompassing 58 townships which span from lower Sagaing region, to the western and central parts of Mandalay region and most of Magway region. It is estimated that approximately one-quarter of the country&#x2019;s population live in the Central Dry Zone area. Situated in the shadow of the Rakhine mountain range, the Dry Zone receives limited rains compared to country averages. Insufficient rain is not the only potential hazard, however, as decreasing forest cover and soil erosion place communities at greater risk of localized flash floods during times of heavy rain. The Dry Zone is particularly affected by food security issues (The MIMU, 2017). In Sagaing region from January till about June (about six months) production can take place. From July till September it is rainy season and cows are moved due to the flooding. Milk production decreases. From October till December production is mediocre as cows are calving.

Sinthe livestock cooperative is based near Mandalay, an area where many cows can be found. The village Sinthe has two cooperatives: one general cooperative focused on agricultural activities mainly for the rice production and the other one is the livestock cooperative which is assessed. The cooperative only activity is providing loans of funding made available through cooperative department, as well as their own equity and savings. About 352 farmers borrow every half year amounts between 100,000 and 500,000 MMK. Not all of the members currently have cows, including the board members. As the milk price is low, the board members want to find ways to increase the livelihood of the villagers. Milk processing might be an option and is supported by the Sagaing cooperative department. Till date, no activities have been carried out to setup this processing activity. Although the board members have (probably) the best intentions, they don&#x2019;t know the steps to be made.

null

The BHAG of the cooperation: &#x201C;Highest income for farmers in Sinthe village through processing milk&#x201D;. The cooperatives has the ambition to start collecting milk and do processing. When the plan can be made concrete, this processing plant could be regarded as a smoking chimney.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DGIS" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SLDPC" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sinthe Livestock and Dairy Production Cooperative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Agriterra" role="2" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31.26.44 55 445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sagain</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sagaing</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Storage and processing</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">17573</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-17">17573</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment from Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#233 Number of value Chain analysis conducted</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic function / The FO has enhanced its profitable farmer-led rural enterprises with good potential for sustainability (to provide inputs, trade, storage, processing services or financial products to its members)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#233 Number of value Chain analysis conducted</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0.0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#231 MBO has set Targets for agricultural production of members</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical function / Advisory, training and coaching services to members</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="4">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#231 MBO has set Targets for agricultural production of members</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0.0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># + number at title refers to internal id</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
