<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-KRA-P051155108P-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002504-005</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P051155108P" secondary-reporter="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya National Commission on Human Rights</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Access to Justice; Rule of Law and Accountability for Human Rights Violations</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced redress and accountability for human rights violations and respect for the rule of law</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002504" crs-channel-code="12004" ref="KE-KRA-P051155108P" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya National Commission on Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019/2020 Financial year</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2019-07-01">50185000</value>
  </budget>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADR entrenched as a mechanism for resolving legal disputes and human rights complaints</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Article 252 of the Constitution of Kenya as read with the KNCHR Act empowers the Commission to employ alternative methods of dispute resolution including mediation, negotiation and conciliation. Through the project, the commission applies and promoted the use of Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) by other actors.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of human rights violations handled through ADR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of cases admitted by KNCHR which were handled through alternative dispute resolution mechanism.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="2" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">KNCHR successfully resolved eight (8) complaints through ADR. This marked a 60% increase in the uptake of ADR and a 200% increase in the number of complaints successfully resolved through ADR.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of partners and staff formally engaged and trained on mediation</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="27">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">21 stakeholders and 6 KNCHR staff trained on ADR/AJS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Systemic human rights violations resolved through Public Interest Litigation (PIL)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Interest Litigation (PIL) is one of the means by which the Commission is able to influence policy direction and interpretation of the Constitution through the judicial process. It also serves as a mechanism for the resolving human rights violations. The Commission participates in PIL through either originating petitions in its own name or joining existing petitions filed by other parties which have a major public interest component either as amicus curiae or an interested party as appropriate.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of PIL matters undertaken to affirm Human rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of PILs undertaken by the KNCHR</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="19" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">KNCHR attended to 13 PIL matters. 5 cases (38.5%) of the PIL cases were successfully concluded within the reporting period with favourable judgments that uphold human rights. 8 cases (61.5%) are ongoing at different stages awaiting final determination. 3 of the cases (23.1%) seek to address gender related concerns including the plight of widows</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intersex Persons Implementation Coordination Committee (IPICC) Strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Commission was represented in The Task force on Policy, Legal, Institutional and Administrative Reforms regarding Intersex Persons . Notably, the Task force completed its report, launched and submitted the same to the Hon AG. To support the implementation of the recommendations, the Hon Attorney General established the Intersex Implementation Coordination Committee (IPICC) to oversee the implementation of the recommendations in the report. The Commission is both Chair and Secretariat of the committee.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rate of work plan implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of activities implemented over the total activities planned on IPICC support.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation will commence in the 2nd financial year.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to and timely processing of human rights complaints, with particular attention to SGBV cases</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The KNCHR in line with its statutory and constitutional mandate receive and process complaints on alleged human rights violations. Complaints that fall within the KNCHR&#x2019;s mandate are subjected to further analysis and follow up that includes among others investigations. Complaints that fall outside the KNCHR&#x2019;s mandate are referred to relevant complaints handling institutions for further action.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of investigations and recommendations documented (% of investigations touching on gender, PWDS and marginalization issues)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of investigations conducted with investigation reports highlighting recommendations to various target groups.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="123" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">123 investigations conducted per year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="38"></target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">KNCHR conducted twenty-one (21) investigations within the reporting period. The KNCHR conducted two investigations pursuant to court orders and filed relevant reports in court to assist in resolution of the complaints. Eight (8) investigations (38.1%) sought to resolve complaints on gender and marginalized related violations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of complaints received, processed and documented</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of human rights complaints received, processed and documented by the KNCHR.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="3,440" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">3,440 cases received annually</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3,500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The KNCHR screened, processed and documented a total of 2,248 complaints against an annual projection of 3,500 complaints, Out of the total cases received, 6 cases were on SGBV, representing 0.27% of the total complaints received; 3.2% of the complaints were from PWDs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2,248">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The KNCHR screened, processed and documented a total of 2,248 complaints against an annual projection of 3,500 complaints, (64.2% of the total target and 30.2% decrease from 3,219 complaints received in the 2018-19FY).  Out of the total cases received, 6 cases were on SGBV, representing 0.27% of the total complaints received; 3.2% of the complaints were from PWDs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A victim-centered human rights based approach (HRBA) integrated in the delivery of justice</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project grant will aim to intensify the advocacy for Human Rights Based Approach (HRBA) in delivery of justice. In doing so, the National Commission is to adopt the following approaches: Capacity building of justice actors; trial observations &amp; targeted court observations; strengthening the legal capacity for persons with disabilities and advocacy for establishment and actualization of reparations mechanism.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of justice actors trained on HRBA and access to justice</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total number of judges, magistrates and Court Users Committees trained on HRBA and access to justice for the vulnerable populations.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="131" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">131 magistrates trained per year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="57">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">33 members of court users committee (CUC) from Kitui and 24 justice actors from Trans Nzoia County trained. The training of judges, magistrates and other justice actors scheduled for the last quarter of the reporting period was not done owing to break out of the Covid-19 Pandemic.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of advisories to justice actors on infusion of human rights principles in delivery of justice</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. An Advisory to the Inspector General of Police (IGP) on 8th April 2020. The KNCHR called on the IGP to ensure that all law enforcement officers under his command uphold human rights in the management and response to the Covid-19 pandemic. 
2. An advisory to National Council for Administration of Justice in March 2020. The KNCHR raised access to justice related concerns (accessibility of courts and use of technology to facilitate virtual courts) during the covid-19 pandemic.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened institutional capacity for project implementation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the project, the commission will ensure efficient and effective utilization of resources, accountability, effective monitoring and evaluation of the entire process. The National Commission will also work towards strengthening its Human Resources; leveraging on Information and Communication Technology (ICT), strengthen internal policies, systems and processes for effective service delivery.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Budget absorption rate</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="98" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
