<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-KRA-P051155108P-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002504-004</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P051155108P" secondary-reporter="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya National Commission on Human Rights</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Access to Justice; Rule of Law and Accountability for Human Rights Violations</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To secure appropriate redress, accountability for human rights violations and respect for the rule of law</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002504" crs-channel-code="12004" ref="KE-KRA-P051155108P" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya National Commission on Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 4 2019/2020 Financial year</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2019-07-01">50185000</value>
  </budget>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADR entrenched as a mechanism for resolving legal disputes and human rights complaints</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Article 252 of the Constitution of Kenya as read with the KNCHR Act empowers the Commission to employ alternative methods of dispute resolution including mediation, negotiation and conciliation. Through the project, the commission applies and promoted the use of Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) by other actors.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of human rights violations handled through ADR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of cases admitted by KNCHR which were handled through alternative dispute resolution mechanism.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="2" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Systemic human rights violations resolved through Public Interest Litigation (PIL)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Interest Litigation (PIL) is one of the means by which the Commission is able to influence policy direction and interpretation of the Constitution through the judicial process. It also serves as a mechanism for the resolving human rights violations. The Commission participates in PIL through either originating petitions in its own name or joining existing petitions filed by other parties which have a major public interest component either as amicus curiae or an interested party as appropriate.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of PIL matters undertaken to affirm Human rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of PILs undertaken by the KNCHR</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="19" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Attended to 3 PIL matters within the quarter and supported litigation by residents of Kariobangi North area who had been evicted during the Covid-19 pandemic period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to and timely processing of human rights complaints, with particular attention to SGBV cases</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The KNCHR in line with its statutory and constitutional mandate receive and process complaints on alleged human rights violations. Complaints that fall within the KNCHR&#x2019;s mandate are subjected to further analysis and follow up that includes among others investigations. Complaints that fall outside the KNCHR&#x2019;s mandate are referred to relevant complaints handling institutions for further action.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of investigations and recommendations documented</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of investigations conducted with investigation reports highlighting recommendations to various target groups.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="123" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">123 investigations conducted per year</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="38"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 investigation was conducted within the reporting period concerning alleged torture and assault by Uasin Gishu County Inspectorate in the process of inspecting trade licenses and on alleged Extra Judicial Killings within Kwale county</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of complaints received, processed and documented</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total number of human rights complaints received, processed and documented by the KNCHR.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="3440" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">3,440 cases received per annum</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="875"></target>
     <actual value="395">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Received and processed 395 complaints within the Quarter, of these complaints 95 were lodged by Women,43 Complaints by Intersex Persons and 14 Complaints by PWDs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A victim-centered human rights based approach (HRBA) integrated in the delivery of justice</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project grant will aim to intensify the advocacy for Human Rights Based Approach (HRBA) in delivery of justice. In doing so, the National Commission is to adopt the following approaches: Capacity building of justice actors; trial observations &amp; targeted court observations; strengthening the legal capacity for persons with disabilities and advocacy for establishment and actualization of reparations mechanism.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of advisories to justice actors on infusion of human rights principles in delivery of justice</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened institutional capacity for project implementation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the project, the commission will ensure efficient and effective utilization of resources, accountability, effective monitoring and evaluation of the entire process. The National Commission will also work towards strengthening its Human Resources; leveraging on Information and Communication Technology (ICT), strengthen internal policies, systems and processes for effective service delivery.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Budget absorption rate</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The budget spent over the total budget (Dutch) for 2019/20 financial year</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-06-30" value="98" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
