<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-PH3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Resilient Green Growth Planning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As one of the countries most vulnerable to climate change impacts, the Philippines encounters extreme weather occurrences, such as Typhoon Haiyan, that have resulted in significant loss of lives and damage to properties. Recognizing the threat of climate change, the Government of the Philippines passed the Climate Change Act of 2009, which created the Climate Change Commission (CCC) and paved the way for the adoption of the National Climate Change Action Plan. Building on the lessons of the &#x201C;Demonstration of Eco town Framework Project (Phase 1)&#x201D;, which was completed in 2014, and responding to Government request to support more local governments units (LGUs), the GGGI, CCC and the Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) initiated in 2015 the Climate Resilient Green Growth (CRGG) Planning Project. Currently implemented in the provinces of Palawan and Oriental Mindoro, the project is designed to promote climate resilience and inclusive, pro-poor green growth to a greater number of LGUs and Micro-Small and Medium Enterprises (MSMEs).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate change resilience enhanced and inclusive green growth achieved in participating local government units.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juhern Kim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04549 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.35 121</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="MS" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Sectoral</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">768990.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">751132.09</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="PH3-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">639060.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PH3-EX0418">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">618425.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PH3-IF0118">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Philippines_ClimateResilientGreenGrowth_v02_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Climate Resilient Green Growth (CRGG)&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate resilient and green growth related national and local policies, resulting from the Provincial CRGG Strategies completed in 2016, developed and officially submitted to the appropriate authority</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 2018, six pilot MSMEs in Oriental Mindoro and Palawan continue to adopt green business practices. Continuous monitoring will be undertaken to help them sustain these practices even as they are encouraged to share their lessons with other MSMEs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Official acknowledgement by appropriate authority for at least 1 national policy and at least 2 local policies per province by 2018</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="50"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green business practices adopted by MSMEs in 2 participating provinces</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 2018, six pilot MSMEs in Oriental Mindoro and Palawan continue to adopt green business practices. Continuous monitoring will be undertaken to help them sustain these practices even as they are encouraged to share their lessons with other MSMEs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 1 pilot MSME adopts greening business practices in each province, 2 years after project completion</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="50"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Case for Greening MSME Operations Piloted</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, selected green business practices were introduced and piloted in six (6) MSMEs in Palawan and Oriental Mindoro. These greening practices include a.) Use of low energy consumption LED lights; b.) Retrofitting of facilities to utilize natural lighting and ventilation; c.) Waste recycling; d.) Efficient water and fuel usage; and e.) Use of solar energy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green business practice piloted in at least 1 MSME per participating province.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Information, Education and Communications (IEC) activities to effectively communicate CRGG lessons/results delivered</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2018, seven press releases were developed to capture the results of the activities where lessons and the outcomes of the CRGG Project were communicated. These lessons, outcomes and next steps of the CRGG Project were presented and delivered through various activities. The CRGG Project also developed two Audio Video Presentation (AVP) for the IEC Packages, on CRGG Projects in Palawan and Oriental Mindoro.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 3 IEC activities to communicate CRGG lessons/results successfully delivered</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional Capacity Development strategy and training modules, to support the implementation and mainstreaming of Provincial CRGG Strategies developed in 2016, delivered.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2018, the CRGG project conducted seven capacity building activities to support the implementation of the CRGG strategies. These training activities were in the subject of A) Project proposal development; B) Basic economics for LGU practitioners; C) Information, education and communication training; D) GHG inventory training; and E) Green growth orientation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 3 institutional capacity development activities successfully completed by 2018</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Resilient Green Growth (CRGG) Strategies that promote climate resilience, inclusive green growth, and poverty alleviation accepted, adopted, and implemented in 2 participating provinces and replicated in other local government units</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the case of Palawan, the Provincial Government has adopted the Green City Framework in the formulation of the Comprehensive Land Use Plans (CLUP) of all municipalities in the Province. The Provincial Development Council (PDC) also approved the Annual Investment Program (2019) and the Provincial Development Investment Plan (2019 to 2023) to provide budgetary and investment support for activities and sectoral projects that align with the Palawan Climate Resilient and Green Growth Framework. On the other hand, the Province of Oriental Mindoro has adopted as its provincial planning strategy the Provincial Climate Resilient and Green Growth Framework.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. CRGG Strategies and supporting CRGG investments, which promote climate resilience, green growth, poverty reduction and social inclusion, incorporated in the development and investment plans of participating provinces, 2 years from project completion.         
2. Priority CRGG investments of participating provinces funded and implemented, 2 years from project completion.   
3. Key elements of the CRGG planning approach incorporated in preparation of local development plans of at least 2 other LGUs, 2 years from project completion.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="50"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate change resilience enhanced and inclusive green growth achieved in participating local government units</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Incidence and amount of climate change related damages in participating provinces reduced by 10%, 5 years after project completion in 2018.  
2. Poverty incidence in participating provinces reduced by 5%, 5 years after project completion in 2018. 
3. Amount of public and private investments supporting climate change adaptation and green growth in participating provinces increased by 10%, 5 years after project completion in 2018.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and Pro-Poor Green Growth approach, which engages the marginalized sectors at the community level, demonstrated to enhance the social and environmental aspects of the CRGG Project.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CRGG project collaborated with the Municipality of San Vicente in the development of an inclusive and pro-poor green growth approach pilot program: Sustainable and Inclusive Municipal Tourism Code (SIMTC). Activities for the SIMTC development were conducted through a consultative approach that involved the members of the marginalized and vulnerable sectors, in order to ensure that their needs and aspirations are captured. The SIMTC embodies provisions that upholds the interests and welfare of the marginalized and vulnerable sectors while ensuring that the tourism industry of Municipality of San Vicente pursues a direction that is inclusive, resilient and green.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and Pro-Poor Green Growth approach piloted in 1 municipality by 2018</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policies resulting from the Provincial CRGG Strategies supported by the concerned government agencies.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Provincial Government of Palawan passed &#x201C;Provincial Ordinance
No. 1865, Series of 2017: Prescribing the Climate Resilience and Green
Growth Framework for the Province of Palawan&#x201D;, aligned with CRGG
Strategies. The outcome was achieved in 2017.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 1 policy resulting from the Provincial CRGG Strategies recognized by the concerned government agencies.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development modules for the implementation of the Provincial CRGG Strategies supported by the concerned government agencies</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The package of capacity development assistance provided by the CRGG Project were recognized by the Provinces of Palawan and Oriental Mindoro. The Oriental Mindoro Provincial Development Council (PDC) passed PDC Resolution No.4, Series of 2018 adopting the Climate Resilient and Green Growth Framework as a planning strategy for the Province. On the other hand, the Provincial Government has formally communicated its appreciation and recognition of the technical assistance provided by CRGG Project in its letter of 22 February 2018 and through the Plaque of Appreciation bestowed by the Province of Palawan on GGGI dated 12 October 2018. The Province of Palawan also utilized the IEC Training provided by the CRGG Project in developing AVP materials using in-house talent.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 2 capacity development modules for the implementation of the Provincial CRGG Strategies recognized by the concerned government agencies.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
