<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-KH3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kep Solar Development Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribute to reducing Cambodia&#x2019;s greenhouse gas emissions outlined in the country&#x2019;s NDC targets by catalyzing the solar market and replace/reduce the deployment of more expensive and polluting power generation alternatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In support of the Government of Cambodia aimed to develop the City of Kep as an eco-tourism destination, GGGI developed and proposed the Kep Solar Development Project (KSDP)as a key component of this strategic vision. KSDP was focused on Kep Province and neighboring Kampot Province and envisaged to help scale up solar development in Cambodia. The project was identified and prioritized from a pipeline of projects developed under the current Country Planning Framework (CPF) 20162020 with Cambodia. Following the prioritization of projects, the Government of Cambodia requested GGGI for assistance to develop the project and help mobilize financing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment Policy Solutions Division</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lasse Ringius</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04518 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.5657 104.9910</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="SE" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Landscapes</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="23183" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">26766.29</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="KH3-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">26766.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Cambodia_KepSolarDevelopment_v04_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;KEP Solar Development Project (KSDP)&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribute to reducing Cambodia&apos;s greenhouse gas emissions outlined in the country&apos;s NDC targets by catalyzing the solar market and replace/reduce the deployment of more expensive and polluting power generation alternatives.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGGI&apos;s scoping team identified three relevant options for solar development for consideration by the Government of Cambodia (GOC). The options include a single 5 MW solar plant, a phased 2*5MW solar plant, and roof top solar primarily targeted at the commercial and household consumer segments in urban centers country-wide. In addition, the team designed an innovative corporate social responsibility (CSR) component and associated financing mechanism (&quot;The Green Jobs Fund&quot;) that would initially be linked to the KSDP but was designed to be mainstreamed into private sector projects and scaled up as the solar market mature. During a July 2017 mission, GGGI presented the proposed arrangements for KSDP at a stakeholder meeting chaired by the Minister of Environment (MOE). This meeting was regarded as essential to secure the commitment of sector stakeholders, including the Ministry of Mines and Energy (MME), Electricit&#xE9; du Cambodge (EDC) and the Electricity Author of Cambodia (EAC), confirm the offtake from KSDP through a power purchase agreement (PPA) between the project company and EDC, and issue a generation license and sharing of relevant data and technical requirements to prepare the technical specification. While the Minister of Environment re-iterated MOE&#x2019;s support for KSDP, no commitment was articulated from energy sector stakeholders (MME, EDC, and EAC) to advance the requirements for project preparation. Following the stakeholder meeting separate discussions were held with EDC and subsequently with senior levels of MME. EDC expressed that they would not be interested in pursuing a PPA and deferred to MME. MME clarified that EDC had put in place PPA commitments for an additional 700 MW of coal and hydro and that no further capacity additional would be required until 2023. MME further clarified it would not support the preparation of KSDP. &#x2022; Decision made to cancel project preparation based on the strategic direction of sector stakeholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project was dropped before indicators were defined.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
