<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-GL2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BMZ GreenInvest Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Find new innovative approaches to mobilize private capital 
for inclusive green investment in developing and emerging 
economies by sharing knowledge and enabling the public 
sector to work more efficiently and effectively with the 
private sector and institutional investors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The need to mobilize private capital for inclusive green 
investments is one of the most pressing issues for the 
achievement of green growth and, since 2015, the targets 
set in the Paris Climate Agreement and Agenda 2030. The 
establishment of GreenInvest aimed to contribute to driving 
convergence between the different but related initiatives. 
GreenInvest works to overcome challenges including:
High barriers for private-sector investments persist, 
including uncertainty and incoherence in policy and 
regulatoryframeworks. Project sponsor inexperience in designing bankable green 
growth projects to submit to potential investors</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">German Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development (BMZ)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Investment Solutions</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lasse Ringius</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04518 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGGI Headquarters</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>37.543706445032754 126.96679674088955</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="SE" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Landscapes</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">367500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GL2-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">298205.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Global_BMZgreenInvest_v02_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;BMZ Green Invest&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects designed under a country NDC (only countries that 
are part of the NDC-Partnership).</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In addition to the 3 projects GGGI targeted to design, 2 
additional projects were identified and delivered through 
BMZ GreenInvest Program. All projects were aligned to the 
country NDC targets.
Project 1: Solar Refrigeration for Vanuatu Rural Tourism 
Operators.
With the successful completion of the project in 2017, the 
Government of Vanuatu has indicated a strong interest 
to scale-up the project. This interest stems from the initial 
outcomes of the project, which saw a significant increase 
in local business activities within the 2 months after the 
solar freezers were introduced. This is also being fostered 
by strong business sentiments among rural tourism 
bungalow operators to grow their business and improve 
their income earnings. Furthermore, there is high interest 
among other bungalow operators to participate in similar 
projects, and businesses are now willing to make financial 
contributions having seen the demonstrated benefits. 
Consequently, with GGGI&#x2019;s support, the Government 
of Vanuatu prepared a concept note to scale-up the 
project late 2017, to seek further funding from interested 
development partners.
Project 2: Mongolia Green inclusive infrastructure private 
public partnership (PPP) program.
Business cases for ten demonstration projects along 
with detailed procurement support documents were 
prepared and delivered to the UB city. UB city has 
formally endorsed this project, with a clear intent to take 
it forward to financing. The Investor Forum to support the 
matching of the 10 business cases to potential financiers 
was organized on December 19, 2017, in Ulaanbaatar, 
Mongolia. There were more than 70 participants from 
national and local government authorities, regulatory 
organizations, local private sector companies, ESCO 
companies from China, international organizations, 
and members of the Business Council of Mongolia. The 
partnership between UB city and potential financiers 
from China will be continued in 2018 via knowledge 
and capacity sharing events. Private sector companies 
(ESCOs) in China have indicated a keen interest to 
collaborate with UB city on PPPs in 2018.
Project 3: Mongolia Energy Efficient Residential 
Retrofitting in Bayangol District of Ulaanbaatar City.
Energy Auditing for 3 residential buildings completed and 
submitted for Government review and validation. The 
energy audits provide overall energy efficiency potential in 
across UB (of 1077 buildings), which would show overall 
energy efficiency potential in UB. The Government of 
Mongolia set out ambitious targets and goals to improve 
energy efficiency, conserver energy and reduce energy 
losses. For instance, in Mongolia&#x2019;s Green Development 
Policy and NDC document, it set out goal to reduce building 
heat loss by 20% by 2020 and 40% by 2030. Furthermore, 
Law on Energy Conservation (2015) has been adopted 
in order to implement these goals, and identified 99 high 
energy consumers, also known as designated entities, 
which are obliged to carry out energy efficiency measures 
every three years. Through this activity the UB Mayor&#x2019;s 
office has received crucial support to achieve its residential 
energy efficiency targets, as well as to contribute towards 
the national goals, by carrying out investment-grade energy 
audit for model residential buildings to assess energy 
efficiency potential and its investment needs. Second 
phase of this cooperation is to develop a business model to 
explore market-based energy performance contracting for 
large scale residential buildings.
Project 4: Mongolian Sustainable Finance Forum 
(MSFF) 2017.
The Mongolian Green Credit Fund (MGCF) and 
introduction of MGCF-developed pipeline projects 
to potential domestic and international investors was 
successfully convened on September 14, 2017 in 
Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia. The focus theme of the forum was 
&#x201C;Fostering Partnerships to Scale Up Sustainable Finance&#x201D;. 
The forum attracted more than 500 people attended the 
event from government and regulatory organizations, 
banks and other FIs, DFIs and international organizations, 
clients, businesses, civil society organizations and the 
academia. The Forum announced the MOU between 
Mongolia&#x2019;s Ministry of Environment and Tourism, 
Ministry of Finance, Mongolian Bankers Association, 
and GGGI. The MoU establishes an MGCF Steering 
Committee to accelerate the MGCF&#x2019;s legal establishment 
and initial operation. The Forum also included a discussion 
of the National Sustainable Finance Roadmap with 
financial regulators. This Roadmap, supported by UN 
Environment, includes policies and regulations to support 
the introduction of sustainable finance in the non-banking 
financial sector that covers micro-finance institutions, 
insurance companies, and the stock exchange. There was 
also showcasing of MGCF pipeline projects and crucial 
feedback from potential investors at the forum.
Project 5: Colombia, Innovative business models and 
financing mechanisms to catalyze private investment for 
waste biomass to energy biogas projects.
This activity was undertaken to support MME in 
developing policies to attract private sector investment 
in the production and commercialization of biogas and 
biomethane. The broader objective of the activity was to 
promote the development of non-conventional energy 
sources with lower GHG emissions through support for the 
formation of a Nationally Appropriate Mitigation Action 
(NAMA) to meet Colombia&#x2019;s NDC. Aside from the concrete 
business plans for the three waste-to-energy streams, 
policy recommendations were presented and discussed 
with the government. This activity was well received by 
the main government counterparts (MME and UPME), 
demonstrating a strong commitment to the National 
Climate Change Policy approved in mid-2017. Colombia 
is aware of the necessity to draw on external technical and 
finance assistance to meet its national climate ambitions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 projects designed that are aligned to the country NDC targets</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-23"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution to implementing projects under a country&#x2019;s 
Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC).</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific project implemented and targets under a country 
NDC addressed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific project implemented and targets under a country NDC addressed</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-23"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mitigation and Adaptation targets of countries under the Paris agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia&apos;s annual deforestation rate</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-23"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
