<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-GY07</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical Advisor for Mainstreaming Low-emission Energy Technologies to build Guyana&#xB4;s Green Economy&#x201D;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to ensure that there is a robust technical management system in place for the execution of the Project. It is the expectation that the consultancy will ensure:

-        the articulation of Guyana&#x2019;s Energy Pathway, inclusive of Renewable Energy;

-        the development of energy sector business models;

-        the establishment of the enabling legal and regulatory frameworks; and

-        the deployment of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Technologies in prioritised sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed is to provide Technical Advisory services to UNDP project (funded by GEF and Government of Guyana) called &quot;Mainstreaming Low-emission Energy Technologies to build Guyana&apos;s Green Economy&quot;.

The project is managed by UNDP in collaboration with Office of Climate Change (OCC). The project was submitted four years ago and approved in 2017. Only in August 2019 the project was initiated. 

The project was designed to cover all gaps that exisit in the policy, legislation and regulation in the Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency sector in Guyana. The UNDP project is divided in 3 components, the Technical Advisory support would be in the three components:

1. Technical and financial de-risking. Technical studies will be done in the national grid and new business models developed. The business models will include PPP and other innovative ways to leverage private investment. 

2. Policy framework and Institional capacities. The project intended to develope a roadmap and review some of the legal arrangements. Since the project was designed some studies has already been done. The ladscape is also difference as recently Government is assessing the natural gas (associated to the recent oil discoveries) to be used as power source. The new scope would be to compile the studies and support Government on deciding the way forward. 

3. Pilot projects. The project aim to is mobilize 5mUSD in key pilot projects. The techincal Advisory role would be supporting the consultants and Government to select and implement the projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP; Guyana</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="6"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Fernandez</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04523 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="23110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
