<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-PH2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mainstreaming Green growth in Development Planning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the government in ensuring that green growth is incorporated into national, regional and provincial development planning. Facilitate the improvement of development guidelines for adoption and the development of a replication plan in order to scale up the use of the guidelines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Philippines&#x2019; decentralized governance structure and cyclical changes in Government Administrations &#x2013; six years for national government and three years for local government- have impacted the continuity of government plans and projects. Recognizing these institutional constraints, NEDA, the lead socio-economic planning agency of the Philippines, has developed a National Long-Term Vision (NLTV) to give continuity to government programs across ensuing administrations. The NLTV embodies the aspirations of the Filipino people and provides the basic framework in the formulation of national, sectoral and local development plans, such as the Philippine Development Plan. The NLTV serves as a strategic platform to introduce new approaches in national development planning. However, a critical gap remains in the operationalization of the NLTV, particularly in its ability to be cascaded with appropriate climate goals and adopted by the Local Government Units to eventually influence the formulation of their respective local development plans. Strengthening the national, regional and local government planning nexus, and harmonizing the sectoral and thematic planning, strategies and targets through the use of a green growth lens would be a critical element in ensuring that SDG targets are achieved as envisioned by the NLTV, and inclusive growth and climate resilience are promoted.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juhern Kim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04548 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.8797 121.7740</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="MS" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Sectoral</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">405995.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">421935.24</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="PH2-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">390738.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PH2-EX0418">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">387371.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PH2-IF0118">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Philippines_MainstreamingGreenGrowth_v02_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Mainstreaming Green Growth in Development Planning&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth approaches institutionalized in pursuing government development targets</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 50% of Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) targets achieved by 2030</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guidelines for mainstreaming green growth tools in planning adopted as reference in government development planning</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NEDA, as the key government partner has welcomed the project results - the adoption for reference in local development planning the Green Growth Planning Toolkit for Development Planning. NEDA has requested the support for the scaling up and wider application of the Green Growth Planning Toolkit.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government communication acknowledging green growth principles, tools and techniques in the overall and respective planning processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National and Local Development Plans enhanced using green growth planning guidelines and tools</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recommendations on integrating green growth to the target local development plans were discussed, reviewed and validated with the project stakeholders and respective pilot agencies, and then submitted to the Government partner, NEDA, the DTI-BSMED as pilot NGA, and to the LGUs Bataan and Dinagat Islands as our pilot LGUs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recommendations on integrating green growth into 2 LGUs and 1 NGA development plans (based on use of the GG Toolkit) submitted to LGUs/NGAs/NEDA</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning Guidelines and Toolkit Drafted for Piloting</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Green Growth Planning Toolkit contains both tools and techniques and is developed in two volumes: 
- Volume 1: Operational Guide- is a step-by-step guide to integrating green growth within the Philippine development planning context and anchored on the Philippine Government&#x2019;s Provincial/Local Planning and Expenditure Management Guidelines; and
- Volume 2: Resource Note - features the green growth concept and model; explores how green growth evolved and how it operationalizes sustainable development; andshowcases some global and local good practices, particularly relevant to green growth and energy, tourism and MSMED promotion.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">One (1) set of Green Growth Tools and Techniques developed and submitted to NEDA</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training for Partners and Key Stakeholders on the Green Growth Tools Conducted</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">To pilot-test the Green Growth Planning Toolkit, training modules for mainstreaming green growth in development planning were designed and training workshops were delivered in the pilot LGUs, Bataan and Dinagat Islands, and in the pilot NGA, the DTI-BSMED.  For LGU Bataan, the module implementation was divided into 5 training workshops for the targeted TWG-member offices including the representatives of the 10 out of 11 Municipal LGUs of Bataan Province; for LGU Dinagat Islands, the module was implemented into 3 training workshops including representatives of the 7 Municipal LGUs of the Dinagat Islands Province as part of the TWG, and for DTI-BSMED, one national and 3 local workshops were conducted to implement the training module on mainstreaming green growth in the MSMED Local Action Planning.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">One (1) training event on green growth planning delivered to NGA and LGUs</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
