<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-MN3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Readiness Support Program for Enhancing the Access to Green Finance in Mongolia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mongolia has made commitments to increase renewable energy generation and improve urban planning and resilience in its National Green Development Policy (NGDP) and Action Plan, Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) and Sustainable Development Vision 2030. While the supporting policy environment has improved, implementation and financing to address these challenges remain well below the levels needed to transition to inclusive green growth. Mongolia&#x2019;s energy sector is highly dependent on fossil fuels with over 90% of heating and electricity derived from coal. The resulting soil and air pollution is particularly acute in the peri-urban areas of Ulaanbaatar and other secondary cities, where poverty exceeds the national average. Given the current impacts of weak commodities prices and low investment, a stretched government budget reduces the ability to introduce many of the intended green development measures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seeks co-funding GCF Readiness Programme to: (i) prepare investment projects/programs within the scope of three high impact sub-sectors (ii) undertake market and technical assessments to ensure the investment potential of MGFC programme to scale up and enabling the development of bankable funding proposals. Potential impact of MGFC includes: small-scale renewable and alternative electricity and heating solutions for peri-urban areas; green and affordable residential buildings; waste management and sanitation technologies and services in peri-urban areas; energy efficiency measures for buildings, SMEs, and industrial&#xA0;markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Climate Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Climate Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Romain Brillie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04539 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mongolia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>47.860940990833086 106.73437178134918</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="MS" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Sectoral</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">79616</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">299778.83</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="MN3-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">50221.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MN3-EX0418">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">281296.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MN3-IF01">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">297500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MN3-IF0118">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Mongolia_GCFreadinessProgram_v03_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;GCF Readiness Program for Mongolia&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding proposal development support</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A funding proposal to the GCF was submitted in March 2018 and re-submitted in July 2018 by the Accredited Entity XacBank. No-objection letter to submit the funding proposal to GCF was issued by the GCF NDA in March 2018. Two letters of commitment to invest in MGFC were obtained from the GoM (Ministry of Finance) and the Mongolian Sustainable Finance Association representing 10 commercial banks. Each letter pledges a USD 5 million equity investment from the GoM and the banks. The project is now expecting GCF&#x2019;s review and possible board approval in 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 funding proposal</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal service consultancy - Scale-up phase of the MGCF</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All documents for incorporation and operations (Draft shareholder agreement, Draft Term Sheet, Draft Operations Manual, Draft CEO contract etc.) have been prepared as part of the project and transferred to MGFC Steering Committee, as well as to the accredited entity XacBank. It is now likely the GoM would seek to establish MGFC in 2019, prior to the resubmission of the funding proposal to GCF, due for the 23rd Board Meeting of GCF.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MGCF is legally established under relevant Mongolian laws</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Market demand and investment potential study - Small scale RE and alternative energy solutions to peri-urban areas and follow up with implementation work.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the scoping study made by the Market Analyst, and after discussions with project partners and stakeholders, the scope of the market assessment was changed to energy efficiency measures with two focuses (i) Energy efficiency measures in industry (ii) Thermal insulation for Ger areas houses. Final report was produced in March 2018 and incorporated in the feasibility study. Additional pipeline development activities and engagement with private sector and other development partners took place between March 2018 and September 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 market assessment final report</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-11-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-21"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector engaged in country consultative processes.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector was consistently engaged in the funding proposal development process, both on the side of project developers and institutions participating into MGFC (commercial banks). All three workshops organized included representatives from the private sector. A large part of the work carried out under the market assessments included meetings with project developed or technology providers. The details to these discussions are available in the final market assessment reports and feasibility study of MGFC.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector engagement is systematically part of the country consultative processes and structured dialogues with the NDA/FP, accredited entities and the GCF Secretariat.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-21"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Market demand and investment potential study - Waste management and sanitation solutions and follow up implementation work</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoping study revealed the lack of bankability of individual improved sanitation investments and the weak connection between both sanitation and waste management and GHG emissions reduction. As a result, the waste management and sanitation solutions market was not included in the feasibility study, not in the funding proposals submitted to GCF. The report was completed in September 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 market assessment final report</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-11-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-21"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Market demand and investment potential study - Green and affordable residential building and follow up implementation work</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scoping study revealed the large potential of this market, strongly connected to GHG and air pollution reduction. Final report was produced in March 2018 and incorporated in the feasibility study. Additional pipeline development activities and engagement with private sector and other development partners took place between March 2018 and September 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 market assessment final report</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-11-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-21"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposal for project preparation support, including project preparation facility, is submitted to GCF</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MGFC GCF Readiness proposal was implemented as planned, delivering three market assessments, a full feasibility study and a funding proposal submitted in March 2018 and re-submitted in July 2018 by the Accredited Entity XacBank. No-objection letter to submit the funding proposal to GCF was issued by the GCF National Designed Authority in March 2018. Two letters of commitment to invest in MGFC were obtained from the GoM (Ministry of Finance) and the Mongolian Sustainable Finance Association representing 10 commercial banks. Each letter pledges a USD 5 million equity investment from the GoM and the banks. The project is now expecting GCF&#x2019;s review and possible board approval in 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project/program preparation support to develop funding proposals approved.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-21"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Workshops organized</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first workshop was held on March 16, 2018, focusing on national stakeholder consultation on the MGFC funding proposal to GCF as part of the no-objection letter issuance process. 75 attendees representing various entities ranging from government, private sector, and civil society organizations were present at the workshop. The key outcomes include: (i) Awareness of green finance and the role of MGFC in channeling climate finance to Mongolia strengthened among participants (ii) Positive feedback from stakeholders on MGFC main features (iii) No-objection Letter issued by NDA.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 workshops organized</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-05-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance Mongolia&apos;s readiness to access green finance and accelerate innovative multi-stakeholder work underway in the country, especially for crowding in private investment. Pipeline project/programme development support in key green development areas of energy, housing, waste management and sanitation has the potential to unlock green financing at scale.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MGCF has received seed capital to start its operations.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-21"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="50"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
