<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-PH1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for the Operationalization of the People&apos;s Survival Fund</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve and strengthen the operational capacity of the PSF Board members, particularly the Secretariat&#x2019;s ability to manage, deploy and track progress of the Fund&#x2019;s utilization.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PSF was legislated through Republic Act 10174 amending the Climate Change Act of 2009.  The PSF was established as a special fund under the National Treasury dedicated to finance local climate change adaptation interventions that aim to respond to the National Framework Strategy on Climate Change (NFSCC) and the National Climate Change Action Plan (NCCAP) with a minimum allocation of approximately USD 25 million annually.  The PSF is mainly designed for the local government units (LGUs) and government-accredited local community organizations (LCOs), specifically to address the funding gaps for the local climate adaptation projects that are aligned with the national/ local climate change adaptation-disaster risk reduction plans and/ or national/local climate change action plans. The Climate Change Commission (CCC) as one of the PSF Board member requires assistance to operationalize the Fund, as well as in delivering its mandate and function to mainstream climate change policies in the national and local development plans and projects.  Particularly assisting those poorer LGUs who are relatively behind in terms of capacity to satisfy the technical conditions and requirements of PSF and other similar climate financing facilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juhern Kim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04547 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.8797 121.7740</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="MS" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Sectoral</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">631682.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">693806.11</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="PH1-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">577300.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PH1-EX0418">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">622073.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PH1-IF0118">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Philippines_SupportOperationalizationPeopleSurvivalFund_v03_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Support to the Operationalization of the People&apos;s Survival Fund (PSF)&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PSF Financing Framework and Resource Mobilization Strategy developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A resource mobilization (RM) framework for CCA financing has been developed Project.  The objective of the framework is to stimulate the growth of adaptation investments in these LGUs and communities by serving a catalytic role in mobilizing resources?funds, knowledge and partnerships. The framework seeks to turn the Fund into an effective and sustainable tool for communities that need to build their adaptive capacity amid potential and real climate change risks affecting their area.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financing Framework and Resource Mobilization Strategy developed and submitted to PSF Secretariat</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Toolkits to support LGUs and communities developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A toolkit for policy-makers and non-scientists for developing CCA projects was prepared to support the LGUs in coming up with a science and evidence-based proposals for submission to PSF Board. It contains simplified approaches, processes and frameworks that will help the local government and community organizations develop and prepare CCA projects and programs with the aim of reducing their climate vulnerabilities and increasing their resilience.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Revised PSF Proponent&apos;s Handbook with accompanying modules and manuals for the LGUs and POs, and training design and curriculum drafted and presented to the PSF Secretariat</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PSF operational tools for the efficient and effective 
management of PSF accepted by the Government.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGGI developed an Institutional Capacity Development (ICD) plan through this project. The plan provides a brief description of the PSF including its legal basis and objectives; describes the status of PSF performance, identifies specific issues and challenges as well as the emerging gaps from the PSF&#x2019;s desired performance; and outlines the specific strategies that shall be implemented to strengthen the institutional capacity of the PSF secretariat. To support the ICD plan, a Strategic 10-year Road Map for the implementation of the PSF was likewise developed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development and Strategic Action Plan, design of PSF M&amp;E system, Financing Framework and Resource Mobilization Strategy, and PSF KM products are endorsed for use by the PSF Secretariat/CCC</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PSF related Knowledge Management Products and Activities developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGGI has produced two audio visual presentations to support CCC in its capacity building activities in assisting the LGUs in the project identification, development, and preparation of the needed technical documents required to access the PSF.  These video materials were developed to give a standard message on PSF and to help raise awareness among relevant stakeholders on how to properly access the Fund to support their pursuit of implementing climate change adaptation projects.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">New KM products developed for the PSF</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened multi-stakeholder&apos;s strategies for climate change adaptation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">30% of the stakeholders in the country are knowledgeable and equipped by 2018</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and capacities of the LGUs on PSF project 
proposal preparation enhanced.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This outcome has a baseline data of 42 PSF proposals received in 2016 by the PSF Secretariat.  Though the submission of proposal was beyond the control of the project, it was ensured that this outcome falls below the target.  However, with the tools provided in Outcome 1, the Project has high hopes that these tools will be able to enhance and improve the capacities of the LGUs in drafting the proposal for PSF financing.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of funding proposals submitted to the PSF annually is increased by at least 30% compared to 2016</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
