<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-RW22</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greening Rwanda&#x2019;s Existing Public Building Stock</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first component of the PIN aims at providing guidance to RHA to develop a decent database that captures the basic elements related to managing existing public buildings such as year of construction, area of the building, no. of floors, building typology, no. of building occupants, the current condition of the building, etc. to name a few. The component will further focus on conducting a baseline survey of all large-scale buildings using the data that is available. At a minimum, the baseline survey would assess 74 large-scale buildings in Kigali and secondary cities.

The second component will focus on preliminary/walk-through audits for select public buildings (up to 5 buildings) and propose recommendations to improve the performance of the buildings. The audits will also provide guidance on retrofitting interventions and high-level cost-benefit analysis. This information will be helpful the compute the green investment potential for greening all large-scale public buildings in Rwanda.

The third component of the PIN aims developing an investment proposal (of at least $10M) to green the existing public buildings, the associated financial cost-benefit analysis, and the climate mitigation and adaptation potential. The investment proposal will also seek to enhance the financing mechanism by stimulating private sector involvement and integrating existing policy instruments to enhance the long-term sustainability of the implementation of resource efficiency measures. 

The fourth component of the PIN proposes to develop easy to use guidelines to green existing public buildings. The guidelines will be an extension of the Green Building Minimum Compliance System (already approved and applicable to new buildings only), but with a lot of emphasis on greening the operational aspects of existing public buildings and will be voluntary in nature in terms of their applicability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to bring in a transformational, scalable and replicable change in the way existing public buildings are operated in Rwanda by encouraging green and resource-efficient operational practices to reduce energy &amp; water consumption and better waste management, promote net-zero energy initiatives (where feasible) by conducting a baseline survey of all large-scale public buildings in Rwanda, preliminary/walkthrough audits of at least 5 large-scale public buildings including cost-benefit analysis of recommendations, and develop a green investment proposal (worth at least $10M) to green 74 large-scale buildings that are operating in Kigali and six secondary cities. The conservative estimate of annual CO2 mitigation potential by &#x2018;greening&#x2019; 74 large-scale public buildings operating in Kigali and 6 Secondary cities would be 6364 tonneCO2e/annum. This directly contributes towards the implementation of updated Rwanda NDC. 

Further, based on the findings from the baseline survey, and audits the project aims to develop technical guidelines to green existing public buildings in Rwanda. The guidelines will help the facility managers to undertake green retrofitting initiatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arrabothu Dheeraj</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04556 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">150088.55</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="RW22-EX0420">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">144291.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Conduct walk-through audit of 5 public buildings and identify improvement measures.

2. Present the audit findings, recommendations and cost-benefit analysis to the building management

3. Develop guidelines to green existing public buildings</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Audit report available

2. Meeting minutes

3. Guidelines available

4. Monthly, quarterly monitoring reports and mid-year and end of year results reports</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Audits conducted
2. Audit report developed
3. Green existing public building guidelines developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline survey of large-scale public buildings in Rwanda.

1. Conduct a baseline survey of all large-scale public buildings operating in Rwanda by working closely with the RHA division in charge of public building maintenance and Rwanda Social Security Board (RSSB). RHA informed that 74 large-scale buildings are operating in Kigali and secondary cities. The overall aim of this activity is to cover all large-scale buildings operating across the country managed by RHA and RSSB.

2. Provide guidance to RHA to develop a decent database of existing public buildings that captures all key parameters such as year of construction, built-up area, no. of floors, no. of occupants etc.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Baseline survey report available

2. Recommendation report available

3. Monthly, quarterly monitoring reports and mid-year and end of year results reports</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Baseline survey completed
2. Recommendations provided to RHA to develop a new database</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop an investment proposal to green existing public buildings in Rwanda</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lack of availability of sufficient existing public buildings utilities data to develop an investment proposal</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green investment proposal developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda&apos;s existing public building stock converted into resource efficient green buildings</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monthly and quarterly monitoring reporting and mid-year and end of year results</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Extent to which green growth policies adopted by governments are likely to lead to transformational change. To be assessed on a 4-point scale balanced scorecard with a maximum score of 4.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total volume of green growth financing catalyzed with GGGI&#x2019;s support, disaggregated by public and private investment.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GHG emission reduction achieved by greening Rwanda&apos;s existing public building stock</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monthly, quarterly monitoring reports and mid-year and end of year results reports</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">GHG emissions reduction from business as usual (MtCO2e)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
