<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-MX4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico Sonora Bond</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To support key actors in the State of Sonora (Mexico) to issue Sonora&#x2019;s first Green Bond to finance the implementation of the State&#x2019;s Green Growth Strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upon submission of the Framework and after consultations with the
Office of the Governor and Sonora Social and Environmental Commission,
the State Treasury selected the Bus Rapid Transport system as the State&#x2019;s
priority project and committed to issuing a first green bond tranche worth
MDP 500 (approximately USD 25 million) to finance the first stage of
BRT development. Provided the issuance will lead to reduced cost of debt
and improved visibility of the State&#x2019;s Green Growth Strategy, Sonora will
leverage Sonora Green Bond Framework for future issuances for the full
implementation of the BRT project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investment Policy Solutions Division</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pablo Martinez</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04572 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>29.0730 -110.9550</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="MS" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multi-Sectoral</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="MX4-EX0418">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">10448.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MX4-IF0118">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The State Treasury is committed to issue Green Bonds</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGGI Team led the design of Sonora Green Bond Framework. The
Framework is the foundation for the development of the Bond Prospectus
and the issuance of green certified bonds. The Framework submitted
to GGGI provides interested external parties and investors with a clear
understanding of the processes and characteristics of the Green Bond,
the process for evaluation and selection of eligible projects and how the
issuance meets the Green Bond Principles (GBP).
The Green Bond Framework developed by GGGI includes the
identification of 8 eligible green projects across five sectors: renewable
energy, green buildings, waste &amp; water treatment, public transport and
sustainable landscape. Upon submission of the Framework and after
consultations with the Office of the Governor and Sonora Social and
Environmental Commission, the State Treasury selected the Bus Rapid
Transport system as the State&#x2019;s priority project and committed to issuing
a first green bond tranche worth MXP 500 million (approximately USD
25 million) to finance the first stage of BRT development. Provided the
issuance will lead to reduced cost of debt and improved visibility of the
State&#x2019;s Green Growth Strategy, Sonora will leverage Sonora Green Bond
Framework for future issuances for the full implementation of the BRT
project (up to MXP 2,0</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Official letter of commitment including Green Bond issuance timeline and bond face value</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The State of Sonora is capable and committed to issue Green Bonds</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Treasury of the State of Sonora officially endorsed the Green
Bond Framework developed by GGGI and included Green Bonds in
the funding strategy of the State of Sonora for the year 2019 with the
condition that all infrastructure and capital projects funded through
green bonds will be climate resilient and, where relevant, support the
reduction of greenhouse gas emissions.
After consultations with the Office of the Governor and Sonora
Social and Environmental Commission, the State Treasury selected
the Bus Rapid Transit (BRT) system as the State&#x2019;s priority project
and committed to issuing a first green bond tranche worth MXP 500
million (approximately USD 25 million) to finance the first stage of BRT
development. Provided the issuance will lead to reduced cost of debt and
improved visibility of the State&#x2019;s Green Growth Strategy, the Treasury
will leverage Sonora Green Bond Framework for future issuances for the
full implementation of the BRT project (up to MDP 2,075).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Official commitment letter with bond issuance timeline and bond face value signed by the Sonora State Treasury</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financing of technologies and infrastructures is aligned with IPCC low-carbon economy and Mexico&#x2019;s NDC targets</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green project(s) aligned with Mexico&#x2019;s NDC are identified and included in the State of Sonora Green Bond Framework</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased awareness and capacity of key state-level decision makers about green bond processes and requirements</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">on-the-job training with key stakeholder groups in Sonora, including
the State Treasury, Office of the Governor, Social and Environmental
Commission, and members of the Green Growth Cabinet.
? Between March and April, the project team pursued efforts to
increase the government support towards the initiative, focusing
on the development of briefing notes and delivery of information
sessions to key decision makers. By May 2018, the project
team had secured letter of support from Sonora State Treasury,
Sonora Social and Environmental Commission, and Sonora Green
Growth Cabinet.
? Between May and December 2018, the team focused on demandled
training targeting capacity gaps identified by the country team.
? The capacity building efforts took the form of 5 consultations with
key actors aimed at delivering targeted presentations, sharing
briefing notes and walking them through costing simulations with
the goal of providing participants with a solid grasp of the green
bond issuance process, reporting requirements and certification.
? In December 2018, GGGI team delivered a capacity building
workshop addressing key state and non-state actors involved in
green bonds issuance. The event was attended by approximately
40 participants, including: investors, underwriters, regulators,
potential verifiers and state actors. During the workshop, leading
national finance experts shared their knowledge and handson
technical expertise on the following themes: Green Bond
Definition, Selection, Verification, Monitoring &amp; Reporting as well
as further market trends of Green Bonds.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff from key government bodies possess the technical capacity to implement and lead the Green Bond issuance process</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
