<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-GY02</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Guyana&#x2019;s Access to GCF to Transition to Renewable Energy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project objective is to support the development of potential utility scale renewable energy projects for public-private partnership and GCF funding. To facilitate the implementation of renewable energy projects, and ultimately the Country Programme being developed, potential national accredited entities from the Energy Sector will be assessed and the nomination by NDA of two entities will be supported, while raising their awareness on GCF funding opportunities. As key Government partner, the private sector will be engaged in the process of prioritizing utility scale renewable energy projects and made aware of potential access to GCF through Private Sector Facility. Addressing barriers to scale up and make use of the country&#x2019;s abundant natural energy resources would help reduce the cost of power and pave the way for sustainable access to renewable energy.&#x202F;In line with this, the proposed project will undertake policy and institutional assessment and provide recommendations as well as for innovative financing to leverage private sector investments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project outcome will be the following: i.) Develop the country program by preparing a pipeline of renewable energy utility scale projects and pre-feasibility analysis for the shortlisted projects and preparing at least 2 concept notes ii.) Nominate Direct Access Entities and prepare gap assessment&#x202F;iii.) Leverage private sector investment into renewable energy projects; Review and recommend changes in regulation and propose innovative business models that leverage the private sector investment in the renewable energy iv.) Increasing awareness of GCF and its Private Sector Facility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Environment, Ministry of the Presidency / Office of Climate Change (NDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Climate Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Fernandez</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04523 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="SE" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Energy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="23111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">289003.18</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GY02-EX0419e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">127113.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GY02-IF0119">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">119659.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Outcome 2.6:
Feasibility of selected climate technologies for mitigation and adaptation assessed and incorporated into planning process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 2.6.1: Identifying and assessing the prioritized utility scale renewable energy projects in reference to the Technology Needs Assessment (2016)/Country Program Document through technical research and analysis (including GCF investment criteria for funding proposal), desktop reviews and data collection from Government/utility for project selection. Review and update the existing Country Programme and ensure integration of the result. / Activity 2.6.2: Consultation workshop with Government/utility on short listed pipeline of utility scale renewable energy projects (including the public and private sector) / Activity 2.6.3: Conduct pre-feasibility study on renewable energy project(s) in identified project sites</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 2.6.1: Initial project pipeline identified by M1</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 2.6.2: Workshop report delivered to identify potential project sites by M2</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 2.6.3: Pre-feasibility study of renewable energy project(s) in identified project sites by M9</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-26"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Outcome 3.1:
Direct Access entities nomination</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 3.1.1: Continuing previous Readiness project by conducting assessment of the strengthened procedure for identifying DAEs for integration of energy criteria to act as executing entities in the implementation of an energy sector pipeline of fundable GCF proposals. Assessment of the identified entities from previous Readiness deliverable applying set energy criteria with further study in the case there is no qualified entity from the list. / Activity 3.1.2: Engaging with identified candidate DAEs to raise awareness of opportunities, processes and requirements of engaging with the GCF. Existing awareness-raising materials developed through previous readiness activities to be updated/improved appropriately to fit for use of potential national accredited entities from the energy sector. / Activity 3.1.3: Collecting and reviewing relevant information from interested candidate entities against GCF accreditation requirements and selecting entity(ies) which demonstrates to best meet eligibility requirements. Gap assessment to ascertain their level of compliance with GCF&#x2019;s requirements will be undertaken and recommendations will be provided / Activity 3.1.4: Supporting NDA in the nomination process of up to two selected entities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 3.1.1: Long-list of candidate DAEs prepared by M3</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 3.1.2: List of participants, training material and workshop report by M4</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 3.1.3: Gap assessment report and action plans for prioritized entities selected by NDA in M7</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 3.1.4: Letters of nomination by M10</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-26"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Outcome 4.3:
Project concept notes development</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 4.3.1 Preparing project concept notes for at least two prioritized utility scale renewable energy projects. Integration of the concept notes to the Country Programme.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.3.1: At least two project concept notes prepared by M12</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-26"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Outcome 4.5:
Private sector engagement</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 4.5.1: Preparing communication materials (e.g. PSA, brochure) on GCF Private Sector Facility. / Activity 4.5.2: Awareness raising workshop for the private sector in 2 cities (Georgetown and New Amsterdam) / Activity 4.5.3: Engaging the private sector in the process of prioritizing utility scale renewable energy projects and seeking their support.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.5.1: Communication materials prepared by M5</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.5.2: Awareness workshop report by M6</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.5.3: Consultation meetings conducted, list of participants is submitted by M10</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-26"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Outcome 4.6: Crowding-in private sector investments</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity 4.6.1: Assessment of status and impacts of policies, grid codes, procurement, and technical requirements</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">and institutional arrangements for implementation of policy and regulatory recommendations. / Activity 4.6.2: Options analysis and recommendations for innovative financing to leverage private sector investments. / Activity 4.6.3: Workshop with Government stakeholders, entities and utility on (4.6.1) policy recommendations and associated institutional arrangements and (4.6.2) innovative financing models to leverage private sector investments</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.6.1: Assessment report by M9</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.6.2: Recommendation report for innovative financing to leverage private sector investments prepared by M9</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliverable 4.6.3: List of participants, training material and workshop report on policy, institutional and financing recommendations by M11</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-26"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project management</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports to GCF prepared and submitted in a timely manner</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-02-26"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-26"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
