<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-MA1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco Green Cities and Territories</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Morocco to adopt the methodologies, action plans and tools to implement green city and 
territorial development projects, develop two green city and territory project proposals to leverage 
financing. 
Provide technical support to Morocco to implement its NSDS and its NDC n&#xB0;9 commitment to develop a 
model framework for low-carbon green territories including optimized energy, transport and waste 
management, in alignment with its ongoing advanced regionalization transition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Kingdom of Morocco is acutely vulnerable to climate change and is prone to environmental constraints 
(water scarcity, land degradation, energy dependence, pollution, natural resource depletion). These increasing 
pressures are a catalyst for rural migration, as the rural economy largely depends on subsistence farming, 
further straining urban areas and their limited capacities and resources. The Government of Morocco has been 
cultivating an inclusive green economy for a number of years in collaboration with international development 
partners. Additionally, in the NSDS, urban development issues are emphasized, with a focus on conceptualizing 
territories as sustainable ecosystems, and improving design, coordination and implementation of urban 
interventions and rural-urban linkages. Such examples provide a strong foundation for GGGI&#x2019;s Morocco country 
program, which encompasses green territorial development, the circular and social solidarity economy, and implementing the NSDS on a sub-national level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UAE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nicole Perkins</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04540 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.955759 -6.872717</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="GC" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Cities</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">459182</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">365462</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="MA1-EX04">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">333386.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MA1-EX0418">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">364682.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MA1-IF0118">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://report.gggi.org/2017/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/18002_PRR_Morocco_v03_JM.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Green Cities and Territories&quot; - Project Results Report</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building and Knowledge Dissemination</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. July 26, 2018: Knowledge sharing and exchange meeting around the structuring and implementation of an NFV in Morocco, supporting the process of the implementation of the National Strategy for Sustainable Development (NSSD) and National Determined Contributions (NDC). Highlighting GGGI&apos;s expertise in this area with the participation of GGGI GIS.
2. October 1-2, 2018: Conducted Output D3: regional knowledge exchange on green cities development. Participated in the GGGI-Government of Egypt joint workshop on Egypt&#x2019;s green growth potential, which was a capacity building workshop on green growth concepts and approaches in Cairo, Egypt.
3. November 26-29, 2018: Knowledge sharing event at GGGW2018 in Senegal: sharing of Morocco experiences in urban mobility through low carbon initiatives under structuring with the Secretary of State in Charge of Transport, as part of the development of green cities and territories program.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deliver 3 training events per year to strengthen the knowledge and skills of participants</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two green city and territory implementation projects designed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through consultation and data analysis, GGGI has selected pilot
territories through a mapping that identifies marginalized territories,
and territories facing particular resource pressures (Activity E4). The
territories that have been identified are the Draa ? Tafilalet region, which
contains vulnerable oasis and mountain ecosystems. A total of 40.00%
of the national territory is considered part of the oasis ecosystem. The
second region identified is the Beni Mellal ? Khenifra region, which also
contains a marginalized mountain ecosystem.
These activities have led to the drafting of two climate finance projects
for implementation and financing within the scope of the green city and
territory model which is described below:
2 climate finance projects designed as PINs and approved by GGGI
Management Team:
? The development of a multi-sector NFV to support territories
in accessing green financing for the implementation of bankable
programs and projects within the framework of support for the
implementation of the national sustainable development strategy
and the NDCs;
? Support to Regional Project Execution Agencies (AREPs) in structuring
a pipeline of bankable projects to attract green investments and
accelerate the transition to a green and low carbon economy,
financeable via the NFV, in the areas of expertise of the GGGI</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two green territory projects designed</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-06-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of Morocco (GoM) or relevant financier leverage finance for green city territorial projects</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upon request from the Ministry of Interior, GGGI and Green Investment Services (GIS) teams conducted an assessment mission where a series of bilateral meetings were held with key ministries and stakeholders. The results provided the background material for the development of a PIN that covers two technical assistance projects. 
Upon request by the Secretary of State for Transport, the TL team conducted technical assessment on green transport policy development. The result provided the material for GGGI Concept Notes, which are under development. These Concept Notes aim to provide GGGI Morocco with earmarked project funding.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of signed funding agreements</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="50"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The creation of a model, low-carbon city centered on energy-efficiency actions, transport and waste management (NDC no. 9)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribute to the total emission reduction potential of 1,232 million tons of CO2 related to NDC no.9 between 2020-2030
Increasing the sorting-recycling-recovery rate to 20% by 2020; Contribute to the National target of reaching 60% of treated wastewater by 2020 and of 100% by 2030. Contribute to the National target of reuse 50% of wastewater in inland cities by 2020.
Number of regions involved</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="50"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
