<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-47136-FJ07</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-47136" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Access to Climate Finance in Fiji</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fiji, as Small Island Developing State, faces extreme climate vulnerability is already experiencing the negative impact of climate change because of changing weather patterns, including droughts and flooding events, and increasingly damaging natural disasters. The current average asset losses due to tropical cyclones and floods are estimated at more than FJD 500 million per year which is 5% of Fiji&#x2019;s GDP. Climate change will affect all areas of life for the people of Fiji, and the expected impacts include reduced agricultural and fisheries productivity, declining health outcomes,&#x202F;eroding shorelines and riverbanks, shortage of water&#x202F;and higher infrastructure costs.  
The Fijian government recognizes the importance of adapting to climate change and coordinating climate change related adaptation policies, strategies, plans, and activities to reduce the vulnerability and enhance the resilience of Fiji&#x2019;s communities to the impacts of climate change and disasters.  

Fiji&#x2019;s national CO2&#x202F;equivalent emissions make up a mere 0.006% of global emissions.SO, the Fijian Government and other non-government stakeholders have already taken steps to achieve decarbonization in the Fijian economy. Fiji has developed its NDC Roadmap setting a clear pathway to achieve its NDC targets and also launched the Fiji Low Emission Development Strategy (LEDS) 2018-2050 at COP24, through which Fiji aims to reach net zero carbon emissions by 2050 across all sectors of its economy.  This project is aligned with IO1. Strengthened national, sub-national and local green growth planning, financing, and institutional frameworks,&#x202F;IO3. Improved multi-directional knowledge sharing and learning to empower local and external agents necessary to drive green growth processes in partner governments and IO3. Improved multi-directional knowledge sharing and learning to empower local and external agents necessary to drive green growth processes in partner governments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the projects are i.) Establish a coordination mechanism to govern and coordinate climate action and finance and strengthen the capacity of the NDA &#x2013; Climate Change Division (CCD) of the Ministry of Economy &#x2013; to take the lead role. ii.)Prepare the Entity Work Programme of a national accredited direct access entity (DAE) &#x2013; Fiji Development Bank (FDB) &#x2013; aligned with the Country Programme which is being developed this year with assistance from WRI - which aims to result in a number of project concept notes to be submitted to the GCF iii.) Prepare and submit the nomination of the Ministry of Economy (MoE) as DAE and support in their submission of application for accreditation to the GCF and facilitate Stage I accreditation. This will include carrying out gap assessment and preparing action plan for accreditation, followed by institutional and capacity building support, as required iv.)Provide Institutional and capacity building support to accredited and nominated DAE &#x2013; FDB and MoE &#x2013; to ensure compliance policies and procedures are in-place and capacities to manage, implement and oversee climate change projects and programs in line with the GCF fiduciary standards, environmental and social safeguards (ESS) and gender policy are built.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-XM-DAC-47136" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Climate Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Economy, Climate Change and International Cooperation Division</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Growth Planning and Implementation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Katerina Syngellakis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>82-2-2096-9991</telephone>
   <email>info@gggi.org</email>
   <website>http://www.gggi.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Green Growth Institute, 19F Jeongdong Bldg., 21-15 Jeongdong-gil, Jung-gu Seoul 04523 Republic of Korea</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FJ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="889" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="CC" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://aidstream.org/reference/codelist/XM-DAC-47136/sector">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cross-cutting</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">0</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="FJ07-EX0419e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="FJ07-IF0119">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">495538</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[GCF Sub-outcome 3.2] Accreditation of Direct Access Entities</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accreditation documents</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.1.a. Nomination of MOE for accreditation submitted by M3</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.1.b. Assessment report including recommendations/action plan to address these gaps by M6</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.1.c. Capacity building workshop for MoE on GCF fiduciary principles and standards conducted by M11. Workshop agenda, presentation/ info materials and report including
list of participants noting number of women who participated will be prepared.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.1.d. Capacity building workshop on GCF ESS and gender policy standards conducted by M12 with workshop report,including list of participants (noting number of women) and outline for ESS and gender policies prepared</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2.a. Roundtable event to share accreditation knowledge and experience held by M5. Agenda and report including list of participants noting number of women who participated will be prepared</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2.b. Information materials developed by M5</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.3.a. MOE application for accreditation submitted to the GCF by M12.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.3.b. MoE policies drafted/updated (fiduciary policies, ESS and gender policies) in line with the GCF accreditation standards by M18 to facilitate Stage II accreditation</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Direct Access to Climate Finance in Fiji leading for greater mobilization of resources for implementing Fiji NDC and NAP</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCF direct access entity nomination acceptance
Correspondence from GCF
Project pipeline documents, concept notes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Direct Access Entities in Fiji (additional)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[GCF Outcome 3] Direct access to finance</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOE as direct access entity application for accreditation submitted to GCF</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOE as direct access entity application for accreditation submitted to GCF</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[GCF Sub-outcome 3.3] Direct Access Entity&#x2019;s
(DAE) Work Programme alignment with Country Programme</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">a. DAE-GCF Work Programme developed and aligned with the Country Programme
b. Entity Work Programme (EWP) operationalized
c. FDB Capacity assessment conducted</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.1.a. Develop a toolkit in applying both GCF and FDB
policies and processes in applying for GCF finance by
M4.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.1.b. Prepare a process/decision matrix in developing and
assessing project proposals for submission to the GCF,
including an FDB Category &#x2018;C&#x2019; identification process
and template for use by M6</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.1.c. Develop financial risk mitigation processes for projects
by M6.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.1.d. Develop the second EWP by M12</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.1.e. Prepare at least 2 draft concept notes by M18</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.a Assessment report and training action plan prepared by M4.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.b. Develop a capacity development framework in terms of structure and skills required by M6</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.c.Training materials for mainstreaming of the policies (Gender, Procurement, etc.) developed as part of the accreditation conditions</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.d. Draft ESS policy and procedure and necessary
templates to assist FDB in upgrading its accreditation to be able to fund Category &#x2018;B&#x2019; projects by M11</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.e. Internal audit assessment and evaluation template for
GCF funded projects by M12</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.f. An annual audit plan and an annual audit report template by M12</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.g. Draft M&amp;E policy and reporting templates to assist FDB in implementing the requirements under the AMA by M12</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.h. Six training sessions delivered. Report on institutional support and training sessions for FDB staff (including MoE staff where appropriate) including on gender, procurement, ERM, etc. (noting number of female participants)</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2.i. Develop progress report for the FDB in carrying out its functions as an accredited entity and implementing the GCF accreditation conditions</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[GCF Outcome 1] Institutional
capacity and coordination
mechanisms in place to govern
and coordinate climate action
and finance</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">a. Expert engaged by project (18 months) embedded in Climate Change Division
b. Coordination mechanism established
c. NDA institutional capacity increased/enhanced.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordination mechanism established</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[GCF Sub-Outcome 1.2] NDA &#x2018;No Objection&#x2019; procedure for funding proposals and PPF applications</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">a. No objection procedure established
b. Awareness raising for no-objection procedure conducted</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.1.a. Establish no objection procedure and develop an
evaluation tool by M5.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.1.b. Conduct awareness raising workshops on no objection procedure &#x2013; one for government agencies by M7 and one for the private sector (e.g. through the Fiji Commerce and Readiness and Preparatory Support
Employers Federation), accredited and potential DAEs and other key external stakeholders by M9. Workshop
agenda and report, including list of participants noting number of women who participated, will be prepared.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[GCF Sub-outcome 1.1]: NDA inter-institutional coordination mechanism</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">a. Platform (working group) for climate action established
b. Meeting minutes
c. Meeting attendance sheets</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1.a. Platform (working group) for climate action, led by the NDA, established by M7</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.1.b. At least 3 sectoral group meetings and meeting briefing notes presenting and discussing the NAP, LEDS and
NDC Roadmap with stakeholders, particularly private
sector.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.2.. Operational guideline for the platform
(working group) developed by M7</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3.a. Meeting agenda and report, including list of participants
noting number of women who participated, will be
prepared. Training/capacity building activity report,
including participant evaluation</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3.b. A quarterly report including results of the dialogue will be prepared including a report that details best practices
when preparing concept notes.</narrative>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1.3.c. A training plan to build capacity over a 3-year period and on-boarding plan related to GCF knowledge for new
staff will be developed. Two reports including reviewed document/projects and support provided will be prepared.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Management and Implementation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">a. Recruitment process completed within schedule
b. Timely submission of high quality reports</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recruitment process completed within schedule</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-16"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="n/a"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
