<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-16/HSS10/SA2/H/NGO/3441</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency life-saving and gender sensitive high impact health services for hard to reach, under-served and conflict affected IDPs and vulnerable communities in Leer county of Unity state and Fangak county of Jonglei state.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leer and Fangak have become among the extremely affected counties following the aftermath of the 2013 and now, July 2016 Juba crises. Communities in Leer County are currently living in swampy area where accessibility to reach them is quite difficult and other moving far east to Fangak where access is much fair. Partners reaching this displace population in leer even through other county like Panijar- Nyal is difficult since it take two to three days by canoe to reach the IDPs.  Women, Girls, Boys and Men in these counties are the most vulnerable in terms of food insecurity, malnutrition and diseases. Active hostilities, in-accessibility and Insecurity are among the constraining factors limiting women, Girls, Boys and Men to move freely to more secure places to access assistance. There are rampant reports of women and girls being raped and subjected to other forms of violence under the hands of armed men. In the absence of livelihood opportunities, (that have successively been weakened over time by incessant emergencies) many boys are encouraged and even others forced to join armed groups. Reports from communities living in these locations indicate that several families have been separated, with children and elderly left to fend for themselves. Basic infrastructures including health facilities are limited and not effectively supported and the war has markedly destroyed a good number of the few existing ones. Women, Girls, Boys and men are forced to seek traditional ways of treatment. Women and Girls who are exposed to myriad gender base violence do not get special services including psychosocial support or treatment in case of rape. RH services in these conflict-affected counties are nearly nonexistent. Men and Boys from the battlefield are exposed to traumatizing experiences thus requiring psychological support. Immunization coverage is very low in these counties thus predisposing Boys and girls to outbreaks of diseases. Men and women with disability lack special services. However, Nile Hope through this project will support the existing health facilities mostly in Fangak and also set up mobile clinics (1 in Leer and 3 in Fangak) to provide emergency health services to women, girls, boys and men who are in need of the health services including women and men with disabilities. Special services will be provided to targeted highly vulnerable people including clinical management of rape, HIV services in emergencies and psychosocial support to traumatized affected women and Men. Through this project, we shall work to increase accesses to timely equitable emergency primary health care including emergency obstetric care, securing and strategically preposition emergency drugs supplies and equipment in order to alleviate suffering of the vulnerable groups.  Nile Hope have developmental funding from HPF in Leer but due to High needs in the area the amount is very limited on the hand in Fangak, Nile Hope has currently no funding to support the influx of IDPs after the first round of CHF ended in June.  However, with the current conflict affecting mostly Leer County and more and more displacement being experienced where the community is moving Far East in Fangak County, coupled with difficulties in accessibility to the area, less significant amount of resources will be used in the area compared with the Fangak response. Nile Hope will spend more of the budget in Fangak (80%) as compared to Leer (20%) since the county is more accessible and has experienced relatively calm.  Vigilance and close monitoring will be ensured and in events where there will be need for resources to be increased for the county, the organization will initially share her concerns with the cluster for approval and way forward.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tolu Lemiso</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ass Health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0920010329</telephone>
   <email>dtolu@nilehope.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Getachew Gezaghen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0920010326</telephone>
   <email>getachew@nilehope.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">163860.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">79898.91</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00060794">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-14">59252.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-3441">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">243759.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00062207">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-01">119400.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00063485">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-20">65105.63</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Hope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
