<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-16/HSS10/SA1/WASH/INGO/845</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Emergency Response in South Sudan improving the access to Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH) to contribute to the health and nutrition status of vulnerable people</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This concept note proposes WASH activities in two priority locations in South Sudan. Firstly, Fangak County has remained a priority location since the start of the ongoing conflict and continues to
have a significant Internally Displaced Population (IDP) population and affected host population that remain vulnerable under the current
circumstances. Secondly, a critical nutrition situation with Global Acute Malnutrition (GAM) prevalence far above the 15% emergency threshold is persisting in the Warrap State. The proposed activities aim to reduce vulnerability malnourished children through targeted WASH interventions in both locations.
During the ongoing ACF CHF project in Fangak county, ACF have identified remaining WASH needs, a lack of institutional capacity to continue meeting needs and /or a lack of WASH partners to meet needs. ACF have also identified new locations through collaboration with local nutrition partners and WASH partner assessments. Thus, ACF propose to expand the coverage of the current emergency WASH project and to stabilize the factors which contribute to mortality and morbidities in the target IDP and host populations in Keew and Juaibor Payams located in Fangak County, Jonglei State. Juaibor has received no support in terms of WASH services and in Keew there is need to continue a meaningful WASH intervention to ensure that minimum standards are maintained. 
This response will increase the ability for populations to access to safe water supply and improve hygiene and sanitation practices through context specific approaches considering the limited access for sustained material support and the potential for future displacement of the population. Ensuring safe water supply to affected populations remains one of the main priorities for the WASH Cluster strategy and in Jonglei, this project, using CHF funds, will continue to work through a gender sensitive approach to improve access to safe water sources for the communities by distribution of water transporting containers to reduce number of trips to water sources.
The response is integrated with the life-saving nutrition activities and food security and livelihoods projects being undertaken by ACF and local partners in same target area through WASH activities that will target vulnerable malnourished children and caregivers in the same catchment area. Specifically this WASH intervention ensures a minimum package of WASH for households of malnourished children under 5 and caregivers and will target to increase the basic access to WASH services through improving the ability for populations to treat and store drinking water and increase the hygiene practices through a combined approach of age and gender specific messaging and community mobilization campaigns. The WASH minimum package is a cross sectorial approach to prevent and treat causes of under nutrition and will be executed in both targeted locations. 
Across both locations hygiene and sanitation actions will be taken to improve knowledge, behavior and practices through appropriate behavior change approaches and messaging. Mother to mother support groups will be formed and trained to continue the hygiene promotion activities in the villages and ensure sustained good hygiene practices linked with malnutrition status. The intervention in Jonglei will also contribute to increasing community preparedness for cholera outbreaks training of staff and community workers on AWD and cholera response activities. The result is to provide people with both the capacity and knowledge to maintain an adequate level of protection against disease outbreak while improving their overall hygiene practices that will pave the way for a more long term WASH programming in the area. These activities will lead to reducing incidence of water related diseases, reducing morbidity and mortality and reducing malnutrition incidence as diarrhea is a direct cause of malnutrition</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lionel LaFont</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0911072918</telephone>
   <email>cd.ssd@acf-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eve Mackinnon</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0925733131</telephone>
   <email>washco.ssd@acf-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Warrap</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.22093080 28.85968040</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-04">299666.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-845">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-04">299666.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00057507">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-12">156303.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00061713">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-16">102241.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
