<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-16/HSS10/SA1/H/INGO/731</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated and lifesaving Primary Health Care (PHC) services for conflict affected and vulnerable populations and strengthening emergency responses in Baliet, Melut, Maiwut and Ulang Counties, Upper Nile State (UNS), Twic, Warrap State and Agok: Abyei Administrative Area (AAA).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under this grant, GOAL will respond to the acute needs of the IDP populations in Melut County (Koradar and Dethoma), Ulang County (Nyangora, Barmach, Riangnam), Maiwut County (Pinthor) and Returnees in Baliet counties (Baliet, Galachol, Rianyang). GOAL will also strengthen the outbreak response of Malaria that significantly hit Twic county in Warrap state and Agok, AAA through provision of emergency preparedness and response, lifesaving curative consultations, routine and outreach immunization coverage and a minimum initial service package (MISP) for RH services. 
GOAL will strengthen availability and access of services to essential emergency health care needs, including addressing the major causes of mortality among U5 (malaria, diarrhoea and Pneumonia), and emergency obstetrics and neonatal care services as well as scale up the prevention, detection, and response to outbreaks among IDP&#x2019;s, returnees and host communities, bolster service integration and case management of acute malnutrition with complication in stabilization centres in Ulang, Maiwut, Twic, and strengthen the mapping, linkage and referral to mainstream management of GBV, and child protection. 
Under this grant, GOAL will respond to the acute health needs of the IDP populations in Melut County (Koradar and Dethoma ), Ulang County (Nyangora, Barmach, Riangnam), Maiwut County (Pinthor) and Returnees in Baliet counties (Baliet, Galachol, Rianyang) through provision of primary health care through a network of xxx  primary health care centres (PHCCs), primary health care units (PHCUs) and mobile facilities Facilities provide curative consultations, routine and outreach expanded programme of immunization (EPI), reproductive healthcare including antenatal and postnatal care and deliveries, health education, and growth monitoring closely integrated with treatment of malnutrition in children 6-59 months. Provision of primary health care is part of integrated programming also including nutrition, food security and livelihoods (FSL), and water sanitation and hygiene (WASH) interventions.  GOAL will also strengthen emergency preparedness and response (EPR), through community disease surveillance and routine and outreach EPI to prevent and identify outbreaks, as well as lifesaving curative consultations, and prepositioning of drugs and supplies.
. 

GOAL will strengthen its response to the acute needs of the population through ensuring availability of the right mix of staff, uninterrupted drug supply including RH commodities, provision of basic health services, case management of communicable diseases, integration of services, supporting stabilization centres, integrated disease surveillance and reporting, outbreak control, contingency planning and focusing on emergency preparedness, response capacity and population resilience.  EPI will be strengthened through expansion of cold chain, improvement of cold chain maintenance, and improved micro-planning and coordination of cold boxes.  

GOAL will ensure beneficiaries and affected communities are consulted in planning, implementation, and evlautioin., Community feedback is collected through focus group discussions (FGDs) and interviews, conducted both in routine programme monitoring and supervision, as well as through a formal complaints response mechanism  (CRM). Barriers and concernswill be communicated to field and Juba level, as appropriate, and addressed. GOAL ensures that vulnerable populations are taken into account, targeting women and children and working with communities to reduce barriers to service uptake.  GOAL will continue to participate in the protection cluster and GBV sub-cluster to ensure mainstreaming of gender and protection in programme planning, implementation and evaluation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Binyam Getachew</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211959462505</telephone>
   <email>bhailu@ss.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daniel Muhungura</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assistant Country Director - Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0959462507</telephone>
   <email>dmuhungura@ss.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emma Cullen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211959462501</telephone>
   <email>ecullen@ss.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willow Rook</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0924153687</telephone>
   <email>wrook@ss.goal.ie</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Warrap</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.22093080 28.85968040</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-16">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00055762">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-23">180653.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-731">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-16">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00059567">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-26">119345</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
