<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-16/HSS10/SA2/WASH/INGO/3586</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Emergency Response in South Sudan improving access to Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH) to contribute to the health and nutritional status of vulnerable people in Northern Bar el Ghazal and Jonglei</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current proposal proposes WASH activities fully integrated with the nutrition intervention carried on by ACF in 18 OTPs sites in two priority locations in South Sudan: Fangak County (Old Fangak and Toch), Jonglei state and Aweil Est and North Counties, NBeG state. Both counties still remain a priority locations due to the ongoing conflict and the critical nutrition situation with Global Acute Malnutrition (GAM) prevalence far above the 15% emergency threshold is persisting in NBeG and Jonglei States. The proposed activities aim to reduce vulnerability malnourished children through targeted WASH interventions in ACF nutrition facilities in Old Fangak and Toch, Jonglei state and Aweil Est, North and center, NBeG state.
During the ongoing ACF CHF projects in Fangak, Aweil Est, North and center counties, ACF have identified remaining WASH needs, a lack of institutional capacity to continue meeting needs and /or a lack of WASH partners to meet needs. Thus, ACF proposes to continue covering  the areas mentioned above through the emergency WASH intervention and to stabilize the factors which contribute to mortality and morbidities in the target IDP and host populations in Old Fangak Fangak County, Jonglei State and Aweil Est, North and Center, NBeG State. This response will increase the ability for populations to 
-	ensure a basic WASH access in nutrition sites with potable water, through water treatment and storage in health centers, latrine construction/rehabilitation
-	train the caregivers of undernourished children to treat drinking water at household level through filtering and boiling and ensure improved hygiene practices. 
-	Improve sanitation and hygiene practices through various participatory channels hygiene promotion sessions using such as PHAST and CHAST approaches with targeted support to caregivers of SAM amp MAM children at OTPs and SC sites 
-	Train and provide of latrine 100 kits  to caregivers of SAM children willing to build their own latrine at household level 

Ensuring safe water supply to affected populations remains one of the main priorities for the WASH Cluster strategy and in Jonglei, this project, using CHF funds, will continue to work through a gender sensitive approach to improve access to safe water sources for the communities by distribution of water transporting containers to reduce number of trips to water sources.
The response is integrated with the life-saving nutrition projects being undertaken by ACF and local partners in same target area through WASH activities that will target vulnerable malnourished children and caregivers in the same catchment area. Specifically this WASH intervention ensures a minimum package of WASH for households of malnourished children under 5 and caregivers and will target to increase the basic access to WASH services through improving the ability for populations to treat and store drinking water and increase the hygiene practices through a combined approach of age and gender specific messaging and community mobilization campaigns. The WASH minimum package is a cross sectorial approach to prevent and treat causes of under nutrition and will be executed in both targeted locations. 
Across both locations hygiene and sanitation actions will be taken to improve knowledge, behavior and practices through appropriate behavior change approaches and messaging. Mother to mother support groups will be formed and trained to continue the hygiene promotion activities in the villages and ensure sustained good hygiene practices linked with malnutrition status. The intervention in Jonglei and NBeG will also contribute to increasing community preparedness for cholera outbreaks training of staff and community workers on AWD and cholera response prevention activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guy Halsey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 (0) 911 072 91</telephone>
   <email>cd.ssd@acf-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valentina Ferrante</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DCD Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211(0) 914 733 901</telephone>
   <email>dcd-programme.ssd@acf-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.53604490 26.79678490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">223226.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">220773.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="10395">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-22">4274.65</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00060849">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-17">215320.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-3586">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">444000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00066107">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-10">228680.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
