<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-22/DDA-3379/RA2/WASH/INGO/22257</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH response for conflict affected communities in Waghimira zone, Amhara region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The northern conflict started in November 2020, and the tension spilled over to Amhara regions as a result, 1.8 million people were displaced and lost their assets. According to the UNOCHA report, on March 31, 2022, in Amhara, the situation along areas bordering Tigray, namely in Wag Hamra, North Wollo, and North Gondar zones, remains volatile. Several locations remain hard to reach for humanitarian operations, including Abergele, Tsagibji kebeles, some parts of Zequala kebeles in Wag Hamra Zone, and large parts of Kobo in North Wollo Zone and Addi Arkay in North Gondar. However, according to April 14, update in Amhara, the situation in the above woredas and zones, remained unpredictable but relatively calm during the reporting period. In addition, according to the DTM report in February 2022, 462,529 IDPs and 1.4 million returnee IDPs are living in the region. The regional government authorities continued with the relocation of IDPs in Kobo and Sekota. In Wag Hamra, more than 4,000 IDPs have been relocated to the Weleh IDP site, out of an estimated 12,000 IDPs in the zone planned for relocation. While regional authorities and a few humanitarian partners are constructing basic facilities at the relocation sites and providing essential assistance including food, there is still a vast need and setting-up proper camp structures mainly emergency shelter, water, sanitation and hygiene, health and nutrition services, and non-food items. . In Waghimira zone shelter is the most pressing need of IDPs there is a large number of homeless, and they sleep in open spaces and rent in the host community, and it is difficult for them to afford the monthly payments
Since the crises occurred in the region, CARE has provided emergency WASH, shelter and NFI assistance for the conflict-affected peoples in South wollo, North wollo, South Gondar, and North Gondar zones. CARE has a longstanding presence in the Amhara region with different programs, to address the huge needs through this project in coordination with ANE local partners plan to respond to the current crises in the Wag Harmar zone through emergency Water supply, hygiene and sanitation activities.
. 
Hence, the objectives of the project are to improve the protection risks by ensuring the conflict-affected people to have adequate and safe drinking water, improved sanitation facility, and equitable access to hygiene promotion and awareness raising events and to strengthen access to appropriate live-saving WASH Non-food Items (NFI) to safeguard the health and protection of the conflict affected population. This project will target 3000 individuals in collection camps in Sekota town.  The major proposed activities are 
1.	Water trucking with water storage tanker installation
2.	Rehabilitation of motorized schemes, 
3.	Provision of WASH NFIs
4.	Latrine construction
5.	Hygiene promotion with volunteers
6.	Fuel support for strategic water supply schemes</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action for  the Needy in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caitlin Goggin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251- 911- 23-01-31</telephone>
   <email>Caitlin.goggin@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Demelash Habtie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911237582</telephone>
   <email>demelash.habtie@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET03">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amhara</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.56495272 38.04353749</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">350000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-22257">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">350000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
