<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25783</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Energy II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consorcio Energetico Punta Cana Macao (CEPM), an existing IFC client, and its wholly-owned subsidiary, Compania Electricidad Bayahibe (CEB), are off-grid, vertically integrated utilities.  They serve resort hotels and their surrounding communities along the eastern and south-eastern shores respectively in the Dominican Republic. The companies have thus far generated all of their electricity requirements from their own generation facilities.  However, in order to meet accelerated growth in peak demand, the companies plan to interconnect to a power plant of their sister company, EGE Haina, to benefit from its more cost-competitive electricity.  EGE Haina is the largest generator in the country, which is majority owned and controlled by the sponsors of CEPM.  The proposed IFC investment, a corporate loan of $20 million to CEPM and CEB, will finance part of the construction of a 129 km transmission line with 100MW capacity, including three sub-stations.  The transmission line will be off-grid and dedicated to transfer electricity from the EGE Haina power plant in San Pedro Macoris through CEB in Bayahibe to CEPM in Punta Cana.  Total project costs are estimated at $35 million.  ELECNOR of Spain will construct the transmission line, while ABB from Switzerland will be responsible for the substations.  The construction period is expected to be 18 months. CEPM has secured approvals for the project from CDEEE, the state-owned electricity utility. The borrowers will purchase electricity from the EGE Haina under a power purchase agreement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed IFC investment will continue fostering the tourism sector, which depends critically on reliable electricity supply. The tourism sector is one of the country&apos;&apos;s largest foreign exchange earners and provides much-needed local employment. Approximately 85% of CEPM&apos;&apos;s electricity sales are to hotel clients in the tourism zones of Punta Cana and Bayahibe. CEPM is delivering reliable power, while the national grid remains unreliable. The only alternative for these hotels is self-generation, which is a significantly costlier alternative.  Furthermore, the availability of reliable electricity supply in CEPMs and CEBs franchise areas has facilitated residential and commercial development in these areas, which were originally exclusively for resort hotel development.    The project will utilize the existing generation capacity of EGE Haina in lieu of the construction of greenfield generation facilities at CEPM and CEB.  From a view point of the electricity sector as a whole, this results in economic savings, as it improves the utilization rate of the sectors existing generation capacity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consorcio Energetico Punta Cana Macao, S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25783" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-06-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-09-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tito Sanjurjo, Gerente General Consorcio Energetico Punta Cana Macao S.A. Av. Abraham Lincoln esq. J. F. Kennedy, Edificio Ambar, 5ta. Planta,  Post Office Box 4052, Santo Domingo Rep&#xFA;blica Dominicana   Telephone: (809) 549-7659   Fax: (809) 549-7757  Environmental documentation will be made available at the following locations:    Consorcio Energ&#xE9;tico Punta Cana-Macao (CEPM).   Av. Abraham Lincoln, Esq. J.F. Kennedy   Edif. Ambar, 6to. Piso   Santo Domingo    Compa&#xF1;&#xED;a de Electricidad de Bayahibe   Carretera Dominicus   Bayahibe    Consorcio Energ&#xE9;tico Punta Cana-Macao (CEPM)   Carretera Arena Gorda   B&#xE1;varo, La Alta Gracia</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="DO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominican Republic</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="DO-Dominican Republic">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overhead power transmission line will be deployed on section at the east part of the island, with a length of 129 km, passing through three provinces: San Pedro de Macor&#xED;s, La Romana and La Altagracia.  It includes the construction and installation of two sections of the overhead power transmission line:  - from San Pedro de Macoris where an EGE Haina 150MW Sultana power plant (a diesel power plant running on HFO) is located to La Romana where CEB is located;  - from La Romana to B&#xE1;varo where CEPM is located. There will be three substations, each at the Sultana power plant in San Pedro de Macor&#xED;s, in La Romana for CEB, and in B&#xE1;varo for CEPM.  The transmission line will cover mostly tourist and rural areas of the eastern shore of the country.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.0000000000 -70.6666720000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DA - Electric Power Transmission</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-06-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-06-28">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-06-28">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consorcio Energetico Punta Cana Macao, S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25783/basic-energy-ii">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
