<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/Shelter-HLP/NGO/19885</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Life-saving Integrated Emergency Shelter/NFI and Housing Land  Property (HLP) assistance to flood-affected communities in Jowhar District of Middle Shabelle  Beletweyne district of Hiran Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project by JF aims by providing lifesaving integrated Emergency shelter/NFI and Housing Land and property to 1450 IDPs HHs/8,700 individuals affected by the recent flood where affected community urgently require shelter/HLP assistance. The affected IDPS are from Bareey, Lebiga, Moiko and Marerey villages in Jowhar district of Middle Shabelle. JF proposed intervention will achieve through the distribution of emergency shelter kits (ESK), NFIs and promoting access and enhance knowledge to HLP rights. The project will intend to distribute 1450 ESK and 1450 NFIs as in-kind support to families displaced from their homes in the district. The targeted 1450 HHs will comprise of 2,300 women, 2,200 men, 2,150 girls and 2,050 boys. The target individuals will be inclusive of Elderly people, and persons living with disabilities. The provision of emergency shelter assistance will ensure that there will be basic site planning at the settlements with feasible and minimum security of tenure in line with the Shelter cluster guidelines and recommendations on response to the recent flooding in the district, the target will mainly focus on those living in makeshifts shelters which exposes them to the risks of privacy and security. In summary the project will target 1450HHs with both Basic NFIs andESKs, each of the selected beneficiary will receive both Esks/NFI together during the project implementation in the project target area. Juba Foundation will make sure that community is mobilized and sensitized on project scope and information as well as the beneficiaries&#x2019; selection process. PCM/PDM exercise will be conducted four to six weeks after the distribution to know more about the future preference of IDP communities. A Complaint Response and Feedback Mechanism (CRFM) will be set up so that anyone with complaints about the beneficiaries&#x2019; selection process or any other issue will be able to complain. A hot-line number will be available for anyone to forward his/her complaints. Secondly, complaints will be channeled through CRFM desk attendants and Juba foundation MampE team on the ground, settlement leaders and community elders. The project will consider the protection mainstreaming of gender and HLP related issues, as well as inclusion of people with disability matter in both the response and it&#x2019;s monitoring to ensure safety and dignity of target beneficiaries

1.	Procured NFIs will be distributed to the registered beneficiaries {HH} of 1450 comprising of 2,300 women,2,200 men 2,150 girls and 2,050 boys.
2.	Shelter Kits will be distributed among the same targeted beneficiaries
3      Undertake Eviction Risk assessment, monitor eviction threats through assessment, capacity  development, dispute resolution and cash assistance to 750 HLP beneficiaries

JF will ensure inclusivity and transparency in targeting amp will employ a participatory approach when identifying and selecting beneficiaries. The key focus will be on HHs with the most vulnerable and marginalized groups of people including those with disabilities, children headed HHs, HHs with orphans, and HHs with elderly people and young children under the age of 5 years. This approach will ensure that the interests of those people are captured and to be tailored for.  With the aim of promoting ownership of the project and adherence to commitment number 3 of the Core Humanitarian Standards, the project will employ an owner-driven approach where the response will strengthen local capacities on putting up the shelter structures. COVID-19 SOPs will be strictly followed to minimize the risk of the spread. This will also promote adherence to the do no harm policy 
JF will work closely with AYUUB for shelter, SOYDA for GBV/GP, LRDDO for GP and CESDO. This project shall be implemented in Baarey, Lebiga,Marerey, Moiko, Tawakal IDPs and Jiliyaye IDPs in Jowhar and in Beletweyne</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juba Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juba Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abukar Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 615 571454 / +254710298101</telephone>
   <email>jubafoundation@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="88.8" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="11.2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">467628.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">463763.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19885">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">931392.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juba Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305214276">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-04">558835.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juba Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305440780">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-23">372556.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juba Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
