<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/FSC/NGO/19829</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing Agro inputs and Restore Livelihood for Drought affected agro-pastoral Communities in Rural Bardhere, Gedo Region of Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADA is planning to support the most vulnerable communities in Bardhere district, Gedo region of Somalia, through supporting the community with agricultural inputs including (legume seeds, cereal seeds, assorted vegetable seeds, basic farming tools). The project will primarily target agro-pastoralist, IDPs, pastoral drop outs and urban poor living in and around the IDP camps and in rural villages closer to Bardhere district. A total of 3,600 households will be supported in the life cycle of the project in rural Bardhere district, Gedo region of Somalia.

The overall objective is to provide agriculture-inputs and restore livelihoods for 12,144 women, 4,470 men, 2,976 girls and 2,010 boys affected by drought and protracted humanitarian crisis in Bardhere district of Gedo region in Somalia. The action will directly provide farm inputs for the rural agro-pastoralist communities to restore livelihood system.The project will target the following villages Mardha, Shimbirole east, Af yar, Buulo cadey, Sarinley, Buulo Asharaaf, Buulo Garas, Buulo Kurman, Bulo amin, Bulo Goof, in Bardhere district, Gedo region of Somalia

The strategic objective of this project: 

1. To protect and restore livelihoods related to food and income sources. Priority activities include provision of the following inputs, services and related trainings: (i) seasonally appropriate agricultural inputs (e.g. quality seed, farm tools, training, land.

ADA will ensure that the project is implemented through engagement with all relevant stakeholders, ADA has planned activities such as Beneficiary selection, vulnerable Households with preference women headed Households will be selected and enrolled for the farm inputs activity. At least 70% would be women, girls and disabled persons.

Procurement of seeds and distribution - the agro-pastoralist will be given 12 kgs sorghum seeds, 10 kgs cowpea seeds, assorted vegetables seeds 240 grams and basic farming tools such as hoe and forked hoe with a total value of $112.4, a total of 3,600 farmers will benefit from farm inputs activity where at least 70% will be women and girls. ADA will procure the seeds from certified supplies and ensure that a germination test is carried out before distribution to beneficiaries. Seed quality will be done according to agriculture and livelihoods minimum guidelines. ADA will carry out the distribution process and carry out according to the seasonal calendar which will be on October 2021, additionally this activity will be aligned with FSNAU guidelines on seed distributions, and thus October 2021 the agro-pastoralist are expected to embark on land preparations and planting. The prices of the farm inputs was guided by rapid market price assessment linking consultations with local community in Bardhere district on the understanding of current market prices which are the norms(See attached detailed budget breakdown). ADA will provide adequate training for 360 farmers on good agronomic practices including conservation agriculture on October, November and December 2021, thus reaching 10% of the target farmers, which means that on average each village 36 agro pastoralist will be provided with the training. 

Lastly, ADA will conduct post distribution monitoring survey to assess the effectiveness of the distribution process, to verify the number of beneficiaries who received their food distribution entitlements through the support of ADA&apos;s Monitoring, Evaluation, Accountability and Learning Unit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Ali Mohamed Durow</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722458120</telephone>
   <email>activedev1_gedo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-08">397872.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-08">101934.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19829">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-08">499806.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305190458">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-20">299883.75</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305440777">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-23">199922.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
