<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/WASH/INGO/19794</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased access to safe water, sanitation facilities and improved hygiene practices for drought affected populations in Baidoa District in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inadequate and poor access to water sanitation and hygiene services continue to remain among the biggest threats to lives of the internally displaced persons (IDPs) who are streaming into Baidoa district due to extended drought and conflict. The host communities also face the spill overs of problems facing the IDPs due to strained capacities of existing  WASH resource occasioned by high influx of IDPS. Through this action, Action Against Hunger envisions to increase sustainable access to safe water, sanitation facilities and improved hygiene practices among 17,000(4,715 men, 5,057 women, 3,782 girls and 3,446 boys)   drought affected IDP populations living in Horseed and Berdale IDP clusters in Baidoa District, Somalia Action Against Hunger will undertake rehabilitation of  one (1) borehole to improve access to clean water for 5,000 (1387 men, 1487women, 1,013boys and 1,113girls) individuals as per WASH cluster standards . In addition, four water kiosk will be constructed and linked to borehole through an extension pipeline to serve IDPs. Moreover, ACF will rehabilitate three non-functional shallow wells by installing apron, hand pumps  and upgrading to solar powered system to increase water access among 7500(2,080 men, 2,231 women, 1,521 boys and 1,668 girls) individuals. The program will also improve access to safe sanitation facilities through construction of 150  culturally appropriate, disability friendly and gender segregated latrines targeting 4,500(1,248 men, 1,339 women, 912 boys and 1,001 girls)   in both Horseed and Berdale IDP clusters. To enhance safe sanitation practices, the project will engage 24 (10 male and 14 female) community hygiene promoters (CHP)  to conduct hygiene promotion campaigns focusing on hand washing with soap and distribute 3500 hygiene kits (2,500 from WASH cluster and 1,000 through vouchers), including female sanitary materials for personal hygiene and to newly displaced vulnerable HHs to promote women and adolescent girls&#x2019; dignity. Additional kits will be sourced from WASH cluster on need basis to bolster practice of sound hygiene practices. To ensure sustainability of the water access and continued uptake of handwashing practices to promote hygiene practices, Action Against Hunger will conduct capacity building to the selected 24 CHPs and training 46 (19 male and 27 female) water management committees members on operation and  maintenance of the established water kiosks. The project will adopt a market-based programme (MBP) approach to deliver essential WASH goods and services by utilizing the functional market in Baidoa district which also act as the business hub for South West State (SWS) to provide relief and basic services through purchase of goods in the local market, source of local contractors and supporting demand through vouchers. The MPB approach will therefore ensure appropriateness and dignity by allowing targeted affected populations to purchase according to their needs and preferences and improve efficiency of programme delivery by using existing supply chains can be cost-effective, reduce duplication and provide supplies quicker through market actors who are already present.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Khalif</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252613181122</telephone>
   <email>cd@so-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Haji</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615439203</telephone>
   <email>pd@so-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">276141.25</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">273859.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19794">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">550000.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305208667">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">330000.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
