<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/Ed/NGO/18101</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to lifesaving education in emergencies for drought and environmental shocks affected girls and boys in Bari Region of Puntland Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed 12-months intervention will be targeting 3,300 school-aged children (1580 girls and 1720 boys) including children with disabilities affected by the drought in the Bari region of Puntland state. The targeted schools are either closed or at the brink of closure due to the impact of the deteriorating drought conditions in the target locations. The proposed intervention aims to provide lifesaving humanitarian assistance to drought-affected school children whereby the proposed project will be targeting to improve access to quality education and increase access to critical WASH inputs for the lifesaving of the affected school children in (10) Ten schools (three in xafuun and Seven in Bosaso )Hanaqad IDP Daryeel Primary School, Gargaar IDP Primary, Bilaal IDP Primary School, Bandarqasim IDP Primary School, often primary, Daryeel IDP Primary School, Yaasiin IDP Primary School, Foocaar Primary School Hadha Primary School, Barmadoobe Primary Schools are among the schools that are most affected by Drought and Cyclone Gati in Bosaso and Xaafun districts bari region of Puntland State of Somalia.
These Programme specific activities will include the provision of educational supplies and equipment including school furniture&#x2019;s for refurbished and constructed classrooms based on the minimum standards of education cluster School feeding program for Most vulnerable pupils to meet student&#x2019;s minimum caloric needs emergency teacher incentives to motivate teachers rehabilitations of learning spaces that are affected by the cyclone, sanitary kits for adolescent girls to encourage their regular attendance at school and establishment of school WASH facilities, etc... 
Specific WASH activities in schools will include increasing schools&#x2019; water storage capacity through the provision and installation of PVC water storage tanks, Water tracking for affected schools rehabilitation of latrines, and construction of Child- and gender-friendly latrines in the affected schools, Provision of Aqua tabs, where necessary, rehabilitated to minimize disruptions in learning for girls and boys. To ensure water availability in targeted schools, a joint assessment along with Community Education Committees (CEC) will be conducted in schools to find a sustainable solution for water availability but currently, PMWDO will conduct a water trucking for 3 months for 3,300(1720 boys and 1580 girls) school children in IDP and affected schools.
The proposed project will be complemented with other ongoing PMWDO education interventions in the region, as well as other wider emergency responses. PMWDO is currently implementing a UNICEF-funded &#x201C;Educating girls with disabilities&#x201D; in the Puntland State of Somalia but not in the target location for this project. This proposed project will not only complement but also retain children in the affected target locations to have access to continued learning otherwise children would have displaced to where there is an ongoing intervention which could create a burden on the ongoing response. The proposed response is therefore meant to link up to reach to school being supported under this program to enable the children to continue access education support. The project will also extend to cover other schools where high EIE needs have been established but are not covered by PMWDO or any other organization. PMWDO will rehabilitate classrooms and other affected infrastructure like Latrines. The project also envisages addressing the immediate needs of the students through the distribution of scholastic materials/TLM including learning kits, curriculum books, and recreational materials. The project will guarantee gender mainstreaming, and equity as 1200 girls will be supported with dignity kits and sanitary pads. Using the reflective circles&apos; approach PMWDO will train 32 teachers (18 males and 14 female) teachers and the students on Education in Emergency contents and life skills development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Abdirizack Hashi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907795961</telephone>
   <email>ahmed.hashi@pmwdo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Maymum Farah Samatar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907795960</telephone>
   <email>pmwd2000@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9663">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bari</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.64800000 50.23200000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">271711.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">108684.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18101">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">380395.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305023302">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-19">152158.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305154771">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-24">114118.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305289924">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">114118.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
