<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/FSC/INGO/19788</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Agricultural Inputs to Drought-affected Vulnerable Households to Improve Immediate Access to Food in Garbaharey in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed intervention will provide an emergency response to address acute food insecurity and alleviate humanitarian needs. Specifically, the project will provide life-saving support to 3,500 vulnerable, food-insecure and drought-affected households, reaching a total of 21,000 individuals. Out of the total 2,134 are women, 1,366 are men, 7125 are boys and 10375 girls 

ACTED will provide assistance to 3,500 agro-pastoralist households with distribution of agricultural inputs for the upcoming Deyr season in Garbaharey District, including Towfiq, Kaboy, Hashi werar, Shabel, Busul, Horset, Halgan, Warsan, and Doofarey villages 
In regard to the timeline, mindful of the emergency nature of this project, ACTED plans to distribute the agricultural inputs as quickly as possible, beginning with the beneficiary registration and verification exercise in August. ACTED intends to provide agricultural inputs kits before the Deyr rainy season which is between October to December to increase food production/enhance their food security, nutrition and income generation potential. in addition to this, ACTED also plans to conduct Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) two weeks after the distribution of agricultural inputs with the aim to assess beneficiary perceptions on selection criteria, overall satisfaction of the beneficiaries with the quality and quantity of agricultural inputs received, the efficiency of the distribution process and beneficiaries&#x2019; awareness and use of the Complaints Response Mechanism.
ACTED will capitalize upon its area-based approach and graduation model which forms the basis of ACTED&#x2019;s programming. The approach layers, sequences and integrates interventions for a specific geographical scope, and includes participation of the community and a multi-sectoral response. Therefore, whilst delivering short-term agricultural input assistance to help drought affected people address their basic needs through this proposed intervention, ACTED also intends to link this project with longer-term interventions such as an upcoming World Bank-funded ACTED-led project. The mentioned project will target Garbaharey and include assistance such as cash-for-work, basic health and nutrition services, household hygiene promotion and treatment and restoring and protecting agricultural crop production, thus allowing ACTED to continue to address persistent needs of targeted groups. 

Overall, the proposed activities therefore clearly align with the Food Security cluster objectives as below: 
1) to protect and restore livelihoods related to food and income sources. 

Moreover, the project aligns with the Somalia HRP 2021 objective to provide life-saving and life-sustaining integrated assistance to reduce acute humanitarian needs and excess mortality among the most vulnerable people. 

Finally, the project will adopt an Integrated Protection Approach (IPA), with a specific focus on the most vulnerable groups, including women, girls, boys, the disabled and the elderly. Gender principles will be mainstreamed throughout the entire action, as will Accountability to Affected Populations (AAP) by giving account to, taking account of and being held to account by affected populations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adam Klink</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 636 291 172</telephone>
   <email>adam.klink@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">453947.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">46052.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19788">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-17">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
