<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/FSC/NGO/18115</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food availability and accessibility among rural households in Cabudwak and Taleex districts of Galgaduud and Sool region of Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is in response to Somalia Humanitarian Fund 2021 standard allocation for drought affected regions in Somalia. The project will aim at providing an immediate lifesaving intervention to drought affected population in Abudwak and Taleex district of Galgadud and Sool regions of Somalia, where food security situation is very critical. HOD will provide immediate lifesaving to drought affected population targeting 700 households (4,200) persons, (500 men, 934 women, 1332 boys, 1434 girls) in Galgaduud and Sool region through conditional cash transfer for three consecutive months and distribution of Sudanese grass seeds as an alternative livestock feed to be planted and grown by 400 household who also beneficiaries of CFW activities in Abudwak district. The project will ensure inclusion of disability by targeting 114 people living with disability including (12 men, 62 women, 19 boys and 21 girls). The intervention will result improved food availability and accessibility among the most vulnerable households in IPC 3 and 4 in Abudwak and Taleex district of Somalia in the short term and in the medium and the long term will result reduced negative coping mechanism of the targeted beneficiaries. The intervention will employ community based targeting where local community leadership will have more role and say on who will be targeted and benefit from the project. The 700 households (4,200) will benefit from rehabilitated water catchments which is a productive livelihood asset for the rural community as it enhances access to water for their livestock. They will also benefit from distribution of   Sudanese grass seeds which is drought resistant grass which  will be grown by same CFW beneficiaries in Abudwak to be used as alternative livestock feed during the dry period. Women dependent households will be given priority and other marginalized segments of the target communities. Protocols of observing the community culture, privacy and dignity will be observed   in close collaboration with the local community leadership and other stakeholders. COVID 19 protocols of social distancing, hand washing and wearing of face mask will be promoted and observed throughout the project. Through this project, five (5) water catchments and 3 contour bunds will be rehabilitated for a period 68 working days. Daily wage will be 4 dollars per day. Beneficiaries will be paid every 24 working days through mobile money by credible mobile money agency acquired in competitive procurement process. The transfer value will cover 74% of CMB as the cash working group guidelines recommendations in Galgadud, while in Sool it will be 77%. 190,400 USD will transferred to 700 beneficiaries in Abudwak and Taleex. 2000kg of Sudanese grass will be distributed to CFW beneficiaries in Abudwak only.  Taleex beneficiaries will only benefit CFW activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himilo Organization for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himilo Organization for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdi Omar Diriye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executie Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254-702574247/252617690383</telephone>
   <email>info@hodsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">299999.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18115">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">299999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himilo Organization for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305023298">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-19">239999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Himilo Organization for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
