<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/Nut/NGO/19798</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of equitable access to quality lifesaving curative nutrition service among boys and girls (06-59) months  PLW through systematic identification, referral and treatment of acutely malnourished cases.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to FSNAU-Quarterly-Brief-May-2021, In Somalia, high levels of acute malnutrition tend to persist across most population groups due to several factors, including high morbidity, low immunization and Vitamin-A supplementation, poor care practices and widespread acute food insecurity.
The prevalence of acute malnutrition is also likely to rise, driven by reduced food and milk intake and seasonal and long-term factors. Based on nutrition experts&#x2019; analysis of current GAM prevalence and historical trends, GAM is expected to increase from Serious (10-14.9 percent GAM WHZ) to Critical (15-29.9 percent GAM WHZ) in rural livelihood zones in Bay region. In agropastoral livelihood zones, Crisis (IPC Phase 3) outcomes are expected in Bay.
According to FSNAU February 2021 projects, Malnutrition burden in Baidoa district is at 9,663 for SAM and 39,910 MAM caseload. 
DMO purposes of focusing on a massive MUAC screening for malnutrition specially MAM and SAM will be conducted and all OTP sites will refer severe cases to BRH Hospital SC. In this proposed intervention DMO will carry out both curative and preventative interventions targeting children U5 years (boys and girls) and pregnant and lactating women. 
1.	DMO will work in Identification, referral, and treatment of children suffering from severe acute malnutrition through the community, facility-based approaches, and OTP Mobile teams. Complicated cases of SAM will be referred to SC and MAM to TSFP centres. Mother-led MUAC approach will be used to identifying and diagnosing malnutrition by mothers. Mothers will use MUAC tapes to measure the Mid-Upper Arm Circumference (MUAC). Mother led MUAC training will be conducted to support mother&#x2019;s to screen, detect oedema and self-referral of their children to nutrition sites. Technical local capacity will be strengthened for the integration of IMAM into the Primary Health Care system through the functional MCH facilities. Additionally, the ability of nutrition staff will be maintained for effective service delivery at facility and community level. In coordination with the Child Protection section, survivors of gender-based violence (GBV) identified at the nutrition sites and catchment areas, will be referred.
2.	OTP/TSFP - DMO plans to integrate the management of acutely malnourished at OTP centre U5 children (4,350 Boys, 5,313 Girls), TSFP (4136 Boys, 5,479 Girls, 3970 PLWs) with the ongoing routine health services at all levels to reduce the alarming malnutrition rate among under-five children and pregnant and lactating women within the target populations. DMO aims to provide OTP/TSFP services with a clear referral pathway between TSFP and OTP services to ensure continuity in care and management to avoid further deterioration of the situation. 
3.	Deworming for children 12-59 months and pregnant women in the 2nd and 3rd trimester, counselling, and promotion on infant and young child feeding. Community mobilization and screening as well as micronutrient supplementation for PLW (multiple micronutrients and Iron folate) and children 6-59 months with Vitamin A supplements.  
4.	Provision of routine immunization services to children and pregnant women in these project sites&#x2019; catchment area, through its both fixed and mobile OTP. 
5.	The community approach will be overlaid with essential service provision of crucial nutrition basic services for prevention, promotion and referral.
Engagement of CHWs (4 female and 4 male) as change agents during IYCF Promotion, nutrition screening, Health and nutrition education on groups (Mother-led groups, father-mother led groups) coupled with other aspects of nutrition sensitive interventions will go a long way in mitigating malnutrition within the affected communities in Baidoa district outskirt villages (Bulo Jaay, Geldhere, Aragaduud, Hagarka madegere IDP, Abal 5 IDP, Hoobishoole IDP, Abow casharow IDP and the New IDPs relocation site &#x2013; Barwaqo 1).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deeg-Roor Medical Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deeg-Roor Medical Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirahim Moalim Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615529065</telephone>
   <email>abdirahim.moalim@dmosomalia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Nur Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program assistance</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+25261-5599852</telephone>
   <email>alinur.mohamed@dmosomalia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">79648.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">159954.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19798">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">239602.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deeg-Roor Medical Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305224500">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-11">143761.78</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deeg-Roor Medical Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305561382">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-11">95841.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deeg-Roor Medical Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
