<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/FSC/NGO/19792</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restoration of livelihoods related to food and income sources to the affected communities in Belet Weyne district of Hiran region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to OCHA report March 2021, during the first quarter of 2021, most parts of Somalia experienced moderate to severe drought as a result of below-average Deyr (October to December 2020) seasonal rainfall, a warmer than normal dry Jilaal season (January to March), and a delayed and poor start to the 2021 Gu (March to June) and a delayed and poor start to the 2021 Gu (March to June) season rainfall coupled by the impact of the desert locust infestation, the poor Deyr rains and the delayed, poor start of the Gu season has worsened the food security situation. The number of people across Somalia who are expected to face a crisis or worse (IPC Phase 3 or higher) and are in urgent need of humanitarian assistance increased from the previous estimate of 2.65 million between April and June 2021 to 2.73 million. Further increases to 2.83 million are projected for July-September 2021. By mid-May heavy rains hit various parts of Somalia including Belet Weyne district of Hiran region, triggering riverine and flash flooding affecting 166,000 people. Armed conflict between local clan militias, which took place in Belet Weyne district in May resulted in the displacement of civilians, 25 injuries, and 15 deaths. Houses were burnt and farms destroyed. According to the local authority, about 5,432 households were displaced with total persons of 32,592 and integrated into their relatives in Belet Weyne town and other safe villages in Belet Weyne district. Despite the fighting, the situation exasperated when floods hit the areas where the fighting occurred, and the displaced people were affected by a subsequent displacement. Almost every year during the rainy season, Belet Weyne district faces severe floods, which roads across the villages along the Shabelle river are damaged or become impassible adding challenges to the humanitarian community to reach people. The affected households rely on food purchases from local markets, have weak purchasing power due to limited income, and lack access to credit services due to cumulative debts. To restore the livelihood of the affected populations to enable them immediately access food, water, healthcare, education expenses, and other basic services. 2,321 farmers&apos; households from (Quracley, Shabellow, Dharkeynley, Beled Salaama, Jeerey, Leebow, Gambarlaawe, Jiiqley) representing 13,926 men, women, boys, and girls including people with disabilities and minorities will be provided agricultural input. This activity aims at restoring the livelihoods of the affected households and envisages reducing workload and stress on women and girls. In addition, gender-based violence and exploitation malpractices associated with in search of other alternative livelihoods (e.g., charcoal production) for long distances will be mitigated through the proposed activity.  AADSOM will support the affected farmers with the following:
I. Community mobilization and sensitization: At the inception of the project, 
AADSOM will undertake meetings with the community stakeholders inclusive of women, people with disabilities, IDPs aimed to hear their voices and give a good picture about the project deliverables and criteria for the selection of the beneficiaries. AADSOM will inform the community of the intended project objectives and inputs, share, and revise the inclusion criteria to the community. register the selected beneficiaries.

II. Support 2,321 affected farmers with agricultural inputs: Each farmer will receive:
1) Cereal seeds (20 kgs maize)
2) Legume seeds (10 kgs cowpeas)
3) Assorted vegetables seeds (240 grams)
4) Irrigation support (3 hours)
5) Basic farming tools (1 hoe, 1 fork, and 1 shovel)
III. To keep the sustainability of the project outputs and increase the production of the beneficiaries, AADSOM will train selected 200 lead farmers from the target farmers shared equally men and women (25 farmers per village) on the best technologies and methodologies to increase their livelihoods production.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulet Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>254722800129/252616487065</telephone>
   <email>gulet@aadsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">398026.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">101973.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19792">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305187344">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-16">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305354286">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-30">100000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
