<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/H/INGO/19828</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DHUSA MAREEB EMERGENCY HEALTH SERVICES (DHEHS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE  will implement an emergency health services project directly, working in with the Ministry of Health, Galmudug targeting THREE Health Centres and ONE  Mobile unit in drought and conflicted affected Villages of Dhusa mareeb District. The proposed  intervention will provide services to 17,550 women, 18,450 Men, 4,410 Girls and 4,590 Boys, from Dhusa mareeb  District.These will include approximately 4,500 IDPs, 40,500 Host community members, of which 2,250 will be individuals with different forms of disability. A total of 45,000 individuals will benefit from the proposed action. The Emergency Health interventions will  aim to provide primary and essential lifesaving services in Gadon HC, Ceeldheer HC, Dayah and 7 mobile sites.  
The health interventions  will be aligned to the Health cluster objectives of increasing access to essential primary health care services for the vulnerable drought affected population  as well as reducing excess morbidity and mortality for affected population including persons with disabilities and survivors of GBV/intimate partner violence, through patient-centered  approaches. CARE emergency health services will closely be aligned with other partners and Ministry of Health for referral of complicated deliveries, medical cases requiring specialized services and for linkages and coordination. CARE will provide  outpatient consultations for common illnesses which will include diarrhea, acute respiratory infections, influenza, malaria, measles, and pneumonia. Nurse clinicians  will use the Somalia treatment guidelines and the integrated management of childhood illness (IMCI) guidelines (translated into the Somali language) to diagnose and treat patients. CARE will provide outreach services to 7 hard to reach villages with comprehensive primary health including consultations, immunization , sexual reproductive health services, SGBV and health education.
 CARE-supported health facilities will provide Antenatal care, Post natal care and  free BEmONC services. Pregnant women requiring comprehensive emergency obstetric and newborn care will be referred to  Dhusa mareeb hospital providing CEMONC services (including cesarean sections and blood transfusions) to ensure access to timely life-saving services for mothers and neonatal babies. 
Community engagement to create awareness and behavior change will be key in the project. CHW-led dialogue-based awareness sessions will complement service provision. SGBV (Sexual and Gender-based violence) survivors will be offered confidential CMR (clinical management of rape) services in line with WHO and MOH guidelines. In light of the COVID-19 pandemic, CARE health staff will use standard IPC as outlined by WHO. In all health centers and mobile clinics , health workers will be encouraged to exercise a high level of clinical suspicion. Equipped triage stations will be positioned at the entrance to each facility and  manned by trained clinical staff (wearing personal protective equipment, PPE), and screened according to updated COVID-19 case definitions. Staff will be placed at the entrance to manage the crowd and enforce social distancing.
CARE will procure essential medicine and medical equipment for the static health centers and mobile units. All the medical supplies which will be aligned to  Somalia&#x2019;s Essential Medicines list and purchased with while adhering to UN OCHA and CARE procurement standards to ensure quality is not compromised.  CARE will train all Health workers on diseases surveillance and health information management for submission of weekly communicable disease surveillance reports to MOH/WHO.  The CHWs, and community health  committees will also be trained on disease outbreak reporting using the Early Warning and Response Network (EWARN).  CARE will coordinate with other Partners including SAVE the Children, Mercy USA and local Organizations to provide harmonized delivery of essential health, nutrition and protection services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABDI NUR ELMI</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMERGENCY DIRECTOR</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906794487</telephone>
   <email>Elmi.Nur@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABDULKADIR AHMED</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HEALTH SPECIALIST</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634619001</telephone>
   <email>abdulkadir.ore@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">123917.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">279581.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19828">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">403498.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305208669">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">242099.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
