<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/WASH/INGO/19806</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to WASH services for drought affected and displaced populations in Garbaharey</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trocaire has been present in Gedo region of Somalia since 1992, and has been providing integrated health, nutrition, protection and WASH services in five districts including Garbaharey district. This proposed intervention is designed to provide access to improved WASH services for 18,000 drought-affected IDPs and host communities in Garbaharey District. These will include approximately 4,020 IDPs, 13,980 host community members. Among these target populations, 2,700 individuals have different forms of disability. 
The project will complement health services provided by Trocaire in Garbaharey. Furthermore, Trocaire has also requested for SHF funding for health interventions in Garbaharey to enhance the complementarity of services through relations between the health outreach and WASH teams, working closely to reduce morbidity and mortality rates, as well as reducing cases of malnutrition. Preventive approaches will be utilized through 11 hygiene promotion sessions with community-based hygiene promoters. Hand-washing practices will be promoted through the distribution of 3,000 hygiene kits through restricted cash vouchers in collaboration with the local vendors. According to a detailed site assessment by REACH in March 2021 (Annex A), about 100 percent of the population in Garbaharey use unsafe water from unprotected shallow wells. The town has been grappling with challenges with high salinity levels of groundwater, making it unfit for human consumption. Many of the few shallow wells in the town are also unprotected from the elements, making them vulnerable to microbiological and other contamination. Trocaire has recently rehabilitated two of these shallow wells with funding from Irish Aid. Within this project, Trocaire will seek to construct five new protected, flood-resistant shallow wells which will be equipped with hand pumps. Water treatment will be encouraged at the household level to encourage uptake of safe and clean water. One representative Water-User Management Committees (WMCs) will be set up to manage the shallow wells which will be constructed. 100 universal design emergency latrines will also be constructed and hand-washing facilities with soap installed. The project will give a specific focus to the participation of women, girls and persons with disabilities and will in this regard, conduct a disability mapping. The 2021 Somalia Humanitarian Needs Overview notes that issues related to access to WASH facilities for vulnerable groups including persons
with disabilities and elderly persons are an ongoing challenge that requires the availability of reliable data, extensive consultations and community engagement on planning and design while considering the unique needs of each group. This disability mapping will, therefore, enhance the involvement of persons with disabilities in the planning, designing and implementation of project activities, ultimately, improving their access to services. Trocaire will work closely with the government Regional and District Water Officers, the Garbaharey District Health Board, the Local Authority, other implementing partners and with coordination through the WASH cluster. Coordination will be prioritized as it remains a key assumption of the project for effective and efficient delivery of lifesaving WASH assistance to vulnerable populations in Garbaharey.
Trocaire is discussing with other partners to ensure that once this project is operational there will be opportunities to continue implementing necessary services, and working closely with the local, regional and national stakeholders to ensure that they are well equipped to continue provision of these services when time is right for Trocaire to exit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSOM21-WSH-171628-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdi Tari Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director: Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 722 590 255 +254 729 404 490</telephone>
   <email>abdi.tari@trocaire.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdiwahit Ahmed Jama</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722761046/ +252618392092</telephone>
   <email>abdiwahit.jama@trocaire.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSOM21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">142939.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">287060.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19806">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-14">430000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305192734">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-20">344000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tr&#xF3;caire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
