<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/FSC/NGO/18244</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support immediate access to food while restoring livelihoods related to food and income sources to the affected communities in Belet Weyne district of Hiran region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall project objective of the project is to improve immediate access to food to drought-affected men, women, and children with inclusive to people with disabilities, IDPs, and marginalized communities in the Belet Weyne district of Hiran region, while restoring their livelihoods related to food and income sources that have been impacted by water shortages. The objectives of this project are threefold:
i) to meet the food consumption gap of the most vulnerable men, women, and children affected by droughts (i.e., short-term access to food), 
ii) to build and rehabilitate community assets that reduce the risk of disaster, strengthen livelihoods and build resilience over time, and
iii) to restore livelihoods related to food and income sources that have been impacted by droughts and floods, through the distribution of fodder seeds, in order to save the lives of the animals in the project locations and boost the income of the vulnerable people during the dry seasons.
To reach those objectives, AADSOM will carry out the following activities: 
1. At the inception of the project, AADSOM will undertake meetings with the community stakeholders inclusive of women, people with disabilities, IDPs aimed to hear their voices. AADSOM will inform the community of the intended project objectives and inputs, share and revise the inclusion criteria to the community. register the selected beneficiaries.
2. AADSOM with the support of the community, will rehabilitate 4 irrigation canals in 4 villages of Belet Weyne district namely Beled Salaama, Dharkeynley, Leebow, Jeerey, through conditional cash transfer. 340 food-insecure households representing 2,040 vulnerable people (306 men, 510 women, 612 boys, and 612 girls) will participate in the rehabilitation works (men and women will equally share the rehabilitation works) for a period of two months. During the rehabilitation of the canals, AADSOM will distribute hand tools for the rehabilitation works. Each village will be distributed 20 sets of hand tools, and when the rehabilitation activities completed, AADSOM will hand over the tools to the village committees for future rehabilitation of the canals and any other productive assets required for the future. AADSOM will provide USD80/month per household (Minimum Expenditure Basket in Hiran Region - FSNAU - February 2021) for a period of two months to the selected beneficiaries who participated in the rehabilitation works through mobile transfer.
3. AADSOM will provide fodder seeds (e.g., Sudan grass) to 1000 farmers, representing 6,000 vulnerable men, women, and children inclusive disabled, IDPs and minorities. Each farmer will receive 5kg of quality-controlled Sudan seeds, and is expected each farmer to harvest 6-8 tons for a period of 2 and half months. Sudanese Grass production as an alternative and sustainable source of pasture/fodder for livestock. 
4. To keep the sustainability of the project outputs and increase the production of the beneficiaries, AADSOM will train selected 100 lead farmers from the target farmers (25 farmers per village) on the best technologies and methodologies to increase their livelihoods production.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulet Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>254722800129</telephone>
   <email>info@aadsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18244">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305008025">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-05">160000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
