<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/CCCM/NGO/18215</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve the living conditions of 36,000 displaced people in Banadir through improved site management and coordination, enhanced service delivery and site upkeep and
decongestion initiatives.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to enhance the living conditions and access to service for estimated 36,000 IDP persons from 40 settlements in Kahda and Daynile districts of Benadir. This will be achieved through a number of interrelated and complementary activities including enhancing the capacity of camp governance structures and site-level committees to promote information-sharing and foster system-wide coordination among service providers. Key program activities also include organizing site-level coordination meetings among service providers and local authorities to highlight priority needs and challenges, mitigate protection risks and ensure efficient use of existing referral pathways. 10 site-level mobilizers, each serving as a focal point for 4 sites, will be hired from target IDPs to circulate key messages, report on gaps, conduct service mapping, needs and new arrivals, conduct site monitoring and take shelter-level CFM complaints in close coordination with the CCCM cluster and other partners to effectively address vulnerabilities and maximize efficiency of the humanitarian response. 

Site maintenance committees and IDPs in target settlements will be equipped with a range of site maintenance tools and supplies before engaging in cash-for-work schemes through which community-led site upkeep and maintenance activities will be carried out. In the selection of cash-for-work beneficiaries, AVORD will adapt a systematic approach with a clear criterion to prioritize the most vulnerable households including the marginalized, single headed-households, large families and/or families with children under the age of 5, women at risk as identified by protection officers and those with special needs. Data collected to inform beneficiary selection will be segregated by gender to ensure that no group is left-out. List of beneficiaries along with their contact numbers will be availed to SHF and other actors responding in the area to avoid overlap. 

The effectiveness of the aid package will be evaluated through monitoring of activities thus ensuring that beneficiaries access their services safely and in a dignified manner. Protection will be mainstreamed throughout project duration by closely coordinating with other partners operating Sexual and Gender Based Violence (SGBV) crisis centers and facilitating principled referrals where necessary. An elaborate feedback and complaint mechanism will be setup to ensure accountability to the affected population. Target sites will be prioritized based on vulnerability such as congestion levels, proportion of minority groups, potential exposure to protection risks and overall living conditions. AVORD will utilize cluster tools such as the IDP site risk map or DSA data in the process of site selection. A site-level Complaint and Feedback Mechanism (CFM) will be developed and the project team will ensure that the system is accessible for all populations and that the mechanism is clearly understood and supported by the community.

The present proposal will complement an interagency program currently being implemented by AVORD and other partners in Banadir to provide WASH and awareness raising services to reduce Covid 19 transmission. Synergies will be developed with these activities to ensure complementarity, value for money and efficiency of the resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Volunteers for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Volunteers for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdikarim Idow</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+25261) 5515829</telephone>
   <email>director@avord.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">166045.65</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">81661.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18215">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">247707.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Volunteers for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305008026">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-05">148624.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Volunteers for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305309848">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-08">99082.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Volunteers for Relief and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
