<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/WASH/INGO/19784</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Emergency Support to populations in need</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">More than 8.9 million people are affected by poor and deteriorating WASH conditions in Somalia, which have been further exacerbated by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic affecting people&#x2019;s health and livelihoods. The WASH Cluster estimates that 3.3 million people are in severe and extreme need of humanitarian WASH assistance and 1.1 million people are in catastrophic need of assistance. WASH is one of the two main drivers of humanitarian needs across Somalia, which highlight the increasingly central role of WASH relative to food security in driving the severity of humanitarian needs of both IDPs and non-IDPs. Therefore, the IRC proposes a project that aims to provide life-saving and basic WASH services through rehabilitation of three strategic water boreholes with hybrid power systems ( solar and diesel power), distribution systems, construction of water collection points and capacity building of new and existing water community structures. The project will also improve overall hygiene and sanitation of the target communities through the construction of 150 emergency latrines, organizing hygiene promotion campaigns and trainings, and providing essential hygiene items.  The IRC is proposing a 12 months WASH project targeting drought and conflict affected communities in Galgaduud region with a focus on Adado district targeting IDP settlements within Adado town namely Karama, Kulmiye, Hebed, Badbaado, and Daryeel and as well as villages such as Xinjilib, Carmoley, baxda and Docoley under Adado district to provide immediate life-saving WASH services to the most vulnerable members of the community, reaching a total of 15,000 individuals (Men: 3300, Women: 3450, Boys:4050, Girls: 4200)

In terms of centrality and mainstreaming of protection, the project targets to reduce the risk of violence against women, children and vulnerable groups while accessing water and sanitation facilities by providing gender segregated facilities and establishing the facilities within 500 meters&#x2019; distance of the settlements. The project will also address gender issues by collecting gender and age disaggregated data. IRC will analyze this data to identify gaps, provide gender sensitive interventions and ensure participation and empowerment of women. IRC will ensure protection during access and utilization of services, to reduce the risk further. The project beneficiaries will be selected through a community consultative process with the community leaders and local authorities in order to ensure that only those who meet the specified vulnerability criteria including women and girls, people living with disability, people from minority clans, female headed households, child-headed households, survivors of sexual and gender base violence, and households with a high number of dependents (children, elderly, people with disabilities, pregnant and lactating mothers will be given high priority. IRC will maintain and expand synergies across all the programs by ensuring that this project is implemented alongside the other emergency response programs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdikani Muse</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 (907) 921402</telephone>
   <email>Abdikani.Muse@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cynthia Onyango</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722418564</telephone>
   <email>cynthia.onyango@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">114008.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">228959.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19784">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">342968.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
