<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/Nut/NGO/18191</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated lifesaving Nutrition project aimed at reducing morbidity and mortality related to acute malnutrition among the most vulnerable in Dhobley, Afmadow district,Lower Juba.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FSNAU 2020 post Deyr assessment indicates both GAM and SAM are serious with aggravating factors.  Food security is expected to worsen. The poor October to December 2020 Deyr rains led to the inadequate pasture, water resources and below average crop production. Weather predictions point towards a second consecutive season of below-average rainfall from April to June due to the La Nina effect. 
The key issues for children and women remain access to prevention and treatment interventions in the absence of a fully functional and stable health system. Tied to that is scarce availability of health professionals and poor community literacy levels (UNICEF 2019 OCHA 2020). Malnutrition is one of the key issues affecting children 6-59 moths and significantly contributing to mortality, considering relationship between malnutrition and disease. 
Services in Dhobley barely reach rural areas because of poor infrastructure . Therefore poor performing indicators like: Poor IYCF, low latrine coverage,low immunization coverage, severe food shortages and poor coverage of nutrition service/health facility are reported (WHO,2020SARA ,2016 FSNAU,2021).  Water shortage has already been reported in Dhobley with population displaced due to water shortage. This is expected to get worse if the predicted La Nina manifests next month (OCHA, 2021)
Women and children urgently need integrated services targeting prevention and treatment of both moderate and severe acute malnutrition.  WRRS is currently implementing a nutrition project by WFP that focuses on treatment of moderate acute malnutrition ( MAM) and maternal, child health and nutriton (MCHN) at health facilities . These services have not integrated treatment of  severe acute malnutrition (SAM) therefore children with SAM  are left untreated and so at risk of death. WFP funded project also lacks key primary prevention interventions like Micro nutrient supplementation for children 6-59 months and PLW, de worming and IYCF support. Integrating these services will  contribute to significant reduction in prevalence of malnutrition and related mortality.
The project will apply the grant strategy and help achieve cluster objective 2 of providing life saving interventions especially for those affected by drought like conditions. It focuses on scaling up and fully integrating nutrition interventions that will ensure full treatment of acute malnutrition.The proposed project will link to SHF&apos;s 2021 allocation strategy, the fund&apos;s strategic objectives and cluster specific objectives. We hope this will bring down the effects of the prevailing triple threat of COVID 19, floods and Desert Locusts , in addition to the most recent predicted La Nina, on acute malnutrition state. 
WRRS is currently implementing a nutrition project funded by WFP that covers treatment of Moderate acute malnutrition, MCHN and a relief project. The proposed project will bring in treatment of both complicated and uncomplicated severe acute malnutrition thus ensuring full treatment of acute malnutrition at one stop. Beneficiaries will not be referred to other facilities and/or partners, which sometimes complicates treatment by increasing defaulters. This project will also support primary prevention interventions not covered by WFP project, which are very vital. These will include Infant and young child feeding (IYCF) support and micro nutrient supplication for both children under five and pregnant and lactating women (PLW). This proposed project seeks to scale up and integrate treatment of acute malnutrition through a fixed site in Dhobley,being in a health facility. which will of will offer TSFP for treatment of MAM,OTP for treatment of  uncomplicated SAM and Stabilization center for treatment of complicated SAM, all these with prevention interventions. There will also be 1 mobile team to cover IDP  and hard to reach rural areas with treatment of MAM and uncomplicated SAM integrating  prevention interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wamo Relief and Rehabilitation Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wamo Relief and Rehabilitation Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aden Bundiid</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excecutive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615924990</telephone>
   <email>wrrs_ngo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">133951.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">65877.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18191">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-07">199828.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wamo Relief and Rehabilitation Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305016570">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-14">159862.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wamo Relief and Rehabilitation Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305354285">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-30">39965.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wamo Relief and Rehabilitation Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
