<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/SA1/Prot/NGO/18162</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boys and girls in Beledhawo district of Gedo region including adolescents, children with disabilities, facing life-threatening risks of abuse, neglect, violence, exploitation, and severe distress have access to well-coordinated and disability, gender-sensitive quality and integrated child protection services by 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to build synergy with WASH, CCM, Shelter cluster to ensure comprehensive, multi-sectoral response to the protection needs of children in the district. By establishing community-based interventions through community-based services for child protection, the program will enhance community capacity to respond effectively to child protection concerns. The project will further ensure IDP settlements are assessed for safety standards through safety audits, child safety walks and child led participatory mapping exercises. Activities will be implemented in Beledhawo district particularly in Tula Amin, Malkariyey, Idaan, Jirale, Arabo, Odaa, Gawido, Tulo Jibril and Sheikh Barre villages. The project will reach out to 5590 beneficiaries (322 M 708 F 2650 B 1910 G)

Project Activities will  include:
The project Beneficiaries will include:
1.1.1 800 ( 400 b 400 g) The project will establish community-led IDTR procedures for unaccompanied and separated children from both IDPs and host communities in Baledhawa district. 

1.1.2:  270 ( 170 boys 100 g) Provision of material assistances to separated and unaccompanied children according to their special needs. 

1.2.1: Transport assistance will be provided to reunify 180 unaccompanied children (100 boys 80 girls) with their parents/care givers.

1.2.2: 80 separated and unaccompanied children will be provided with family care (50 b 30 g). 

1.3.1: The project will provide  age, gender and culturally appropriate recreational activities for 3000 children (1800 boys 1200 girls) in child Friendly Space.

1.3.4:  15 facilitators ( 8 male 7 female) who will be given refresher training in child care will run the facility. Kindly include the duration for the training and the location. 

1.4.1: Provide guidance and support to 300 caregivers (50 M 250 F)  to improve care for their children and deal with their own distress, and to link them to supports and services. 

1.4.2: The project will provide 300 caregivers (50 M 250 F) with $50 every month to purchase crafting materials for 3 months through mobile banking Conditional cash transfer.
2.1.1: 100 CP actors [social workers, community volunteers, Government officials, field coordinators] and non-child protection actors in Baledhawa district will be provided with capacity building in women rights, child rights and international human rights standards. 
2.2.1: SEDHURO will identify and train 100 community child protection committees (50 M 50 M) from both in IDP camps and from host communities in Baledhawa district and will be facilitated to form 10 committees  spread across the district including rural and outlying villages. 
2.3.1: 2.3.1: The project will carry out extensive sensitization campaigns in IDP settlements and local villages as well as rural and outlying villages on prevention and response to child rights violations and child protection issues. 
2.4.1: 50 (30 M 20 F) Case workers, social workers, health workers and service providers  will be trained in case management including referrals and CPIMS+.
3.1.1: 50 participants (25 M 25 F)  drawn from field staff from DRC, NOFYL, and HAPEN as well other humanitarian actors in Beledhawo will receive child protection mainstreaming training including child safeguarding and PSEA training to ensure includion, meaningful access, accountability, safety and dignity and avoid doing harm. Each organization will be required to avail two personnel for the training
3.2.2: The project will provide capacity building for the existing 15 member CBCPM in identification and documentation of grave violations against children, which will be fed into MRM database held by DRC and UNICEF. 
3.3.1: The project will organize a five-day training for 50  WASH stakeholders (25 M 25 F) on Child Protection concerns
3.4.2: SEDHURO will train WASH partners and hygiene promoters including local authority hygiene arrangements on prevention, response and referral to CP</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Socio-Economic Development and Human Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Socio-Economic Development and Human Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hared Ibrahim Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615442225</telephone>
   <email>h.osman@sedhuro.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Yussuf Jama</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615568361</telephone>
   <email>m.jama@sedhuro.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">234512.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">115334.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-18162">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-11">349847.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Socio-Economic Development and Human Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305025150">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-20">209908.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Socio-Economic Development and Human Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305309857">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-08">139938.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Socio-Economic Development and Human Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
