<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA2/WASH/NGO/19772</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase the accessibility of lifesaving safe WASH services to the flood and drought-affected host communities and displaced IDPs in the Belet Weyne district of Hiran region, Hirshabelle State of Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to OCHA 2021 report, climate change continues to be a major contributing factor to displacement and food insecurity in Somalia. Increasing erratic weather patterns and climatic shocks have led to prolonged and severe drought conditions and floods, with devastating humanitarian consequences. Flooding displaced 919,000 people in 2020 and destroyed WASH infrastructures and productive assets. In tandem. Communities living in conflict areas were severely impacted by armed violence. The ongoing conflict continues to reduce the resilience of communities, trigger displacement and impede civilians&#x2019; access to basic services and humanitarians&#x2019; access to those in need. Exclusion and discrimination of socially marginalized groups are contributing to high levels of acute humanitarian need and lack of protection among some of the most vulnerable. IDPs remain the most vulnerable population group in Somalia. The protracted nature of displacement caused by floods, conflict, and drought continues to affect the physical and mental wellbeing of 1.6 million IDPs who require humanitarian assistance. Many IDP households have faced a steady depletion of assets and an increase in negative coping mechanisms, culminating in severe conditions with regards to their food insecurity, malnutrition, disease outbreaks, water and hygiene conditions, and critical protection concerns. According to the FSNAU report March 2021, large parts of Somalia faced severe drought conditions, triggered by below average 2020 Deyr rains and above-average temperatures during the Jilal season. Over 116,000 Somalis were displaced by water shortages between October 2020 and March 2021. Availability of water and pasture conditions have significantly deteriorated, leading to increased livestock migration and the rapid rise of water prices. According to the latest UNICEF humanitarian situation report, the water shortages and challenges of getting safe drinking water have contributed to cases of acute watery diarrhea (AWD) /cholera cases in some areas across the country. At the beginning of the rainy season in mid-April 2021, heavy rains in the Ethiopia highlands resulted in flood waves along the Shabelle River basin and streamed into Somalia leading to the displacement of the riverine population particularly in the northern parts of Beletweyne town, as well as damage of some community infrastructure and agriculture farms. In this project, AADSOM will implement safe WASH services to the flood and drought-affected communities and displaced IDPs in BeletWeyne district amp 5 villages (Gambarlaawe, Jeerey, Beled Salaama, Quracley, Dhariyow)  through carrying out the following:
1. At the inception, AADSOM will organize community mobilization meetings to the different sectors of the community, local authorities including women, people with disabilities, and minorities to give a good picture of the project deliverables. 
2. Rehabilitating/constructing strategic 30 flood-proof shallow wells with hand pumps with equal access of men, women, children including people with disabilities and marginalized communities.
3. Capacity building training of gender shared 30 WASH committees and 60 well operators (2/water source) from the rehabilitated water sources, each WASH committee composing 7 persons (3 women and 4 men), to ensure the sustainability of water sources after the project is faced out.
4. Construction of 124 gender-sensitive flood-proof latrines to reduce the open defecation practices (11 of the latrines will be accessible with people with disabilities).
5. AADSOM will train 10 Community Hygiene Promoters on better practices of hygiene and protection/prevention methodologies of Covid-19 to carry out hygiene/covid-19 awareness campaigns. 
6. The trained CHPs will carry out hygiene/covid-19 awareness campaigns to targeted to reach the targeted 15,000 men, women, and children.
7. AADSOM will distribute 2,000 HP kits to the most vulnerable households including the displaced IDPs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulet Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>254722800129/252616487065</telephone>
   <email>gulet@aadsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">160264.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">239735.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-19772">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-09">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305187352">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-16">240000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305354282">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-30">160000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Disasters Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
