<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA4/Nut-WASH/INGO/20864</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTEGRATED NUTRITION AND WASH  RESPONSE TO DROUGHT AFFECTED COMMUNITIES IN  GALKACYO NORTH DISTRICT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE plans to implement an integrated emergency Nutrition and Water, Sanitation and Hygeine (WASH) response to crisis affected  Women, Boys, Girls and vulnerable IDPs and rural populations. in Galkacyo North district, Puntland. The project which will be implemented for 
7 Months, and will support   25,577  individuals including  10,436 men, 10,026 women, 2,609 Boys, 2,506  Girls. The Project will operationalize nine  nutrition sites to provide  nutrition , support one mobile team to carryout outreach covering 7 drought affected villages with no access to nutrition and WASH services. This will eventually be supported through CARE&apos;s other funding after proposed project duration. CARE has operational presence and access to Mudug region where it is  implementing WaSH, education and food security and livelihoods (mainly Cash voucher assistance) to IDPs and hard-to-reach communities.  The proposed integrated Nutrition  and WASH response will therefore complement and build on CARE&#x2019;s ongoing humanitarian and long-term programs in addressing the new emerging needs in Nutrition and WASH as a result of the current drought and reach additional beneficiaries. Beneficiaries targeted under the proposed interventions will also benefit from WaSH hygiene kits and cash voucher to mothers who are malnourished or with severely malnourished children. CARE is able to roll out the activities within a short time for effective response soonest the grant is awarded and documentation is finalized with UNOCHA. CARE has active FLA with WFP and PD with UNICEF which will provide prompt and continuous availability of nutrition supplies which will  complement the project resources. In WASH, CARE will rehabilitate strategic community water points (Boreholes) to increase access to water for both Human and livestock use. In addition, the project will construct new latrine facilities and conduct hygeine promotions for IDPs and vulnerable rural populations. CARE has the advantage of long term relationships with local authorities and communities while building on its current strategy of providing a comprehensive package of humanitarian support in its areas of  operation which will sustain and provide humanitarian support beyond the proposed project response period. CARE will implement the Nutrition and WASH interventions with support from line Ministries of Health and Water in Puntland while coordinating closely with HADMA and other cluster members.  Ministry of Health staff who will be provided with nutrition related trainings will implement the nutrition interventions to ensure sustainability beyond project period while CARE technical teams from Nutrition and WASH sectors will continue to provide technical backstopping. CARE is an active member of the key coordination mechanisms in Puntland and will continue to engage with other Humanitarian agencies while sharing project information through meeting and the monthly reports to relevant institutions.
The project proposed interventions are life saving, targeting population facing humanitarian need, are underserved and are in hard-to-reach areas, while ensuring centrality of protection and accountability to the drought affected populations. CARE has well built processes and systems (including its digitalized Feedback and Response Mechanism (FAM)) that will be applied during the implementation of the project to promote beneficiary engagement and feedback.
Project will target the following nutrition sites Garsoor HC, Hormuud HC, Central HC, Yamays HC, Donyale HC, Cagaaran and Godod , and one mobile team covering  the villages of Maragel,Teeraged</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABDIKADIR ORE AHMED</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HEALTH AND NUTRITION SPECIALIST</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634619001</telephone>
   <email>abdulkadir.ore@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABDI NUR ELMI</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMERGENCY DIRECTOR</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906794487</telephone>
   <email>elmi.nur@care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9672">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mudug</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.49100000 48.01000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-12-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">3917</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">846072.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-20864">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-13">849989.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305375359">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-20">509993.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
