<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-21/3485/RA4/Nut/INGO/20899</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of lifesaving Integrated Management of Acute Malnutrition in Children under 5 years and PLWs in IDPs camps and surrounding host communities in drought affected locations in Abudwak district, Galmudug State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acute malnutrition remains a challenge and a major public health problem for children 6-59 months, as well as Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLWs). 2021 Post Gu FSNAU nutrition analysis shows that at the national level the median prevalence of Global Acute Malnutrition (GAM) has still remained at a serious level of 11.1%. According FSNAU Post Gu technical release released on 9th September 2021 in the absence of humanitarian assistance nearly 3.5 million people across Somalia are expected to face food consumption gaps or depletion of livelihood assets indicative of crisis (IPC Phase 3) or worse outcomes through the end of the year. The key drivers of acute food insecurity in Somalia include the combined effects of poor and erratic rainfall distribution, flooding and conflict.
To avert worsening nutrition situation in Abudwak, CISP will implement life-saving malnutrition prevention and treatment interventions including mass screening of children 6-59 months and PLWs and appropriate referral for care and treatment, Integrated care and treatment of severe acute malnutrition through both static and outreach clinics in IDP camps and in underserved and hard to reach areas in communities with Fixed health centres: 1) First Lulyo Health Centre Located on North West of Abudwak town 2) Waberi Health Centre East of Audwak town, Bangeele and Mirjicle locations and as outreach to IDP camps: 1) Khalif Gowracane IDP camp North West of Abudwak town, 2) Dayacan IDP Camp West of Abudwak town 3) Garasle IDP Camp East of Abudwak tow Abudwak district. The project will contribute to scale up nutrition services for early malnutrition cases detection and timely treatment and referrals where necessary to avoid morbidities and mortalities related to malnutrition.
The project targets the most affected people who are pregnant and lactating women and under 5 children who bear the brunt of the protracted emergency in Somalia. The project will screen, treat and refer 4948 under 5 children and 2227 PLWs in Abudwak district from both IDP camps and surrounding host community for acute malnutrition and offer treatment and care to 1484 and 309 under 5 children for moderate and severe acute malnutrition respectively. CISP will work closely with UNICEF and WFP to ensure 2227 pregnant and lactating women are connected to the MCHN programmes and receive multiple micronutrients. The project will also look into the bottle necks by addressing socio-cultural barriers which hinder utilization of available health and nutrition services such as health seeking behavior of the local communities.
The project will also work towards strengthening human resources for health and nutrition by engaging in capacity building initiatives. The health facility staff engaged in service provision will be trained on various thematic areas (e.g. IMAM and IYCF). The project will also ensure the benefits of working with community structures such as the Community nutrition workers (CNWs) and Community Health Committee (CHCs) to be able to address the nutrition needs of vulnerable groups.
CISP will ensure quarterly review meetings and joint support supervision with MOH is carried out in supported facilities, while assessing the availability of human resources for nutrition programming, their training needs, availability of nutrition supplies, equipment and medical products.
To promote Infection prevention and control and cross contamination during COVID-19 Pandemic most vulnerable beneficiaries such as families with children with severe acute malnutrition will receive hand sanitizers, liquid soap and face masks. This will go a long way in ensuring beneficiaries do not contract respiratory infections as they wait services at various service delivery points in Waberi and 1st Luulyo villages in Abudwak town, Bangeele and Mirjicley  locations and Khalif Gowracane IDP camp in Abudwak.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adan Abdi Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252617898913</telephone>
   <email>adan.ali@cisp-ngo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Michele Stela</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254741079137</telephone>
   <email>michele.stella@cisp-ngo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-11">248052.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-20899">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-11">248052.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305383999">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-21">148831.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Comitato Internationale per lo Sviluppo dei Popoli</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
