<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-USAGOV-14-PEPFAR-17020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mechanism 17020 - Systems Strengthening for Better HIV/TB Patient Outcomes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Additional detail on PEPFAR financial information and terminology can be found at https://data.pepfar.gov/financial.   
The PEPFAR IATI activity file and PEPFAR IATI Activity File User&apos;s Guide can be found at https://data.pepfar.gov/additionalData


Anova Health Institute (Anova) will provide Technical Assistance (TA) and Health Systems Strengthening support within the Partnership Framework, and South African Government&#x2019;s (SAG) National Strategic Plan (NSP). Anova will work in close partnership with the Department of Health (DOH) in 3 provinces: Limpopo, Gauteng and Western Cape, encompassing over 5.2 million people (10% of the population). T
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.6: Adult Care and Support. All facility-based and home/community-based activities for HIV-infected adults and their families aimed at extending and optimizing quality of life for HIV-infected clients and their families throughout the continuum of illness through provision of clinical, psychological, spiritual, social and prevention services.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.11: Treatment/Adult Treatment. Including infrastructure, training clinicians and other providers, exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, and community-adherence activities.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.9: Counseling and Testing. Includes activities in which both HIV counseling and testing are provided for those who seek to know their HIV status (as in traditional VCT) or provider initiated counseling and testing.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.5: Sexual Prevention - Other Sexual Prevention. Other activities (including training) aimed at preventing HIV transmission including purchase and promotion of condoms, STI management (if not in palliative care settings/context), messages/programs to reduce other risks of persons engaged in high-risk behaviors.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.7: TB/HIV. Includes exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, treatment and prevention of tuberculosis (including medication), as well as screening and referral of TB clinic clients for HIV testing and clinical care.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.1: Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission (PMTCT). Activities (including training) aimed at preventing mother-to-child HIV transmission, including ARV prophylaxis for HIV-infected pregnant women and newborns and counseling and support for maternal nutrition.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.13: Health System Strengthening. Include activities that contribute to national, regional or district level systems by supporting finance, leadership and governance (include broad policy reform efforts including stigma, gender, etc.), institutional capacity building, supply chain or procurement systems, Global Fund programs and donor coordination.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.17: Pediatric Care and Support. All health facility-based care for HIV-exposed children and their families aimed at extending and optimizing quality of life for HIV-infected clients and their families throughout the continuum of illness through provision of clinical, psychological, spiritual, social and prevention services.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.18: Treatment/Pediatric Treatment. Including infrastructure, training clinicians and other providers, exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, and community-adherence activities.
objectives</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anova Health Institute (Anova) will provide Technical Assistance (TA) and Health Systems Strengthening support within the Partnership Framework, and South African Government&#x2019;s (SAG) National Strategic Plan (NSP). Anova will work in close partnership with the Department of Health (DOH) in 3 provinces: Limpopo, Gauteng and Western Cape, encompassing over 5.2 million people (10% of the population). Target populations include: women, children, groups with highest HIV prevalence, least access to health care, and key populations such as men who have sex with men and sex workers.
Interventions include: Consolidating current quality service provision; TA to health facilities and community groups for adult and pediatric care, support and treatment, TB and prevention of mother to child transmission; Strengthening health systems financial and project planning, management, leadership, health information systems, workforce planning, service delivery; Supporting PHC Re-engineering and Ward Based Outreach Teams (WBOTs); and Supporting SAG policy, guideline and standards development and implementation. 
Anova will facilitate well-capacitated and managed district management teams and systems, delivering sustainable high quality patient care. The strategy will provide intensive cost-effective support for 2-3 year and then scale down to a mentoring role to ensure full managerial and financial responsibility by DOH. 
The M&amp;E plan includes baseline and end of project evaluations, and quarterly collection of process and output indicators, such as health workers trained and facility TA activities. Annual assessments will use District Health Information System data for outcome, impact and NSP target indicators, and feedback dashboard mechanisms will monitor health service coverage and quality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ANOVA HEALTH INSTITUTE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-14" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">State Department</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="17020" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="AID674A1200015" type="A9"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+1 202-663-2440</telephone>
   <email>CA_SGAC_Public_Affairs@state.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.state.gov/pepfar/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2100 Pennsylvania Avenue, Suite 200, Washington, DC 20522, USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="PEPFAR" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.state.gov/pepfar/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The U.S. President&apos;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) is the U.S. government&apos;s response to the global HIV/AIDS epidemic and represents the largest commitment by any nation to address a single disease in history.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-27">521045</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2019-c">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-27">521045</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2019-e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-27">1372615</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.pepfar.gov/evaluations">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEPFAR Evaluations</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/annual-reports-to-congress-on-the-presidents-emergency-plan-for-aids-relief/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Reports to Congress on the President&#x2019;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/reports-pepfar/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports and Guidance &#x2013; PEPFAR</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/PEPFAR-Fiscal-Year-2019-Country-Operational-Plan-Guidance.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEPFAR Fiscal Year 2019 Country Operational Plan Guidance</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B04"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.stateoig.gov/system/files/aud-si-20-17.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Audit of the Department of State&#x2019;s Coordination and Oversight of the U.S. President&#x2019;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://oig.usaid.gov/search-content?keys=PEPFAR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HHS OIG Reports on President&apos;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) Funds</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
