<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-USAGOV-14-PEPFAR-14336</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mechanism 14336 - HMU follow on</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Additional detail on PEPFAR financial information and terminology can be found at https://data.pepfar.gov/financial.   
The PEPFAR IATI activity file and PEPFAR IATI Activity File User&apos;s Guide can be found at https://data.pepfar.gov/additionalData


The Hanoi Medical University (HMU) is has a diverse pool of experts providing technical assistance in education, research, and evaluation in Vietnam. HMU has a close relationship with Ministry of Health (MOH), with a strong network of Medical and Public Health Universities. PEPFAR Vietnam has partnered with HMU to expand institutional capacity within the Government of Vietnam (GVN) and focuses on 
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.12: Laboratory Infrastructure. Development and strengthening of laboratory systems and facilities to support HIV/AIDSrelated activities including purchase of equipment and commodities and provision of quality assurance, staff training and other technical assistance.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.11: Treatment/Adult Treatment. Including infrastructure, training clinicians and other providers, exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, and community-adherence activities.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.9: Counseling and Testing. Includes activities in which both HIV counseling and testing are provided for those who seek to know their HIV status (as in traditional VCT) or provider initiated counseling and testing.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.5: Sexual Prevention - Other Sexual Prevention. Other activities (including training) aimed at preventing HIV transmission including purchase and promotion of condoms, STI management (if not in palliative care settings/context), messages/programs to reduce other risks of persons engaged in high-risk behaviors.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.14: Strategic Information. HIV/AIDS behavioral and biological surveillance, facility surveys, monitoring partner results, reporting results, supporting health information systems, assisting countries to establish and/or strengthen such systems, and related analysis and data dissemination activities fall under strategic information.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.16: Biomedical Prevention - Prevention Among Injecting and Non-Injecting Drug Users. Activities including policy reform, training, message development, community mobilization and comprehensive approaches including medication assistance therapy to reduce injecting drug use.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.13: Health System Strengthening. Include activities that contribute to national, regional or district level systems by supporting finance, leadership and governance (include broad policy reform efforts including stigma, gender, etc.), institutional capacity building, supply chain or procurement systems, Global Fund programs and donor coordination.
objectives</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Hanoi Medical University (HMU) is has a diverse pool of experts providing technical assistance in education, research, and evaluation in Vietnam. HMU has a close relationship with Ministry of Health (MOH), with a strong network of Medical and Public Health Universities. PEPFAR Vietnam has partnered with HMU to expand institutional capacity within the Government of Vietnam (GVN) and focuses on the coordination and implementation of program evaluation and building national and provincial capacity of lab and addiction medicine pre-and in-service training.
Goals are to:
1.	Strengthen GVN health system&#x2019;s capacity to implement public health monitoring, evaluation and research, as well as analyze and utilize data.
2.	Build capacity of HMU and other medical universities in Addictions Medicine pre-and in-service training.
3.	Strengthen lab pre-service education, lab quality management systems, and testing quality assurance.
4.	Build institutional capacity to standardize HIV-related continuing medical education.
These activities strengthen health system at national level and provincial levels and target MOH managers, hospital leaders, doctors, nurses, lab staff, and other health care workers. This supports the implementation of national strategic plans, as well as ensuring improved health care services are integrated into the healthcare system.
Activities will be monitored by CDC Vietnam staff through quarterly meetings with the partner. CDC VN staff will review the quality of materials developed by HMU. Monitoring and evaluation will be integrated into program functions.

Pipeline was considered to set the COP 14 budget request. Pipeline has been small and is less than new funding. Outlays have been larger than pipeline; additional activities should increase outlays</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hanoi Medical University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-14" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">State Department</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Health and Human Services/Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Health and Human Services/Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="14336" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="NU2GGH002150" type="A9"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+1 202-663-2440</telephone>
   <email>CA_SGAC_Public_Affairs@state.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.state.gov/pepfar/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2100 Pennsylvania Avenue, Suite 200, Washington, DC 20522, USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="PEPFAR" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.state.gov/pepfar/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The U.S. President&apos;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) is the U.S. government&apos;s response to the global HIV/AIDS epidemic and represents the largest commitment by any nation to address a single disease in history.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1254000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1275000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1280840</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2019-c">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1254000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2019-e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">654000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-c">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1275000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">714000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2021-c">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1151173</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.pepfar.gov/evaluations">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEPFAR Evaluations</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/annual-reports-to-congress-on-the-presidents-emergency-plan-for-aids-relief/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Reports to Congress on the President&#x2019;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/reports-pepfar/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports and Guidance &#x2013; PEPFAR</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/PEPFAR-Fiscal-Year-2019-Country-Operational-Plan-Guidance.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEPFAR Fiscal Year 2019 Country Operational Plan Guidance</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B04"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.stateoig.gov/system/files/aud-si-20-17.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Audit of the Department of State&#x2019;s Coordination and Oversight of the U.S. President&#x2019;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://oig.hhs.gov/newsroom/podcasts/pepfar/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HHS OIG Reports on President&apos;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) Funds</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
