<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-USAGOV-14-PEPFAR-18442</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mechanism 18442 - GHSC-PSM</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Additional detail on PEPFAR financial information and terminology can be found at https://data.pepfar.gov/financial.   
The PEPFAR IATI activity file and PEPFAR IATI Activity File User&apos;s Guide can be found at https://data.pepfar.gov/additionalData


GHSC-PSM will take over pooled procurement from SCMS and implement several critical changes in the supply and delivery of commodities with COP 2016 resources.  GHSC-PSM will start planning the transition of the unified supply chain and PEPFAR procured commodities to the GON National Supply Chain as being designed under the Global Fund National Supply Chain Integration Project in the next five year
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.6: Adult Care and Support. All facility-based and home/community-based activities for HIV-infected adults and their families aimed at extending and optimizing quality of life for HIV-infected clients and their families throughout the continuum of illness through provision of clinical, psychological, spiritual, social and prevention services.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.3: Biomedical Prevention - Blood Safety. Activities supporting a nationally-coordinated blood program to ensure a safe and adequate blood supply including: infrastructure and policies; donor recruitment activities, blood collection, testing for transfusion-transmissible infections, component preparation, storage and distribution; appropriate clinical use of blood, transfusion procedures and hemovigilance; training and human resource development; monitoring and evaluation; and development of sustainable systems.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.4: Biomedical Prevention - Injection Safety. Policies, training, waste-management systems, advocacy and other activities to promote medical injection safety, including distribution/supply chain, cost and appropriate disposal of injection equipment and other related equipment and supplies.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.10: Treatment/ARV Drugs. This includes procurement, delivery and in-freight of ARV drugs.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.11: Treatment/Adult Treatment. Including infrastructure, training clinicians and other providers, exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, and community-adherence activities.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.9: Counseling and Testing. Includes activities in which both HIV counseling and testing are provided for those who seek to know their HIV status (as in traditional VCT) or provider initiated counseling and testing.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.5: Sexual Prevention - Other Sexual Prevention. Other activities (including training) aimed at preventing HIV transmission including purchase and promotion of condoms, STI management (if not in palliative care settings/context), messages/programs to reduce other risks of persons engaged in high-risk behaviors.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.7: TB/HIV. Includes exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, treatment and prevention of tuberculosis (including medication), as well as screening and referral of TB clinic clients for HIV testing and clinical care.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.1: Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission (PMTCT). Activities (including training) aimed at preventing mother-to-child HIV transmission, including ARV prophylaxis for HIV-infected pregnant women and newborns and counseling and support for maternal nutrition.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.13: Health System Strengthening. Include activities that contribute to national, regional or district level systems by supporting finance, leadership and governance (include broad policy reform efforts including stigma, gender, etc.), institutional capacity building, supply chain or procurement systems, Global Fund programs and donor coordination.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.17: Pediatric Care and Support. All health facility-based care for HIV-exposed children and their families aimed at extending and optimizing quality of life for HIV-infected clients and their families throughout the continuum of illness through provision of clinical, psychological, spiritual, social and prevention services.
Funds allocated for Program Element HL.1.18: Treatment/Pediatric Treatment. Including infrastructure, training clinicians and other providers, exams, clinical monitoring, related laboratory services, and community-adherence activities.
objectives</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GHSC-PSM will take over pooled procurement from SCMS and implement several critical changes in the supply and delivery of commodities with COP 2016 resources.  GHSC-PSM will start planning the transition of the unified supply chain and PEPFAR procured commodities to the GON National Supply Chain as being designed under the Global Fund National Supply Chain Integration Project in the next five years. GHSC-PSM will also work with other stakeholders to further strengthen the Logistics Management Units at the State level to manage state-level supply chain thus encouraging co-ownership of the National Supply Chain.

ONGOING ACTIVITIES
GHSC-PSM will continue to pool the procurement of ARV drugs, rapid test kits, cotrimoxazole and other opportunistic infection drugs, viral load, EID and CD4 reagents under COP 2016.  Savings from previous procurements have been reflected in GHSC-PSM&#x2019;s budget.  GHSC-PSM will continue to provide technical assistance to the GON on nearly every aspect of the supply chain, and GHSC-PSM will continue to assist other PEPFAR partners in re-supplying HIV/AIDS commodities.

NEW ACTIVITIES
Under the 2016 COP, GHSC-PSM will work with the GON and other stakeholders to implement supply chain innovations in line with new direction from OGAC and WHO recommendations on &#x201C;test and treat&#x201D;. These will include multi-scripting, community ART and change in the review and resupply cycle for the supply chain from bi-monthly to quarterly with stable patients being given six month prescriptions. These will be done with the aim to improve efficiency, improve products&#x2019; availability and further reduce waste due to expiry.  

The new pharmaceutical grade warehouses in Lagos and Abuja will be completed in COP 2016 and the GHSC-PSM project will work with the GON and the</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chemonics International, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-14" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">State Department</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="18442" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="AIDOAAI1500004" type="A9"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+1 202-663-2440</telephone>
   <email>CA_SGAC_Public_Affairs@state.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.state.gov/pepfar/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2100 Pennsylvania Avenue, Suite 200, Washington, DC 20522, USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="12110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="PEPFAR" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.state.gov/pepfar/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The U.S. President&apos;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) is the U.S. government&apos;s response to the global HIV/AIDS epidemic and represents the largest commitment by any nation to address a single disease in history.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">136385046</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">164419613</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2019-c">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">80601311</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2019-e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">121870761</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-c">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">164419613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2020-e">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">162934269</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://data.pepfar.gov/evaluations">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEPFAR Evaluations</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/annual-reports-to-congress-on-the-presidents-emergency-plan-for-aids-relief/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Reports to Congress on the President&#x2019;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/reports-pepfar/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports and Guidance &#x2013; PEPFAR</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/PEPFAR-Fiscal-Year-2019-Country-Operational-Plan-Guidance.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PEPFAR Fiscal Year 2019 Country Operational Plan Guidance</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B04"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.stateoig.gov/system/files/aud-si-20-17.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Audit of the Department of State&#x2019;s Coordination and Oversight of the U.S. President&#x2019;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://oig.usaid.gov/search-content?keys=PEPFAR">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HHS OIG Reports on President&apos;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) Funds</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
