<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR435</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community and Legislative members Interactive Platform (CLIP) Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are trying to close the gap between the legislators and their communities to ensure a synergy between them and create room for quality representation.
With reference to the 2nd phase of the CLIP project carried out, we have achieved a great deal of cordial relationship between the communities and their legislators through the following channels and means of impacts.
1. Through our legislative intervention, we can boldly say that the 12 constituencies we are covering now have 12 functional constituency offices. 
2. We now have a functional mechanism for town hall meetings. The 12 constituencies now experience quality interactions at the town hall meetings void of any form of partisanship.
3. The impact of the radio program has been very awesome. With the radio show, we have recorded  the presence of 4 legislators live on air while 5 have been on air via phone as they called into the show.
On the radio show, we have also recorded the presence of 2 Igwes and 8 President Generals of different communities.
Many community members and vanguards call into the radio program to interact and proffer solutions to some of the problems facing the communities.
4. The submission of charter of demands by the constituencies have also been very helpful as we use these charter of demands to engage the legislators.
During the implementation of the 2ndstage of the Community and Legislative members Interactive Platform [CLIP] project, the capacity of the identified community (members) vanguards was upgraded, strengthened and put to test. They engaged their legislators through advocacy and interactive visits and now seek for ways to consolidate this conversation and extend the interaction to the local government and ward levels.
1. LEGISLATIVE AUTONOMY 
2. JUDICIARY AUTONOMY 
3. LOCAL GOVERNMENT AUTONOMY
4. SYMPOSIUM- 
5. CONTINUED RADIO SHOW- 
6. CAPACITY BUILDING TRANING-  
7. LEGISLATORS UNITY FORUM- 
8. TOWN HALL MEETINGS-
Also, Civil Society Organizations and the strength of the Media would be employed to sensitize the public on the outcome of oversight activities relating to budget provisions of the focal communities as well as the roles and functions of the legislators to clearly raise awareness and push for positive change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR435" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR435" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR435" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">38511.4626</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="53951">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">38511.4626</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68527">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">19255.73</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
