<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR390</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to local resources for development interventions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project&#x2019;s goal is to increase the visibility of Caritas Nigeria thereby creating easy access to locally generated funds for development interventions. This becomes imperative since there is little or no control on the fast dwindling of international funding. Increasing awareness of the organization will boost the fundraising drive and drive the focus away from over dependence on foreign aid.  
The change, which is a plausible solution to fostering self-reliance with local funding, will be launched using appropriate channels and processes. This will be strengthened over time while boosting local ownership and benefits. This will also be done by increasing parish fundraising drives to other Arch/dioceses in Nigeria.
The Caritas Nigeria Strategy Development Workshop; Resource Mobilization Framework in October 2016, had the aim of identifying the gaps which dispel inefficiency regarding the access to local resources.
The key resolutions reached at the workshop which will help facilitate development of a strong internal resource base for Caritas Nigeria, and expand Parish fundraising to other Arch/dioceses reinforced some of the resolutions highlighted below. 
- Fundraising Diversification: Fostering greater involvement of Nigeria Bishops with Caritas Nigeria
- Leverage the Church Structure: Using existing church structures to drive interventions.
- Increasing visibility: Initiating activities that will create greater public awareness through media approach, strategic branding etc.
- Boosting Fundraising: Increasing avenues for raising funds for the organization
- Building Capacity: Increasing capacity for fundraising for local Caritas members.
- Optimizing Donor relationship: Managing and improving the relationship with donors.
- Building trust and accountability: Creating environment for trust by all Stakeholders
- Involving CAFOD:  Invite CAFOD team to facilitate a training session for Caritas Nigeria local fundraising team.
- Formation of Caritas Club: Introducing the formation of Caritas club among Catholic institutions
- Involving Caritas Nigeria Staff: Letting potential Caritas Nigeria staff from the job interview stage and orientation know that they would be part of Caritas Nigeria fundraising drive.
- Promoting Volunteerism: Encouraging and recruiting volunteers into Caritas Nigeria projects.
- Partnership with Professional Groups: Identifying and building partnership with professional groups.
- Expanding the revenue stream: Fostering good relationships with State Governments.
- Strengthening JDPC at Diocesan level: Advocacy to Bishops to promote ownership and support to existing structures like JDPC, Health, Education, Family and Human Life.
- Improving the coordination role of Caritas Nigeria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR390" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR390" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR390" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-20">26506.9157</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="49565">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">26506.9157</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="63500">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">26506.92</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
