<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR393</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing Citizens participation and inclusive governance for improved Water, Sanitation and Hygien</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The social accountability project 2017 aims at sustaining the success story of the 2016 social accountability project and to further promote citizens participation and inclusive governance in the decision making processes of Kogi State. Since the communities have been mobilized in the 2016 project and since promises are made by the duty bearers as reflected in the 2017 draft budget of kogi state to build eastern, western and central water project schemes which would alleviate water shortages in communities such as Ejule, Idah, Anyigba, Agaliga Ankpa, Adogo, Ege, Obangede and Idoji communities all in JDPC areas of intervention. 

On the part of the duty bearers, the state government has moved to complete 22 abandoned water projects across kogi state. Among which are the following communities of JDPC intervention: Idah, Anyigba, Imane-Agaliga, Ege, Idoji and Obangede and to extend Lokoja greater water project to other communities within Lokoja yet to be connected to the water schemefour of these communities are JDPC areas of intervention. 

Looking at the successes recorded in the 2016 JDPC social accountability project above, it is imperative to put in place mechanism to ensure these successes are sustained and further expanded to other target communities where significant success are yet to be recorded. This therefore informed the need for the 2017 social accountability project.  
JDPC will therefore work with the already mobilized citizens/communities to dialogue with the duty bearers to further the demand for improved supply of water to the people of Kogi State, create awareness and advocate for behavioural change on sanitary and hygiene practices in Kogi State.
Since the legislator as the watch dogs to the Executives, play key role in the implementation of the state appropriation bill, it becomes necessary to partner with them to put more pressure on the Executives towards implementing the contents of the appropriation Law. .</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR393" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR393" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR393" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">22444.2402</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="49665">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-17">22444.2402</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="63501">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-17">22444.24</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
