<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR435</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community and Legislative members Interactive Platform (CLIP) Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will build on the achievements of the CLIP project, the relationships built between the citizens and their elected representatives. This relation will provide the platform for the added on interventions to promote a more inclusive governance structure, where the govern make inputs to, monitor implementation and recommend on status of government interventions in the public sector Budget

PROPOSED STRATEGIES
- Budget Analysis of key important development sector such as Education, Health, Agriculture and Water/Sanitation. This provides an evidence based advocacy tool for engagement with the relevant Legislative and Executive Arms of Government especially on increased budgetary allocation
- CLIP CLINIC- This activity will be exclusively community initiated, with support from JDPC. The aim is to help communities identify projects sited in their communities and included in State Budget. The community will then monitor the status of the project and relate with the various arms of government to ensure the timely completion of the project and ensure value for money.
  CLIP CLINIC is a brain child of the CLIP project that will institutionalize the project in all communities and ensure sustainability of the CLIP project. It has the capacity to stand the test of time because it will be managed by community members and supervised by the CLIP VANGUAURDS while the JDPC CLIP PROJECT team provides total executive assistance. Its an organized grassroot establishment at community that will complement the work of the legislators as regards to the primary community development programs such as waste management, boreholes, drainages, medical outreach, environmental sanitation, neighborhood watch, provision of seedlings for local farmers and erosion control.
- Media Engagement through existing Radio Phone-in programme. This medium will continue to provide a platform for citizens to engage government officials and entities on issues that bother them and get feedback. It will also provide the government side the opportunity to proactively provide information and clarifications on burning issues that affect governance and citizens. Activities of the CLIP CLINIC will also serve as a content provider for the radio program.
- JDPC AWKA FACEBOOK page and WEBSITE will be flooded with video, audio and written evidences of the CLIP CLINIC, thereby creating awareness that is enough to attract the attention of the Legislators to wake up to their duties.
- Press releases and conferences: this activity is a continuation of the Media engagement and will be done periodically to address emerging issues in the governance of the state.
- Production of documentaries that will display evidence based successes recorded by the CLIP project with the introduction of the CLIP CLINIC.
- Engagement of Governance at Local Government levels: This exploratory activity is aimed at connecting the citizens with the executive and legislative structure closest to them</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR435" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR435" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR435" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">38511.4626</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-10-01">28997.2135</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="53951">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">38511.4626</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="55337">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-23">28997.2135</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68527">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">19255.73</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69367">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">19255.73</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70088">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-23">14498.61</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70791">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-23">14498.61</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
