<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR366</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Initiatives for Sustainable Development (WISD) in Kogi state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Women Studies and Intervention in tandem with this project has identified two important areas that it wishes to
collaborate with CCFN to add value to the lives of people in the Catholic dioceses of Idah and Lokoja in Kogi state, towards sustainable development. 

Thus we are focusing on the two areas of intervention specified below:

1.    Continuation of the gender based Human Rights Initiatives which was flagged off in 2013 to address violations of women and the girl child rights in the dioceses of Idah and Lokoja.

2.    Addressing gender gaps in politics and governance i.e. Mainstreaming of women&#x2019;s participation in politics and governance in the two Catholic dioceses in Kogi state.


Below is the analytical explanation on the project.
&#xB7;      Continuation of the gender based Human rights initiative:


CWSI identified incidences of gender based human rights violations in these dioceses and took it as a critical area of concern deserving intervention as there is nothing more fundamental to peace and sustainable development than the full realisation of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights which guarantees the enabling environment for a happier world where people live in justice and treat each other with respect and dignity. To curb the gender based human rights violations, CWSI embarked on the formation of community human rights club to engage volunteers who will work in concerto for the achievement of human rights regime in these dioceses. The formation of the human right clubs was successfully carried out in both dioceses on the 12th and 13th of February 2014, which is the first phase. Now, we are focusing on human rights education and training of the human right club members. In other words, 70 members of the human rights clubs 35 in each dioceses will be trained. This
is  aimed at equipping the human rights clubs members with the requisite knowledge to carry out their responsibility of human right training and monitoring, evaluation, reporting and counselling with a view to helping their respective communities address
human right challenges.

Therefore this project will address gender based human right violations in both dioceses which will be achieved through the informed activities of the community human right club members whose capacities must be built to make them efficient and effective as catalysts for the change desired. The methodology of capacity building is imperative because it is the process of developing and strengthening of skills, instincts, abilities, processes and resources that organisations and communities need to
thrive. It is the element that gives fluidity, flexibility, and functionality of a programme or of an organisation to adapt to the changing needs of the population that is served. According to the United Nations briefing paper (1991) capacity building is human resources development and the strengthening of Managerial System.
&#xB7;      Addressing gender gap in political participation: Mainstreaming of women&#x2019;s participation in politics and
governance in Kogi state.

Absence of women in decision making has been a source of concern for long, thus in Beijing in 1995, it became imperative to
propose a formidable solution to support inclusion of women in all areas of life, the platform for Action recommended both formal and substantive equality and action, calls on government to support at least 30% Affirmative Action for women in political space. Since 1995, there have been advocacies in Nigeria for increase in the number of women in political space, very little have been achieved in this regard. As at 2011, the total number of women in political offices in Nigeria is put at 8%.

Democracy is about fair representation of all interest groups in the society and the low representation of women is a violation of the principle of democracy. Furthermore, the hall mark of democracy is representation, participation, and citizenship, a combination of this indicator will provide a better democracy. The exclusion of women in the sphere of governance and politics is a serious gender gap that needs to be addressed. Women are estimated to constitute about 50% of Nigerians population and accordingly deserve a degree of portfolios commensurate with their number (pls. see &#x201C;women, marginalisation and politics in Nigeria 2004 pg. 22, edited by Jibrin Ibrahim and AminaSalihu).

Kogi state in focus:
The very low level of women participation in politics and governance in Kogi state is the rationale for proposing an intervention to change the situation. Our decision to address the gap in women participation in Kogi, is the second ambit of this project and proceeds from the analysis of a survey carried out by CWSI in the month of August 2013 to determine a number of gender issues in Idah and Lokoja dioceses for a proactive intervention. A total of 200 questionnaires were distributed. The respondent
were thirty (30) males and (50) fifty females in Idah diocese while in Lokoja, the respondents were 63 males and 48 females. Nine questionnaires were returned unattended.

Responding to the questions on leadership and women participation in politics and governance, only 5% of females representing 10 % of the total number of all respondents supported women&#x2019;s inclusion in leadership, politics and governance. 90% of the respondents are of the opinion that leadership and political participation is the exclusive privilege of men and  that infact, men are ordained and approved by God to lead in all spheres of life.This expression of gross ignorance is worrisome and points to a major factor responsible for exclusion of women&#x2019;s low participation in politics and governance in Kogi state. Achieving an increase in the level of women participation in the two dioceses is propitious because the year 2015 is Nigeria&#x2019;s general elections. It is a
great opportunity to change the political situation that have relegated women to cheer leader&#x2019;s in a democratic dispensation where they are equal stakeholders. 

Our strategy to occasion change is to organize sensitization summit and seminars on leadership training and political reorientation for women in preparation for the next general election. We will encourage women to join political parties and play an active role within the parties of their choice so as to be relevant. CWSI will also encourage women professional and capable women to participate in partisan politics and advocate for greater political appointments for qualified women as a means of achieving the desired increase in the number of women in governance . This project addresses the need to sensitize women to be mainstreamed and also facilitate the incorporation of the &#x2018;gender agenda&#x2019; in politics and governance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR366" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR366" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR366" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-05-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-04-01">34000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="45712">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-06-02">34000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="59777">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-06-02">17000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60346">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-06-02">17000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
