<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR414</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water, Sanitation and Hygiene Support to IDPs in 2 LGAs of Plateau State, Nigeria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plateau State is not new to inter-communal violence. Over 38,000 persons were displaced by the latest violence in the State in late June 2018.  With many displaced families taking refuge in Jos as internally displaced persons (IDPs). JDPC Jos, through its Emergency Preparedness and Response Team (EPRT), an inter-agency and inter-faith coalition conducted humanitarian situation assessments. Report of the assessment visits draws attention to the plight of people displaced by the recent violent attacks on several communities. The immediate needs of the victims are food, non-food items, water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH) support as a short-term intervention; while psychosocial support, women and youth empowerment, building bridges of trust through peacebuilding and conflict transformation as well as re-settlement of the IDPs was identified as long-term needs. Through this project, the dignity and privacy of men, women, boys and girls will be ensured through the provision of water, sanitation and hygiene materials and messages. Dignity kits including sanitary wears will be provided for women and girls. Gender segregated latrines will be constructed. Most vulnerable categories will be targeted and inequalities in access will be addressed. This project will also lead to prevention of outbreaks of contaminated and airborne diseases such as cholera, and would aim at developing a health conscious IDP camps and host communities.  Complaints and feedback mechanism will be established to enable target communities/camp to air their views about the project. 
This project&apos;s outcomes include
1. Improved access to sanitation facilities in emergency affected communities
2. Improved access to safe drinking water in affected communities and camps 
3. Deliver humanitarian WASH supplies and services to meet vulnerable</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR414" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR414" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR414" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-24">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="51322">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-19">30000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="65615">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-19">30000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
