<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR477</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scaling-up Assistance in Hard-to-Reach Areas (SAHaRA)- ECHO Phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The needs in Nigeria continue to increase in all sectors, as conflicts and violence persists in the region. The limitations of movement in the Northern part pose great challenges for the delivery of humanitarian assistance and for people in need to access humanitarian aid. The action&#x2019;s principal objective is to contribute to improving the living conditions and dignity of people affected by the Boko Haram crisis in Borno state, Northeast Nigeria. In this context, the implementing partners will be mindful of the Humanitarian-Development-Peace (HDP) Nexus and consider longer-term sustainability of their activities. The specific objective is to provide inclusive, safe, and dignified access to immediate food, WASH, and protection assistance and to strengthen community resilience in at 20 communities in hard-to-reach areas of Kaga and Magumeri LGAs in Borno state. The intervention will focus on providing direct access to integrated multi-sectoral, context-adapted assistance, which will cover the most urgent humanitarian needs of the most vulnerable people and communities. The partners will apply a conflict-sensitive and rights-based approach, taking into consideration their risk analysis while ensuring a flexible, secure, and coordinated response. The action will include humanitarian protection, food assistance, access to water for domestic use, improved sanitation and hygiene, and a scheme for gender-based violence prevention. The villages to be covered have been selected in coordination with local authorities and humanitarian clusters to ensure reaching into areas with high needs that have largely been deprived of humanitarian assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR477" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR477" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR477" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-01">64291.563</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="56050">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-05-30">64291.563</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
