<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR476</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Linking relief, rehabilitation and Dev.  through climate sensitive livelihood in Adamawa State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria is faced with water scarcity and droughts which occur every five years, on average, with the potential to increase in frequency due to climate change. This scenario not only threatens food security, livelihoods, and productivity, but also exacerbates fragility and increases the risk of violence. Nigeria has a tropical climate with two precipitation regimes: low precipitation in the North and high precipitation in parts of the Southwest and Southeast. This can lead to aridity, drought and desertification in the north; and flooding and erosion in the South. The drying up of rivers, and particularly the shrinking of Lake Chad is attributable to the effects of climate change and is having a significant impact on conflict-affected population. Climate change poses serious threat to life in rural communities in Northeast Nigeria, particularly in conflict-affected states bordering Cameroun such as Borno and Adamawa.   

Climate change and conflict in Adamawa state:
Conflicts over resources and communal violence, mostly involving contested resources, have killed at least 10,000 Nigerians in less than a decade . A case in point is Nigeria&#x2019;s frequent farmer-herder conflicts: feed scarcity and water shortages caused partly by desertification and drought have sent nomadic pastoralists, most of them ethnic Fulanis, wandering south, outside their normal grazing routes. 
Additionally, for over a decade, the insurgency in Northeast Nigeria has caused severe population movements with large influxes of displaced population seeking safety. As of February 2022, IOM has reported a significant growth of displaced population numbers settling in Adamawa State, particularly in 12 Local Government Areas.  Adamawa has already suffered significant deforestation in recent years with the apparition of large desert areas and deforestation in the proximities of the Dambisa Forest. Agriculture is the mainstay of about 80% of the inhabitants of the State; farming activities include cultivation of root crops (e.g. sweet potatoes, yam and cassava), cereals (maize, sorghum, millet and rice), horticulture and rearing of livestock (cattle, goat, sheep, pig and poultry). In recent years, and with the increase of displaced population in the area, the area has suffered deforestation due to unsustainable charcoal production, and the use of wood for cooking and farming activities. The use of harmful farming practices including an increased use of inorganic fertiliser and chemicals (pesticides and herbicides) on farmlands has contributed to soil erosion and aridity. Rural communities have also resorted to hunting of wild animals in the forest for food, also affecting the biodiversity in the area</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR476" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR476" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diocese of Yola, Justice and Peace Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR476" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55886">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-07-06">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
