<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR367</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Governance Action For People&#x2019;s Development in Kogi State phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria though endowed with both human and material resources, has not been able to harness these resources for the overall well being of her citizens. This is attributable to weak governance structure ranging from bad management of resources to the high level of citizens apathy to governance issues.The project seeks to address issues that will bring about  good governance using the Caritas Nigeria and the Justice Development and Peace Commission (JDPC) in Idah and Lokoja Dioceses of Kogi State, in North-Central, Nigeria. During the first phase of the project, some issues that hindered the entrenchment of good
governance were discovered.


First, it was discovered that issues of accountability will be taken more seriously by government only when  citizens use
existing Policy and Legislative instruments to demand for improved social well being and accountability from those in government. Secondly, the democratic processes of electing candidates into offices are weak thereby making the citizens to believe that their votes do not count. This brings in voters apathy and even the few people that participate in voting, do so just to fulfil all righteousness. At the end of the day, candidates are elected into offices without regard to their knowledge of the issues on ground, and their ability to propose solutions to them. As the 2015 general elections draw nearer there is the need to conscientize the people and galvanise them towards active participation in the electoral process. This will no doubt raise the bar on the quality of candidate that vie for elective offices and help the people make well informed choices of candidates to vote
during the election. 


Thirdly, the Gender and Equal Opportunities Bill, which is the instrument that would have given more access to women participation in governance in Kogi, though passed by the Kogi State House of Assembly is yet to be signed into Law by the Governor of Kogi State.  

Lastly, at the last plenary of the Catholic Bishops&#x2019; Conference of Nigeria, there was a request by the Bishops that the President
should look into the matter of government support for services rendered by voluntary agencies. It is noteworthy that some state governments have identified the complementary role of civil society organizations in the provisions of social services to the citizens especially in the hinterland and have entered into funding partnership with them. There is the need to make the
support regular, consistent and justiciable because progress of society cannot be pinned on goodwill of a few willing leaders but through established framework that force even those without goodwill to have a minimum of responsiveness. In view of the complementary role of CSO in development, there is the need for a National Policy measure to be put in place to encourage non
state actors to more than ever before partner with government in development.

The project will work both at the national level at the state level. At the national office, the CCFN will midwife the passage of a
bill for the setting up of National Development Fund, which will be accessible to Civil Society Organization for their pro-poor interventions. Consultation meetings and media campaign will be had with relevant stakeholders to drum up support for the proposed bill. Advocacy meeting with the Catholic Legislators at the National Assembly will also be intensified.  At the State, Diocesan and Community levels, JDPC Offices in Idah and Lokoja Dioceses will consolidate on the gains already made in the good governance projects. Awareness will be created to create avenue for citizens especially women participation in next year&#x2019;s general election.  Relevant stakeholders will also be engaged to fashion out ways of having non violent general elections next year. In order to improve on the level of women participation in governance generally, there will be advocacy for the signing into Law of Gender and Equal Opportunities Bill by the Kogi State Governor.

The impact on the project will be cross-cutting as it will to create avenue for good governance, accountability and more women participation in governance. The establishment of a National Fund for use by Civil Society Organizations will given room for subsidiarity as it will make funds available to CSOs who are closer to the problems and have a better understanding of the issues.  With the signing into Law of the gender and Equality Bill, more women will participate in decision making.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR367" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR367" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR367" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-05-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-04-01">84875</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="45715">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-06-02">84875</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="59778">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-06-02">42437.5</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60347">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-06-02">42437.5</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
