<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NGR381</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing Popular Participation in Governance in Kaduna State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Executive through the ministries&apos; departments and agencies each year prepare and present a budget to the State House of Assembly. Government traditionally will name budgets such as &#x201C;the peoples&#x2019; budget or budget of consolidation&#x201D; etc. Even though the budgets are called &#x201C;the peoples&#x2019; budget&#x201D;. These budgets when passed end up not being implemented or partially implemented because  the government do not see the provisions in the budget as a covenant with the people. 

The Church in Nigeria has seen the importance of citizens&#x2019; involvement in governance. As a result of this, the project intervention will be hinged on Social Accountability (SA) with an objective to &#x201C;give voice to the people by making them take up the responsibility of advocating for better service delivery for the well-being of all in Kaduna State&#x201D;. The project is expected to create a culture of demand and accountability from citizens on the duty bearers that will bring about participation of the citizens on issues that affects them&#x201D;.

Community based Development Associations, Traditional Rulers, Civil Society Groups and other non-state actors will be mobilised and empowered to take initiative for building engagement platforms. The engagement will strengthen participatory governance, ensure accountability and better service delivery of road infrastructure and functional health centers in Barnawa and Kakuri in Kaduna South Local Government; Sabon Tasha and Narayi in Chikun LGA and Ungwan Rimi and Doka communities in Kaduna North LGA. 

The project will leverage on the Kaduna State 2016 budget is designed to among others construct/rehabilitate rural roads and equipping 255 primary health care facilities. Some of these projects have begun while some are yet to commence. The project will have a 7 man Project Implementation Committee (PIC). It will be composed of 2 project staff, and 5 CSOs whose roles shall be to facilitate all engagements of the CDAs with the duty bearers. The PIC will also meet regularly to review and evaluate planned activities and call for action on decision taken.  The PIC will also develop terms of engagements, and facilitate the organisation of each of the town hall meetings. At the community level,  there will be 30 selected representatives of CDAs (5 from each community), made up of  males, females, boys and girls who will directly drive all engagements with duty bearers. The CDAs will monitor projects being implemented by government within their communities and ensure that allocations provided in the 2016 budget are adequately used to provide the basic services aforementioned.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR381" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NGR381" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NGR381" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-15">9352.3466</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="48799">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-26">9352.3466</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="62881">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-26">9352.35</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Caritas Foundation of Nigeria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
