<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9634</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEF-ALTYN AJYDAR CORRUGATED CARDBOARD &amp; PACKAGING</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    KYRGYZ Republic - SEF-Altyn-Azhydahar        Modernization and expansion of a corrugated cardboard production plant in the vicinity of Bishkek.        Region    Central Asia Middle East and North Africa      Sector   Project No009634   Projected Board DateJune 28, 1999   Company NameAltyn-Azhydahar   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The project will be owned and operated by Altyn-Azhydahar, a limited liability company, manufacturing corrugated cardboard.  The Company was established in 1995 by three individuals, Mr. Van Yun Chan and Mr. Lyan Mi En, who are Chinese citizens, and Mr. Pavel A. Terekhov, a Kyrgyz citizen.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	Estimated Project Cost: US$653,000   IFC is expected to provide SEF financing of up to US$300,000.    Location of project and Description of site    	The project is to be located in the vicinity of Bishkek.  The new building is to house the new equipment and will be on a newly acquired property which is in the immediate vicinity of the existing facilities.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project involves the modernization and expansion of a corrugated cardboard production plant close to Bishkek.  The production is used for cardboard packaging materials.  It is seeking up to US$300,000 to modernize and expand its manufacturing facilities to meet the anticipated growing domestic demand.    This will be IFCs first investment in general manufacturing in the Kyrgyz Republic under the Small Enterprise Fund.  This project is expected to help raise the level of technical expertise in the country&apos;&apos;s general manufacturing sector, give domestic manufacturing companies access to improved product quality, improve production efficiencies and economies of scale, and promote intra-regional trade.    Environmental Category and Issues    	&quot;This project is a Category B project according to IFCs environmental and social review procedures.  Main potential issues related are air emissions; wastewater treatment and discharge; solid waste management; workspace air quality and employee health and occupational safety.  The sponsor will only use electric power and will implement measures to ensure that there is no generation of fugitive emissions.  The process and consumption water will be obtained from the local water authority system.  Liquid effluents  will all be collected into a cesspool and sent to the municipal sewage system for final treatment.  All waste paper will continue to be packed and transported for recycling to a carton paper plant with whom the sponsor already has an agreement.  Domestic solid residues will continue to be collected and picked up by the communal services of Ken-Bulun village.   Altyn will appoint an Environmental Manager to oversee and implement the companys environmental activities and will ensure that the environmental, health and safety measures are up to date and that the employees are properly trained.  The project is being designed to comply with World Bank guidelines.&quot;    The  is  from the InfoShop.       Host country location of environmental documents    Ivanovka village, Bishkek,Kyrgyz Republic       Date SPI sent to InfoShop May 27, 1999   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KYRGYZ-CHINESE JOINT VENTURE ALTYN-AJYDAR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9634" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-09-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-02-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kyrgyz Republic</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Kyrgyz Republic">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.5000000000 75.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AG - Paper Packaging Products (Including Boxes, Cartons, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.30 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-09-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-09">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-09">300000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KYRGYZ-CHINESE JOINT VENTURE ALTYN-AJYDAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9634/sefaltyn-ajydar-corrugated-cardboard-packaging">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
