<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CA-CRA_ACR-817387277-PROJECTS-983</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CA-CRA_ACR-817387277" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mastercard Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017 SETI in Rwanda - Leading, Teaching and Learning Together in Secondary Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB will raise the effectiveness of teachers and school leaders in secondary education by improving the delivery, sustainability and institutionalization of continuous professional development services to school leaders and teachers.  This project will develop the capacity of national and local education authorities supporting teachers and school leaders. VVOB will work in partnership with the University of Rwanda&#x2019;s College of Education and the Rwanda Education Board to train Head Teachers and Deputy Head Teachers, Sector Education Officers and District Directors of Education, School Based Mentors and Heads of Department in Mathematics and Science in school leadership, peer coaching and mentoring. In addition, VVOB will support the establishment of Professional Learning Communities for teachers, led by Sector Education Officers and School Based Mentors. The VVOB program activities support the achievement of key objectives under the Secondary Education Teachers Initiative &#x201C;Train&#x201D; and &#x201C;Lead&#x201D; pillars.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand (VVOB)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11320" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-14">9599863</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
