<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CA-CRA_ACR-817387277-PROJECTS-980</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CA-CRA_ACR-817387277" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mastercard Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017 Elimu Haina Mwisho: Skills Development Program for Young Women through Folk Development Colleges</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project - Second Chance Education for Young Mothers will be implemented by Aflatoun International, a known partner that completed a successful project within our Youth Livelihoods Program. Aflatoun in partnership with Karibu Tanzania Organization, will work with 20 Tanzanian Folk Development Colleges (FDCs) to provide accredited secondary education for out of school young mothers to support their transition to higher education and life after school. Aflatoun will facilitate the training of young mothers in entrepreneurship, financial and soft skills to ensure alternative pathways to decent livelihoods. 

The anticipated impact is 2,400 young mothers to complete secondary education from 20 accredited FDCs. These FDCs will improve their processes and practices to provide quality secondary education. 7,200 young mothers who dropped out of school due to pregnancy will be informed about the second chance programs at FDCs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aflatoun</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-03">999868</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
