<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CA-CRA_ACR-817387277-PROJECTS-1250</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CA-CRA_ACR-817387277" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mastercard Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Project - Creating Decent Jobs Using the Lead Firm Model</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Lead Firm Structure for Youth Employment (LFS) interventions will enable 281,960 youth to secure direct dignified and fulfilling work. The LFs will also create indirect opportunities for another 269,739 people. This transformative approach focuses on increasing incomes of the population which will stimulate greater demand for goods and services which in turn will lead to increased production and growth at household (HH), Micro, Small and Medium Enterprise (MSME) and Lead Firm (LF) levels.  The catalyst for this transformative change is the organisation and coordination of increased production and productivity under Lead Firm Structures. The LFS aims at bringing poor excluded young women and men dominated HHs into linked economically rewarding production activities as well as catalysing and placing MSMEs on a growth path to bigger companies themselves. As the result of this, different players will together overcome production, productivity and market access (domestic and export) challenges that they individually and collectively face. Lead Firms and MSMEs will make an investment amounting $11 million as a contribution to the implementation of the LFS. This intervention will fuel income and economic growth, firm expansion and job creation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Foundation Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-27">41419513</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
