<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CA-CRA_ACR-817387277-PROJECTS-526</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CA-CRA_ACR-817387277" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mastercard Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014 Management Program - Peer-Led Leadership Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will involve a targeted group of Scholars, including (1) members of the Scholars Council and (2) graduating Scholars, in a series of interventions designed to contribute to their growth as transformative leaders. The interventions will be rooted in ethical leadership and will be organized around four distinct aspects of transformative leadership: insight; knowledge; experience; and courage. 
The Scholars who undergo the leadership interventions will be tasked with working with the wider Scholars Community in order to contribute to the leadership growth of their peers. As such, the project will have a cascade effect. 
A customized communications platform will be developed to support and sustain the leadership interventions. The platform will enable immediate communication and collaboration, as well as more long term peer mentoring and sustained motivation of the Scholars as transformative leaders. 
Finally, the project will involve an exploratory component with secondary education partners and Scholars to design a framework and proposal for a secondary school peer-led leadership development program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <sector code="11430" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-02-13">249642</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
