<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CA-CRA_ACR-817387277-PROJECTS-987</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CA-CRA_ACR-817387277" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mastercard Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017 Innovation Fund - Enabling creative and social enterprise in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective
&#x2022;	Young Ugandans benefit from skill development, certification and mentorship which will increase their opportunities for employment and entrepreneurship in the creative industries. Broader outcomes include elevated youth voice, strengthened civil society, peacebuilding and socio-economic development through arts-based enterprise.
&#x2022;	This project seeks to innovative in several ways. First, it offers the opportunity to explore youth livelihoods in African creative industries, a small but growing sector that is youth-oriented and often youth-driven, and has links to larger growth sectors, particularly hospitality/tourism and the digital economy. Second, it offers opportunity to explore whether formal, internationally-recognised short course certification enhances access to job and business opportunities for African youth with different levels of formal education.  Third, we will test whether and how the Foundation and its partners can facilitate a more flexible, modular approach to local partnership development and training. Finally, youth voice will compellingly present in the creative, cultural and artistic projects they develop, offering an opportunity for the Foundation to diversify the ways we communicate youth stories and elevate African youth expression.

Core Activities
&#x2022;	60 youth trained and certified in creative and social entrepreneurship 
&#x2022;	15 youth awarded prizes towards their enterprise idea, and an additional 20 youth receive mentoring, based on a competitive pitching process
&#x2022;	Research conducted to assess the effects of training, certification, mentoring and prize fund support</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Place of War C.I.C.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-13">99761</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
