<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CA-CRA_ACR-817387277-PROJECTS-456</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CA-CRA_ACR-817387277" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mastercard Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2013 Management Program - Facilitation Assistance for Collaboration for Impact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposal for Facilitation Assistance to pursue Collaboration for Impact Partnerships 
EARTH turns to The MasterCard Foundation for $155,000 USD in funding which will be used for staff salaries to provide additional support to EARTH&apos;s leadership team in order to plan and begin to implement  several projects with Collaboration for Impact members.   
Specifically, we would like to explore or deepen partnerships with the following organizations that are part of Collaboration for Impact:
1)	Internships and exchange programs with other academic institutions including Ashesi University in Ghana and Legatum Center at MIT in Boston , MA, USA
2)	Work study and summer internship programs between EARTH University students and Collaboration for Impact members with a particular focus on BRAC, Camfed, Technoserve, and Equity Bank. 
3)	Training for Camfed alumni and mothers programs in Camfed&apos;s 5 countries of operation and at EARTH University 
4)	Identification and recruitment of EARTH applicants across Africa
5)	Training for EARTH University students in mobile communication technologies for development facilitated by GMSA</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EARTH University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="43081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-07-22">155000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
