<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/H-Nut/NGO/17379</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency Response  for Health and  Nutrition to the  floods displaced populations through mobile medical services in Wenlaweyn district, Lower Shabelle region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of this IERT project is to increase access to essential primarily Health and Nutrition services through Four IERT mobile health and Nutrition services targeting 4250 Boys, 4350 Girls ,2250 PLW and 1150 Men beneficiaries directly affected by floods in Wenlaweyn district. The project will compromise the following activities 
1) Capacitate 28 qualified health and nutrition field staffs (15 male and 13 female) for affective management of acute malnutrition and IYCF counselling
 2) Increase access to essential primary health care services for hard-to-reach floods displaced populations through supporting Four  outreach health and Nutrition team with Emergency medical supplies 
3) Provide Health education awareness to the community Members , Social Mobilization of communicable and non-communicable diseases including pneumonia, malaria, diarrhea, measles, skin conditions, injury care in children and urinary tract infections among others.
 4) Provide quality and safe routine and supplementary immunization to 8600 children under the age of five years 4250 Boys, 4350 Girls, 1150 Women of child bearing age in Wanlaweyn dist 
5) Integration of mental health, psychosocial support consultations, AWD outbreak early warning, response (EWAR) and case management of epidemic prone diseases.
 6) Community Workers Screening to 4,250 boys, 4,350 girls and provide RUFT to (15%) out of severely malnourished lt5 children boys,girls without medical complications and moderately malnourished pregnant and lactating women(1250) in Wenlaweyn IDPs through Four OTP/health Mobile, hence the complicated cases of severely malnourished under five children will be transfer to Wenlaweyn and Afgoye hospitals.
 7) IYCF/E Support for care givers  best practices, Nutrition, health and hygiene promotion (NHHP) as well as treatment of Children U5(Sam) with out medical complications through Outreach therapeutic treatment
Through this project, Health, Nutrition activities will be integrated with child protection and health activities in the nearby areas of Wenlaweyn districts in the sense that under five children boys, girls admitted at the OTP/health Mobile sites will be able to access immunization services against measles and other vaccine preventable disease ,Vitamin A and Multiple micronutrient supplementation and as well the SAM complicated cases referred to the stabilization centers for proper medical treatment while GBV cases among children are referred to GBV AoR in the same location. On the same note, mothers visiting ANC/PNC (Antenatal Care, Postnatal Care) at the mobile clinic will access both NHHP/IYCF-E and shall be able to receive hygiene promotions messages through community health workers on Nutrition, hygiene and health promotion. AYUUB will provide Mothers MUAC led sessions at the Mobile outpatient therapeutic centers to ensure that mothers gain knowledge and skills in undertaking MUAC measurement on their own.  This will ensure increased community caregivers&#x2019; knowledge as well as provide localized way of doing things differently. However, AYUUB will coordinate with MOH (Ministry of Health) SWS as well as the Nutrition Cluster to coordinate response activities for maximum impact to beneficiaries. AYUUB shall also coordinates with other local actors in the target district to avoid any duplication of services as well as promote coordinated response to increase access to life-saving emergency Health and Nutrition response to the floods affected population in the locations of Malable, Shanta Kulan, Cagaboore, Bakaal, Hakaba, Haakaaw,tendhada, Xudurweyn, Geed Kaama Dambeeyo, Lafoole, Caanoole, Baaraan, Maynuun, Daarusalaam, Awdiirow, Kontoroolka, Waaberi and Muuri of Wanlaweyn Districts in Lower Shabelle region by establishing 4 Mobile teams (Health and Nutrition) and each Mobile team will compromise 1 Clinical officer, 1 Nurse, 1 Midwife, 1 Auxilary Nurses, 1 Registers, 1 IYCF/Community mobilizer and 1 vaccinator.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Hassan Shariif</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615598290</telephone>
   <email>ayuubcenter@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Yusuf Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615815907</telephone>
   <email>ayuubngo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">93437.65</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">126201.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17379">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">219639.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304783715">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-09">175711.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
