<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/CCCM-Prot/NGO/15428</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated Emergency Support Through Protection, CCCM, WASH, and Shelter Interventions in Deynille and Kaxda IDP Settlements.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed integrated response aims to respond to the urgent needs of IDPs in Kaxda and Deynille through the implementation of Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM), WASH, Protection and Shelter/NFIs activities. NoFYL will implement a multi-cluster intervention around Protection and CCCM aiming at strengthening coordination structures, improving the coordination, community-led site maintenance activities to ensure the upkeep of sites, support governance structures to ensure community participation and self-management of sites and information management at a site level, sites improvement activities to minimize protection risks and ensure safety in sites. 
On protection, the intervention is geared toward preventing and responding to eviction, monitoring of threats to evictions by assessing potential eviction sites, monitoring, documentation and reporting to relevant authorities and relevant clusters to mobilize support for advocacy. The advocacy and campaigns will aim to ensure actors facilitate lawful eviction processes. Capacity development targeting settlement managers, local authorities on Housing, Land and proper protection monitoring through ensuring collection of information based on the methodology of the Somalia Protection Monitoring System (SPMS). WASH intervention will be complemented by PAH through the distribution of complete kits of hygiene, capacity building of water committees and community hygiene promotion through community outreach and awareness campaigns, addressing sustainable access to water, hygiene, and capacity building needs. ESNFI intervention will be complemented by HINNA by improving the IDPs living conditions through the distribution of emergency NFI kits and emergency shelter kits.

At the initial stages of project implementation, the partners will organize an inception meeting with different actors with the support of the relevant cluster Coordinators. Rapid service mapping of actors will also be conducted to understand who is doing what and where to inform intervention areas and avoid duplication. NoFYL field teams shall actively participate in coordination mechanisms in Kaxda and Deynille to ensure other actors are updated on NoFYL plans in targeted districts to avoid overlap. This project will fill existing gaps in ESNFI, CCCM, Protection, and WASH support and complement activities undertaken under other ongoing projects. NoFYL will carry out post-distribution monitoring utilizing a tailored PDM tool in all targeted locations within 1 month of each assistance intervention sampling 20-30% of beneficiaries in each location. 
 
NoFYL, PAH and HINNA will implement these activities in 15 IDP sites in Deynille and Kaxda, targeting the most underserved area home to most newly displaced drought IDPs in the same sites to enhance the delivery of protection services as a complement to the other activities. 4,064 households, approximately 24,384 people (3,283 male, 4,886 female, 6,505 boys and 9,710 girls) will benefit from this intervention, as well as the whole community working in these 41 IDP sites including local authorities, clusters, and other organizations. The multi-sectoral approach will be useful to create synergies enabling the concentration of services and expertise within the same location and the same population leading to achieving a greater impact.
 
The three partners (NoFYL, PAH and HINNA) will build on each other strengths and better complement each other to ensure community acceptance and success in implementation. The synergy between the 3 sectoral partners will ensure sound management of the program, greater impact, efficiency, and more cost-effective operations. The project target sites includes the following

Deynille - Yaagle camp, Igadabagey, Bacaad, Alle suge, Shidane k7, walaalaha, Wanaagsan, Ramaas, Taad, Iskaashi IDP camps
Kaxda - Owbaale 1, Jimale 1, Bananey, Waraanle, Rabisuge, and Mudan IDP camps.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Musa Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616345252</telephone>
   <email>a.musa@nofyl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mustafa Abdullahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252618416874</telephone>
   <email>mabdi@nofyl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-14">476057.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-14">294609.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15428">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-14">770666.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304612410">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-21">308266.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304792783">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-18">231199.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304956200">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">231199.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
