<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/WASH/NGO/15251</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of sustainable life-saving WASH assistance to the most vulnerable drought and AWD affected communities in Eyl , Nugaal region,  Puntland</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recent WASH assessment report conducted by KAALO in Nugaal region in December 2019 indicated that  65% of the assessed households (700HHs) did not meet the minimum recommended sphere standards of 7.5L/day. Villages settlements assessed including shale, Qarxis, Eyl and Canjeel, budunbuto villages and host communities (32%) are facing insufficient access to safe drinking water to cover all family water needs and 84% primarily rely on unprotected water sources. IDPs (98%) and host communities (54%) have no sufficient access to hygiene commodities (soap, detergent, etc.). 86% have insufficient access to latrines and bathing areas. Many households practice open defecation due to the lack of latrines. Thus, people Use of unprotected water points and berkeds.  transportation of water is done  by donkeys and camels exposing to water borne disease . 
The proposed project is to response the existing WASH gaps to drought and vulnerable  affected people in Eyl district in Nugaal region, KAALO proposes to provide WASH interventions mainly increasing access to water and improvement of hygiene and sanitation standards to the target groups men, women and children during this critical period of water shortage and Acute Water Diarrhea (AWD) risks in providing safe water and good sanitation practices through: (1) Rehabilitating of two (2) spring water points equipped with hybrid system in Eyl districts in Nugaal region respectively. (2) Rehabilitation of (7) berkads through rehabilitation of cracks and provide roof to protect dust and animals to get in and will protect water contamination hence reduced  AWD cases . 3)Provide emergency water for voucher to 1000 drought-affected households. Each household will receive voucher redeemed, number of persons/hh x 7.5 lt/person/day for 30 days. (4) WASH committees and well operators will be trained  on management amp maintenance and Disaster Risk Reduction to keep the sustainability of the rehabilitated water infrastructures ,a  total of 9 wash committees will be trained, each facility will have one wash committee . KAALO will target the most affected people with equal access to boys, girls, men and women. (5) Construction of 50 gender separated latrines with washing basin and lockable doors for privatization purpose. Sensitization within members of WASH committees are needed, 6)community education activities on hygiene practices will be widely used to promote greater hygiene promotion and key messages on  COVID-9 risks in Somalia. 7) Distribute 1000 HP kits to 1000 households (6000 PEOPLE ) who are at risk of AWD and malnutrition. Each HP kit consists (1 jerry can (20L), 1 bucket (20L), 3 bars of 800mg of soap ,1 menstrual hygiene and 200 aqua tabs).KAALO will ensure that the proposed WASH project will be fully in line with WASH cluster strategy and also will build the existing market system in Nugaal region and create job creation for beneficiaries including IDs.. Distribution of sanitation tools to at 5 IDP camps to reduce AWD cholera and COVID 19, This activities will support environmental sanitation. Each IDP camp will be allocated 6 sanitation tools and each tool comprises 1 wheelbarrow, 1 pickaxe, 1 rake, 2 shovel, 2 brooms, 1 box of gloves and 1 box of nose mask). The sanitation tools will be under the custody of IDP leaders or gate keepers and used only during the clean-up environmental campaigns in camps. The IDPs  will undertake environmental sanitation campaign using the distributed sanitation tools and Kaalo CHPs will support and monitors and report the voluntary-based clean up campaigns, especially in IDP settlements and its environments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAALO Aid and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAALO Aid and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Omar Shiikh Hamid</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 907793964</telephone>
   <email>Omarshiikh001@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9673">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nugaal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.20900000 48.84600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-21">333991.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-21">164258.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15251">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-21">498249.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAALO Aid and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304617933">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-29">298949.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAALO Aid and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304947020">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-22">199300</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAALO Aid and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
