<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/Nut/INGO/15156</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve equitable access to safe quality curative and preventive nutrition services for the conflict and drought affected vulnerable population in Hudun district of Sool Region aimed at reducing avoidable morbidity and mortality</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed 12-month nutrition program builds on the successful model of ARC&#x2019;s current emergency health and nutrition programming in Sool region, the proposed project will complement the ongoing UNICEF and OFDA support in Hudun district. This intervention will enhance continuation of ongoing life-saving assistance while ensuring access to essential and quality nutrition services for displaced and vulnerable host communities in a manner that is accountable, conflict-sensitive and supports the Ministry of Health and Development (MOHD) responsibilities. ARC coordinates with the MOHD Nutrition sector and Regional Medical Team in providing Nutrition services that is integrated with health/WASH with mainstreamed protection supported by UNHCR

The project coordinate close with UNICF, WFP and deepens ARC&apos;s humanitarian response in hot spots and hard to reach locations, building on ARC&apos;s current programming experience. The proposed critical life-saving response will be carried out through support to 3MCHs that includesLafweyne, Huddun and Awrbogeys MCH and 2 outrreach teams serving 13 villages  in Hudun districts expanding nutrition outreach capacity in areas where no other actors exist. the proposed intervention will Screen children for malnutrition and malnourished children (6-59) referred by CNW to appropriate programme (TSFP/OTP, SC) for treatment. The fixed nutrition/health sites and mobile teams will provide at least 5 out of 9 BNSP components. This will allow ARC to treat  2,428 children with MAM and  816 children(6-59 months) with SAM, including 60 with medical complication treated by April 2021. ARC has PCA with UNICEF/WFP will provide all the supplies needed for treatment in-kind, Promote, enable and sustain behavior change related to improve infant and young child feeding (IYCF-E), ARC started engaging UNICEF and WFP for proposed project supplies. ARC will implement family -led MUAC approach and train community health workers on IYCF -E, Capacity building on the revised IMAM guideline for 19 nutrition health staff and Improve reporting, monitoring and report regular reporting. All health/nutrition sites will report monthly statistical data through DHIS/ONA to the government, health and nutrition cluster


The nutrition situation in Hudun district continues to deteriorate further without humanitarian assistance. Post deyr 2019 FSNAU indicated that Sool region has high caseloads of acute malnourished children, with estimated caseloads of 26,900. From the total caseloads estimated, 4,300 were severely malnourished with higher risk of medical complications and death. To address this situation, ARC will improve access and provide nutrition services to children aged 0-59 months, Pregnant and Lactating Women with acute malnutrition through detection, treatment and referral of complicated cases to the stabilization centers. Priority activities will include: Training of Community Volunteers in identification/referral of malnutrition cases, and mothers trained in mother-led MUAC Provision of Outpatient Therapeutic Feeding for 3,244 children aged 6-59 months with SAM and Targeted Supplementary Feeding Program for MAM and 5,418 PLWs. Community members including women of all age groups, men of all age groups, all the race and gender will be engaged to directly influence the project through the life-cycle of the project creating a platform to share information with recommendations that is used to further guide the program performance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wardere Hassan Abdikarim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Cordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+262618943469</telephone>
   <email>Warderea@arcrelief.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">234616.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">115385.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15156">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">350002.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304605463">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-15">210001.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304947019">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-22">140000.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
