<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/SA1/WASH/INGO/15396</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH response for drought affected communities in Eyl district Nugaal region, Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to water supply and improved hygiene and sanitation practices are major components of the overall Water Sector programme  aimed to reduce child mortality and morbidity in Somalia and hence a key constituent of this project. The response will provide comprehensive WASH services in  Eyl district, saving lives by meeting Sphere standards/Somalia WASH Cluster Strategic Operational Framework through gender-sensitive services, contributing to overall health and disease prevention of IDP and rural communities. The project targets floods, cyclone and conflict affected populations (Internally displaced persons, Pastoralists communities and host communities.)  The project is designed to meet the needs of PAWAN cyclone affected populations in Eyl district of Nugaal region, Puntland Somalia. The project aims to reach 15,000 (3,000men, 3,750 women, 3,750 boys and 4,500 girls)
The WASH response will reduce health risks through hygiene promotion campaigns in communities while using participatory approaches. Responses will prioritize needs of women, girls and vulnerable people, include environmental safeguards to prevent degradation from humanitarian operations and afford affected people dignity and choice through Cash and Vouchers Assistance (CVA). A total 1500 women and girls will be supported through restricted CVA for hygiene/dignity items ensuring that women and girls can access preferred items for MHM and incontinence. Gender-segregated latrines (120 with locks and hand washing facilities) will be constructed and will include units accessible for people with disabilities limiting open defecation. Immediate water access will be ensured through durable solutions such as rehabilitation  and  construction and expansion of 2 water supply and improved subsurface dams/ 5 berkards are put in place. Gender-balanced WASH committees(2) will be supported to maintain facilities. In regard t improving protection environment of vulnerable groups 885 solar lamps will be distributed to enhance access to facilities
Delivery of services will  further prioritize inclusion, participation of and accountability to affected populations. Integrated response will provide holistic aid that can respond rapidly to emerging needs, and this multi-year response will increase communities&#x2019; resilience to future shocks. The project will strengthen capacities through training of water committees, hygiene promoters and general hygiene awareness campaigns including environmental sanitation to influence behaviour change and achieve adoption of appropriate hygiene and sanitation practices. 
The project will make deliberate effort to maintain a protective environment throughout its interventions so that girls and women in particular are not exposed to harm such as sexual and gender-based violence while accessing WASH services. Further, gender equity will be observed while implementing all project activities. Men, women, Boys and Girls will be treated equally with their different needs being targeted and support provided accordingly. Women will be fronted to participate in decision making structures like the community WASH committees where they will be involved in project monitoring efforts.
NCA will work closely with the existing local administration and community structures such as religious leaders, clan and community elders, minorities&#x2019; women group and youth networks, men, women, girls and boys from IDPs community to accommodate the most vulnerable communities and will ensure inclusiveness, accountability and transparency.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enzo Vecchio</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Representaive</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254734585685</telephone>
   <email>enzo.vecchio@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rispa Were</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH and Protection Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722276718</telephone>
   <email>rispa.were@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9673">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nugaal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.20900000 48.84600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">308172.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">171206.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-15396">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-06">479379.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304604116">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-14">287627.7</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
