<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/Prot/INGO/17330</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 Flood Response Protection Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Displacement, cramped living conditions and other related stressors following flooding all serve to exacerbate tensions and increase violence in the home and in communities, with women and girls most at risk. With an increase in Gender Based Violence following flooding in Beledweyne and Afgooye, there is an urgent need to improve access to quality multi-sectorial support for survivors and enhance community based protection mechanisms.  
To address this, RI will run two Women and Girl Safe Spaces (WGSS) in Beletwyne and Afgooye. One of the WGSS will be static located within a health facility in Afgooye and the other WGSS in Beletwyne will be mobile in nature and linked to one of RI supported static WGSSs at the health facilities for referrals and further support of the survivors. RI is running 4 static WGSS in Beletwyne with support of UNFPA. The Mobile WGSS will be able to reach out to higher grounds where communities have relocated yet cannot access the static WGSS facilities. Approximately 400 women and girls will be reached with advocacy, PSS, referral, case management and material support. 
Both static and Mobile WGSS will be staffed with female and male GBV staff, CHWs and medical staff who will provide GBV response and services to targeted communities. While the medical team will be responding to offering GBV related medical treatment, the GBV staff will run both men and women sessions separately while the CHWs will be conducting door to door GBV awareness and provide avenues for safe reporting of GBV and referrals to Mobile unit team for medical, PSS and case management. WGSS staff will provide survivor centred case management through PFA, medical treatment and facilitating referrals for other services. In addition, the WGGS will serve as a place where women and men meet weekly to get information on GBV prevention and response and establish social support groups where they share and learn from each other. The WGSS are designed with the specific needs of women and girls to have the space they need to be able to voice their concerns and needs in regards to issues that affect them personally.
RI will update and strengthen already existing linkages with other GBV service providers for referral purposes and to ensure survivors and those at risk are able to access quality multi-sectoral services as needed with RI providing support and follow-up on all cases. RI will work with community health workers to ensure they have the necessary skills and understanding to identify GBV cases and make appropriate referrals. 
To enhance community-based protection mechanisms, RI will work with all members of communities, including both IDPs and Host Community members women, men, boys and girls, and community/ religious leaders. Activities will include awareness campaigns, advocacy platforms, community protection audits and trainings. 
The project is expected to reach 5,989 direct beneficiaries (3,929 female and 2,060 male) and 93, 545 indirect beneficiaries. Approximately 50 (20 girls and women) will be engaged in GBV safety audit and action planning in their communities. 4,000 (1,220girls,1,260 women, 800 boys and 720 men) will be reached through door to door community outreach and over 25,000 reached through GBV radio advocacy and awareness creation. 450 dignity kits and 250 emergency support kits and 2000 sanitary kits will be distributed. Approximately 150 GBV survivors will be supported to access survivor centered multi-sectorial response and material support. A total of 25 religious leaders will be engaged in GBV advocacy and 14 (9 female) clinical and non-clinical staff will be trained on GBV response including Clinical Management of Rape (CMR), Psychological First Aid (PFA), and Psychosocial Support (PSS) and GBV Case management. Through the two WGSS, a total of 800(400 women and girls) will be reached through weekly GBV prevention and response sessions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fatuma Abdilahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254719859784</telephone>
   <email>fatuma.abdilahi@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kevin Raabe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254757129108</telephone>
   <email>kevin.raabe@ri.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">74205.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">126260.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17330">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-03">200466.77</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304783714">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-09">160373.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305109841">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-26">40075.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
