<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-20/3485/RA1/CCCM/NGO/17368</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Essential Camp Coordination and Camp Management services and Protection of Sites residents in Floods affected Daynile, Banadir Region and Afgooye Districts Lower Shabelle</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In summary, this project proposes to contribute to three core aspects of Camp Coordination and Camp Management in Daynille District and spontaneous settlements in the Afgooye District, including leading essential coordination functions, developing and maintaining camp infrastructures that have been devastated by recent flooding.establishing/Rehabilitating/Enhancing drainage systems in IDP sites through incentivized workdays carried out by site-level site maintenance committees, and promoting humanitarian accountability through the operation of feedback and complaint mechanisms. Moreover, this project will also focus on building the capacities of the IDP leadership and local actors to gradually take over the camp management responsibilities. 

NoFYL will conduct the basic care and maintenance of the camps in Daynille District and spontaneous settlements in the Afgooye District the upcoming care and maintenance phase presents a different range of challenges, requiring strong humanitarian leadership and very close engagement with the population to promote community ownership and empowerment, as well as the gradual transfer of responsibility for the care of the site infrastructure. NoFYL will continue to work regularly with IDP camp leadership and committees to strengthen collaboration and their participation in decision-making processes, while also striving to improve diversity in representation and gender balance in the governance structure. As NoFYL anticipates, new arrivals will continue to seek shelter within the sites and spontaneous settlements throughout the project period, NoFYL&apos;s Camp Management team will support this population with reception and conduct site verification monthly. The quarterly Site Verification exercise in Afgoye district will be conducted to provide multi-sector information on access and availability to basic services in the floods affected sites to ascertain gaps in service provision and monitor services being provided, the verification will be conducted by NoFYL&apos;s multi-functional mobile teams, this will help to produce detailed information on the population of each site, its perimeter, access and services available in sites. NoFYL will use this data and contribute to its dissemination in order to inform humanitarian response at each level.

This overarching objective will be achieved by enhancing the overall protective environment for flood-affected population, increasing access to basic services linked to different sectors, reducing the risk, and availing specialized support assistance to beneficiaries to help them address other interconnected protection concerns. The action is also conceptualized to consolidate the ongoing humanitarian response to the flood situation in the targeted locations. Through this grant, NoFYL will reach 1,550 HHs in 8 umbrella Camps (considering minimum 180 HHs per settlement) with a total target beneficiary of 12,400 in Daynille and  Afgooye districts with necessary services through a coordination mechanism set in place with relevant stakeholders and other partners.

This project will also be linked to this ongoing protection/HLP activities through monitoring, documentation, and reporting of threats to evictions by assessing potential eviction sites, preventing and responding to eviction. Capacity development targeting settlement managers, CMCs, and local authorities on Housing, Land, and proper protection monitoring through ensuring collection of information based on the methodology of the Somalia Protection Monitoring System (SPMS).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Musa Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616345252</telephone>
   <email>a.musa@nofyl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mustafa Abdullahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252618416874</telephone>
   <email>mabdi@nofyl.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-11">55295.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-11">74684.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-17368">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-11">129979.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304795818">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-19">77987.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Frontier Youth League</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
