<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-1624114-DCF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralised Climate Funds</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRACED aims to create more effective climate adaptation planning and finance by local governments in Mali and Senegal, which will improve communities&#x2019; resilience to climate change. In partnership with national and local governments, the project will pilot six devolved decision-making and funding mechanisms  in four D&#xE9;partements and three Cercles in Senegal and Mali, respectively, to fund community-prioritized, public good investments that directly build the resilience of 750,000 local people to climate variability and extreme events. The pilot will deliver national policy  and improve readiness of local government to draw down, and national government to disburse, global climate finance in support of local adaptation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DCF</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved resilience to climate change will be accomplished through achievement of the following objectives:
(1) Investment in local, community-prioritized adaptation; 
(2) Improved climate resilience planning, including use of climate information; 
(3) Improved local government capacity to distribute devolved climate financing; 
(4) Encouraging national governments to adopt reforms that are supportive of local resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Mali and Senegal, climate extremes manifest in droughts, floods and, in Senegal, wildfires. Climate data analysis indicates increases in total rainfall in Mopti (Mali) and Koungheul (Senegal) from mid 90s to present, with &#x201C;no trend&#x201D; at nearby stations of Douentza (Mali) and Kaffrine (Senegal), although rainfall records there are incomplete. Maximum temperatures are on an upward trend, and minimum temperatures are also increasing. Extreme variability from year to year is still the norm, which makes long-term climate trends difficult to establish statistically. Climate remains characterized by great inter-annual and rainy season variability, including late onset and/or early termination of rains, significant gaps between &#x2018;useful&#x2019; rainy days, and violent late-season storms.

Climate extremes challenge the ability of vulnerable people to prosper and, in some cases, to survive. In 2011, for example, rainfall in Mali was 40% less than the 10-year average, resulting in low crop production and leaving 60% of households dependent on humanitarian food aid. Flash floods after heavy rainfall, such as those in Kaffrine in 2013, displace people, put them at risk for physical harm, flood productive areas and destroy crops and infrastructure. In Kaffrine, wildfires are a recurrent and increasingly frequent phenomena, causing significant damage to dry season grazing, stored crops and vegetative cover, and damaging the capacity for soil regeneration. 

For targeted areas, climate change is expected to yield further increase in temperature, increased frequency and severity of drought and increasingly unpredictable and frequent floods. These effects are expected to have major impacts on food security for rural populations.  

In the Mopti Region (Mali), 98% of the population are farmers and agro-pastoralists. In the wetlands of the Cercle of Mopti, households combine irrigated and flood-recession family farming with some commercial agriculture, pastoralism and fishing. In the semi-arid and arid Cercles of Koro and Douentza and the Kaffrine Region (Senegal), production systems rely on rainfed cultivation, some irrigation, pastoralism, forestry and seasonal migration. Unpredictable rainfall, combined with periodic drought, undermines crop productivity and pasture regeneration, placing longer-term pressure on tree resources as poor households harvest wood and non-timber forest products (NTFP) to survive. Impacts on trees and shrubs adversely affect women and girls, who are responsible for collection of firewood and NTFP. For fishing communities, low water levels and dried up riverbeds reduce fish production. Transhumant herders find it difficult to maintain seasonal rights to grazing and passage on grasslands and floodplain pastures, which are increasingly occupied by expanding cultivation. 

Successive years of low agricultural or pastoral productivity due to erratic rainfall patterns and drought erode communities&#x2019; asset base (e.g.. livestock, cereal stores) thereby undermining their short-term food security and longer-term capacity to cope with climate extremes and rebuild sustainable livelihoods in years of improved rainfall. Chronic malnutrition affects 32.3% of the population in the Mopti region (Mali) and 24% in Kaffrine region (Senegal). To cope with reduced income from cash crops and commercial ventures, agro-pastoralists increasingly turn to labor migration to diversify their livelihood portfolios. 

Food and income insecurity in the targeted areas impacts women and girls more intensely than men. Women and youth, who are socially and politically marginalized, are particularly vulnerable to climate extremes because of unequal access to common resources. Women are typically responsible for ensuring family food security but lack control over assets and agricultural inputs. Intra-household food allocations mean that during shortages, women and girls generally eat last, receive less food with lower nutritional value. Women are responsible for collecting water and firewood for cooking, but dwindling ground water and scarce surface water resources mean that women must travel greater distances to find water or use less water for basic hygiene and sanitation. Access to deep (pumped) wells may require unaffordable payments to Water User Associations. When men migrate to find work, women and children left behind may experience increased burdens and income/food insecurity, but these impacts are not well documented &#x2013; the implications of migration on households will be included in the resilience assessments undertaken at the beginning of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy development through participatory action and learning with key stakeholders is a cornerstone of project design and sustainability. The project will pursue a multi-pronged strategy with communities and national and local governments to share changes that increase their capacity to build resilience to climate extremes through the CAFs. 

The project seeks to build local ownership and national acceptance of decentralized CAF mechanisms so that they become institutionalized and used widely. By focusing on institutional development and strengthening local capacity, the project will ensure that financing mechanisms can function independently of BRACED in the future. The project will foster buy-in for change by demonstrating that empowered local leadership is central to effective adaptation and resilience investments over time and that viable approaches exist for this approach at scale. 

The project will deliver on key national climate change and development policy objectives by introducing reforms that work through and strengthen, rather than replace, existing government systems consistent with national policy and legislation. Two pillars of this strategy are (i) working with and through local governments to identify policy and institutional changes required to build resilience to climate extremes, and (ii) closely engaging AEDD and CSE in the project. 

Seconding project staff to local governments and providing training and technical support to government staff will further build local capacity for continued implementation. This principle has also been followed during the PDG phase, when relevant policy stakeholders were actively involved in the design and leaning process. 

Through this participatory action-learning process, we expect to generate lessons around: (1) institutional linkages and financial transfer mechanisms from global funds to local decentralized government; (2) decentralized governments&#x2019; ability to program inclusive investments for climate adaptation in favor of vulnerable groups (especially women and children); (3) accountability, transparency and effectiveness in delivering adaptation investments locally; and (4) the nature and effectiveness of resilience investments that provide enhanced value for money. These lessons will be important to ensure replicability by government (not project-based) systems in Mali and Senegal as well as in other arid/semi-arid environments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="9" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The people of Mali&#x2019;s Mopti Region and Senegal&#x2019;s Kaffrine Region are vulnerable to climate extremes because of their strong dependence on natural resources, poor development infrastructure and the limited institutional, technological and financial capacity of local governments to manage climatic shocks and stresses and to support local adaptive strategies. 

Local governments in Mali and Senegal have limited capacity to build resilience to climate stresses. Existing centralized planning mechanisms (a) are inflexible, top-down, and fragmented across sectors, (b) evidence poor understanding of local coping strategies, (c) reflect limited use of climate information to ensure &#x2018;climate smart&#x2019; investments and (d) poorly integrate sustainable development planning with DRR or climate risk management. Further, despite strong evidence that resilient productivity and adaptability are part of rural communities&#x2019; livelihoods and institutions, stronger political and economic interests have captured planning systems that do not adequately reflect community adaptation strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will produce four outputs through a number of activities:

Output 1: Vulnerable communities in three Cercles (Mali) and four D&#xE9;partements (Senegal) benefit from public good investments that build resilience. 
(A) Convene multi-stakeholder meetings in each Cercle/D&#xE9;partement to build common project vision.
(B) Establish climate Adaptation Planning Committees at the Commune/CR level to prioritize investments in public goods aimed at strengthening local adaptation and resilience and, once awarded, implement projects, and at the Cercle/D&#xE9;partement level to provide oversight on CAPC proposals for resilience investments.
(C) Build local government capacity on climate change science, policy and implications for local economies/ecosystems; participatory budgeting that prioritizes women and children; conducting resilience assessments; risk management; and managing and monitoring projects.
(D) Conduct Resilience Assessments (RA) to assess vulnerability, stresses and local adaptation strategies and capacities (differentiated by livelihood group, age and gender, with an emphasis on risks specific to women and children). CAPCs will conduct RAs with support from local government planners and project staff. 
(E) Radio broadcasts to disseminate climate information and promote participation in project activities and government planning. 

Output 2: Devolved finance and planning mechanisms are established and functional in three Cercles (Mali) and four d&#xE9;partements (Senegal) to support community-prioritized investments in public goods that build climate resilience.
(A) Mainstream socially inclusive resilience planning into existing systems
(B) Expand Climate Information Services (CIS). CIS will be extended to Mopti and Kaffrine regions through a multi-stakeholder platform, linked to existing national systems.
(C) Establish six Climate Adaptation Funds. Three CAFs (&#xA3;500,000 each) will be established in each country. In Mali, each Cercle will have a CAF. In Senegal, two CAFs will be inter-municipal and a third fund, competitive among the 4 D&#xE9;partements, will be managed by a RAPC. 
In Years 1 and 2, NEF/IED-Afrique will co-manage CAFs to ensure oversight and accountability. In Year 3, control over CAFs will pass fully to local governments.
(D) Ensure capacity of adaptation planning committees to manage funds. CAFs will conform to public finance policy and law, have the necessary fiduciary controls to ensure value for money and accountability, and complement local government development budgets. An auditing company will train CAPC, APC, and RAPCs.

Output 3: Evidence and learning on the effectiveness of decentralized climate finance investments to improve communities&#x2019; resilience is generated and disseminated.
(A) Generate project learning through action research. Studies will include RAs, effectiveness of local government planning in building resilience, and economic profiles of each Cercle/D&#xE9;partement. Learning will focus on project experience with devolved funding, tools that enable existing planning systems to identify public-good resilience investments, and the contribution of adaptation to delivering more resilient livelihoods and economies. The project will also support Cercle/D&#xE9;partements to design a research agenda, enabling them to commission research that supports planning and investments for climate resilient growth and development.
(B) Develop local capacity for monitoring and evaluation. In addition to project M&amp;E, the project will build the capacity of local government to monitor and evaluate resilience (building on RAs, Activity 1.1.4). The M&amp;E system will be designed to track BRACED and appropriate TAMD indicators.

Output 4: Mechanisms and processes established for national governments to engage with locally generated evidence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will reach 750,000 people through CAF-funded resilience projects &#x2013; approximately 250,000 in Senegal and 500,000 in Mali. Through the CAF, we expect to fund approximately 75 projects reaching an average of 10,000 people per project. Tis equals 50% of the total population in the targeted areas.

Target communities in Mali and Senegal were selected based on their exposure to climate extremes, chronic food deficits, high levels of poverty, and territorial connectivity and variation in ecological zones to facilitate collaboration and learning on natural resource management between communes/CR. Additionally, partners have long-established relationships in these communities, providing a foundation of knowledge, trust and credibility that will facilitate beneficiary participation and successful project implementation.

In Mali, NEF will work in 24 communes in Mopti Region, in the three Cercles of Douentza, Koro, and Mopti. The poverty rate is 72% in these Cercles. Agro-pastoralists and farmers (98% of the population) practice a combination of irrigated and flood recession farming, rainfed millet farming, pastoralism, fishing, and agroforestry. In Senegal, IED-Afrique will work in Kaffrine Region, in the four D&#xE9;partements of Kaffrine, Koungheul, Maleme Hoddar, and Birkilane, which include 28 CRs. The region&#x2019;s poverty rate (63.8%) is significantly higher than the national average (47.6%). Rainfed agriculture, spring-fed crop irrigation, pastoralism, agroforestry and seasonal migration dominate local economic activity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="None" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IIED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="None" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovations-Environnement-D&#xE9;veloppement Afrique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="6261" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yacouba Deme</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director and Regional Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>ydeme@neareast.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="59.7"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="40.3"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.105202 -15.5415755</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.4874284 -4.1974627</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">1139149</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">3047570</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-31">2442363</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-24">142512</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-31">194522</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">2779297</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-05-27">225072.9</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-01">290000</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-05">420885.43</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-22">202051.01</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-04">199862.69</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-19">1000000</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-08">284610.09</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-13">253064.58</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SGD" value-date="2016-11-02">1000000</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-18">323785.89</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-29">268120.22</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-21">407985.14</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-30">161750</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-21">298876.55</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-14">420926.59</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-28">162362.7</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">36136.46</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-22">747210</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-29">121125.28</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-22">257206.13</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-12">257363.78</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-14">343968.83</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-30">220819.57</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">483333</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">657770</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-05-20">92230</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development UK</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-13-1624114" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Near East Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://www.neareast.org/download/materials_center/DCF_Factsheet_English.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DCF Factsheet</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://www.neareast.org/download/materials_center/DCF-infographic-GEN-ENG.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralizing Climate Adaptation Funds Graphic</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://vimeo.com/187675535">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralizing Climate Funds Video</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/6261/Project_6261_current_image_2017-07-05_16.13.05.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="GB-1-202921" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Vulnerable communities in 3 cercles and 4 d&#xE9;partements in Mali and Senegal improve their resilience to climate extremes</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1: Number of people whose resilience has improved in the seven cercles and d&#xE9;partements in Mali and Senegal as a result of BRACED support</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">950 000 people are more resilient in the area targeted by the public good investment. Endline household survey in communities. Categorisation exercises what % of households fall into each category compared to baseline. Survey conducted in representative sample with individuals.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">**Baseline data:**

**&#x2022; Level of resilience / 5 (self-evaluation): Male: 2.71, Female: 2.38, Average: 2.54**

&#x2022; Level of resilience by type of investment:

Mali: Drinking water additions (Male: 3.28; Female: 3.15), Vegetable gardens (Male: 2.96; Female: 2.71), Runway development/erosion control (Male 2.40; Female 2.10), Rice perimeters (Male 2.98; Female 2.47), Pond landscaping (Male: 2.84; Female: 2.28)

Senegal: Drinking water additions (Male: 2.26; Female: 2.20), Food processing units (Male: 2.57; Female: 2.19); Reforestry (Male 2.69; Female 2.08); Vaccination parks (Male: 2.85; Female: 2.20); School (Male: 2.76; Female: 2.41); Grain stores (Male: 2.12; Female: 2.18); Vegetable gardens (Male: 2.27; Female: 2.23)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="950,000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1099048.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 1,099,048 people are more resilient in the area targeted by the public good investment. 

&#x2022; Level of resilience / 5 (self-evaluation): Male: 2.7, Female: 2.54 Average: 2.62

&#x2022; Level of resilience by type of investment:
Mali: Drinking water additions (Male: 2.62; Female: N/A), Vegetable gardens (Male: 3.04; Female: 3.93), Runway development/erosion control (Male 3.64; Female 3.62), Rice perimeters (Male 2.9; Female 2.81), Pond landscaping (Male: 1.98; Female: 2.03)
Senegal: Drinking water additions (Male: 2.15; Female: 2.18), Food processing units (Male: 2.69; Female: 2.53); Reforestry (Male 3.06; Female 2.78); Vaccination parks (Male: 2.71; Female: 2.61); School (Male: 2.62; Female: 2.03); Grain stores (Male: 2.41; Female: 2.25); Vegetable gardens (Male: 2.86; Female: 2.56)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 2: Number of localities in which the use of climate information to inform responses to climate extremes has improved</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">7 LAs have moved at least 10% compared to Y3 scores on their climate information use defined in the TAMD scorecard adjusted for each LA. Y3 scores:

++Climate change integrated into planning:++

**Mali**: _Cercles_: Mopti, 83.3%; Douentza, 83.3%; Koro, 83.3%. 

_Communes_: Douentza: Douentza 66.7%, Koubewel Koundia 75%; Mopti: Konna 66.7%, Sio 83.3%; Koro: Koro 58.3%, Pel Maounde 58.3% 

**Senegal**:  _Departments_: Kaffrine 83.3%; Birkelane 66.7%; Malem Hodar 66.7%; Koungheul 66.7%

_Communes_: Kaffrine: Boulel 66.7%, Kahi 83.3%, Birkelane:  Mabo 83.3%, Keur Mboucky 75%, Malem Hodor: Sagna 66.7%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 83.3%, Koungheul: Lour Escale 58.3%, Missira Wadene 75%.

++Climate information++

**Mali**: _Cercles_: Mopti, 58.3%; Douentza, 66.7%; Koro, 75%. 

_Communes_: Douentza: Douentza 58.3%, Koubewel Koundia 58.3%; Mopti: Konna 83.3%, Sio 58.3%; Koro: Koro 75%, Pel Maounde 75%

**Senegal**:  _Departments_: Kaffrine 83.3%; Birkelane 58.3%; Malem Hodar 50%; Koungheul 50%

_Communes_: Kaffrine: Boulel 16.7%, Kahi 33.3%, Birkelane:  Mabo 66.7%, Keur Mboucky 66.7%, Malem Hodor: Sagna 16.7%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 33.3%, Koungheul: Lour Escale 50%, Missira Wadene 83.3%.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="16.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: Y4 TAMD (below) can now be compared against baseline scores to evaluate progress towards project targets:

Climate change integrated into planning:
Mali: Cercles: Mopti, 100%; Douentza, 100%; Koro, 100%. 
Communes: Douentza: Douentza 83.3%, Koubewel Koundia 91.7%; Mopti: Konna 83.3%, Sio 100%; Koro: Koro 100%, Pel Maounde 83.3%
 
Senegal:  Departments: Kaffrine 100%; Birkelane 66.7%; Malem Hodar 91.7%; Koungheul 100%
Communes: Kaffrine: Boulel 66.7%, Kahi 91.7%, Birkelane:  Mabo 83.3%, Keur Mboucky 91.7%, Malem Hodor: Sagna 100%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 100%, Koungheul: Lour Escale 100%, Missira Wadene 83.3%.

Climate information
Mali: Cercles: Mopti, 83.3%; Douentza, 100%; Koro, 100%. 
Communes: Douentza: Douentza 91.7%, Koubewel Koundia 91.7%; Mopti: Konna 100%, Sio 100%; Koro: Koro 100%, Pel Maounde 50%</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1: Devolved finance and planning mechanisms are established and functional in three Cercles (Mali) and four d&#xE9;partements (Senegal) to support community-prioritized investments in public goods that build climate resilience.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1: Number of local governments using TAMD Track 1 indicators as part of planning and Track 2 as part of performance monitoring processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analysis of existing M&amp;E system shows us that there are existing systems for M&amp;E but they are largely not functioning due to lack of capacity and resources. They also focus on outputs rather than outcomes. There is a lack of data.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 4 local governments applying refined TAMD Track 1 and Track 2 indicators to support resilience and tracking outcomes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="63.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 63 local government entities applying refined TAMD Track 1 and Track 2 indicators to support resilience and tracking outcomes. 

These not only include the 3 cercle-level (Mali) and 4 department-level (Senegal) governments, but also the 24 commune-level governments in Mali and 32 commune-level governments in Senegal who are already engaged in adaptation committee activities at various levels of the system, including monitoring and evaluating the 150 investments using simplified investment-specific theories of change.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: Proportion of Local Authorities (LA) with improved capacity for Climate Risk Management</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Y3 TAMD data (below) to be compared against Y4 data for indicator target. Y3 is effectively the baseline data in this instance:

&#x200B;

++Institutional coordination on integration (2)++

**Mali**: _Cercles_: Mopti 70%, Douentza 70%, Koro 70%.

_Communes_: Douentza: Douentza 70%, Koubewel Koundia 80%; Mopti: Konna 70%, Sio 40%; Koro: Koro 60%, Pel Maounde: 60%

**Senegal**: _Departements_: Kaffrine 60%, Birkelane 30%, Malem Hodar 60%, Koungheul 80%

_Communes_: Kaffrine: Boulel 40%, Kahi 70%; Birkelane: Mabo 80%, Keur Mboucky 80%; Malem Hodar: Sagna 60%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 60%; Koungheul: Lour Escale 30%, Missira Wadene 80%.

&#x200B;

++Budgeting and finance (3)++

**Mali**: _Cercles_: Mopti 66.7%, Douentza 75%, Koro 66.7%.

_Communes_: Douentza: Douentza 50%, Koubewel Koundia 83.3%; Mopti: Konna 66.7%, Sio 66.7%; Koro: Koro 83.3%, Pel Maounde: 83.3%

**Senegal**: _Departements_: Kaffrine 83.3%, Birkelane 66.7%, Malem Hodar 66.7%, Koungheul 75%

_Communes_: Kaffrine: Boulel 33.3%, Kahi 75%; Birkelane: Mabo 66.7%, Keur Mboucky 58.3%; Malem Hodar: Sagna 50%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 66.7%; Koungheul: Lour Escale 83.3%, Missira Wadene 66.7%.

&#x200B;

++Institutional knowledge and capacities (4)++

**Mali**: _Cercles_: Mopti 85.7%, Douentza 71.4%, Koro 71.4%.

_Communes_: Douentza: Douentza 57.1%, Koubewel Koundia 73.8%; Mopti: Konna 85.7%, Sio 79.8%; Koro: Koro 73.8%, Pel Maounde: 73.8%

**Senegal**: _Departements_: Kaffrine 85.7%, Birkelane 85.7%, Malem Hodar 14.3%, Koungheul 42.9%

_Communes_: Kaffrine: Boulel 14.3%, Kahi 73.8%; Birkelane: Mabo 85.7%, Keur Mboucky 79.8%; Malem Hodar: Sagna 0%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 73.8%; Koungheul: Lour Escale 57.1%, Missira Wadene 85.7%.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of LAs with improvement by 20% compared to their Y3 score, derived from changes in at least two areas (across TAMD Indicators 2-4)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: Compare Y4 TAMD (below) against baseline scores to evaluate progress towards project targets:

Institutional coordination on integration (2)
Mali: Cercles: Mopti 80%, Douentza 90%, Koro 80%.
Communes: Douentza: Douentza 90%, Koubewel Koundia 90%; Mopti: Konna 90%, Sio 90%; Koro: Koro 60%, Pel Maounde: 80%

Senegal: Departements: Kaffrine 80%, Birkelane 50%, Malem Hodar 80%, Koungheul 100%
Communes: Kaffrine: Boulel 60%, Kahi 100%; Birkelane:  Mabo 80%, Keur Mboucky 80%; Malem Hodar: Sagna 90%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 100%; Koungheul: Lour Escale 100%, Missira Wadene 100%.

Budgeting and finance (3)
Mali: Cercles: Mopti 91.7%, Douentza 91.7%, Koro 91.7%.
Communes: Douentza: Douentza 100%, Koubewel Koundia 91.7%; Mopti: Konna 100%, Sio 75%; Koro: Koro 87.3%, Pel Maounde: 87.3%

Senegal: Departements: Kaffrine 91.7%, Birkelane 58.3%, Malem Hodar 83.3%, Koungheul 75%
Communes: Kaffrine: Boulel 75%, Kahi 91.7%; Birkelane:  Mabo 75%, Keur Mboucky 91.7%; Malem Hodar: Sagna 75%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 100%; Koungheul: Lour Escale 91.7%, Missira Wadene 66.7%.

Institutional knowledge and capacities (4)
Mali: Cercles: Mopti 100%, Douentza 100%, Koro 92.9%.
Communes: Douentza: Douentza 100%, Koubewel Koundia 100%; Mopti: Konna 100%, Sio 85.7%; Koro: Koro 92.9%, Pel Maounde: 100%

Senegal: Departements: Kaffrine 100%, Birkelane 64.3%, Malem Hodar 57.1%, Koungheul 100%
Communes: Kaffrine: Boulel 85.7%, Kahi 85.7%; Birkelane:  Mabo 50%, Keur Mboucky 50%; Malem Hodar: Sagna 92.9%, Dianck&#xE9; Souf 100%; Koungheul: Lour Escale 71.4%, Missira Wadene 71.4%.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.3: Number of trainings or capacity building events organised by the project and where &gt;50% of participants rated the trainings or events positively</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="175">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">175 trainings or capacity building events / &gt;50% of participants rate the training or event positively</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="178.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: DCF held 20 training or capacity-building events with at least 50% of individuals rating the training or events, reaching a total of 967 individuals of which 314 were women. Over a 4-year period, DCF has collectively held 178 training or capacity-building events for 4,292, including 1,221 women) with at least 50% of attendees rating the event or training positively.

Mali: 15 training or capacity building events with 714 participants, including 214 women:

Senegal: 5 training or capacity building events with 253 participants, including 100 women</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.4: Number of countries where people have improved access to climate and disaster risk-related information disaggregated by region</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 Sahel countries</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 2 Sahel countries</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.6: Number of organisations (internal and external to BRACED consortia) in which BRACED has contributed to improvements in their plans to address climate related shocks and stresses</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="209">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_Disaggregation:_

**Internal:** 2

**External**: 101 in Senegal; 106 in Mali</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="209.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: Internal: 2
External: 207
101 in Senegal: 89 management committees + 8 department level entities + 2 commune level entities + 2 regional level entity

106 in Mali: 61 management committees +  6 cercle level entities + 37 commune level entities + 2 regional level entity</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.5: Number of effective partnerships between organisations of different types (e.g. between NGOs and research organisations, between NGOs and private sector bodies, KM and other resilience initiatives etc.) built to deliver interventions</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="190">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_Disaggregation by country:_

**Mali**: 105

**Senegal:** 85</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="199.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: Mali: 107
Senegal: 92</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.7: Number of local government policies/strategies incorporating climate change adaptation and risk reduction, supported by the BRACED programme</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="12 PDSECs in Mali"></target>
     <actual value="12.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: Mali: 12 PDSECs developed incorporating climate change adaptation and risk reduction. 

Senegal: 2 communes, Maka Yopp and Dianke Souf, integrated climate change adaptation considerations into Plans de D&#xE9;veloppement Communal (PDC).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Well-being (specifically livelihoods, health and food security) of poor people in Mali and Senegal, improves despite their exposure to climate shocks and stresses.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Indicator: % of people with improved wellbeing in the seven cercles and d&#xE9;partements in Mali and Senegal as a result of BRACED support</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Months of food security from the household survey data were as follows:  

Mali: Douentza - 5.3; Mopti 7.6; Koro 9.1

Senegal: Birkelane - 8.6; Kaffrine - 8.9; Malem Hodar - 9.2; Koungheul - 9.8</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="66%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target is 66 % of population to have increased wellbeing as a result of increased resilience (950,000/ 1.448 M +)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="75.9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 75.9% (1,099,048) of the total population improved their resilience and well-being through the investments. Of the total reached, 554,065 or 50.4% were women.

Mali: Douentza - 63%; Mopti - 89%; Koro - 44%
Senegal: Birkelane - 68%; Kaffrine - 100%; Malem Hodor - 100%; Koungheul - 100%

Results from the household endline in comparison with baseline indicate that 57% of the population has already increased food security (against 66% targeted). Additionally, survey results indicated that 75% of BRACED and BRACED-X beneficiaries had increased their food security.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2: Vulnerable communities in three Cercles (Mali) and four D&#xE9;partements (Senegal) benefit from public good investments that build resilience</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.1: Number of devolved climate adaptation financial mechanisms established with local government partners, transparently managed and fully accountable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No public goods funded to date by other climate funds similar to DCF in 2015. Y3 description of CAF status below, which effectively serves as baseline:

All 4 climate adaptations funds - 3 in Mali and 1 in Senegal - are currently operational, though dormant, and stand ready to channel BRACED-X funding to finance additional CAF investments. 

As of Milestone 3 (December 2017), CAFs disbursed 566,625 GBP, 596,568 GBP, and 575,979 GBP in climate adaptation funding to finance 48 resilience-building goods investments at the cercle level in Douentza, Mopti, and Koro respectively. In Senegal, 1 CAF fund nested at the national level has disbursed 1,169,788 GBP in funds to the department level to finance 75 resilience-building goods investments.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4 CAF funds increasing transparency compared to Y3"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: All 4 climate adaptations funds - 3 in Mali and 1 in Senegal - operational and channelling BRACED-X funding to finance CAF investments. A total of 150 investments were funded for a total of &#xA3;3,578,986.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.3: Number of people supported to cope taken within DCF to be: Number of people directly accessing initiatives funded by climate resilience investments in the cercles and d&#xE9;partements</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="950,000 direct beneficiaries reached">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 50% women</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1099048.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 1,099,048 direct beneficiaries (50.4% women, 60% youth) are reached by 150 financial investments currently in operation, of which 612,232 are in Mali (48.5% women, 60% youth) and 486,816 are in Senegal (51% women, 60% youth).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.2: Number and type of public good climate resilience investments responsive to community prioritisation, demonstrating social and gender inclusion</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="100%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">100% of BRACED-X investments selected with improved tools and processes compared to Y3</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="100.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 100% of 27 (13 in Mali; 14 in Senegal) BRACED-X investments are selected with improved tools and processes. 
- 70% drinking water additions (78% Senegal; 61% Mali)
- 15% vegetable gardens (30% Mali)
- 7% anti-corrosion measures (7% Senegal; 8%Mali)
- 3% pond landscaping (7% Senegal)
- 3% forestry (7% Senegal)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.4: No. of cercles/depts. where clear links between vulnerabilities (identified in resilience assessments) &amp; investments made demonstrate that decision making processes have become more inclusive of vulnerable groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="75%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">75% of beneficiaries report involvement in the CAF process that led to their local investment</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="32.0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: Across both countries, 32% of household respondents reported being involved in the DCF project at some stage (33% for BRACED households have mentioned taking part in the CAF process against of 28% of BRACED-X households).  
Differences can be observed between countries which is linked to the specific DCF models applied in each country (see Final Evaluation).

In Mali, 46% of households mentioned being involved in the DCF process at some stage. 83% of respondents mentioned they could feel the effects of the BRACED investments on their community.
In Senegal, 17% of households reported participating in the DCF process leading to their local investment. 57% of respondents mentioned they could feel the effects of the BRACED investments on their community. 

We note however that qualitative research pieces (social inclusion study and the final evaluation) finds the levels of social inclusion to be very positive. We extrapolate that the survey questions perhaps did not capture all nuances and levels of participation in communities, which are better captured qualitatively.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3: Evidence and learning on the effectiveness of decentralized climate finance investments to improve communities&#x2019; resilience is generated and disseminated</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3.1: Number of research/knowledge products on the effectiveness, accountability and inclusion of local adaptation strategies co-produced by consortium partners</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14 products demonstrate the varied effectiveness of investments to build resilience</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="16.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: DCF finalized the production of 4 knowledge products between January 2018 and March 2019. Knowledge products were submitted in June 2019, as typesetting, translations and stylistic adjustments were made in the months of April and May. In total, 16 total knowledge products were produced through the four years of the project. 

BRACED-X knowledge products include:
&#x2022; DCF Stabilisation Document
&#x2022; Two DCF Manuals (one per country)
&#x2022; A study focusing on the social inclusion of the DCF processes and mechanisms entitled &quot;Impact and Pertinence of the DCF Mechanism&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3.2: Use and uptake, locally and more widely, of the research and evidence generated</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2,500 downloads - 16 citations">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2500 downloads, 16 media citations and a presence on social media</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2756.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: To date, BRACED knowledge products have been downloaded 2,756  times from the NEF and IIED websites &#x2013; 598 in Y1, 1,055 in Y2, 316 in Period 3, and 787 in Period 4. Our social media presence, first launched in Y1, continues to connect stakeholders to BRACED-related news and updates. The DCF project has been cited in media pieces 20 times as of the Y4 milestone.  5 instances were in printed publications: Le Soleil, Sud Quotidien, Reuters, ReliefWeb, and the Guardian. 11 were in online news publications, including: the 4 by the Senegalese Press Agency, 3 by Reuters, and 1 each for Seneweb, Senego, Senegal Niooz, Relief Web. 4 instances were via radio,: DCF staff in Senegal sat down for interviews with Kaffrine FM, Koungheul FM, Pakala FM, and Birkelane FM.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 4: Mechanisms and processes established for national governments to engage with locally generated evidence</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 4.2: Number of national government institutions that adopt or amend policies, plans, or frameworks that will support or facilitate devolved finance and/or local climate risk management</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 (ANICT, either CSE or PNDL, as result of the accreditation and/or platform support)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">05-11-2019: 2 government insitutions

Mali: ANICT has submitted an application for accreditation to the GCF with a concept note for Enhanced Direct Access that aims to obtain additional funding for decentralized climate finance. 

Senegal:- The National Platform has facilitated the development of a proposal to be submitted to the Green Climate Fund. This proposal is being developed with an eye towards continuing and capitalizing upon the progress made by the DCF project in Senegal.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 4.1: Number of national government institutions with senior decision makers engaged</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">National government institutions take concrete steps to facilitate local risk management related to climate shocks</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="Mali: Ongoing support from DCF has facilitated the accreditation process to the GCF by the Ag&#xE8;nce Nationale d&apos;Investissement des Collectivit&#xE9;s Territoriales (ANICT). After an iterative and interactive process improving upon application and annex drafts by incorporating stakeholder feedback, ANICT formally submitted its application for accreditation to the GCF on December 10th, 2018 while attending COP 24 in Poland. Feedback has since been provided by the GCF Secretariat, which will be integrated into a finalized application to be resubmitted for final consideration. Furthermore, an Enhanced Direct Access concept note building upon the DCF project entittled &quot;Dentralising Investments in Public Goods to Support Agriculture and Livestock-Based Economies and to Build Resilience for Rural Women&quot; was developed and submitted to the GCF on February 13th, 2019. 

Senegal: Continued institutionalisation of the National Platform in Senegal through capacity building sessions and regular meetings. Additionally, during the period covered by Milestone 4, the National Platform worked with the communes of Maka Yopp and Dianke Souf to integrate the National Guide&apos;s climate change considerations into their Communal Development Plans (PDC)."></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
