<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-17/NIG_ERF/SA2/RR/UN/6905</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Community Recovery  Stabilization of  Bara Ward in Gulani LGA of Yobe State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the HRP 2017, there are currently 8.5 million people in need of urgent assistance in the 3 States of Borno, Adamawa and Yobe with 1.3 million targeted for assistance in Yobe State alone. The proposed project, which will be part of UNDP&#x2019;s Integrated Community Stabilization and Early Recovery Programme in Northeast Nigeria, is based on the recognition that (a) durable and sustainable  resolution of the on-going conflict in North-East Nigeria requires addressing the structural and underlying drivers of violent conflict, and (b) it is now critical to supplement on-going humanitarian interventions with early recovery activities in areas of relative security and stability (especially Yobe, Adamawa) to sustainably address the looming food and livelihoods crisis and to further encourage and promote community recovery and stabilization. Accordingly, its main objectives of the project are:
1.	Contribute to the immediate stabilization of women, girls, boys and men of Bara Ward in Gulani LGA of Yobe State in a holistic and sustainable manner 
2.	Strengthen the resilience of the target community and its affected populations especially women, girls and the elderly against future vulnerabilities. 
These will be achieved through the synergistic provision of key gender-sensitive basic services that include healthcare, primary education, water supply (boreholes), livelihoods stabilization interventions including small grants and  linkages to markets and support for effective local governance and social cohesion at community levels. A recent knowledge, Attitudes amp Practices (KAP) Survey conducted by the Danish Demining Group in the northeast of Nigeria, found that the local population in conflict-affected areas were relatively uninformed about mines/ERW, particularly when it comes to recognition of explosive devices. Assessments of the humanitarian crisis have continued to reveal an increase in the numbers of female-headed or child-headed households in many of the LGAs in the 3 States most affected by the crisis especially those LGAs that became more accessible to humanitarian actors as of the last quarter of 2016 to date. In response to these findings, the project has been designed to address the specific situation and needs of conflict-affected people in a strategically-located community. The project will provide tailored support to facilitate the revival of sustainable livelihoods for community people in a way that will systematically promote full socio-economic participation of the most vulnerable as revealed by the assessments discussed above. As such, the project proposes a new way of working in northeast Nigeria which moves away from geographically and thematically fragmented interventions towards a collaborative approach that harnesses the comparative strengths of multiple actors to strengthen the resilience of conflict-affected women and men, girls and boys in northeast Nigeria in a gender-responsive, sustainable and environmentally-friendly way. UNDP will collaborate with DDG and other local NGOs to deliver a range of recovery interventions that address some of the root causes of the conflict in a sustainable way. For example, the region&#x2019;s deeply-rooted patriarchal norms, often codified in law and reinforced by socio-cultural institutions, have defined women&#x2019;s status through marriage and childbearing and largely confined them to gender roles that do not go beyond the domestic sphere. The conflict has further exacerbated these discriminatory practices and greatly increased insecurity for women and girls who are now among those directly targeted by Boko Haram. Considering the foregoing situation, the project is designed to directly target 13,000 people in one of the most affected and currently accessible LGAs in Yobe State (Gulani) with early recovery interventions and durable solutions spanning a period of 12 months under the project .The project will complement on-going interventions of UNDP in the location.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 local NGOs to be determined</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Demining Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marie-Josee Hamel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Head of Programme (DHoP)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234814 834 9730</telephone>
   <email>dhop.ddg@drc-nigeria.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maureen Lance-Onyeiwu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234907 025 1698</telephone>
   <email>maureen.lance-onyeiwu@undp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samuel Bwalya</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+234907 025 1692</telephone>
   <email>samuel.bwalya@undp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG036">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yobe</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.29868022 11.43706584</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-15">1042291.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-15">257709.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-6905">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-15">1300000.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303202227">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">1300000.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400352931">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-21">59524.31</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
