<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-17/NIG_ERF/SA/LOG/UN/6405</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobile storage solutions at Humanitarian Hubs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The WFP-led Logistics Sector is supporting the relief efforts of the Government of Nigeria by augmenting the capacity for logistics coordination and logistics information management among humanitarian logistics actors and is facilitating access to, and implementation of key common services on behalf of the Humanitarian Community. Through maintaining a continuous presence in Borno State since August 2016, and constant liaison and consultation with the government agencies and humanitarian responders, the Logistics Sector has ensured that its support remains agile and fitted to the needs on the ground.
Main activities:
	Coordination: to minimize duplication and gaps in logistics response efforts
	Information Management: to support operations and decision-making
	Service Provision - Temporary Storage: to supplement existing capacity
	Civil-Military Liaison and Access: to ensure regular and secure delivery of humanitarian cargo
	Training: to support local capacity strengthening
Following a recommendation from the Inter-Sector Working Group and the Government of Nigeria, the Humanitarian Country Team determined the gradual establishment of Humanitarian Hubs in Borno State last year. These Hubs will provide a common base of operations for humanitarian actors present in the selected areas with critical enablers, including security, radio, internet, office space, accommodation, as well as logistics support and warehousing. These Hubs will provide a unified framework for coordinating overall response efforts. 
A &#x2018;2017 Logistics Sector Strategy Workshop&#x2019; was held in Maiduguri on 12 November 2016, in which participants also identified the need for common storage sites outside Maiduguri. The identified locations where in alignment with the Humanitarian Hub locations, however not in the same order of priority.
Progress made so far in terms of service provision &#x2013; storage:
The Logistics Sector is encouraging a common approach for storage in hard to reach areas outside Maiduguri through a variety of means including: implementation of Common Storage in coordination with Humanitarian Hubs as needed and as they come online establishment of dedicated Common Storage managed by Logistics Sector partners in locations, where Humanitarian Hubs are not yet established direct provision of equipment to augment the capacity of individual organisations were other options are either not necessary, or not feasible.
To ensure readiness to implement any of the three options listed above (as appropriate to emerging needs and limitations) the Logistics Sector has acquired and dispatched critical logistics equipment (i.e. Mobile Storage/Warehousing Units [MSUs], generators, pallets, office containers)  to support its partners, and will ensure sufficient materials are procured and in-country to meet emerging needs (i.e. equipment to support implementation of temperature-controlled storage, and additional common storage).
To date, the Logistics Sector has identified NGO partners who will take on the management of the Logistics Sector common storage in Monguno (Solidarites International) and Banki (Intersos). As the Humanitarian Hub is being finalised in Ngala, the common storage is being established on the compound next to the IHP camp. Project readiness in all three location is expected by early July 2017. 
Planning to establish additional common storage locations is ongoing, in consultation with IOM as manager of the Humanitarian Hubs, humanitarian partners and the Government of Nigeria. After the rainy season, future common storage sites shall be aligned with the Humanitarian Hub sites.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACTED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-HEALTH AFRICA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antonio Galli</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CMCoord  Access Officer (and OIC during the Coordinator&apos;s absence)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0907 026 5287</telephone>
   <email>antonio.galli@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Katja Hildebrand</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Logistics Sector coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0907 454 3036</telephone>
   <email>katja.hildebrand@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Logistics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-31">176016.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-31">174858.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-6405">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-31">350874.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302812210">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-02">350874.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
