<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-LPI-0001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-LPI" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Implication des hommes pour le renforcement de la s&#xE9;curit&#xE9; et le soutien de la stabilisation dans le Nord et le Sud Kivu</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with men to increase security and stability in North and South Kivu</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Military and Police ; (2) Men Living in High risk communities ; (3) Husbands of SGBV survivors (4) Ex combattants</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gendered sources of conflict and war in Eastern DRC and gendered responses for security and stability Several wars and conflicts over the past decades in Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) have caused tremendous damage to relationships between men and women and have greatly exacerbated partner violence, including sexual violence between partners. War-related rape of women and girls, committed by uniformed and armed men, militia members, or civilian men, was a daily reality for many families. Many men and boys were also raped, and countless were forced to watch their wives or daughters being raped. The results of the International Men and Gender Equality Survey (IMAGES), carried out in North Kivu by Promundo-US in 2012, explore the numerous and complex factors that contribute to high levels of sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV) in a context of post-conflict DRC (Slegh et al, 2014). The study found that support for traditional gender norms, including male dominance, is high among both men and women in North Kivu. Men who are less supportive of gender equality were more likely to have perpetrated physical or sexual violence against a partner. The study also found that nearly 24% of women reported being raped during the conflict; their husbands and families often rejected those women who experienced sexual violence in the conflict. In addition, the findings show that men who were exposed to violence as children were more likely to use intimate partner violence as adults. Men who were forced to have sex or raped in conflict were also more likely to use physical or sexual violence against their partners. The construction of violent masculinities in men is strongly influenced by childhood exposure to violence and exposure to violence during armed conflict. In North and South Kivu specifically, rape and sexual violence in private and public domains remains an epidemic. In this context, rape is usually primarily portrayed as a weapon of war to destroy others. Yet, several other studies confirm that rape and sexual violence should also be understood as an expression of failed masculinity in a failing state. (Baaz et al, 2013). Men&#x2019;s multiple identities in conflict and post-conflict settings &#x2014; as perpetrators of violence, but also as witnesses to and victims of violence &#x2014; must be appropriately addressed in any effort to end violence against women and girls, to promote gender equality, and to facilitate women&#x2019;s and men&#x2019;s access sexual and reproductive health resources and services. As noted in both MONUSCO&#x2019;s International Security and Stabilization Support Strategy (ISSSS) and the Government of the Netherlands&#x2019; Multi-Annual Strategic Plan for the Great Lakes Region, the continued presence of SGBV and the traditional norms contributing to it also prevent healing and stabilization of communities, thus driving further conflict. Female survivors of sexual violence in conflict are frequently ostracized and lack support, including within their own families; children born of sexual violence in conflict also face rejection. Even when these women remain in their families and communities, they are often subjected to violence and relegated to lower social status, as Promundo&#x2019;s research and that of others has found. IMAGES research in DRC found that nearly half of women and men thought that a woman who had been raped should be expelled from her family and community. The fractures in the community are not mended, and security, social cohesion and reconciliation &#x2014; both between men and women, and between men and other men &#x2014; remain elusive. In this context neither men nor women are able to heal. These issues also play out in terms of economic stress. Men&#x2019;s reports of higher levels of economic stress (due to poverty, displacement and loss of property) and regular binge drinking were further associated with elevated levels of violence against their partners. This is unfortunately common, as communities affected by conflict in the region are often left in economic turmoil. In the case of DRC, conflict left many men and women without the ability to provide for their families, with IMAGES revealing that 71% of men post-conflict (versus 39% before conflict) reported never having enough means to support their families. This, in turn, is likely to lead to further interpersonal conflict, stress and depression. To this regard, one man interviewed during a formative research for the pilot project in Burundi affirmed, &#x201C;If you have nothing [no income or work] you are nothing.&#x201D; In a context where economies are in need of rebuilding, women&#x2019;s increased access to economic resources can contribute to a range of positive outcomes for themselves and their families, as well as for economic growth more broadly. As a result, many livelihood and economic empowerment initiatives in the Global South, including those in the Great Lakes region focus primarily or exclusively on women: of the 82 million people served by microfinance programs in 2005, 84% were women. However, as the Dutch multi-annual strategic plan for the Great Lakes region has assessed, &#x201C;For many men in the region, it remains difficult to accept new and equal rights of women. The majority of agricultural workers are women, with a large percentage of female-headed households, which has changed the role of women in communities.&#x201D; Indeed, efforts to boost economic development after the conflict that focus (solely) on the empowerment of women may aggravate men&#x2019;s sense of lost power and fragile sense of manhood. When men are unable to fulfill the culturally defined male roles as protectors and providers for their families due to war and poverty, self-perceptions of failure and loss of power and control lead many of them to use more violence at home, as affirmed in the IMAGES DRC study. Indeed, the study found that many men cope with shame and feelings of loss and failure with alcohol abuse and violence against women; for some, this sense of lost masculinity is also a motive for joining armed groups. Constructions of masculinity based on rigid and traditional notions of power, control, and honor also contribute to a perspective that fighting and violence are the only way to resolve interpersonal and inter communal conflicts. All of these arguments suggest that women&#x2019;s economic empowerment initiatives can work better when men are engaged as partners or with efforts to promote men&#x2019;s attitude and behavior change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the proposed intervention&#x2014;Living Peace in the DRC&#x2014;is to achieve sustainable, gender-equitable peace at all levels of society in North and South Kivu by engaging men to end SGBV in the post-conflict setting of DRC. Strategy: Ideas of violent masculinity are deconstructed through evidence-based psychosocial support programs for men, women and their families with the aim to end violent behaviors and adopt norms and values that support gender equality at individual and community levels and more broadly. Key representatives from institutions in health and security sector will be trained and included in the programs to end and prevent cycles of violence in conflict-affected areas and to establish sustainability of the impact of the program. Objectives: Within this goal, the following objectives at different society levels have been identified: 1. Individual Level: Trauma Healing of Individual Men and Women, ensuring that men and women heal from conflict- and violence-related trauma in ways that are specific to their gender identity and that take into account gendered coping mechanisms. 2. Family Level: Reduce violence at home and restore peaceful partner relations in the family. To this aim, reduce the use of violence by men against their partners and children and increase gender equitable behaviors in the household, thus creating a safer environment for all members of the family. 3. Community Level: Create and restore social support systems at the community level to support men, women and families suffering of consequences of conflict, including survivors of SGBV, to prevent violent behavior and conflict (including inter ethical conflict) and engender cooperation between civilians and security organs. 4. Society Level: Capacity building of Congolese civil societies and public services to institutionalize the Living Peace approach. Building capacity of Congolese public services and civil society organizations to integrate the Living Peace methodology in their institution.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institut Sup&#xE9;rieur du Lac</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="livingpeace" ref="XI-IATI-00000" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-28704" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living peace institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Direction</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aloys MAHWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+243 970 965 771</telephone>
   <email>a.mahwa@livingpeaceinstitute.org</email>
   <website>http://livingpeaceinstitute.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@livingpeaceinstitute.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region percentage="100" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CD" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
  </location>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-01">1078747</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-01">1774532</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">1566379</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-06">783169.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fifth installment in 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="Living Peace Institut" type="22"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-09">974240</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fourth Installment in 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="22"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="LIving Peace Institute" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living Peace Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-12">539346</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second installment for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the Ministry of foreign trade and development cooperation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="LIving Peace Institute" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-15">675283.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sixth Installment in 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="LIving Peace Institute" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-06">362291</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first installment for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="LIving Peace Institute" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-31">824000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Third installment in 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="LIving Peace Institute" type="22"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Outputs results for the Living peace Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(targeted participants include men in community high risk zones, husbands of SGBV survivors, military men, police forces, ex-combatants and ex-child soldiers)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Master trainers trained in delivering LP methodology</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; In March 2016, eight Master Trainers with mental health background were recruited: Six of them are based in Goma for the training of facilitators identified in North Kivu and two others in Bukavu for the training of facilitators identified in South-Kivu. &#x2022; After the recruitment of Master trainers, Living Peace has organized the induction training in April to all new staffs and then from 3th to 7th May 2016, the Master trainers was trained on Living peace methodology, on trauma, violence and consequences of SGBV, the training on clinical supervisions was held from 15th to 17th July 2016, and then the refresher training was conducted from 09th to 11th November 2016 and the training of Living peace Monitoring and evaluation was also conducted in November 2016 to all master trainers</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="8" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">8 masters trainers were trained on Living peace methodology, on trauma, violence and consequences of SGBV,</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <location ref="Goma and Bukavu"></location>
      <dimension name="Master trainers" value="12"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target was to train 12 masters trainers but during the last three years, Living Peace trained 16 because some of them resigned and others their performance was weak.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12">
      <location ref="Goma and Bukavu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of men who attended more than 70% of sessions of LP Program psychosocial group sessions for men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, more than 93% of men attended LP Program psychosocial group sessions for men</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="70" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Living Peace participants men have to attend at least more than 70% of sessions of LP Program psychosocial group sessions but during the year 2017, the participation rate to the living peace group sessions was in average 93%,</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="70">
      <location ref="North and south Kivu"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="93">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of group facilitators recruited by CSOs and trained to conduct group therapy sessions in communities and ranks(Police and Military)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">From 2016 to 2018 LPI has trained a group facilitators recruited by CSOs to conduct group therapy sessions in communities and ranks(Police and Military)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2015-12-31" value="82" year="2015">
     <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="360">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="445">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health care professionals trained in gender-specific methodology, including trainings on supporting women survivors of SGBV and their partners, gender-specific mental health care and psychosocial support, and identification of men and women with severe mental health problems</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of health sector workers trained on gender-specific mental health care, psychosocial support strategies, and identification of men and women with severe mental health problems</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-03-01" value="0" year="2016">
     <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="32"></target>
     <actual value="32">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="3">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted men attended LP Program gender-specific psychosocial group education sessions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, Living Peace Institute implemented 142 psychosocial support groups to reach 1980 men and their spouses in the communities located in North and South Kivu to address different challenges that are facing the LP targeted group</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-02-28" value="1980" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="4905">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="5055">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Outcomes result for Living Peace project</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with men to increase security and stabilization in North and south Kivu</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved mental health (depression/PTSD symptoms) among LP Program participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports (from men and women participants) of men&#x2019;s reduced mental health problems</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-03-01" value="65%" year="2016">
     <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2016, 69% of LP participants have suicidal thoughts</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="35">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Decrease of 58% of LP participants with having suicidal thoughts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports (from men and women participants) of reduced men&#x2019;s use of physical, psychological and economic, violence against women &amp; violence against children</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports (from men and women participants) of reduced men&#x2019;s use of physical, psychological and economic, violence against women &amp; violence against children</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-03-01" value="30" year="2016">
     <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">LP participants always beat their kids when their feel stressed/ nervous.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <location ref="North and south Kivu"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="5">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">25% of reduction of LP participants who continue to beat their kids when they face difficult or stressful events in life</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduced substance abuse among LP Program participating men</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reports (from men and women participants) of men&#x2019;s reduced use and abuse of alcohol and drugs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2016-03-01" value="44" year="2017">
     <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Significant reduction of of 50% of using alcohol abuse or drugs of LP participants when they feel nervous or streesed</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="22">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </target>
     <actual value="22">
      <location ref="North and South Kivu"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
