<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=CMB/12/54/JPN" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-103789-1155-2014-KHM226</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the implementation of the social protection delivery system (PEOPLE Service) of the national social protection strategy of Cambodia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at implementing an innovative approach called the PEOPLE Service which will contribute to increase outreach of existing social protection programs and employment services, facilitate coordination at all levels (between line ministries, between central and local administration, and so on), develop a harmonized management information system to keep track of the implementation of the social protection floor in Cambodia and to facilitate the evaluation of existing interventions, create development linkages among social protection programs and between social protection and employment services. Similar integrated approaches have been successfully implemented in India, Brazil, China, Colombia and Pakistan, are being developed in Cambodia (under the present project), Indonesia and Lao PDR and are progressively been seen as cost-efficient strategies to implement nationally defined social protection floors at country level. The strategy of the project is to support the implementation of the PEOPLE Service by working both at national and decentralized levels. At the national level, the project will aim to support the preparation and adoption of a number of legal documents (Prakas (Proclamations) and Memorandum of Understanding (MoU)) to guide the practical implementation of the mechanism, and to support the design and implementation of an integrated management information system. At the decentralized level the project will build enough evidence on the forms the PEOPLE Service can take by working on the concrete implementation of the mechanism in a limited number of districts. To increase ownership of the PEOPLE Service at both national and decentralized level the project will use a participatory approach for the finalization of the design, conduct of activities and evaluation of the project&#x2019;s implementation. This participatory approach will entail workshops and training seminars including representatives of workers and employers&#x2019; representatives, the government (all line ministries represented under the inter-ministerial working group on the NSPS-PV) and the civil society as well as development partners involved in the implementation of social protection programs in Cambodia. The project&#x2019;s team will most probably be hosted by CARD at the national level (with a view to facilitate daily collaboration and increase the future sustainability of the project). At the decentralized level the PEOPLE Service will be hosted in local administration offices which will contribute to reduce costs and ensure long term sustainability. The permanent team of the PEOPLE Service is composed of civil servants (Ministry of Interior / CARD).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="KH">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="KH" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="KH" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">9392</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="CMB/12/54/JPN-2014-KHM226 - Increased quality and coverage for social protection-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">9392</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan, Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="CMB/12/54/JPN-2014-KHM226 - Increased quality and coverage for social protection">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">9392</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=CMB/12/54/JPN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Supporting the implementation of the social protection delivery system (PEOPLE Service) of the national social protection strategy of Cambodia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
