<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=PAK/08/03/EEC" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-101169-1334-2014-PAK102</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Abusive Child Labour II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Abusive Child Labour II (EC/ILO Contribution Agreement No ASIE/2007/144-940) International Programme on the Elimination of Child Labour (IPEC) Salient Features: Project Name: Combating Abusive Child Labour II Geographic Region: Sindh, North Western Frontier, Punjab, and Balochistan Provinces of Pakistan Start Date: 01 April 2008 End Date: 31 March 2013 Duration: 60 months Executing Institution: ILO Partner Institutions: Government, employers&#x2019; &amp; workers&#x2019; organizations, and NGOs EC Contribution: Euro 4.75 million Other Contributions: ILO Contribution Euro 447,900 Government of Pakistan (in kind, as part of the Financing Agreement signed with the EC) Brief Project Profile: The overall objective of this Project is to contribute to the Government of Pakistan&#x2019;s efforts towards eliminating child labour, in particular its &#x201C;worst forms&#x201D;. The Project will contribute to the execution of the Government&#x2019;s National Policy and Plan of Action to Combat Child Labour, mainly the National Time Bound Programme (2008-2016) - its medium term plan for combating the worst forms of child labour. The Project, as the umbrella programme, will take over the technical responsibility from current TBP Project of Support to coordinate all on-going and planned IPEC interventions with a view to maximize synergies among their actions that will eventually lead to multiply the combined effect. The Project focuses on children working in hazardous occupations under the most intolerable conditions ranging from exposure to chemicals and other harmful substances to long tedious working hours. It will cover all hazardous sectors and occupations identified by the national legislation. Building on the past experience of ILO/IPEC, the Project is aimed at a major intervention to remove about 5,500 working children from hazardous occupation and to prevent about 1,000 of their younger siblings from taking their positions in the labour market. The major achievements envisaged under this Project are: 1. Promoting the &#x201C;District Model to Eliminate Abusive Child Labour&#x201D; that has been proven successful under the TBP Project of Support and replicate it in the target districts and beyond; 2. Institutional strengthening at the district, provincial and federal level through the enhancement of capacity of respective child labour units and the establishment of child labour monitoring and referral system; and 3. Creation of child labour knowledge base through conducting the second National Child Labour Survey and related research studies, and promoting the development and adoption of pro child policies and legislative framework. Various partners will be involved in the implementation of Project components. They include: Ministry of Labour &amp; Manpower, employers&#x2019; &amp; workers&#x2019; organizations, local government authorities, NGOs, networking organizations, research institutions, and media. Under the leadership of the National Steering Committee on Child Labour, the Project Advisory Committee will provide policy guidance and direction to the project activities and periodically monitors the project progress. *****************</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="PK" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="PK" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">12108</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="PAK/08/03/EEC-2014-PAK102 - Constituents actively promoting and supporting the elimination of child labour, including its worst forms-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">12108</value>
   <provider-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission, Europe Aid</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="PAK/08/03/EEC-2014-PAK102 - Constituents actively promoting and supporting the elimination of child labour, including its worst forms">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">12108</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15160" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=PAK/08/03/EEC">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Combating Abusive Child Labour II</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
