<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RAS/13/54/ROK" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-104148-1162-2014-IDN126</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrating decent employment in the formulation, implementation and monitoring of development strategies in Indonesia and the Philippines</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development objective: To contribute to poverty reduction in Indonesia and the Philippines through the creation of better income earning job opportunities. Immediate objective: Strengthened national capacities in Indonesia and the Philippines to formulate, implement and monitor employment components of development plans This project proposal seeks to build on the outcomes of the previous project (RAS/11/54/ROK) to continue to support the tripartite constituents in Indonesia and the Philippines in formulating, implementing and monitoring employment components of development plans. In Indonesia, this will include: a) supporting the National Development Planning Agency (BAPPENAS) in undertaking background studies and tripartite dialogue on possible employment targets in the next Medium Term Development Plan 2015-19; b) strengthening the collection and analysis of sex- and age- disaggregated data on vacancies, jobseekers and placements (i.e. data and analysis of employment services) being gathered by two district offices of the Indonesian Ministry of Manpower. The two target districts will be decided based on discussions with the Ministry of Manpower, but could include the Special Capital City District of Jakarta and East Java. In undertaking this component, collaboration with the Korea Labour Information Service (KLIS) will be undertaken, including through a study tour to Korea and KLIS experts undertaking missions to the two districts in Indonesia for knowledge sharing. The enhanced collection and analysis of such data can provide important insights in the formulation, implementation and monitoring of the next Medium Term Development Plan 2015-19, and in the design of appropriate active labour market and other policies to support inclusive job-rich growth in Indonesia In the Philippines, the project will: a) assess the &#x201C;decent work intensity&#x201D; of a number of the priority sectors identified in the Philippines Development Plan (PDP) 2011-2016; b) assess the human resource capacities to support the growth of the priority sectors, in collaboration with the Korea Labour Institute (KLI); c) strengthen the analytical capacities of national constituents, including that of the Institute of Labour Studies of the DOLE so as to strengthen institutional capacities to implement and monitor the Philippines Development Plan (PDP) 2011-2016, Philippines Labor and Employment Plan (PLEP) 2011-2016, and the industrial strategy of the Philippines. Areas for capacity-building in this regard include evidence-based policy analysis and undertaking employment projections. In undertaking this component, collaboration with the Korea Labour Institute will be undertaken.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ID">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ID" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="ID" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">47326</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="RAS/13/54/ROK-2014-IDN126 - Mainstreaming of employment in macroeconomic, labour and social policies through sound labour market analysis and tools-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">47326</value>
   <provider-org ref="KR-GOV-021">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Republic of Korea, Expert Programme</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RAS/13/54/ROK-2014-IDN126 - Mainstreaming of employment in macroeconomic, labour and social policies through sound labour market analysis and tools">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">47326</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RAS/13/54/ROK">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Integrating decent employment in the formulation, implementation and monitoring of development strategies in Indonesia and the Philippines</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
