<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/11/11/USA" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-102984-1277-2014-GLO751</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Action Program (GAP) on Child Labor Issues</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Action Program on Child Labor Issues The Project will involve interventions across three related components: (1) capacity building and strategic policy development; (2) research and statistics; and (3) protection of child domestic workers. The first component will involve assistance to identifying and addressing legal and regulatory gaps in the areas of child labor and forced labor, as well as to strengthening accompanying monitoring and enforcement mechanisms. It will also support national action plans on the two issues, and promote mainstreaming child and forced labor concerns into broader sectoral policies. The second component will seek to improve information and statistics on child labor and forced labor in their various dimensions, and to apply this improved knowledge base in policy design. It will form part of the wider ILO strategy of using statistical information and policy analysis to guide scaled-up and accelerated action against child and forced labor. The third component will help strengthen protections for child domestic workers. It will support a variety of awareness raising and advocacy activities in line with the relevant international legal instruments. It will also support the formulation of enabling regulatory and policy frameworks and the development of pilot intervention models for protecting child domestic workers. Interventions relating to the three Project components will be implemented across a total of 41 countries in 5 regions, 31 of which were specified in SGA 11-02. In each of these ILO member states, efforts will be undertaken in close collaboration with national and local governments, as well as with industry, labor groups, civil society and other stakeholders, as appropriate. This Project would allow the ILO to expand its knowledge base and policy advisory services on child labor and forced labor. This in turn could subsequently be taken by the ILO to a wider group of countries and, in doing so, promote the Secretary of Labor&#x2019;s goal of good jobs for everyone. Funding amount requested from USDOL: US$ 15,000,000 Total value of cost-sharing by ILO: US$ 757,240 The expected outcomes of the project are as follows: Outcome 1: Improved legislation, enforcement and policy coordination on child labor and forced labor as well as national capacity to implement policy initiatives to increase access to quality education and sustainable livelihoods for vulnerable populations. Outcome 2: Innovative research and monitoring systems to guide policy development and program design. Outcome 3: Strengthened protections to children in domestic work. **********</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-09-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-02" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="GLOBAL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.ilo.org/dashboard"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3220079</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/11/11/USA-2014-GLO751 - Mobilizing innovative partnerships to realize the elimination of the worst forms of child labour by 2016-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3220079</value>
   <provider-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">USA, United States Department of Labor, Bureau for International Labor Affairs, Office of Child Labor, Forced Labor and Human Trafficking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/11/11/USA-2014-GLO751 - Mobilizing innovative partnerships to realize the elimination of the worst forms of child labour by 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">3220079</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/11/11/USA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Global Action Program (GAP) on Child Labor Issues</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
