<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41186799-GLA-PoV-Colombia</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41186799" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Engage for a Common Future</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="ES">Green Livelihoods Alliance 2 Colombia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia is the second most biodiverse country on the planet, and has the privilege of being among the nine countries that share territory in the  Amazon: the largest rainforest in the world. The Amazon region in Colombia covers 44.3%, and 64 of the country&#x2019;s 115 native indigenous peoples live there. This natural and cultural heritage is invaluable for humanity and yet it faces great pressures that require diverse protection strategies to maintain its biological and cultural connectivity.

Today, the Amazon region is facing a rapid transformation driven by the construction of legal and illegal routes and hydroelectric plants, as well as the exploitation of hydrocarbons and mining, agricultural activities and illegal economies. In the scenario of these pressures, forest loss stands out as one of the most pressing challenges. According to the Atlas &apos;Amazonia Bajo Presi&#xF3;n&apos; - &#x201C;Amazon Under Pressure&#x201D; 2020, deforestation in the region reached 511,787 km2 in the last twenty years,  (covering an area similar to the size of the continental territory of Spain), and 87.5% of this loss occurred outside Indigenous Territories and Natural Protected Areas of the Amazon.

The Colombian case is no less dramatic. For several years, Colombia has been part of the world ranking of countries with the greatest loss of forests, and in 2020 it ranked number six. In the midst of this breaking context, , the Colombian Amazon concentrates the greatest loss. For example, between 2000 and 2018, 66% of the country&#x2019;s total deforestation occurred in this region, according to data from the Ideam Forest and Carbon Monitoring System.

Indigenous peoples and their knowledge systems have protected these vast territories for millennia, demonstrating that the most effective strategy to govern them, to protect the planet&#x2019;s biodiversity and the health of ecosystems, is based on the traditional management derived from such systems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Colombia,  the Forests for a Just Future Programme addresses the issue of deforestation -one of the country&#x2019;s most serious environmental problems- and degradation, and unsustainable  management of forests and wooded landscapes, in a context of climate change, gender inequality and inequity, and threats to the protection of human rights, as well as rights related to territory and local livelihoods.

This project is mainly developed in the Colombian Amazon: in the Northwest Colombian Amazon also known as the deforestation arc, which covers the departments of Caquet&#xE1;, Guaviare and south of Meta; and also the Northest Colombian Amazon, which covers the departments of Amazonas, Vaup&#xE9;s and Guain&#xED;a. The project also includes some actions in the Andean region (Santander), and Bogot&#xE1;, as an advocacy hub to take actions  with the National Government and State entities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41186799-GLAII" ref="NL-KVK-41186799" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Engage for a Common Future</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Global Forest Coalition</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Juana Vera Delgado</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+31616858011</telephone>
   <email>juanaveradelgado@globalforestcoalition.org</email>
   <website>https://globalforestcoalition.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">25291</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">27887</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">24143</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2024-01-01">21685</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2025-01-01">22976</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">121982</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41186799-GLA-PoV-WECF" ref="NL-KVK-41186799" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41186799-GLA-PoV-WECF" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
