<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2012-2012000284</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Physical Education Development Project in Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Physical Education Development Pilot Project 2013-2014 is LiiKe&apos;s first project in Nepal. It is planned in close cooperation with the Tribhuvan University&apos;s (TU) Department of Health Physical and Population Education which is the local partner in the p
roject. The pilot project is the first step to aiming at: - increasing the equal access to Physical Education for boys and girls - increasing the gender balance within the teachers who are teaching Physical Education- improving the quality of the PE educat
ion- getting the Physical Education into practice and outside the classroom when possible- raising awareness of the importance of Physical Education in the sense of physical health and fitness on the one hand and mental and social health of the students on
 the other hand- raising awareness of the positive impact that physical activity has on learning- raising awareness that through sports and games all the students can learn skills for life and sometimes find a career or become an athlete- improving the Phy
sical Education curriculum and- improving and formalizing the status of Physical Education as a school subject.In the project ten districts and twenty higher secondary schools (grades 11-12) are chosen from all of the five development regions of Nepal. Dis
tricts will be selected considering the Hill and Terai settings. Twenty teachers (female and male) get an intensive training for conducting games and sports for the students. Back in the schools and districts presentation will be given about the key findin
gs to community and the school presonnel. In the schools teachers start programme that includes different sports and games as regular activity and in the form of tournaments. The project schools are provided with necessary games and sports equipment. The s
tudents from grades 11 to 12 are the future primary school (grades 1-8) teachers which adds the value of the programme.The field supervisors are nominated to monitor and support the implementation of the programme in the schools. The experiences from the s
tudents and teachers will be collected before and after the school year in which the project is implemented and best practices manual &apos;How to make Physical Education accessible for boys and girls&apos; will be made based on that. In the beginning of the project
 and after the implementation seminar will be held for all the stakeholders including the Ministry of Education in order to reach the decision-makers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HealthPhysical and Population Education Department (Faculty of Education),Tribhuvan University (TU)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">30000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
