<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2012-2012000114</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowering the Communities for Youth</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to the development problem of youth unemployment and inactive citizenship causing hopelessness and social evils such as crime violence poverty homelessness break up of families alcoholism prostitution and abuse. Namibian econ
omy is not generating enough job opportunities despite the positive economic growth (4-5 %) and thus there is an urgent need to build in a mechanism for targeted youth support.Immediate objectives are: 0) effective project management and administration con
ducted 1) strengthened capacities of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in Namibia (ELCIN) to develop targeted youth support approach 2) succesfully performed pilot project that contribute to capabilities of vulnerable youth and 3) best practices shared with 
relevant stakeholders and partners.Human rights and gender equality are strongly emphasised. Alarming share of youth notably girls has been left out from education and employment and remained vulnerable. The project respects and addresses their human right
s and well-being by empowering them to become subjects of their own development and the society as a whole.The project does not create any new structure but is positioned at the new office of social service by ELCIN. The project will provide a new way of t
hinking and doing together by applying methods of participatory youth work in selected communities. Altogether the project creates a new targeted youth support approach facilitated by ELCIN.The ultimate beneficiaries of the project are vulnerable youth age
s 15 to 25 with special reference to school drop-outs. Major indirect beneficiary is the ELCIN notably its personnel and volunteers whose capacities to provide targeted support for vulnerable youth will be strengthened.The key project activities include bu
ilding the capacity for effective project management, supporting administration with well developed monitoring systems, conducting needs and resource analysis, organising study and training trips for project personnel and community leaders, organising on-s
ite training, training of local communities in targeted youth support, developing new models and working methods, empowering youth in life and non-formal skills, training of youth in citizenship, organising youth clubs, providing case management, organisin
g youth leadership training, organizing joint youth-elderly people workshops, encouraging volunteering, and building network for effective sharing and awareness raising.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evangelical Lutheran Church in Namibia (ELCIN)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-02-19" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">125000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">170000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">155000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">450000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
