<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2012-2012000443</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;UNESCO,&quot;&quot; support to the 2013 World Summit on the Information Society Review Event (WSIS+10)&quot;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;UNESCO&apos;s 36th General Conference requested the organization of a high level WSIS review meeting in 2013.  The meeting entitled &quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;Towards Knowledge Societies for Peace and Sustainable Development&quot;&quot;&quot;&quot; will be organized at UNESCO&apos;s headquarters in Paris fr
om 25-27 February 2013. It is an integral part of the WSIS +10 preparatory process which will assess the progress made in the implementation of WSIS commitments in accordance with the Resolution 60/252 of the United Nations General Assembly and the paragra
ph 111 of the Tunis Agenda for Information Society. The outcomes of the UNESCO review meeting will feed into the UN wide WSIS+10 process and into the UN MDGs review process.Finland&apos;s contribution  will be channeled firstly to the participation from develop
ing countries and to the offering of remote participation possibilities through online tools and secondly  to the production and sharing of quality reports on the outcomes of the meeting. The objective of the Finnish support is to enhance the openness and 
inclusiveness of the meeting  by giving priority to the least developed countries and the marginalized groups and to  raise the quality of the meeting by facilitating the collection analyses  and sharing of its outcomes. The overall goal of the event is to
 review the progress made in the implementation of the WSIS commitments from the perspective of UNESCO&apos;s WSIS work. Therefore the review will focus to the soft components of  harnessing the ICTs for development. These include developing relevant content an
d services building human capacities and creating enabling environment and coherent policy instruments. This all is guided by principles that ensure human rights support democracy and good governance. The project is coordinated by UNESCO&apos;s Communication an
d Information Sector and internal Steering Committee created for the purpose of the event.  The preparations  also involve the lead facilitation agencies of the WSIS process as well as all stakeholders through open consultation process. The time frame for 
the implementation of the project extends from August 2012 (research and selection of sponsored participants) till December 2013 (follow-up activies).   &quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41304" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-11-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="22040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">150000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">150000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
