<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2012-2012000387</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethics in Public Governance Training for Public Servants and Related Professionals</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this project is to introduce the participants to viewing governance in the perspective of ethics and integrity. The main objective of the project is to increase the professional competence by advancing the concrete skills and recognition of eth
ical issues in the professionals employed in the public service through a structured training programme.During the 7 months of the project CSS will prepare hold and report on a semester-long training course for members of the police the prosecution the jud
iciary taxation authorities and members of the Anti-Corruption Agency focusing on the main ethical underpinnings of governance and public administration horizontal and vertical dimensions of public administration and decision- making the relationship betwe
en legality and integrity in the exercise of public administration the main definitions and perceptions of ethics in governance in transitional societies. The sessions will also cover the main typologies of ethics and their consequences for the particular 
contexts and methods  of  governance  in  the  areas  covered  by  the  target  groups  for  the  participants.  The curriculum for the course will provide in introduction to the essential integrity-based regulatory themes for public administration thus fa
cilitating the ongoing effort to re-position public sector controls from the strictly legal-positivistic system (based solely on criminal justice) to include a complementary  integrity-based  dimension  of  regulation  which  is  a  recognised  priority  o
f  the Serbian government.The specific activities will include preparation and recruitment during the first two months of the project training that will run month 3 through month 6 of the project and evaluation reporting and publication of results on the w
eb site which will take up month 7 of the project.The project will include a Finnish component in the training itself through the inclusion of two Finnish expert lecturers in the curriculum. The rationale for this aspect of the project is that Finland is o
ne of the countries that are ranked as de facto corruption-free with transparency and institutional integrity standards and policies that are capable of serving as examples for the development of important ethics criteria and practices in Serbia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">33390</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">33390</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">33390</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
