<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2012-2012000164</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable development model for schools and communities - 100 million trees by 2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENO Programme Association together with Arbonaut Ltd (Finland) 4H Tanzania Zambia Forestry College and Copperbelt University Natural Resources and Environmental Society will implement a project to raise awareness of sustainable development issues in school
s and communities and create a model to be used around the world for planning and implementing such activities in the communities. The schools are encouraged to adopt the issues in their curricula to create a wider understanding of sustainable development.
  Tanzania and Zambia are both rich in natural resources. The population in the countries are growing and an increased need for living space and agricultural land as well as industrial activities have increased the countries? deforestation rates  to 450 00
0km2 in Tanzania and 250-300 000km2 in Zambia annually.  Deforestation causes for example climate change erosion and wind damages to farms. The population is rather young for example in Zambia almost half of the population is under the age of 15. Both coun
tries have identified that the lack of capacity is hindering development and actions to address the capacity issue as well as understanding of natural resources and income generation have been seen crucial. The project objectives include teacher training i
n sustainable development activities and community and school engagement in tree nursery activities and tree planting. One pellet factory will be set up in Zambia as a demonstration project for introducing sustainable methods for using renewable energy sou
rces. Training will be hands-on workshops on tree planting nursery establishment pellet production environmental monitoring tools and use and the processes will be documented and followed-up. The documents will be available for all through the project webs
ite to enable other communities to plan similar activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Copperbelt University Natural Resources and Environmental Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Tanzania,Zambia"></location>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2012-01-01">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">50000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
