<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-COMDEV GRT</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Development Grants Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Philippines Community Development Grants Project was used in the past for accounting purposes but it is not currently an active project for the program.?It has no funds either committed or disbursed against it and has a sector code of 99810 (sector not specified).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Philippines</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-05-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-05-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-COMDEV GRT-0130" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-COMDEV GRT-0182" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-COMDEV GRT-0234" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-INFRSTRE" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-KC" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-REV RFRM" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-ROAD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-PHL-2750BXCOMD-ROADS PJT" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11) MCC and DSWD will (i) undertake a study of sub-projects assessing the performance, and causes of failures; (ii) agree upon classifying the sub-projects in KALAHI-CIDSS into the following three classifications: (1) those excluded from the KALAHI-CIDSS Project, (2) those that may be undertaken with additional specialized engineering design and oversight, and (3) those for which communities have demonstrated a high success rate in undertaking; and (iii) agree on how the additional expertise required for sub-projects in category (2) will be provided.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12) Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding, the Department of Social Welfare and Development will provide MCC with a written confirmation, subject to MCC&apos;s satisfaction, of its intent to implement the MCC-funded KALAHI-CIDSS Project in accordance with MCC&apos;s Impact Evaluation strategy, which shall include but not be limited to adopting the MCC-approved methodology for the random selection of both the municipalities to be supported by the KALAHI-CIDSS Project and the control municipalities, from the set of eligible municipalities within each province and providing a focal person throughout the Impact Evaluation who will represent the Department of Social Welfare and Development on the joint advisory board that will oversee the Impact Evaluation.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13) By the date of submission of the first quarterly Disbursement Request following Entry into Force, and annually thereafter, the Department of Social Welfare and Development shall provide MCC with a staffing plan and budget, subject to MCC satisfaction, illustrating measures the Department of Social Welfare and Development intends to take that year in meeting its total contribution of Twelve Million United States Dollars (USD $12 million) in staff and funding over the life of the Compact.  Said budget shall reflect a minimum annual monetary contribution of Nine Hundred Thousand United States Dollars (USD $900,000) to finance operating costs of the KALAHI-CIDSS Project, as agreed by MCC in the multi-year financial plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">14) Prior to the initial Disbursement of any Program Funding for the KALAHI-CIDSS Project, MCC and DSWD will (i) undertake a study of sub-projects assessing the performance, and causes of failures; (ii) agree upon classifying the sub-projects in KALAHI-CIDSS into the following three classifications: (1) those excluded from the KALAHI-CIDSS Project, (2) those that may be undertaken with additional specialized engineering design and oversight, and (3) those for which communities have demonstrated a high success rate in undertaking; and (iii) agree on how the additional expertise required for sub-projects in category (2) will be provided.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">15) Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding, the Department of Social Welfare and Development shall have entered into an Implementing Entity Agreement with MCA-Philippines, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, to ensure proper implementation of the Project.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
