<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12572A0102-AFG-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Government Partnership 2019-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Open Government Partnership 2019-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen avser ett k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till organisationen Open Government Partnership om totalt 45 MSEK under en tre&#xE5;rsperiod 2019-2021. 

Open Government Partnership &#xE4;r ett multi-intressent-initiativ som startade 2011 med syfte att &#xF6;vertyga regeringar om insatser f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja &#xF6;ppenhet, st&#xE4;rka medborgarinflytande bek&#xE4;mpa korruption och anv&#xE4;nda gemensamt utvecklade metoder f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka samh&#xE4;llsstyrningen. Open Government Partnership best&#xE5;r f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande av 79 nationella och 20 lokala regeringar och ett tusental civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer. F&#xF6;r att bli medlem i Open Government Partnership m&#xE5;ste regeringar uppfylla de villkor som &#xE4;r uppst&#xE4;llda, g&#xF6;ra ett offentligt uttalande om &#xF6;ppenhet, utverka en nationell handlingsplan med hj&#xE4;lp av medborgarkonsultationer och rapportera utvecklingen med hj&#xE4;lp av den oberoende &#xF6;versynsmekanism som finns i initiativet. 

Open Government Partnerships vision &#xE4;r formulerad som att &quot;fler regeringar ska bli mer transparenta, mer ansvarstagande och mer lyh&#xF6;rda f&#xF6;r sina medborgares deltagande med slutgiltigt m&#xE5;l att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra styrning och samh&#xE4;llsservice&quot;. Arbetet kretsar kring nationella handlingsplaner som tas fram i en gemensam process mellan regeringar och civila samh&#xE4;llet. Open Government Partnership arbetar utifr&#xE5;n en strategi som uppdaterades 2016 och utg&#xF6;r v&#xE4;gledning f&#xF6;r verksamheten. Strategin kommer att utvecklas under 2019 f&#xF6;r att med utg&#xE5;ngspunkt i nuvarande vision formulera v&#xE4;gar f&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; b&#xE4;ttre genomslag fram till 2022.

Strategin omfattar f&#xF6;ljande omr&#xE5;den: 
1) &#xD6;kat fokus p&#xE5; medborgarcentrerad samh&#xE4;llsstyrning
2) Breddat gemensamt &#xE4;garskap f&#xF6;r nationella handlingsplaner
3) &#xD6;kad ambitionsniv&#xE5; och l&#xE4;rande
4) St&#xE4;rkt kapacitet, koordinering och n&#xE4;tverk f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande
5) &#xD6;versyn av incitaments- och regelstruktur
6) St&#xE4;rkt varum&#xE4;rke och kommunikationsstrategi

Total budget f&#xF6;r 2019 &#xE4;r ca 12,4 MUSD. Budgetarna f&#xF6;r 2020 och 2021 &#xE4;r uppskattade till 13,4 MUSD. Total budget &#xE4;r ca 39,2 MUSD.
Sidas bidrag utg&#xF6;r knappt 10 %.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention concerns a core support of 45 MSEK during the three-year period 2019-2021. 

The Open Government Partnership (OGP) is a multi-stakeholder initiative established in 2011 aimed at securing commitments from governments to promote transparency, empower citizens, fight corruption and harness new technologies to strengthen governance. OGP currently comprises of 79 national and 20 local governments and some thousand civil society organisations. To become a member of OGP, governments must meet OGP&apos;s elibility criteria, endorse a high-level Open Government Declaration, deliver a National Action Plan (NAP) developed through public consultations, and commit to independent reporting on their progress through the Independent Review Mechanism (IRM). 

OGP is directed by a strategy for 2015-2018 that was &quot;refreshed&quot; in 2016 to more clearly articulate the vision and identify the best means to work for that. By early 2020 OGP will complete a medium-term planning process, with the goal of developing a three-year implementation plan and budget (2020-2022). This implementation plan will not lay out a new vision for OGP but will focus on collective results that are aimed to be achieved in three years and how this will happen.

The strategy focusses on the following areas:
1) Deepen citizen-centered gocvernance
2) Broaden collective ownership of OGP domestically
3) Raise collective ambition, peer exchange and learning across OGP countries
4) Strengthen capacity, coordination and coalitions for implementation
5) Review performance incentives and rules of engagement
6) Strengthen the OGP brand and communications strategy

The total budget for 2019 is about 12.4 MUSD. The budgets for 2020 and 2021 are estimated to 13.4 MUSD respectively. Total budget amounts to approximately 39.2 MUSD. 
Sida&apos;s contribution constitutes a little less than 10 % for each year.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Open Government Partnership (OGP) is a multi-stakeholder initiative established in 2011 aimed at securing commitments from governments to promote transparency, empower citizens, fight corruption and harness new technologies to strengthen governance. OGP currently comprises of 79 national and 20 local governments and some thousand civil society organisations. To become a member of OGP, governments must meet OGP&apos;s elibility criteria, endorse a high-level Open Government Declaration, deliver a National Action Plan (NAP) developed through public consultations, and commit to independent reporting on their progress through the Independent Review Mechanism (IRM).&#xA0;
OGP is directed by a strategy for 2015-2018 that was &quot;refreshed&quot; in 2016 to more clearly articualte the vision and identify the best means to work for that.&#xA0;In early 2020, OGP completed a medium-term planning process, with the goal of producing a three-year implementation plan and budget (2020-2022). This implementation plan will not lay out a new vision for OGP but focus on collective results that are aimed to be achieved in three years and how this will happen.
OGP&apos;s vision is formulated as: &quot;More governments become more transparent, moreaccountable, and more responsive to their own citizens, with the ultimate goal of improving the quality of governance, as well as the quality of services that citizens receive.&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Government Partnership Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Government Partnership Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">803500.6569160776</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">803500.6569160776</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-20">782580.18803</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">803500.6569160776</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/12572_12572_GrantAgreementbetweenSidaandOpenGovernmentPartnership.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12572 Agreement Sida and Open Government partnership</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/demo/12572_12572_BeslutominsatsOpenGovernmentPartnership(OGP)2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">12572 Beslut Open Government Partnership</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida has supported OGP since 2019. 2019 was a rather successful year for OGP, with one of the highlights being the summit in Ottawa in May (where Sida participated).&#xA0;
Other highlights reported:
&#x2022; Thirty-one members submitted action plans with 289 commitments.&#x2022; The most popular commitment policy areas were Marginalized Communities, Justice, Gender.&#x2022; Gender and Beneficial Ownership are the fastest growing areas of focus for commitments out of 37 policy areas.&#x2022; 85% of 2019 action plans address key gaps identified in their governments at the national or local level.
Six members submitted their first action plans, covering anti-corruption, civic space, open data, fiscal openness, and other policy areas.&#xA0;Twelve countries re-engaged with OGP by submitting new action plans after elections, showing continued&#xA0; political support for open government.
2020 was marked by the highly unexpected pandemic and the following lockdowns which made work difficult for many of Sida&apos;s partner (and their partner). OGP seized the moment and launched a campaign for open government during the pandemic and the responses that governments took to limit the spread of the disease as well as limiting the economic effects. &apos;Open Response + Open Recovery&apos; started in April 2020 by a crowdsourcing exercise that gathered over 450 examples of open government approaches for tackling COVID-19. Members of the open government community from all over the world shared examples of reforms being implemented by governments, civil society, citizens, or the private sector.&#xA0;Members can now access examples of reforms and related OGP commitments on different topics in the Guide to Open Government and the Coronavirus, along with resources from a wide range of more than 50 partners. OGP gives two examples in its recent annual report: Colombia committed to promote citizen participation by publishing information on COVID-19 emergency projects financed by royalties through its &#x201C;Auditores Ciudadanos&#x201D; (Citizen Auditors) application to allow citizen monitoring of public spending and ensure it has the desired impact. Afghanistan is using community-based monitoring and social audits to oversee compliance with COVID19 screening procedures, as well as to determine the availability of PPE equipment, necessary drugs, medical supplies, and ventilators in health centers across 13 provinces in the country. OGP further highlights supporting activities such as a digital forum which was an effort of multiple regional and thematic conversations with the purpose of sharing and learning from challenges faced by civil society.&#xA0;
According to an ongoing evaluation (Hewlett/FCDO), this initiative has had a mixed impact in the different countries. Nigeria is mentioned as an example where&#xA0;there was a high level round table early on, with&#xA0; hopes that open governance of the Nigerian Stimulus Package for COVID-19 recovery would become a&#xA0; separate annex to the NAP. This how now changed and the plan is now to integrate that work into current&#xA0; commitments. This potentially diminishes opportunities for distinct oversight and it is not mentioned in the current version of the updated NAP.
Another supporting event for the world&apos;s countries was the OGP Virtual Leaders Summit, at the 2020 UN General Assembly, which convened among others&#xA0;five heads of states (French President Emmanuel Macron, German Chancellor Angela Merkel, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, Georgian Prime Minister Giorgi Gakharia, and Nigerian President Muhammadu Buhari).&#xA0;
In the National Action Plans, OGP has focused on the policy areas: Campaigning for Gender and Inclusion, Fostering Justice, Fighting Corruption and&#xA0;Ensuring Effective Digital Governance. A few examples of results from the 2020 report: 1) The government of Sierra Leone is implementing a Gender Equality and Women&#x2019;s Empowerment Policy that will require the application of a gender perspective in policymaking and resource allocation&#xA0; based on gender-disaggregated data. 2)&#xA0;Croatia has been working on increasing transparency of political party and election financing through commitments in their second and third action plans. Using the information provided in the database of election campaign reports, developed by the State Election Commission as their OGP commitment, two civil society organizations that are members of the&#xA0;Croatian Multistakeholder Forum developed a searchable database of contributions and expenses reported by parties and complement this information with their own analysis of key observed trends and issues.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12572" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3248000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Afghanistan 2021-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Afghanistan 2021-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
