<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14048A0104-AFG-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">APSM SADA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">APSM SADA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first objective of this project is to contribute to the incorporation of the voices, demands and concerns for inclusive peace and reconciliation of minority groups in the political transition in Afghanistan. In order to achieve this, minorities have to be incorporated in the ongoing peace debates and negotiations. The expected results of the project are:
1.1. The establishment of a consultative process for various Afghan ethnic groups to openly and safely discuss their perceptions on active involvement of smaller minority groups in the ongoing peace process, and to participate in the implementation of a research that explores how to build an inclusive peace in the country.
1.2. Suggestions for a new inclusion mechanism and policy that will be discussed among the Afghan civil society, government and academic institutions as a result of the Policy Briefing Report published at the end of the project.
1.3. An increase in the awareness of the Afghan citizens on the ongoing peace process and peace inclusiveness, that ensures engagement of smaller minority groups in sustainable peace building.
1.4. An advancement of minorities&#x2019; civil and political rights through group discussion, interview, policy report and other interactive exposures with different groups, which will create a democratic space for inclusion of isolated minorities.
1.5. Providing smaller minority groups with an opportunity to enhance agency to meaningful participation, raise up their voice, demands and engage in conversation on peace process at various levels of Afghan society.
The second objective of the project is &quot;Incorporating of women&#x2019;s demands and strengthening their position in an inclusive talk for a lasting peace process in Afghanistan&quot;. This will be met through the following sub-objectives:
2.1. Supporting women in the peace process and building consensus among different groups of women;
2.2. Providing women rights perspectives on the role of women in the Afghan Negotiation Team with the Taliban;
2.3. Summarizing the views and demands of women and sharing them with various political, social, government, non-governmental organizations can contribute to long-term peace programs;
2.4. Producing articles and manual to emphasize on social awareness and advocacy efforts for women to articulate their views in peace process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med detta projekt &#xE4;r att bidra till att minoriteters r&#xF6;ster, f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntningar och farh&#xE5;gor f&#xF6;rs in i afghanska fredsprocesser, och att verka f&#xF6;r en inkluderande fred och f&#xF6;rsoning i Afghanistan.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of this project is the incorporation of non-dominant minorities&#x2019; voices, demands and concerns for an inclusive peace and reconciliation in Afghanistan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HREVO/Human Rights and Eradication of Violence Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">26059.4807648458</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">26059.4807648458</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-75.5724942181</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-01">26059.480764</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">26059.4807648458</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">-75.5724942181</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has contributed to an increased engagement of marginalised non-dominant ethnic groups in consultative processes forming part of the larger peace process in Afghanistan. The projet has gathered perceptions and concerns of minority constitutencies and built capacity among representatives&#xA0; to jointly carry out evidence-based advocacy efforts vis-a-vis government authorities. The advocacy work has contributed to a larger national debate on the issues experienced by minorities in Afghanistan, and the policy papers and research produced have provided policy-makers with recomendations based on the consultations conducted in 9 provinces across Afghanistan.&#xA0; The project has also contributed to awareness-raising among communities on the issues of minority groups by conducting provincial debates where representatives from different consitutents openly could share their concerns. By working with a rights-based approach, HREVO and CSHRN aimed to also raise awareness on human rights and the principles of accountability between the state and the population, and how it links up with the protection of these under the 2004 Consitution. The aims with this was to inform marginalised population groups of their rights under the current Consitution, and also to increase support for human rights in communities where the conception of human rights have been largely negative and connected to American imperialism. The establishment of a Minority Advocacy Committee has moreover contributed to increased cooperation and coordination among minority representatives and human rights advocates, particularly in advocacy efforts. Through capacity-building workshops, the advocacy committee members have also received practical tools in how to more efficiently undertake their own advocacy efforts going forward.&#xA0; During the course of the project,&#xA0;CSHRN engaged broadly with the Afghan public, both in Kabul and most of the provinces where 100 Afghan women activists, civil society activists, members of the High Council for National Reconciliation, members of the Afghan peace negotiating team, members of parliament, university professors, journalists, and others who are working for promoting human rights were interviewed. These interviews were written into articles highlighting the roles of Afghan women in the ongoing peace talks, pinpointing their hopes and concerns, and placed emphasis on the meaningful presence of women to ensure inclusive and sustainable peace. In total, 100 articles were published in both printed and online format in three main newspapers (8am Newspaper, Etilaatroz Newspaper, and Sobh-e-Kabul Newspaper) reaching&#xA0;Kabul, Herat, Bamyan, Panjsher, Parwan, Kapisa, Farah, Kandahar, Paktia, Kapisa, Nangarhar, and Balkh provinces. With these publications, the partners aimed to mainstream the support for women&apos;s rights and highlight the support among both men and women in order to also advocate for men&apos;s involvement in the pursuit of women&apos;s right to meaningful participation in the peace process, and the connection between an inclusive peace process and a more sustainable positive peace going forward.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="14048" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1040402" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="6494000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Afghanistan 2014-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Afghanistan 2014-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
