<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5205013702-AFG-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">R&#xE4;dda Barnen Afghanistan, Barns r&#xE4;ttigheter 2016-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Afghanistan, Child protection 2016-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention is to strengthened child protection prevention initiatives and quality access to child protection response services and reduce instances of violence, exploitation and neglect of children. Specifically, the project seeks to strengthen child protection systems at the national, provincial, district and community level to protect children at risk of abuse, exploitation, violence and neglect.

Following are the results to be achieved at outcome level:

Result 1: Strengthened community and formal government child protection systems (referring to before the political transition in August 2021) improve access to and utilization of preventive and response services.

Result 2: Violence against children is no longer tolerated in schools and at homes.

Result 3: Children involved in or at risk of entering harmful work can access adequate support and protection that reduce their risk and improves their own and their families&apos; livelihood opportunities as a way out of hazardous work.

Result 4: Local Civil Society organizations (CSOs) demonstrate enhanced organizational operation capacity and more specific capacity in child rights and protection programming.

Result 5: Community institutions, including those led by children and youth, are better able to respond to disasters affecting them.

Result 6: Boys and girls are protected from the direct impact of conflict through the prevention and response to recruitment and use by armed forces or armed groups and indirect impact through awareness-raising and community-based risk reduction activities (Nangarhar province).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning av R&#xE4;dda Barnens/Save the Childrens projekt f&#xF6;r barns r&#xE4;tt till trygghet och skydd i Afghanistan (som p&#xE5;g&#xE5;tt 2013 - 2015). Den nya insatsen &#xE4;r planerad att p&#xE5;g&#xE5; 2016-2019 i sex provinser. Fem av provinserna &#xE4;r samma som i projektets f&#xF6;rsta fas: Nangarhar, Sa-re-Pul, Jawzjan, Balkh och Kabul. En sj&#xE4;tte provins, Faryad, har tillkommit i och med att en humanit&#xE4;r komponent tagits &#xF6;ver fr&#xE5;n R&#xE4;dda Barnens humanit&#xE4;ra barnr&#xE4;ttsprogram i Afghanistan. Det &#xE4;r ett led i Sidas anstr&#xE4;ngningar att &#xF6;ka arbetet med  transition, dvs. &#xF6;verbryggning mellan humanit&#xE4;rt st&#xF6;d och utvecklingsst&#xF6;d. M&#xF6;jligheten fanns i och med att R&#xE4;dda Barnen varit verksamt med b&#xE5;da st&#xF6;dformerna i Afghanistan. Nu ges det humanit&#xE4;ra arbetet m&#xF6;jlighet att arbeta mer med l&#xE5;ngsiktigt st&#xF6;d i den sv&#xE5;ra utdragna konflikten. Den humanit&#xE4;ra komponenten och transitionen ska utv&#xE4;rderas under &#xE5;r tv&#xE5;. 

Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka barns r&#xE4;tt till trygghet och skydd, p&#xE5; en nationell, provinsiell, distrikt- och samh&#xE4;llsniv&#xE5; i Afghanistan och att minska f&#xF6;rekomsten av exploatering, f&#xF6;rsummelse, v&#xE5;ld och &#xF6;vergrepp mot barn. Insatsen &#xE4;r ett projekt.

Projektet kommer att inledas med en fem m&#xE5;nader l&#xE5;ng s.k. &quot;Inception phase&quot;, en inledningsfas med start i januari 2016 och rapporteras i en slutrapport i juni 2016.

Konfliktk&#xE4;nslighet &#xE4;r A och O givet den sv&#xE5;ra situationen f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i Afghanistan. Den inledande beredningen f&#xF6;reslog en projektperiod p&#xE5; tre &#xE5;r. Huvudberedningen och detta beslut f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;r en projektperiod p&#xE5; fyra &#xE5;r, d&#xE5; en fyra&#xE5;rig insats har ocks&#xE5; b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar att m&#xE4;ta resultat. Resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r utvecklingssamarbetet med Afghanistan 2015 - 2019 ger ocks&#xE5; utrymme f&#xF6;r det. Insatsens totala budget ligger i samband med ans&#xF6;kan p&#xE5; 49 700 000 SEK. 

Insatsen har f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngts till 2020 och &#xE4;r d&#xE4;rmed p&#xE5; totalt 62 700 000 SEK.

Sida &#xE4;r den enda givaren.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed intervention will build and expand on the previous project phase 2013-2015. The project will be implemented during the four-year period from 2016 to 2019 in six provinces. Five of the provinces are the same as in the previous project phase: Nangarhar, Sa-re-Pul, Jawzjan, Balkh and Kabul. An additional sixth province is added; Faryab as an additional humanitarian component was included in the project as transition from Save the Children&apos;s humanitarian work in Afghanistan. This is a part of Sida&#x2019;s efforts to link humanitarian assistance with development aid.
 
The overall objective of this program is strengthened child protection prevention initiatives and quality access to child protection response services reduce instances of violence, exploitation and neglect of children. Specifically, the program seeks to strengthen child protection systems at the national, provincial, district and community level to protect children at risk of abuse, exploitation, violence and neglect. 

The project will begin with a five-month &quot;Inception Phase starting in January 2016 and be reported in an inception report in June 2016.

Conflict sensitivity is key, given the difficult situation of human rights in Afghanistan. The initial assessment suggested a project period of three years. The appraisal, and this decision is proposing a project period of four years as a four-year effort is better placed to measure results. The Results Strategy for Development Cooperation with Afghanistan 2015 - 2019 also allows for this. The total budget as of the application was 49.7 million SEK. 

The contribution has been extended until 2020 and the total budget is 62.7 million SEK.

Sida is the only donor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22502" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children, Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22502" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children, Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.2 - By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.2 - Till 2030 m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra och verka f&#xF6;r att alla m&#xE4;nniskors, oavsett &#xE5;lder, k&#xF6;n, funktionsneds&#xE4;ttning, ras, etnicitet, ursprung, religion eller ekonomisk eller annan st&#xE4;llning, blir inkluderade i det sociala, ekonomiska och politiska livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.3 - Ensure equal opportunity and reduce inequalities of outcome, including by eliminating discriminatory laws, policies and practices and promoting appropriate legislation, policies and action in this regard.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.3 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika m&#xF6;jligheter och minska f&#xF6;rekomsten av oj&#xE4;mlika utfall, bland annat genom att avskaffa diskriminerande lagstiftning, politik och praxis och fr&#xE4;mja lagstiftning, politik och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder av l&#xE4;mpligt slag i detta h&#xE4;nseende.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">699553.451713323</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-01">701221.293753</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">699553.451713323</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International (SCI) in Afghanistan formed formal partnerships with three implementing partners: Help the Afghan Children organization (HTAC), Organization of Human Welfare (OHW) and Humanitarian Assistance and Development Association for Afghanistan (HADAAF). These partners implemented the project in five out of six target provinces (Kabul, Nangarhar, Faryab, Jawzjan and Sari-Pol) with technical support from the provincial SCI CP team, while SCI implemented directly in Balkh province.

The Law of Protection of Childrens Rights was passed by presidential decree last year - in 2018. This law provides the required legal framework for supporting children in Afghanistan, though it was not approved by parliament. SCI contributed to drafting the law and has been an active advocate in getting the law passed.

Result 1: The Implementing Partners (IP) capacity in Child protection, case management and referral, Child Rights Programming, Positive Discipline in Everyday Parenting (PDEP), Positive Discipline in Everyday Teaching (PDET), Fatherhood, and CP program development and implementation improved significantly. During 2019, SCI and partners managed to respond to 1,171 (624 girls and 547 boys) cases, including cases of child labor (20), family separations (2), early marriages (7), physical abuse (10), health cases (327), neglect (5), lack of National Identity Card (493), different child protection cases (98), education (193), violence (15) and SGBV (1). All cases were closed successfully and no case remained open. The total number of cases that were managed increased from 785 in 2018 to 1,171 in 2019.

A capacity gap assessment was made and assessed the functionality of child protection mechanisms in five provinces (Nangarhar, Balkh, Jawzjan, Saripul and Faryab) to identify service providers&apos; capacity to respond to child protection cases and to inform the development of a capacity building plan for Community Based Child Protection Networks (CBCPN). Further, SCI met regularly with religious leaders to coordinate and share information on needs and to support safe identification and referrals using the recently developed service mapping. As a result, during 2019 a team of representatives from the Directorate of National Statistics was deployed to IDP villages in Nangarhar to support families to obtain their National Identity Card (NID), which would enable them to access critical public services, including enrolment in schools for children.

During 2019 a total of 750 (348 female and 402 male) individuals representing service providers such as kindergarten teachers, police, orphanages, the Juvenile Justice Rehabilitation Centre (JRC) and others received training on Child Rights and Protection. Following the training, an increase in reporting of cases to CPANs was found, who then provided timely services to affected children. Furthermore, police officers who had received training on child protection started using child friendly approaches handling cases involving children in conflict with the law or interacting with children in JRCs. The children in JRC received access to education, recreational activities and social workers to support them through their trials.

To address gender inequality within communities, SCI developed a manual on Gender Equality from an Islamic Perspective, which was signed off by the Ministry of Haj and Religious Affairs (MoHRA) in 2019. Using this manual, religious leaders were sensitized on gender equality and in turn conducted community sensitisation meetings to raise awareness of gender equality through Friday prayers and religious events.

Result 2: A total of 806 fathers were trained using the contextualized fatherhood manual over a two-day period where they were also able to share their experiences and reflect on how their behaviours impacted their wives and children. Following the training, fathers committed to taking on more significant roles in household chores and to supporting their wives in the home. Average scores of the pre- and post-test knowledge gained was 34% and 49% respectively. Men also received support from religious leaders, which further promoted gender equality and sensitivity.

To make schools violence-free, the program was not only designed to sensitize and train teachers across 40 schools, but also to empower students through Shabnam and Shadab sessions to say no to violence, and to raise awareness of the CGs on childrens rights to protection and self-confidence. Emotional abuse and PHP are perceived to have reduced in all 40 schools. This was reported by children in quarterly meetings to CBCPNs members and program staff. As a result, SCI and its partners continued to use the contextualized version of the Shabnam and Shadab module to sensitize another 602 (313 girls and 289 boys) members of CGs in 2019. These sessions were implemented in 60 villages in all five targeted provinces (Nangarhar, Balkh, Jawzjan, Saripul and Faryab) from April - August 2019. 

Result 3: SCI and partners transitioned 105 children (42 girls and 63 boys) from streets and high-risk places into schools where they received psychosocial and recreational support and were protected from abuse and exploitation. As a precondition for receiving Income Generating Assistance (IGA) support, parents committed to removing their children from the streets where they were engaged in harmful work. IGA beneficiary developed individualized business plans with the assistance of SCI. Common initiatives include opening commerce shops, carpet weaving, and raising livestock. In contrast to 2018, where 24% of businesses were female-led, the figure for 2019 was 35%. 

Result 4: Local CSOs demonstrated enhanced organizational operation capacity and increased capacity in child rights programming. The pre-test paced CSOs existing knowledge at an average of 16%, which increased by an average of 47% in the post-test. 

During 2019, it was observed that female-led CSOs gave more consideration for the rights of women and girls than male-led CSOs in Nangahar. SCI and its partners agreed to identify such CSOs and include them in the cost extension to promote womens rights and increase collective capacity on SGBV case management. SCI will build the capacity of women-led CSOs on SGBV and women rights with support from the Gender Thematic Advisor, and will improve capacity strengthening of the male-led CSOs through coaching based on the Child Led Participatory Situation Analysis findings and childrens recommendations. In addition, the CSOs will coordinate their action points to align with the Directorate of Women Affairs.

Result 5: Following the DRR training in 2018, it was recommended by the CBCPNs members and CGs that Save the Children sensitizes CBCPNs on Child Protection in Emergencies (CPiE), including needs of children with disabilities in an emergency. SCI and its partners consequently trained the CBCPNs members on CPiE. To facilitate a joint and collaborative response in these villages, the CBCPNs collaborated with Community Emergency Response Team and agreed on joint roles and responsibilities. Furthermore, to broadly support CPiE, linkages was established during 2019 between district-level authorities and the Afghanistan National Disaster Management Authority. As a result, each community developed an Emergency Prepared Plan (EPP) with clear roles and responsibilities. 

Result 6: during 2019 SCI and OHW partnered with the CPU in Nangarhar Police to prevent children from joining armed groups. Police were trained on age recognition and the negative impacts of child recruitment into the local police force. In addition, regular meetings and follow-up visits were facilitated with the CPU in order to provide ongoing support and share information. 26 religious leaders were engaged to promote awareness on the responsibilities of parents toward their children. With support from the CPU, ten families were provided with IGA start-up kits and their children left the streets. In 2019, it was recognized that 23 children (all boys), due to violence at home, tried to join the police/army to escape abuse. SCI and its partners will continue training parents on positive parenting skills during the cost extension period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52050137" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3248000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Afghanistan 2021-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Afghanistan 2021-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
