<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11170A0102-AFG-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women Afghanistan 2018-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Women Afghanistan 2018-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen jobbar f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter och j&#xE4;mdst&#xE4;lldhet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution is focusing on improving human rights and gender equality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Revised Addendum to the Strategic Note is the strategy which will drive UN Women&#x2019;s work in Afghanistan 2018-2022. It has been developed as a proposal to Sweden and Norway, but it constitutes also an extension to UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Note 2014 -2017 for activities in Afghanistan. UN Women has ensured Sida that should a formal revision of the Strategic Note be carried out during the latter part of 2018 for UN Women&apos;s internal purposes, it will be fully in line with the vision and strategy in the Revised Addendum, and aligned with global standards in its framing and presentation.
UN Women will focus on the following areas of implementation:1) Women, Peace and Security &#x2013; focused on supporting the implementation of the National Action Plan (NAP) on 1325; 2) Women&#x2019;s Political Participation and Leadership &#x2013; focused on women&#x2019;s full participation in political life and elections; 3) Ending Violence Against Women &#x2013; focused on survivors&#x2019; access to quality services, access to justice, and primary prevention of violence through transforming harmful social norms; and 4) Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment &#x2013; focused on women in the informal sector.
These four programme areas for UN Women in Afghanistan build upon the foundation of support to the implementation of global norms and standards for gender equality and the empowerment of women.
The impact of the Afghanistan Country Office (ACO) on supporting intergovernmental processes and global norms is meant to be that a comprehensive and dynamic set of global norms and standards on gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls is strengthened and implemented in Afghanistan. This is linked to Outcome 1 of UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Plan: Women lead and participate in decision making at all levels.
ACO will continue to implement its normative mandate by leveraging its convening role and technical expertise to strengthen the Afghan government and civil society organizations to engage with global normative processes, and to use global norms and standards in implementing the Sustainable Development Goals at national level. ACO will strengthen the capacity of both the government and civil society to engage with CEDAW monitoring and reporting, and assist incorporating CEDAW into national legislation and policies. ACO will further continue to support Afghanistan&#x2019;s meaningful engagement of in the Commission on the Status of Women (CSW), Beijing + 25 and other global intergovernmental processes, including through support for preparatory platforms and consultations.
In the area of women, peace and security, ACO&#x2019;s planned impact is that an enabling policy and legal environment for implementation, monitoring and reporting of WPS NAP 1325 in Afghanistan is created. This links to Outcome 5 of UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Plan.
Focus of ACO&#x2019;s work on women, peace and security will be on supporting the financing, reporting, and implementation of Afghanistan&#x2019;s National Action Plan on 1325 (2015-2022). NAP 1325 details commitments across the four pillars of participation, protection, prevention, and relief and recovery. Key commitments of NAP 1325 include increasing women&#x2019;s participation in decision making and the executive levels of civil service, security, peace and reintegration; improving women&#x2019;s access to justice, and effective provision of health and psychosocial support for survivors of sexual violence; as well as capacity building for civil society (particularly women&#x2019;s organizations) on women, peace, and security.
ACO will work with government and civil society partners to create an enabling environment for implementation, monitoring, financing, and reporting of NAP 1325 in Afghanistan. This will include advocating for adequately financed accountability frameworks for NAP 1325 that are monitored by the government, with checks and balances by civil society and support as needed; ensuring the government is aware of its obligations and provided with the technical expertise to implement and report on NAP 1325; ensuring that civil society has the capacity and resources to monitor NAP 1325 and carry out evidence-based advocacy for the implementation of the women, peace and security agenda in Afghanistan.
To address the under-representation of women&#x2019;s engagement in elections and in political leadership in Afghanistan and to strengthen the voice of women as&#xA0;leaders in governance, ACO will continue to support Women&#x2019;s Political Empowerment and Leadership. ACO&#x2019;s impact in this area is Afghan women lead, participate in and benefit equally from governance systems and links to Outcome 5 of UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Plan.
To ensure transformative programming in Women&apos;s Political Participation (WPP), UN Women&#xA0; will collaborate with UNAMA and UNDP to implement a comprehensive WPP programming throughout the electoral cycle. ACO will build on its programmatic experience in the region to partner with civil society and national authorities to encourage and enable more women to register and to vote in provincial and presidential elections as well as continue to support aspiring candidates in parliamentary elections. Furthermore, ACO will support a cadre of women leaders interested in running for office and/or leading at the community level, as well as to change the social norms determining how women are perceived as leaders. ACO will do this by supporting women leaders, candidates and aspirants to engage in political life and civil society organizations to engage in community awareness programmes and national campaigns, as well as through South-South cooperation.
This programme will further look to build synergies, where possible, with programming on Women&apos;s Economic Empowerment and, in particular, on efforts under the Safe Markets project to support women&#x2019;s leadership at market vendors&#x2019; association level, for a bottom-up approach to developing women&#x2019;s leadership at all levels.
EVAW- ACO links to Outcome 4 of UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Plan through its impact of all Afghan women and girls live a life free from all forms of violence. To live free from violence, women and girls need a robust, coordinated response to the violence they face that includes accessible, high-quality essential services and comprehensive, transformative prevention programming across all levels of the socio-ecological model. To respond to the high levels of violence against women and girls in Afghanistan, and in line with lessons learned, the EVAW programme will leverage and contextualize the best global evidence on prevention of VAW to transform the social norms that perpetuate gender inequality and violence against women and girls, leading to a reduction in violence in intervention sites, and will, in parallel, strengthen services for survivors of violence. The ACO will deliver comprehensive programming modeled on the EVAW Flagship Programme Initiative (FPI).
Afghanistan is strongly positioned to advance a primary prevention and social norms programme at the community level with a set of parameters in place including: access to services, an advanced policy environment (including legislation), and in some cases, the ability to leverage off of already established community based programmes.
The ACO will support national partners in a number of pilot provinces to develop and implement the community-based prevention programmes and to integrate faith and other key community strengths to create gender transformative social change. The programme will identify and build on what works already in Afghanistan in terms of primary prevention and social norms programming, and will develop a Afghan adaptation of the world&#x2019;s most successful primary prevention approach from Uganda, which documented a 52% reduction in intimate partner violence. Maximizing the impact of community-based programming, the ACO will also work at the national and provincial levels to advance social norms campaigning through partnerships with faith leaders and faith-based bodies.
Provincial community-based prevention programmes will be the focus of research to generate concrete evidence of what works in transforming harmful attitudes, beliefs and norms regarding the acceptability of violence against women and girls. This research will advance the field of violence prevention programming, and will be catalytic in identifying prevention interventions which can subsequently be taken to scale in Afghanistan.
Recognizing that work to prevent violence increases demand for survivor services, the ACO will continue work with and convene Government and CSO partners to develop capacity and best practice standards and guidelines to ensure that women and girls who experience violence, have access to quality essential services to recover; this will include supporting the development of decentralized service delivery to ensure those living outside the main urban areas are able to access services and supporting the coordination of service delivery across sectors.
The work on both primary prevention and essential services will further have national impact through centrally managed technical assistance that will be provided to national stakeholders across Afghanistan, and through evidence generation and dissemination. Through this approach, the ACO will strengthen the capacity of government and civil society actors to develop and implement policies and programmes to prevent VAW.
WEE- The ACO&#x2019;s impact for Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment is Afghan women have income security, decent work and economic autonomy; this links to Outcome 3 of UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Plan. The ACO will continue to develop its work in WEE through a focus on women in the informal sector, both in increasing their engagement in economic activity and addressing their rights and safety.
To create lasting change for Afghan women, it is vital to fully understand the barriers, both structural and cultural, they face when engaging in the economy. The &#x2018;time-use survey&#x2019; to be conducted in fall of 2018, will uncover in inherent gender-biases in the laws and policies governing this sector and identify the key chokeholds where interventions can create the largest impact. The survey will examine topics such as care work, occupational segregation, intra-household bargaining, valuation of time, among others. The results will inform the normative work UN Women are undertaking with Ministries to create policies that promote gender inclusive economies, such as the National Financial Inclusion Strategy for Afghanistan (MoF), Gender responsive Budgeting (GRB), the Small and Medium Enterpices (SME) policy (MoCI) and the National Labour policy (WEE-NPP).
Building on these results and UN Women&#x2019;s global best practices, ACO will streamline evidence-based social mobilization activities jointly being conducted with partners, including UNESCO and Aga Khan Development Foundation (AKDF), to more effectively convey messages and promote social norm change. Changes in attitudes towards WEE will enable more equitable access and control over economic resources, strengthen women&#x2019;s capacities and productivity, reduce poverty and promote economic growth.
A comprehensive initiative within this programmatic area is the Safe Markets project focusing on the informal sector. The project is underpinned by the following strategies: (i) creating and supporting representative marketplace groups that claim the rights and represent the interests of market vendors; (ii) supporting improved socio-economic security of market vendors, through access to appropriate services, training and interventions which respond to their financial and business needs; (iii) building the capacity of local government and market management to implement policies, laws and budgets that ensure gender responsive marketplaces; and (iv) improving marketplace infrastructure to make them safer, more sustainable and accessible.
The Safe Market project is a solid example of inter-sectional programming that supports WEE through leadership, improved governance, infrastructure and safety, and support to gender responsive planning and budgeting at the local government level; it will therefore be implemented in close partnership and coordination with other ACO programmes. ACO will continue to pursue opportunities to develop strategic partnerships with sister UN agencies for project implementation.
ACO is leveraging its convening role in the WEE-NPP working group to support government and agencies (NGOs, UN and Private Sector) to streamline and increase coordination of WEE activities to increase impact and reduce duplication of efforts, particularly in terms of access to finance and vocational training. Further, ACO is working closely with the World Bank&#x2019;s ARTF&#x2019;s programmes (e.g. citizen&#x2019;s charter, EZ-KAR, WEE-RDP) in collaboration with ongoing ACO activities, such as the Safe Markets project and Women&#x2019;s Savings Groups.
Across all strategies, the WEE programme will ensure a continued focus on supporting women from the informal sector, specifically from the rural areas, including refugees and returnees and those with disabilities. Through the WEE programme, women will benefit from increased opportunities to actively engage in the economy from small-scale farming to market linkages to cross-border trading; enterprise and value chain development; financial literacy and savings groups; among others. Engagement with women&#x2019;s private sector and business organizations is also a key strategy to the implementation of the WEE programme.
Leveraging UN Women&#x2019;s coordinating and convening mandate on engagement with civil society organizations who work on women&#x2019;s right is a priority cutting across ACOs work which has the power to propel progress of all national action on gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment. Gender in Humanitarian Action is mainstreamed throughout ACOs work as an emerging area of focus, in response to the demands of partners, national priorities, gaps and needs of women and girls.
In line with UN Women&#x2019;s commitment on Agenda 2030 to leave no-one behind, programmes include interventions targeting the most&#xA0;at risk&#xA0;women and girls in Afghanistan including: adult poor women (rural and urban), especially women working in the informal sector, women with disabilities, women and girls affected by, or at risk of, humanitarian crisis. The programmes will also target men and boys, in particular through community-level interventions, to transform harmful social norms, which drive violence against women and maintain gender inequality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2331844.83904441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2331844.83904441</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">2331844.83904441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2331844.83904441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-05">4602780.079167</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">2331844.83904441</value>
  </transaction>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11170" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3248000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Afghanistan 2021-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Afghanistan 2021-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
