<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-495140-Training Workshop for Civil Society Organizations on Gender Programming for SDGs and Gender Budget Monitoring in Zamfara State</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-495140" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Environmental Programme</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training Workshop for Civil Society Organizations on Gender Programming for SDGs and Gender Budget Monitoring in Zamfara State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training Workshop for Civil Society Organizations on Gender Programming for SDGs and Gender Budget Monitoring WEP in continuation of the implementation of activities under her Project, &#x201C;Ensuring Effective Implementation of Programmes, Policies and Legislations, that contribute towards Achieving Gender Equality in Nigeria by 2030&#x201D; funded by The Kingdom of Netherlands was in Zamfara State to implement the next activity on the project - Training for Civil Society Organizations on Gender Programming for SDGs and Gender Budget Monitoring. The training was held from 22nd to 23rd August, 2017 at the Fulbe Villa Hotel, Gusau and drew participants from 50 CSOs spread across different parts of the state. The workshop was aimed at sensitizing Civil Society Organizations (CSOs) especially women-focused CSOs on designing or facilitating the design of programmes for SDGs that mainstream gender issues. This workshop was deemed critical towards building capacities that will facilitate effective implementation of gender responsive programmes in the states towards attainment of the SDGs. The workshop also equipped the targeted relevant CSOs with the skills to monitor implementation of budgets in their state for effective delivery of basic facilities and services for the citizens, especially the vulnerable populations, and raised their awareness on monitoring and accountability for implementation of SDGs in line with the objective of the project. See pictures of training https://www.facebook.com/womenenvironmentalprogramme/posts/920359914798128</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kingdom of Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-22" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This workshop started on 22 August, 2017 and ended on 23 August.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity is implemented in Nigeria in Benue and Zamfara States</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to contribute to attainment of gender equality in Nigeria by 2030</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2017-08-23">2050500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Training Workshop for Civil Society Organizations on Gender Programming for SDGs and Gender Budget Monitoring in Zamfara State">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2017-08-23">2050500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This amount include hall hire, feeding, transportation for participants, accommodation for staff, resource persons fee and workshop materials</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
