<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-495140-495140</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-495140" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Environmental Programme</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy activities by sub-grantees in Benue and Zamfara States</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The organizations that benefited from the sub-grants in Benue and Zamfara States which received funding in quarter 2 of 2018 carried out the following activities during this reporting period: 1.1 Stakeholders&#x2019; engagement 1.1.1 Advocacy Visits to relevant Government institutions in the Benue and Zamfara states. 1.1.2 Advocacy visits to respective LGAs &amp; selected Communities. (The communities were selected based on communities that are marginalized of social services that affect women, children and vulnerable community members). 1.2 Interactive meetings on rural women&#x2019;s priorities Read full report of activities on the following link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1m27YQlxs-k8Z-IOVHwGoNml-zl_yI3wv</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="49514" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kingdom of Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This advocacy activities were implemented between July and September 2018. Different organizations started on different dates. The activities continue in the next quarter</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">These activities are being implemented in Benue and Zamfara States in Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of these activities is to ensure gender equality in Benue and Zamfara States</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2018-09-30">1800000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
