<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-495140-2017AnnualAnalyticalOverviewNG-CAC-495140</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-495140" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Environmental Programme</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2017 Annual Analytical Overview</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the year 2017, the following activities were planned and implemented: i. Pre-project Advocacy and Sensitization in Zamfara state ii. Development of Training Manual on &#x2013; SDGs and Gender-Responsive Legislations, Policies and Programmes iii. Training workshop for legislators, commissioners and other states executives, legislative aids and staff on SDGs and gender-responsive legislation, policies and programmes iv. Assessment of State&#x2019;s Policies and Legislations related to Gender Equality v. Workshop to Validate Results of Assessment of State&#x2019;s Policies and Legislations: vi. Publication of Result of Assessment vii. Development of a Training Manual for Civil Society Organizations viii. Training Workshop for Civil Society Organizations on Gender Programming for SDGs and Gender Budget Monitoring. Read more on the following link - https://drive.google.com/open?id=1KLAvIOp35L4sDrtMtJnYUxYhVImtH8dd</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="RSG0123117" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kingdom of Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This analytical overview covers the period 1 January to 31 December, 2017</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is being implemented in Nigeria in Benue and Zamfara States</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to the attainment of gender equality in Nigeria</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
