<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-56484038-C_006257</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation ICCO</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting the Human Right to Food and Nutrition</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FIAN International 2017  2018</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FIAN International is a membership based organization that advocates for the realization of the human right to adequate food and nutrition. According to the 2015 FAO State of Food Insecurity in the World Report, around 795 million people continue to face hunger. A further 2 billion remains malnourished due to imbalanced diets, mostly affecting children and women. Lack of adequate and secure access to land, water and quality seeds are among key causes of hunger and poverty. 

FIAN contributes to tackle key causes of hunger and poverty. The realization of human rights depends on two main factors: people&apos;s capacity to claim their rights, and the states&apos;capacity to comply with their obligations under international human rights law. FIAN counts with support from numerous donors and an international network of sections and strategic partners.  During the period from 2017-2018 five interrelated intervention areas will be developed . The first deals with organizational strengthening, based on the outcomes of a comprehensive external evaluation which took place during 2016. The second focuses on documentation and analysis of concrete violations of the right to food,  combined with development of strategies on how to address them, including lobby/advocacy, capacity building, and the linking of cases to policies- identification gaps. Subsequently contributions are made to human rights standard-setting.  This forms part of FIAN&apos;s core &apos;businesses&apos;, particularly among the sections at national level  in different parts of the world, benefiting from a systematic case methodology and technical assistance from the organizations&apos; international secretariat.  Other interventions focus on sustainable access to natural resources, income and nutrition for specific groups and communities and accountability of duty bearers. The later is realized by using and further development of human rights institutions and instruments at the national, regional and international level, and by promoting the empowerment of right holders to claim their rights. Besides providing input for evidence-based lobby and advocacy the agenda and work of FIAN International serves as an important reference on the right to adequate food for ICCO and its partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FIAN is an international human rights organization that has advocated for the realization of the right to adequate food for more than 30 years. The organization consists of an international secretariat, national sections and individual members in over 50 countries around the world. FIAN strives to secure people&apos;s access to the resources that they need in order to feed themselves, now and in the future. To that end awareness is raised among social movements, (international) development organizati</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LOC-1797">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rome, Italy</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.9027835 12.496365500000024</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security &amp; Sustainable Consumption</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="11.0149-001">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-08">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="00000402">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00014542">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FIAN International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="XW"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038-110149" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security &amp; Sustainable Consumption - other</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved accountability mechanisms for extraterritorial obligations (ETOs) in relation to the right to adequate food</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Character of improved accountability mechanism aimed for to be defined in coordination with FIAN and other strategic donors, e.g. BftW</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
