<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-56484038-110165-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation ICCO</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After two consecutive Joint Response interventions in the Central African Republic in which ACT partners LWF and FCA together presented relief projects, the two organisations now for the first time will be implementing a joint program complementing each other&#x2019;s activities in the same ten communities. The joint program is the result of a baseline study realised in December of last year, together with ACT member DCA. The choice was made for 18 villages in the zones of Birvan-Bol&#xE9;, Dan-Ghabrir and Binon, all around Bozoum in the prefecture of Ouham Pend&#xE9;. Needs were identified in the areas of Food Security, WASH and Protection. For instance, negative impacts of food insecurity for children found indicated a higher drop-out rate, a lower school attendance rate and in general terms malnutrition. Also, in 12 out of the 18 schools visited no toilets or water points were found, and out of 38 community latrines surveyed only one was still in use. In general, a lack of hygiene awareness was noted. With regard to protection, more than half of the people surveyed lacked access to information on where to go in case of GBV while even more people indicated that BGV incidents are frequent, the majority of victims being women and girls. The proposal aims to address these needs.

FOOD SECURITY interventions are threefold:
Fighting malnutrition by providing food supplements to schools through the initiation of durable school canteens for which Associations for Mothers of Students (AMEs) will be formed who will be in charge. This will be complemented by the creation of community fields and vegetable gardens in schools, by distribution of certified seeds, and training of trainers on seeds multiplication and use of compost to keep and grow crops and vegetables in support of the school canteens. As proven in CARJR1&amp;2 the community gardens continue to be the primary vehicle to fight malnutrition, whilst at the same time being an activity that unites the community to live together. 
To further strengthen community resilience on the long-run 100 members of Parent Teacher Associations (PTAs, 40% being women) will be trained in income-generating activities and receive a start-up kit to launch the selected income-generating activity to sustain the food security of the students in their schools. This will make children return to schools, prevent drop-outs, and fight malnutrition.

WASH interventions complement the food security interventions:
Access to clean water is provided through the development/rehabilitation of 15 water sources. Furthermore access to sanitation is provided through the construction of 18 latrine blocks (36 cabins separated for boys and girls), including hand washing equipment. Water management committees and maintenance mechanisms will be established and supported, including providing them with repair kits. 
In collaboration with these structures and PTAs, hygiene awareness raising campaigns will be organised in the 3 zones. These wash interventions will reduce the likelihood of diarrhoea and water-borne diseases that otherwise hamper food security.

PROTECTION interventions are mainstreamed in the project to strengthen community resilience and social cohesion through capacity building of and awareness-raising through 20 community leaders, 30 AME-members, 30 PTA-members and 20 members of water management committees. 
Furthermore a Training of Trainers for youth will result in 20 peace ambassadors who will foster social cohesion and reduce GBV by establishing platforms for community dialogues and by holding focus group discussions. These activities will support the establishment of a community support mechanism on GBV. To ensure schools are zones of social cohesion a total of 10 teachers, 30 parent teachers and 10 mothers of AMEs will be trained on the new peace education curriculum developed by ACT/FCA, CAR Ministry of Education and Unicef. Teaching on peace education will be piloted in the selected 10 schools. These bottom-up approaches will be complemented by 20 radio shows on protection, social cohesion, GBV, and promotion of peace and reconciliation. In addition 20 awareness-raising campaigns, linked to cultural events, on the same topics will be held in the 10 villages.    

Implementing organisations
The Lutheran World Federation (LWF), Finn Church Aid (FCA), and Danish Church Aid (DCA) are the active members of the ACT Alliance in CAR. They implement a variety of humanitarian programs with funding from amongst others UNHCR, CHF, Finnish and German Ministries. As ACT we work closely together with the humanitarian branch of the Lutheran Church of CAR (OSEEL-RCA). Linkages of this project with other longer-term ACT programs will contribute to sustainability of results.  
Due to their proven impact the present project is similar to the ICCO Cooperation/ACT CAR JR 1&amp;2 projects but targets other communities in Ouham-Pend&#xE9;. Accompaniment of the 15 targeted communities in Nana Memb&#xE9;r&#xE9; of CARJR2 will be done with own funding to continue to draw lessons. 
LWF/ACT and FCA/ACT have a Head Office in Bangui, as well as field Offices in Bozoum/Ouham Pende, Bouar/Nana Nambere, Sangha Bahere/Mamb&#xE9;r&#xE9; Kadei, Berberati and Nola. This project will be implemented by the regional operational base in Bouar and the sub-base in Bozoum. Field staff and supervisors will be encouraged to be largely stationed in the communities and operate from key locations or the sub-base in Bozoum. Both organizations have regional and international staff to provide further technical advice.

Expected outcome LWF interventions:
Protection: Reinforced protection mechanisms at community level as well as improved access to basic services.
&#x2022;	120 community members (youth ambassadors, community leaders, PTA members, AME members and members of the water committees) have increased capacities to promote protection, social cohesion, peace &amp; reconciliation and the fight against GBV within their communities.
&#x2022;	The awareness of 10.000 community members on protection, social cohesion, peace &amp; reconciliation and the fight against GBV has been raised through radio shows and awareness campaigns.
WASH: access to sustainable WASH services has increased and the resilience of the most vulnerable IDPs, their host communities, returnees and repatriated has been strengthened.
&#x2022;	7500 (3750 women and 3750 men) people have obtained access to water provisions in schools and villages.
&#x2022;	105 members of water committees (42 women and 63 men) are able to repair and maintain bore holes and water sources in their communities.
&#x2022;	529 students (353 boys and 176 girls) have access to latrines at schools.
&#x2022;	7500 people (3750 women and 3750 men) have become aware of health and nutrition issues through public campaigns.
Food security &amp; livelihood: lives have been saved and the economic situation of the population has improved.  
&#x2022;	4500 students at 10 schools have benefitted from food supplies prepared at the school kitchens while awaiting the school garden production.
&#x2022;	4500 students benefit from vegetables grown in the 10 school gardens.
Food Security and nutrition (outside DRA): sustainability of the provision of meals at schools that were part of DRAJR 1 and DRAJR2 has been improved.
&#x2022;	15 schools around Bouar are better equipped and prepared to continue school meal system after external funding has ended.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Central African Republic (CAR) is going through a deep and complex crisis with considerable humanitarian consequences.  A joint baseline study implemented by LWF and FCA identified the needs for increased protection, food security and water points/latrines at schools around Bozoum.  Together, both partners will assist the schools and communities, each focusing on their respective expertise. LWF will be training peace ambassadors and repair boreholes, as well as promoting school gardens.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="00021375" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Cordaid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LOC-1592">
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ouham-Pend&#xE9;, Central African Republic</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">18 villages in the zones of Birvan-Bol&amp;#233;, Dan-Gbabiri and Binon, around Bozoum, in the prefecture of Ouham-Pend&amp;#233;.</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection, Food Security and WASH</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.4850984 16.158093699999995</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">obsolete</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-24">190727</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-24">0</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="11.0165-002">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-24">190727</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00021375">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0165-002-00021375-5002630">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-07-21">120000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00021375">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0165-002-00021375-5003228">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-02-07">70853</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00021375">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0165-002-00021375-5009447">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-21">-126</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00021375">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0165-002-00021375-5010003">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-10">-70853</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00021375">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0165-002-00021375-5010004">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-10">70853</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00021375">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lutheran World Federation - CAR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="CF"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038-110165" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">obsolete - other</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people benefiting from protection activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-25"></period-end>
     <target value="10000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">awareness of 10.000 community members on protection, social cohesion, peace &amp; reconciliation and GBV has been raised through radio shows and awareness campaigns. + cap built of 120 people of com</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12463">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 31/12/17: 12462 people reached in the communities through 10 radio programs; also 10 peace ambassadors trained; 10 training sessions in the 10 schools (50 staff); 10 cultural events + 10 awareness raising campaigns</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">obsolete - output</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using safe drinking water sources</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-138" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-25"></period-end>
     <target value="7500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">7500 (3750 women and 3750 men) people have obtained access to water provisions in schools and villages.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 31/12/17: 2 water points built, 10 boreholes rehabilitated, 10 water sources rehabilitated = 22 x 500 = 11000. Training of 22 water management committees. Also 5 repairmen and drillers trained</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of households with improved food security</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-136" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-25"></period-end>
     <target value="750">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x25CF;	4500 students at 10 schools benefitted from food supplies from school kitchens; incl. school gardens (4500/6=750HHs)
- in addition (outside of DRA):15 schools continued support in meals, cooks</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="924">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 31/12/17: a total of 924 HHs (5543 students) in schools have been reached with school feeding. Also 1860 members of Association of Mothers of Pupils reached by training &amp; IGAs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">obsolete - outcome</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached with hygiene and sanitation related communication activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-144" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-25"></period-end>
     <target value="7500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x25CF;	529 students (353 boys and 176 girls) have access to latrines at schools.
&#x25CF;	and 7500 people (3750 women and 3750 men) have become aware of health and nutrition issues through public campaigns.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5488">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 31/12/17: 5 latrine blocks built (with 10 cabins) in the villages of: Kound&#xE9;, Badali2, Kpar&#xE9;, Bowane and Mboko-Tatal&#xE9;. So 500 students access to latrines. 
Also 5488 people benefit from hygiene &amp; health awareness raising</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK - output</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of local churches/christian organizations empowered and prepared for their missionary and diaconal mandate</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-182" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-02-25"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">LWF is a church-based organisation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">LWF as partner in project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
