<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-56484038-110111-29</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation ICCO</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bale lowlands DRR pilot HUNDEE</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this project is to create better climate smart livelihood opportunities or 295 households (at least 50% will be female; 1770 people). By end 2019 each household will be able to generate a minimum average income of 1500 Eth Birr/month. The project will promote entrepreneurship skills among pastoral and agro-pastoralist communities and strengthen disaster risk reduction structures and early warning systems. This project is jointly implemented by ICCO, EECMY DASSC &amp; HUNDEE</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project arose out of a need to break the cycle of responding to disasters every two years in Bale lowlands which is affected regularly by drought and floods. Away from the norm of asset and seed distribution, the project will aim at integrating business approaches and supporting farmers access markets to improve on household incomes.
A comprehensive assessment was performed in Dec &#x2018;17-Jan &#x2018;18 looking into the Hazards, Vulnerabilities &amp; capacities in Meda Walabu. This assessment informed the set-up of the project, and especially the choice of interventions.  
The partners selected are the regular disaster management partners who have been implementing emergency response projects with ICCO &amp; KIA since 2010. Both EECMY and Hundee are the pre-identified strategic response partners for ICCO &amp; KiA, as identified through the DM mapping exercise. 
One partner  (HUNDEE) was also involved in the economic development program and brings in expertise on bulking and market for produce. EECMY has experience in working in Bale Lowlands on livelihood and emergency response projects. ICCO Ethiopia office will work on business services in the whole response. ICCO Ethiopia Country office being a lead in this consortium will take an overall responsibility to ensure effectiveness of the monitoring and evaluation.


Recognizing the severe impact of drought in Ethiopia, particularly in Oromia EECMY-DASSC and HUNDEE has been implementing different disaster risk reduction (DRR) projects.
To mention major implemented DRR projects, HUNDEE and EECMY-DASSC have implemented projects focusing on community based institutions such as women groups/SHGs promotion and income diversification through provision revolving fund. Though there were gaps especially in relation to market linkages, HUNDEE has worked on beekeeping, incenses and gum, Aloe value addition, small scale irrigation promotion and on revitalization of community support system and practices through provision of productive assets such as heifers and small ruminants. EECMY-DASSC and HUNDEE has also worked on creating access to water both for human and animals, facilitating community engagement in participatory natural resources management/practices as mitigation strategies through area closure, rangeland management, selective bush clearing, etc. Many projects were implemented in partnership with ICCO Cooperation/Kerk in Actie (KiA).]</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="00003804" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hundee, Oromo Grassroots Development Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="00000407" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kerk in Actie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LOC-3183">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oborso, Ethiopia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Madda Walabu near to Oborso on google map, is a  project site .</narrative>
   </description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.1344591 39.40099669999995</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-22">63523</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="11.0111-029">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-22">63523</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00003804">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hundee, Oromo Grassroots Development Initiative</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="ET"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0111-029-00003804-5010230">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-21">63523</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00003804">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hundee, Oromo Grassroots Development Initiative</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="ET"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/promeva-icco-prod-files/project-images/project1489.jpeg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project image</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038-110111" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
