<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-56484038-110112-33</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation ICCO</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elimination of Child Labour in Agricultural Value Chains</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child labor is work that children should not be doing because they are too young to work, or, if they are old enough to work because it is dangerous or unsuitable.  Child labor is work that has negative effects on children&apos;s both physical and mental health. 
About 70% of Myanmar&apos;s households are rural and rely on agriculture. Data on agricultural workforce, production, income and export remain spotty. The reasons are farmers suffer from ongoing debt cycles and insolvency. Many hold a debt burden larger than their expected annual incomes. Furthermore increasingly landlessness may be pushing workers further away from their villages during certain parts of the year.Beans and pulses is the second largest agricultural export product after rice with Green and Black Gram varietals as the country&apos;s two most valuable pulse exports. Green gram has historically been cultivated more in Lower Myanmar&apos;s Bago and Ayeyarwady Regions, but recently extended to Upper Myanmar where it has grown in popularity.
According to ILO&apos;s Mypec&apos;s research findings of Child labour in beans and pulses sector in Pakoku Township, for child workers in the beans and pulses sub-sector uptake of economic activities dramatically increases at age ten. Between ten and thirteen years old, most of the child workers will start with their activities. So, these few years are pivotal for future interventions. Though children&apos;s engagement with schooling more steadily declines than in other subsectors, the children start working in cultivation with a dramatic increase at age ten. Once children start working in agriculture they do not necessarily stop their schooling. Children who work with beans and pulses handle tasks across the fairly brief growing cycle such as land preparation and simple harvest. There is limited regular upkeep during the growing cycle. Some children also handle sorting, husking or grinding beans after harvest is complete. There was little processing after harvest apart from drying and packing products, the labour demand is limited and the growing season short. 
According to ILO&apos;s Mypec&apos;s research findings of Child labour in beans and pulses sector in Pakokutownship, All children working in beans and pulses encountered hazards. And also Children regularly encountered very hot weather, lots of dust and fires or burning of agricultural matter and work with pesticides. The planting and harvesting times are during a height in heat when temperatures get above 40C. This can be very dangerous especially for young children who may not notice the signs of dehydration. Children tend to use very basic steel tools, but not machinery. The place of project seeks to address are still in undeveloped in many area such as ways of thinking, education, health, social and livelihood opportunities. According to traditional and culture, some child labour in workplace are received less opportunities and encounter hazards in target area.
Despite of Youth and child are the future of our country, youth are in target community are struggling for helping and solving together with their family of financial difficulties. According to our research in Taunggyi at last year, we found many youths have been working in unsafe and worst form of works. Their time and salary are exploited by business owners in informal sector. They are lacking education, health care, social skill and livelihood opportunity. Because of family income problem and difficulties, they are less good job opportunities and losing hope. They do not receive proper guiding and help to develop their life. Therefore, based on their situation, they really need life skill and awareness of their right.
In 2016, RMO&apos;s Child labour elimination project had been implemented for Taunggyi Township and Pyaytownship. There are four main objectives which are prevention, promotion and provision.  In this project, RMO worked closely with department of social welfare and Industry and labour law department. The main activities included awareness raising to community business owner and government, vocational training to child labour, Income Generation to child labour family, small research for the situation of child labour in two township. Moreover, RMO had collaborated with DSW and Industry and labour law department to do the best interest for child labour who have been facing some difficulties or problem with their peer or owner. RMO is very expert in working with community and also a member of Technical working group on the worst form of child labour in national level . 
In provide awareness raising session and training; for child labour we are using tools of ILO (MyPec project) and for child protection session, RMO use the tools from UNCEF. RMO has implemented child protection activities since 2006 and so in partnership with UNICEF. Furthermore, RMO has developed child protection policy or code of conduct (in Myanmar version). The project staffs especially in child protection sector are fully aware of this policy and they have admitted to have common sense and avoid actions or behaviors that could be construed as child abuse when implementing the project activities. In 2016, RMO had finished the small research study of the situation of child labour in Taunggyi and PyayTownships. Based on our research finding and our previous experiences will help much on the effectively implement of child labor program for our country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fighting Child Labour in Myanmar - children at risk (KiA KK)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ratana Metta Organization (RMO) is one of Myanmar&apos;s expert ngo&apos;s working on the topic of child labour. As an ICCO/KiA partner as well as a partner in the Civic Engagement Alliance in Myanmar, in this project RMO will work with communities (incl. teachers, parents and children), local authorities, CSOs and business owners to raise awareness about child labour in agricultural value chains, and to make plans for change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="00000407" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kerk in Actie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="10000539" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ratana Metta</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LOC-2530">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khayan, Myanmar (Burma)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.9075213 96.56232509999995</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location ref="LOC-2528">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shwegyin, Myanmar (Burma)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>17.9293172 96.88067430000001</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location ref="LOC-2529">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thongwa, Myanmar (Burma)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.7646219 96.53297750000002</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11320" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16" percentage="50" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="16,7" percentage="50" vocabulary="8"></sector>
  <sector code="16,7,2" percentage="50" vocabulary="9"></sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="4,3" percentage="25" vocabulary="8"></sector>
  <sector code="4,3,1" percentage="25" vocabulary="9"></sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="25" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="8,7" percentage="25" vocabulary="8"></sector>
  <sector code="8,7,1" percentage="25" vocabulary="9"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="11.0112-033">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">40000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="10000539">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ratana Metta</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="MM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0112-033-10000539-5006363">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-05-15">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="10000539">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ratana Metta</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="MM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0112-033-10000539-5006364">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-06">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="10000539">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ratana Metta</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="MM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/promeva-icco-prod-files/project-images/project1208.jpeg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project image</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038-110112" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK - impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of poor and marginalized people who participated actively in awareness raising activities on their rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-211" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="1300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted community members who indicate an increased knowledge about child rights, child work and child labour</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1136">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">36 awareness raising sessions to community members were conducted in the target area. 250 children (students), 536 parents, 350 business owners (in total 1136) received awareness-raising session with the topics of child/child labour rights (child protection), introduced to CRC, what is child labour and what are the consequences (the risk of child work and labour) reference from ILO article 128, 139 (convention).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="1300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted community members who indicate an increased knowledge about child rights, child work and child labour</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1903">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">449 added. During the reporting period, project team delivered 16 awareness sessions to  the community: male 113, female 336, in total 449 (children- 108, parents- 172, business man 169) got received the knowledge on Convention C-182, the consequence of child labour, safety at work place and child rights related issue. Moreover, RMO could conduct these activities without any overlapping.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="1300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted community members who indicate an increased knowledge about child rights, child work and child labour</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1454">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During reporting period, project team implemented awareness to community for 50 sessions. male 377, female 1077 total 1454 (children-301 , parents- 746, business man 407) were received the knowledge about Convention C-182, Convention C-138, the consequence of child labour and child rights in those sessions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted community members who indicate an increased knowledge about child rights, child work and child labour</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1903">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">final result.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of poor and marginalized people who participated actively in awareness raising activities on their rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-211" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people indicate 
 increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities and representativeness, and learned vocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="250">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">250 children, including students, participated in awareness raising and discussion sessions. They have learned, presented and discussed about child labour, their rights, responsibilities in awareness session.  Each awareness raising session used a pre- and post-test to assess learning</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people indicate 
 increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities and representativeness, and learned vocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="275">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">275 of children including students were participated in awareness session. They have learn, presented and discussed about child labour in awareness session.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-04"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people indicate 
 increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities and representativeness, and learned vocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="51">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">51 targeted young people indicate 
 increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities and representativeness, and learned vocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people indicate 
 increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities and representativeness, and learned vocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="301">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No update.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people indicate 
 increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities and representativeness, and learned vocation</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="301"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK - output</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth (18-30) using improved skills for their employability</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-154" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people have decent and safe work</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="199">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">199 numbers of targeted young people got increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities, representativeness and actively learned vocation in 3R life skills training. In this aspect, we have no overlap on counting beneficiaries. The training topics were - Day 1; family tree, safe awareness and identity; 24 hours clocks; community map; Day 2; (making a happy family); (work and resources in family); (rights in life); (safety in work place); Day 3; problem solving; soc</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people have decent and safe work</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="199">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">199 numbers of targeted young people increased knowledge and skills about their rights, responsibilities, representativeness and learned vocation in 3R life skills training. The training topics were Day 1; family tree, safe awareness and identity; 24 hours clocks; community map; Day 2; (making a happy family); (work and resources in family); (rights in life); (safety in work place); Day 3; problem solving; social skill, healthy baby protection for violence&amp; drugs child labour, Day 4; l</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people have decent and safe work</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="199">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final result.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people have decent and safe work</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="210">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Firstly we observed from community opinion and measure with our project budget for short vocational training. Then we have chosen the topics on how to make soap, soap (liquid), traditional medicine and balm. From the reflection of training, most of the community liked to make soap (liquid), because there were easy to learn and useful for them.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of targeted young people have decent and safe work</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="210">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">New vocational trainings will start in September</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK - outcome</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CSO&apos;s with effective lobby and advocacy towards authorities and businesses</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-156" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of recommendations for policy makers, TCRC and business leaders to mitigate risks of child labour formulated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently no evidence of a policy change yet, though the collaboration with the Township Child Rights Committee is going on well.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of recommendations for policy makers, TCRC and business leaders to mitigate risks of child labour formulated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of TCRC (Department of Social Welfare in Shwegyin) suggest that if ICCO project (RMO) could build a vocational training shelter there would bring a good effect for children development activities. Also its will be a safe place for children or youth who was in case</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of recommendations for policy makers, TCRC and business leaders to mitigate risks of child labour formulated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of recommendations for policy makers, TCRC and business leaders to mitigate risks of child labour formulated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">RMO was able to effectively reach the Minister of ethnic affairs of Bago State to raise the issue of child labour issue on research finding in World Day Against Child Labour event in Shwegyin Township.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of recommendations for policy makers, TCRC and business leaders to mitigate risks of child labour formulated</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of children withdrawn from labour into education</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-157" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of reported cases of child labour successfully responded to police or (if existing) TCRC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During report period, 4 cases were supported by project and the cases responded to police and other related organization.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of reported cases of child labour successfully responded to police or (if existing) TCRC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the reporting period RMO supported 5 cases with 100,000 MM Kyats, Case Management Support, in each case for their communication, transportation, health care (if they need to buy medicine and to go hospital for medical check and other support) and per diem (not a large amount).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of reported cases of child labour successfully responded to police or (if existing) TCRC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project supported (school fee, stationery, health care) a child from a child labour case to return to school and continues studies. The other cases are related to physical abuse, and police were also involved.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of reported cases of child labour successfully responded to police or (if existing) TCRC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Update, total is 17 children. During the reporting period RMO supported 100,000 MMKs, Case Management Support, in each case for their communication, transportation, health care (if they need to buy medicine and to go hospital for medical check and other support) and per diem (not a large amount).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of reported cases of child labour successfully responded to police or (if existing) TCRC</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WDKK - other</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of cases/instances where research documentation on the situation of child labour in the agricultural sector is presented</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At two occasions RMO presented research findings on child labour in agricultural sector for representatives from government and communities in two townships (Kayan and Shwegyin).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research findings were presented in ILO (My-PEC) meeting and also shared the research finding soft file to them as well. Research reports were distributed to Shwegyin, Kayan and Thongwa Townships&#x2019; GAD (General Administrative Department) and also other stakeholder (such as youth library in Shwegyin, DSW in Thalyin, shared the information in coordination meeting).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The research is currently ongoing</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">final result. Research findings were presented in ILO (My-PEC) meeting and also shared the research finding soft file to them as well. Research reports were distributed to Shwegyin, Kayan and Thongwa Townships&#x2019; GAD (General Administrative Department). Also shared with the members of youth library in Shwegyin, DSW in Thalyin, and shared information in coordination meeting).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#TCRC will be activated  in Shwe Kyin township</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TCRC is functioning. TCRC participated in coordination meetings, organized Township meetings, awareness to business owner sessions. TCRC presented about the child rights, child labour and case management to stakeholder in coordination meeting and TCRC presented about the child rights and their services for children in awareness to business owner session. And during report period January to April 2020 TCRC was more active in case management and child protection, organized group discussi</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-04-29"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">TCRC participated in coordination meeting, organized Township meeting, awareness to business owner session. TCRC presented about the child rights, child labour and case management to stakeholder in coordination meeting and TCRC presented about the child rights and their services for children in awareness to business owner session. And during report period January to April 2020 TCRC was more active in case management and child protection, organized group discussion with parents.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TCRC is set up and ongoing</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TCRC participated in
&#x2022;	Coordination meetings
&#x2022;	Organized Township meeting
&#x2022;	Awareness raising of business owners
TCRC presented about the child rights, child labour and case management to stakeholder in coordination meeting and TCRC presented about the child rights and their services for children in awareness to business owner.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-04"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has linked up with ILO (My-PEC) programme to get updated information on child labour issues. Currently RMO staff are actively coordinating with the Shwegyin TCRC (Township Child Rights Committee) when handling cases, because the TCRC have direct contact with parliament (Hluttaw) members and police as well.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-04"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
