<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41177206-616</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation ICCO</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society Mechanism for Committee on World Food Security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mechanism for civil society participation in CFS policy processes 2017</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CSM aims to facilitate civil society participation in policy processes of the Committee on World Food Security. The latter was established in 1974 as an intergovernmental body to serve as a forum in the United Nations System for review and follow-up of policies concerning world food security including production and physical and economic access to food.  The CSM consists of 11 constituencies (including small holder farmers and NGO&apos;s) and 17 sub-regions, represented in the steering committee</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the CSM is to autonomously facilitate civil society participation in policy processes of the Committee on World Food Security. It consists of 11 constituencies, including small holder farmers, agricultural and food workers, indigenous peoples, women, youth and NGO&apos;s.  The participating organizations, particularly those who organize small-scale food producers and consumers, have more than 380 million affiliated members from all continents.  The CSM and its participating organizations are involved in the work of the CFS through: 
a) Policy working groups that contribute to the so-called open ended working group meetings
b) CFS advisory group, channeling inputs and provide necessary follow-up
c) CSM coordination committee, composed of 20 women and 19 men representing 11 constituencies and 17 sub-regions. During 2016 the CSM focust on the following subjects: connection of smallholders to markets, urbanization and rural transformation, sustainable agriculture development, engagement with nutrition and SDGs. 
Gradually the CSM has developed expertise and has become more effective. 
The policy recommendations on &quot;connecting smallholders to markets&quot; that were adopted during the CFS 43 include the major points advocated by the CSM. They recognize that the main bulk of food is channeled through markets linked to local, national and regional food systems, which are those in which most smallholders participate.  In addition they urge governments to employ public policy to support these markets, both by strengthening local markets where they already exist and by opening up new spaces. The CSM also actively contributed to the CFS document entitled &quot;Engagement in Advancing Nutrition&quot;. They managed to mobilize recognition for the fact that addressing malnutrion requieres a holistic approach and focus on the root causes rather than solely a medicalized  or product-based solution. 
Over the years engagement and commitment among CSO&apos;s has grown steadily, recognizing the importance of the CSF space and the opportunity this space can provide them to make their voices and contributions heard.  One of the major challenges for the future is to etablish a sustainable funding mechanism for the CFS and its workstreams and bodies to prevent the risk of moving towrads a donor-driven CFS which is not acceptable to civil society. 
For 2017 the CSM will facilitate civil society participation in numerous CFS workstreams geared towards specific policy recommendations. In addition the CSM will contribute to the use, implementation and monitoring of CFS outcomes. In order to do this effectively the CSM will invest and engagen in internal learning processes, evaluation and strategy development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="xxxx" role="1" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unknown</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1970-01-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1970-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1970-01-01" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-21" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="2,4" percentage="100" vocabulary="8"></sector>
  <sector code="2,A,1" percentage="100" vocabulary="9"></sector>
  <sector code="31164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security &amp; Sustainable Consumption</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038P_7" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security &amp; Sustainable Consumption - output</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of annual reviews of local public plans taken place with civil society involvement</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-5" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The focus will be at awareness raising and capacity building among representatives at international level, who should be inspired and supported to initiate reviews of national/local policies.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="1970-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="1970-01-01"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The civil society mechanism operates at international level. Therefore the partner will only be able to indirectly promote and support participatory reviews of public plans towards FNS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security &amp; Sustainable Consumption - other</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of global, regional and national events for monitoring the use and application of October 2016 CFS outcomes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="1970-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="1970-01-01"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Special attention will be given to countries that form part of the strategic partnership and work on pathway 2; promotion of Right to Food</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of CFS workstreams to which substantive contributions have provided based on broad civil society participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="1970-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="1970-01-01"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">specific attention to be given to the following workstreams: 1) women&apos;s empowerment in the context of FNS and 2) CFS engagement with SDGs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
