<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-56484038-110114-406</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation ICCO</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India Flood Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected outcome of the project, implemented in Assam &amp; Kerala:
Flood affected populations will be able to meet their basic needs such as Food for at least for 15-20  days.
Flood affected populations will be able to meet their most urgent temporary shelter/ NFI needs.
Flood affected women and adolescent girls will be able to meet hygiene  needs
Flood affected population will get support for shelter repair 
Targeted areas:
ASSAM
Golaghat &amp; Laxmipur District, Assam State
KERALA
Idukki, Ernakulam,Wayanad and Kozhikode District of Kerala 

About the partner CASA:
Church&apos;s Auxiliary for Social Action (CASA) is the social action arm of the 24 Protestant and Orthodox churches in India. CASA is mandated to work for the poor and the marginalized, irrespective of any political, religions and caste consideration.  CASA today is operational in 22 states, including five states in North-east India, in approximately 5,000 villages. In addition CASA supports and accompanies around 400 NGOs working on different issues throughout the country.  CASA continues to respond to 60-70 small and medium disasters annually and also responds comprehensively to major emergencies with an enhanced perspective in its strategies of integrating a long-term understanding of the causes and consequences. CASA staff from our Assam sectors office and the Zonal Office at Kolkata who have wide experience in responding to emergency situations and the requisite sectoral expertise will be responsible for implementation of the programme. 

About the context &amp; humanitarian situation:
ASSAM:
During the night of Sunday the 5 August 2018, the state of Assam in India, witnessed severe rains which have substantially increased the level of water flow in the rivers and the rivers breaking their banks. This has led to flash floods in some districts of Assam and destroyed the normal life of the people. The floods have created widespread damage to houses, fields and livelihoods and affecting thousands of people. These floods are exacerbating the recent floods which affected Golaghat, Lakhimpur, Udalguri, Barpeta, Morigaoan and Hojai, districts in Assam. The floods have affected 6 Revenue Circles, 110 Villages, 6,855 Acres of agricultural land and forests. It has been reported that 81,269 people have been affected. 20,651 people took shelter in 109 relief camps. The loss of human life stands at 46 Number so far since the first wave of floods.
 
The second wave of flood in 2018 has affected 1,05,782 population in 224 villages under 18 revenue circles of eight districts of the State. With three more fresh cases of flood-related deaths from the districts of Dhemaji (Gogamukh revenue circle), Udalguri (Mazbat revenue circle) and Golaghat (Bokakhat revenue circle) the total number of flood-related deaths this year has risen to 38. The current wave of flood has affected the districts of Dhemaji, Lakhimpur, Biswanath, Udalguri, Barpeta, Golaghat, Sivasagar and Charaideo. While in Dhemaji district 20 villages under the revenue circle of Gogamukh have been affected by the floodwaters, in Lakhimpur district 24 villages under the revenue circles of Kadam (2), Narayanpur (2), Bihapuria (7) and Naoboicha (13) have been affected. The Brahmaputra (at Dibrugarh, Tezpur, Guwahati, Goalpara and Dhubri), the Ranganadi (at NT Road Crossing), the Subansiri (at Chauldhowaghat and Badatighat), the Dhansiri (South) at Golaghat and Numaligarh, the Jia Bharali (at NT Road Crossing), the Kopili (at Kampur), the Manas (at NH Road Crossing), the Gaurang (at Kokrajhar), the Barak (at Badarpurghat) and the Kushiyara (at Karimganj) were on the rising trend, while The Brahmaputra at Neamatighat in Jorhat district, the Dikhow at Sivasagar, the Dhansiri (South) at Numaligarh and at Golaghat, the Jia Bharali at North Trunk Road Crossing in Sonitpur district, and the Beki river at Road Bridge in Barpeta district are flowing above danger level.
 
KERALA
During the evening of 9/08/2018 the state of Kerala witnessed severe flooding in view of the consistent rains which has been there for a couple of days. Vigours southwest monsoon has left a trail of destruction across Kerala, killing at least 87 people so far.  This vigorous monsoon eventually has led to the increase in level of water in many dams / reservoirs in Kerala. The incessant rains caused havoc flood in many districts in Northern districts of Kerala namely Idukki, Ernakulam, Malapuram, Kozhikode, Palakkad and Wyanad. The flooding apparently had damaged the infrastructure around 10,000 kms of roads and 20000 houses. The release of water has extensively damaged district around Idukki and Ernakulam District. The excessive rains in the other parts have led to severe flooding in Wyanad, Kozhikode, Palakadd and Malapuram Districts. Idukki and Wayand being hilly terrains has witnessed severe landslides also, where reportedly of the 40 human loss from landslides. Many roads in Wyanad and Idukki have been blocked in view of the Landslides. Around 150000 people have shifted to various camps in the state. Army and NDRF has been deployed in all the affected districts. Roads have been cut off and many districts are witnessing power shut down as a precautionary measure. The power shutdown us expected to bring in drinking water crisis.
 
This flood is the second wave of Flood in Kerala in this Monsoon Period. The first wave of Flood affected Wayanad district and the Kuttanad Area of Kerala which is part of Pathanamthitta, Allapuzha and Kottayam.

ASSAM
1,05,782 people affected have been affected so far in the First wave and Second wave of Floods, where 81,269 people of Golaghat have been affected in the Second Wave of Floods during the period 5th to 7th August 2018 of which 20651 people took shelter in 109 relief camps. They are in dire need of relief assistance such as dry food, drinking water, shelter and sanitation materials. The Government is providing food for the people in the Shelter; the flooding is likely to worsen in coming days. Since this being the second wave and the impact are found to have set the people out of normal life and there are still possibilities that if the rains continue the flooding could take place again. Food, temporary shelter, WASH and livelihood restoration measures are very much essential as unmet needs among flood affected households.

KERALA
 Since it is a flash flood the impact has been sudden and most of the areas are filled with backater and canals there are issues of water loggin and sanitation. Further in Kerala most of the houses have ariculture / horticulture plantations within thier house premises which has also been damaged. With the severe flooding taking place in many areas, there is a total standstill of normal life where access to livelihood and food is diminised. The government is evcuating 60000 people from low lying area and shifting them Relief Camps and providing shelter and food. 40 rivers in the state is full with water and of the 58 dams 24 dams are full with water. Given this scenario the impacts are felt with women, children and elderly people there is a pressing necessity to provide immediate assistance to minimize loss of life and to ensure that the needs of the most vulnerable are covered. They are in dire need of relief assistance such as basic food, temporary shelter, non food items, hygiene/dignity kit, water storage container, water purifiers, agriculture seeds and allied services and cash transfer to affected households.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid after floods in Kerala&amp;Assam by ACT Alliance partner CASA</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO &amp; Kerk in Actie provide relief assistance to flood-affected people in India through local ACT Alliance partner CASA. 
Severe flooding affects the state of Assam (North-East India) and the state of Kerala (South-West India). The floods, said to be the worst in a century, affect over 800.000 people and lead to many Internally Displaced people. 
The aid consists of food aid, hygiene kits, blankets, clothing, as well as equipment for emergency tents, and support to restore homes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="00015281" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACT Alliance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="00000407" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kerk in Actie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-05" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-21" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LOC-2731">
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assam, India</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flood affected area; provision relief</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.2006043 92.93757389999996</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location ref="LOC-2732">
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assam, India</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flood affected area; provision relief</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.2006043 92.93757389999996</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location ref="LOC-2730">
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kerala, India</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flood affected area; provision relief</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">relief</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.8505159 76.27108329999999</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="50" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="8"></sector>
  <sector code="2.1.2" percentage="100" vocabulary="9"></sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="50" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="67" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="33" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Management (new)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-20">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="11.0114-406">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-20">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00015281">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACT Alliance</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="IN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11.0114-406-00015281-5007611">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-28">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-56484038">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICCO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="00015281">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACT Alliance</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-country code="IN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/promeva-icco-prod-files/project-images/project1550.jpeg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project image</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-56484038-110114" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Management (new) - impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people provided with non-food items (other than hygiene/dignity kits)</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-262" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1650">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2,200 flood affected households received Temporary Shelter Materials and Non-Food Items, Ground sheet and sleeping mat (330HHs)
150 affected households will be getting support for shelter repair support (23HHs)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Management (new) - output</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people enabled to meet their basic food needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-240" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1650">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2,200 flood affected households received food items (330HHs*5=1650)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people having regular access to soap to meet hygienic needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="ICCO-241" indicator-uri="https://icco.promeva.nl/indicators.jsp?id=1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1650">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2,200 flood affected women &amp; adolescent girls received Dignity/ Hygiene Kits (330)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
