<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-36273</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MHV II Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i)	Linking farmers to markets: Involved farmers will get market access and be integrated into an international supply chain to enhance commercial agriculture production; (ii)	Farmer reach and increased income: Project is expected to involve 15,000 farmer households, affecting up to 20% of Bhutan&apos;&apos;s population of around 750,000; Farmers receive training to grow hazelnuts and generate incremental income on degraded land which would otherwise be left barren; (iii)	Job creation and women participation: MHV has directly employed nearly 500 Bhutanese so far, and plans to double this in the coming years, including women employment at all levels. In addition, linkages with over 1,200 service providers will be expanded; (iv)	GHG mitigation and forest preservation: Hazelnut trees will offset significant amounts of CO2 through carbon fixation over the course of their lifetime, as well as contribute to soil retention and regeneration. The cultivation of hazelnuts will also discourage deforestation, as annual pruning will serve as an alternative source of fuel wood;  (v)	Food safety and traceability: MHV is implementing a comprehensive traceability system using a combination of frequent extension visits by trained staff who use android-based Remote Monitoring &amp; Traceability tools to provide real time information and to ensure consistent high product quality levels from farm to customer;  (vi)	Improved ICT (Information and Communication Technology): The project will provide farmers with market information and improve ICT based knowledge management and information exchange systems at the field level; (vii)	Reduce urban migration: Project areas are predominantly in the Eastern and Central regions of Bhutan; the attractive returns for farmers will help reduce / slow down urban migration towards the capital Thimphu in the West, where employment opportunities are limited.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mountain Hazelnut Venture Private Limited (MHV) was established in 2010 as a greenfield hazelnut project. The project entails the development of a new smallholder based hazelnut industry in Bhutan in order to take advantage of the growing market opportunity for hazelnuts which sees increasing demand from European confectionary and Asian snack producers. The Company supplies raw material (tree plantlets), which it develops at its own nurseries, as well as inputs and support for growing hazelnut trees to local farmers free of charge. Farmers grow and maintain the trees on their own or government leased - fallow - land under the supervision of the Company. Once the trees produce sizeable amounts of hazelnuts, the Company will purchase the crop from the farmers and market the nuts to international purchasers after initial processing. As of Dec 2014, the Company had planted 2.5 million surviving trees planted and registered over 6,000 farmers to participate in the project, which is expected to rise to a total of 10.8 million trees and 15,000 registered farmer households by 2017/18.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOUNTAIN HAZELNUT VENTURE PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-36273" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mountain Hazelnut Venture Private Limited  No. 8, Changjalu  Po Box 1403  Thimphu, Bhutan  Phone: +975 (02) 340009  Fax: +975 (02) 340010</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mountain Hazelnuts Group Limited Ritz Plaza 8th Floor 122 Austin Road Tsim Sha Tsui, Hong Kong Phone: +852 9814 3436</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bhutan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BT-Bhutan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is being implemented all across Bhutan, with MHVs operational headquarters and the main nursery located in Lingmethang in Mongar district. Hazelnuts are being grown in a total of 16 Dzongkhags (sub-districts) from eastern and central regions of Bhutan (viz. Trashigang, Trashiyangtse, Mongar, Lhuentse, Pemagatshel, Samdrup Jongkhar, Zhemgang, Bumthang, Trongsa, Wangdue, Punakha, Gasa, Dagana, Tsirang and Chhukha).  The processing facility will be set up near Lingmethang in Eastern Bhutan. In addition, MHV operates a small office in Thimphu.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.5000000000 90.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1119" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A-AJ - Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $3.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-02">3000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-02">3000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOUNTAIN HAZELNUT VENTURE PRIVATE LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/36273/mhv-ii-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/36273/mhv-ii-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
