<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="1" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/770" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-USF-HT-10-770</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to UNICEF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The U.S. Fund for UNICEF supports UNICEF&#x2019;s relief and recovery efforts in Haiti by raising funds, helping maintain public awareness of Haiti&#x2019;s ongoing needs, and sharing information on UNICEF&#x2019;s work with the U.S. Congress and the U.S. NGO community.

UNICEF&#x2019;s role in emergencies is to focus on ensuring the survival, development, and protection of children.  The January 12, 2010, earthquake in Haiti was a &quot;children&apos;s emergency&quot;: of more than two million people displaced by the earthquake, nearly one million are children.

In Haiti, UNICEF plays a major role in supporting water and sanitation, child protection, education, and health interventions for displaced and vulnerable populations:

&#x2022;	Cholera Response:  UNICEF works with more than 70 partners to support a nationwide cholera response and prevention effort.  UNICEF supports community and clinic treatment of cholera with oral rehydration salts and medical supplies, and works with partners and the Haitian Government to mount a massive hygiene promotion campaign, including providing supplies of Aquatabs and soap.
&#x2022;	Water and Sanitation:  UNICEF continues to work with partners to cover water and sanitation needs of Haitians, focusing on efforts to reestablish and extend access to safe water through repairs to water supply systems.  UNICEF promotes hygiene in schools through installation of latrines and hand-washing facilities at permanent and temporary schools in the South Department and Port-au-Prince metropolitan area.
&#x2022;	Child Protection:  UNICEF continues to support where necessary a network of Child-Friendly Spaces that provide safety and services to thousands of vulnerable children on a daily basis.  UNICEF continues to support the Brigade de Protection des Mineurs to prevention child trafficking, particularly on the Haiti-Dominican Republic border.  UNICEF assisted IBESR in the registration of over 8,000 children in residential care centers, as well as the evaluation of 200 centers to help the Government conduct better quality control and regulation.
&#x2022;	Education:  UNICEF reached more than 400,000 children with essential school supplies in the continuing rollout of UNICEF&#x2019;s nationwide &#x201C;Go To School&#x201D; campaign, with 1,400 of these schools also receiving essential supplies for cholera prevention.  UNICEF also supports the construction of latrines, water supply points, and hand-washing stations for schools in Port-au-Prince.  UNICEF will reach up to 750,000 children with school supplies to be distributed by the end of the year.
&#x2022;	Health/Nutrition:   UNICEF continues to supply partners with Ready-to-Use Therapeutic Foods (RUTFs) to treat children suffering from severe acute malnutrition.  In addition to its provision of emergency immunizations, UNICEF is a key partner in helping the Haitian Government re-launch routine immunization programs through community-based health networks.  With UNICEF support, 36 communes increased immunization coverage, with 8 communes reaching more than 80 percent coverage for the DPT3 vaccine (diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-1760110" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Fund for UNICEF</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="USF-HT-10-770" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Fund for UNICEF</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kini Schoop</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Public Relations</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kschoop@unicefusa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.unicefusa.org/</website>
   <website>http://www.unicefusa.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.unicefusa.org/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
