<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-150245</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Linking the tourism industry to productive activities in the Issyk-Kul region of the Kyrgyz Republic</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ministry of Economy of the Kyrgyz Republic has requested UNIDO#s support to develop and implement a cluster development project aimed at strengthening linkages between tourism and productive industries in the Issyk-Kul region. Following consultations, the Permanent Mission of the Russian Federation expressed interest to fund the proposed project and support the new member of the Eurasian Economic Union to benefit from the development opportunities made available following its accession to the single market. UNIDO field mission was carried out in September 2015 and a project proposal was prepared and validated in a roundtable meeting in Bishkek by the government counterpart. The long-term objective of the project is to stimulate economic growth and employment through promoting linkages between the tourism sector and related productive industries. The immediate objective of the project is to strengthen the processing capacity and market access of selected agro-industry clusters in the Issyk-Kul region. The project will focus on two interrelated outputs: Output 1: Support infrastructure for agro- and light-manufacturing industries established Output 2: Pilot clusters in selected industries developed and formalized This project will contribute to the envisaged Sustainable Development Goals (SDG), in particular</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RUSSIAN FEDERATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-150245" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="KG" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cholpon-A</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>42.64944 77.08225</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="KG" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kyrgyzstan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.20438 74.766098</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
