<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-150345</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to opperationalize the Burera Dairy Community Processing Centre</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the Ministry of Industry and Trade, Rwanda Bureau of Development (RBD) has established Community Processing Centers (CPCs) to drive post-harvest value addition for select commodities. CPCs operational model envisages a build-own- operation set up whereby the centers are operated by an anchor firm or producer cooperatives as profitable business entities. Under the Ministry of Trade and Industry (MINICOM) supported by the Business Development Fund (BDF) the CPC programme aims to demonstrate and foster value addition, innovation and technology transfer, and create jobs, many for youth and women CPCs are operated under the jurisdiction of the National Industrial Research and Development Agency (NIRDA). The purpose of the project is to provide technical assistance, modern dairy equipment and capacity building to support operationalising the anchor Burera Community Processing Centre (CPC) on a sustainable commercial basis. This project falls under the One UN - Rwanda United Nations Development Assistance Plan (2013-2018) Joint Flagship Programme Youth and Women Employment and the UNIDO CP for Rwanda</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust Fund for Increased Food Security t</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-150345" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="RW" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Musanze</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.49984 29.63497</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="RW" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.940278 29.873888</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
