<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-130217</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expansion of the national business registration system (NBRS) to new business entities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following up on prior successful UNIDO assistance co-funded by SECO, NORAD, UNIDO, and the ONE UN Fund Viet Nam since 2008, in establishing a National Business Registration System (NBRS), the project will expand and consolidate existing results. By August 2018, the Agency for Business Registration (ABR) and Business Registration Offices (BROs) in 63 provinces of the country will be enabled to provide accurate, legally binding information on commercial entities to the business community, government agencies and the general public, independently from similar further international donor support.  UNIDO will primary assist the ABR and BROs in expanding the coverage of the existing NBRS, established under the former project entitled Technical Assistance to Business Registration Reform, to other types of businesses. UNIDO&apos;s support to the ABR and BROs will focus on legal advice, institution building, technical upgrading of the NBRS, capacity building of staff, including on enhanced client orientation in service provision and support in conducting public awareness raising campaigns.  UNIDO is today the only development agency working specially on Business Registration Reform (BRR) in Viet Nam. BRR is a field where SECO differentiates itself from other donors and capitalizes on a prior track record of successful assist</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SWITZERLAND</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-130217" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="VN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hanoi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.0245 105.84117</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="VN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Viet Nam</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.058324 108.277199</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
