<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-220089</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco green energy transition</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Confronted with the current multifaceted crisis, Moroccan policy makers recognize the need to adopt an integrated, multidimensional, and coordinated approach to find urgent and innovative solutions to the socio-economic impact of the current crisis and introduce immediate and longer-term measures to protect the most vulnerable, in particular children and women. The crisis, if well managed, also constitutes an opportunity to accelerate the energy transition through the decarbonization of Morocco#s industry, as well as build the resilience and sustainability of the country#s food systems.  To this end, and given the need for a coordinated approach, UNIDO will jointly implement the programme with UNICEF and FAO in Morocco under the framework of the UN Joint SDG Fund Development Emergency Modality. The joint programme working in support of key government efforts, is planning to carry-out a multifaceted assessment of the impact of rising international prices on the country food security, ambitions for carbon free industrial production and protection of the most vulnerable groups.  UNIDO is in charge of energy part of the joint programme. In the first phase, UNIDO will carry out an in-depth assessment of the impact of the crisis on the Moroccan economy overall and key industries to identify the impacts and opportunit</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Joint SDG Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-220089" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="MA" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.791702 -7.09262</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
