<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-170037</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">State of Palestine # Upgrading the footwear value chain in the Hebron district</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Palestinian leather and shoes sector, mainly concentrated in Hebron, has itself suffered from the poor economic conditions and the overall instability in the region. The sector has seen its golden era, in the years 1975 to 2000, and eventually was exposed to a non-balanced competition against the imported goods from Asia, that is mostly lacking quality and is cheaper in prices. This fierce competition is one of the factors that have driven the number of workshops in the sector from 1000 employing (directly and indirectly) over 30,000 workers in the year 2000 to around 230 workshops currently employing less than 2500 workers.  Therefore, given the impact of the competition with footwear and leather imported from China, Turkey, and other sources, among different challenges, it is critical for the industry to invest in new technologies and further capitalize on differentiation through quality and scalability by deploying innovation and creativity targeting improved production and positioning of the Hebron footwear and leather in both internal and external markets. It is within this context that the project main objective is to increase the competitiveness and turnover of the Footwear Value Chain in Hebron in line with the National Policy Agenda and the National Export Strategy (NES) adopted by the Palestinian</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITALY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-170037" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="PS" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hebron</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.52935 35.0938</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="PS" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">State of Palestine</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.952162 35.233154</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
