<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190100</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergrated Watershed approaches for climate resilience in agro-pastoral landscapes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO and UNDP received a joint Letter of Endorsement, dated 27 February 2019, endorsing the proposal of Government of South Sudan on the formulation and execution support to the project #Integrated Watershed approaches for climate resilience in agro-pastoral landscapes#. The project aims to address a range of environmental, land degradation and social economic challenges in the targeted agro pastoral landscape areas and associated value chains.  The project objective is to promote climate resilience and adaptation capacity building amongst agricultural and pastoral communities of South Sudan and addresses the LDCF/GEF strategy objective and outcome indicator on technologies and innovative solutions are adapted and deployed to enhance resilience. The envisaged global environmental benefits include 75Hactares of landscapes under improved practices mostly to be achieved with interventions under UNDP coordination. It is also expected that a total number of 10,000 direct and indirectly targeted beneficiaries (60%F and 40%M) will be reached primarily through joint UNIDO and UNDP contributions.  UNIDO interventions will focus on the promotion of small scale agribusinesses, and triggering scaled community centre investments in improved agro and food processing and preservation technology and working facilities. Small</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GEF - Global Environment Facility</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190100" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="SS" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.352131 29.695427</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
