<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-170211</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience-building through immediate livelihood and income generation for internally displaced persons, refugees, and host communities in Harshm Camp</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed projects aims to build on the agro-processing training center that was constructed to support displaced Iraqi#s residing at the Harshm Refugee Camp located in Erbil.  The majority of the families that reside in this camp have been displaced from the Ninewa Governorate (Mosul).    The agro-processing center is an integrated training facility, which hosts five pilot greenhouses and is managed in-partnership with the Ministry of Agriculture # Research Center in Erbil.  The training program aims to introduce families to greenhouse farming as well as small-scale agro-processing.  The project will build on this training infrastructure to allow for further training as well as additional processing by introducing current production methods.  The farming activities incl. training focus on common agricultural produce (i.e. tomatoes, cucumber, eggplant, broccoli, etc.).  The project will form a cooperative to market the produce to allow for revenue generation for the families trying to cope with the crisis.  The project concept will be submitted to the Austrian Government for funding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AUSTRIA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-170211" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IQ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Erbil</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.19257 44.01062</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IQ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.223191 43.679291</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
