<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200034</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program for Country Partnership (PCP) for C&#xF4;te d#Ivoire: &#xAB;Inclusive and Sustainable Industrialization Program in C&#xF4;te d#Ivoire&#xBB;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Origin of the Proposal: Since 2013, the United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO) was given a new mandate by its Member States at the fifteenth session of the UNIDO General Conference. This new mandate aims to promote Inclusive and Sustainable Industrial Development (ISID) in all its Member States. This new mandate therefore requires new approaches to support the industrialization of countries. They focus on national ownership and the promotion of partnership around industrial development programs.  In a bid to expeditiously operationalize this new mandate, UNIDO has developed a new technical support approach referred to as the Program for Country Partnership (PCP). It encompasses the economic, social and environmental dimensions of development.  The PCP is a comprehensive mechanism of consultation, sensitization, project formulation and development of an industrialization strategy, implemented by States, using partnerships and funding.  In addition, the United Nations General Assembly, at its 70th session on 26 September 2015, proclaimed the period 2016-2025 as the Third Industrial Development for Africa (IDDA 3). On this occasion, UNIDO was designated as the implementing agency for the IDDA 3. The PCP was seen as an instrument that could expedite its implementation.  To foster this initiative</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHINA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200034" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-03-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CI" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abidjan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.30966 -4.01266</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CI" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.539989 -5.54708</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
