<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA1/WASH/NGO/15040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feat work to address the acute WASH needs of the underserved IDPs of Idlib.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of the project are to save lives and reduce human suffering of WASH needs through the re-provision and expansion of the already exists integrated, life-saving WASH programming of Silk Road in the targeted locations and broaden to other communities.
Silk Road proposes a 7-month project to continue and intensify current lifesaving water, sanitation and hygiene services for IDPs and host communities in Termanin, Ram Hamdan , Batenta, Kafr Nabi , Maaret Elekhwan and Ein Shib .
The main components of the project which will be implemented in all targeted locations are:
 Provision of clean water supply to households and community structures with rigorous water quality testing above current practice that also includes minor rehabilitation of broken/damaged water system.  After rehabilitation, the system will be provided with an operations and maintenance support to ensure the sustainability of the provided assistance. The assistance will cover the costs of fuel to operate the standby generators, disinfection chemicals (Chlorine), stipends for operators/technicians and tools/spare parts for a period of 6 months. The rehabilitate the water systems/stations at all targeted locations mainly aim to provide the necessary equipment needed equipment which will allow us to re-operate these water stations and start supplying the safe water to beneficiaries because there are no major works required for the water networks. The quantity of water that will be provided to each person in the targeted communities is 40 L per person a day. During this period of support, a cost recovery system and water safety plans will be established to ensure sustainability of the systems, this will involve a study on a suitable tariff rate that takes into account the dwindling financial capacity of the benefiting population and will be based on focus group discussions with a representative group of the community including members of local councils of targeted communities.
 Support the municipality and waste management system in the targeted locations for 6  months through implement daily waste management services.
 Expanded, comprehensive hygiene promotion with a focus on behaviour change interventions and personal hygiene and WASH-NFI distributions. Hygiene activities will include social and behaviour change communication in target to reinforce positive hygiene behaviours among the target communities and within the household. Activities will centre on the safe water chain such as water storage and household water treatment, hand washing and personal and prevent water and vector-borne diseases.
 The intervention will include also a mobile WASH unit that will be taking a place within the main components of the project while this unit includes hired trucks and tractors that will be utilized to fill the gaps in the response of Water supply and waste management services while we expect more IDPs to come to the project areas, which will cause more pressure on water supply networks and waste management services, therefore, we have to be willing to cover these increased needs on a daily basis. The proposed life-saving WASH activities will allow newly IDPs, the already existed IDPs and other vulnerable groups (disabled, elderly) have access to safe water to reduce vulnerability to preventable illnesses and improve resilience. Furthermore, they will ensure that they do not create additional risks for the affected population (especially IDPs women and children and the newly IDPs) but will provide the best solutions to the suffering population in the targeted areas, also Silk Road will ensure that the health impact in this emergency WASH intervention will reduced disease risk and reduced transmission risk and it adhering to internationally recognized standards and best practices, ensuring that services are provided in line with the Do No Harm framework, Sphere standards, and humanitarian principles, and that services are of the highest quality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-WSH-164606-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-27">798987.19</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400328462">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-05">4207.77</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-15040">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-27">798987.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304560709">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-09">479392.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304740062">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-18">319594.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
