<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA1/NFI-WASH/NGO/14994</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency response to most vulnerable groups displaced from Idleb to North of Aleppo areas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this project is to respond to the needs of newly displaced IDPs from southern/eastern Idleb  and west of Aleppo areas to Afrin and Jarablus areas  who came to theses areas as a last resort due to lack of shelter availability in all camps and communities in Idleb  areas, those families already spent all their savings to reach these communities facing huge challenges to secure money for their needs specially rent fees, NFI/Winterization materials and food as most of them currently living in unfinished houses and weather conditions are extremely bad. This project will add to the emergency response by HIHFAD through cash intervention already ongoing in Idleb.
With clear selection criteria /4054/ HHs among most vulnerable ones will be targeted with one-shot of Multi-purpose cash grants /120/ USD for each/ to cover their needs of NFI, rent, transport, ect,. This modality will help HIHFAD to deliver timely and cost-effective assistance to crisis-affected populations, while at the same time supporting the local economy. This amount ($120) will be distributed in Turkish Lira. Our plan is to distribute a one  cash amount of $120 to 4054 HHs from the newly IDPs who were displaced in the last two months (January - February) in addition to some of the most vulnerable people from the host communities in the targeted areas under this project. After signing the contract with money transfer agent they will be provided with distribution plan by HIHFAD so they can arrange the distribution. The contract will include a clause about data protection of the beneficiaries so it cannot be copied or disclosed to any party. HIHFAD field team will supervise the distribution by the agent that will be in a distibution point in the same community so people will not travel a long distance to get the cash. Project team will be there during pickup process monitoring the whole process, in addition to distribution of PSEA brochures and feedback mechanism printed on leaflets during the cards distribution. 

The WASH component of this project will be in the same ones targeted with the SNFI component  in Jandairis, Sharan and Bulbul  in Afrin by chlorinating water trucks and operating mobile treatment unit to provide safe drinking water in areas where there is no water network or the pumping system is not working specially in the areas that received a lot of IDPs. The targeted areas are .  Water will  be treated in nearby sources of the residential areas of the most vulnerable and needy beneficiaries and in remote settlements where treatment stations are not available, and people use untreated water. The mobile unit will travel to those settlements as far as minimum road structure and security situation allow. This is important not just for the travel of the mobile plant, but also for the safety of staff and beneficiaries.
- Water suppliers receive appropriate quantity of chlorine for the treatment of water. 
In general, the mobile water treatment plant is capable of providing potable water in a fast, reliable and cost-effective manner. This makes them an ideal choice in critical situations like the one in Afrin. Mobile water treatment systems are ideal as emergency water purification systems as they are also portable / transportable if required. In this project, the mobile plant will be used to treat borehole, surface and spring water and will provide drinking water to 7000 people in Afrin subdistrict.  In addition, these mobile water plants will be transported  to outreach any other locations in NW Syria during the lifespan of the units wherever needed in northwest Syria and in coordination with WASH Cluste</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="95" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-24">594005.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-14994">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-24">594005.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304553165">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-02">475204.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304784982">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-05">109927.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
