<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA3/ER/UN/17205</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving and strengthening physical access for transportation of humanitarian assistance between BAH and Northern Aleppo through roads rehabilitation.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to rehabilitate the physical access to ensure that IDPs and host communities&apos; in Northwest Syria continue to receive uninterrupted supply of humanitarian assistance transported through Bab-Al Hawa (BAH) crossing point.The project formulation has been based in needs identified by Logistic and Early Recovery clusters and confirmed by the OCHA Access and CM Coordination Unit, firsthand consultations with local stakeholders, and rapid needs assessments. The project aims to achieve the following outcome: 
The targeted sections of the roads used for the shipment of humanitarian supplies throughout NWS via BAH border crossing, are rehabilitated in good conditions to assure timely and continuous transportation of humanitarian supplies to the most vulnerable in northern Aleppo. 
Additionally, although it&#x2019;s not a formally stated outcome, the communities around the road rehab location will get access to short term livelihoods in the form of unskilled labour.The project will be carried out by two ERL Partners, Bonyan Organization and Imaar Organization, with proven highly-technical record in the rehabilitation and reparation of roads and drainage systems, as well as in the creation of livelihood opportunities, under the general management and monitoring of UNDP.
The project will be targeting the rehabilitation of 20Kms out of the 89km of the road connecting BAH to Azaz via Daret Azza and Afrin. In particular, the road section that will be targeted is the one connecting Al Gazawiha to the northern entrance of Afrin (Aleppo) whose specific rehabilitation needs have been identified in consultation with ERL, Log clusters and the two implementing partners on the ground. To ensure complementarity, coordination mechanisms are in place with the ERL Cluster, Logistic Cluster, OCHA Access and CM Coordination Unit, and any other partner working with complementary purposes.The Logs Cluster&#x2019;s coordination and information management services will continue to support organisations in addressing common logistics gaps and monitor physical accessibility inside the northwest. In line with this, a dedicated GIS team has developed a physical access constraints map for the region to map out the routes that access areas previously served from Bab al-Salam.With the closure of BAS, it is estimated that the road between BAH and Azaz will bare an increased load of around 250 trucks per month. The rehabilitation of key sections of this route will therefore ensure that humanitarian aid continues to reach areas previously served via BAS and maintain an uninterrupted supply chain of life-saving items to those areas. It will directly benefit 645,963 individuals in need of assistance in Aleppo (316,524 women and girls and 329,439 men and boys) -Pin, HNO 2019-. 
In the context of this highly strategic intervention which has to be delivered within a period of four months, UNDP brings in the value addition of its international expertise in infrastructure projects around the world, which is there since the conception of this project. As it&#x2019;s a significant investment of funds within such a short time, UNDP will make sure the fiduciary and programmatic risks are kept in control through rigorous compliance to its SOPs in fund management, contracting, work planning, MampE, reporting, and its experience in successful close collaboration with the implementing partners. In order to make it happen, time from UNDP&#x2019;s Advisor and the Compliance Officer has been formally provided for to guide the project team. This will be further augmented with field level inspections and close collaboration with ERL, Log, and Access clusters. So, to sum it up, the UNDP&apos;s overall role will be:- Overall Project Mgmt.- Contractual arrangements and admin. support - Ensure required coordination among involved clusters and sub-IPs - Ensure progress and results quality through direct field monitoring.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-16">1413665.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-16">100082.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-17205">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-16">1513747.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304740094">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-18">1513747.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
