<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA1/FS/NGO/14999</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Food Security, Food Safety, and Living Standards of Vulnerable Populations in Northwest Syria through food voucher support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The fund will be utilized to providing the irreplaceable food items needed by distributing the food vouchers, which will contribute to supply these items for the newly IDPs in the targeted locations in Idlep Governorate.
Silk Road will contribute $ 799,880.11 over a seven-month period, which will enable food assistance through monthly cash vouchers to extremely vulnerable households in Harim, Kafr - Kafrehmul, Termanin and Maaret Tamsrin. 
Some 2265 newly IDPs households (About 13,600 individuals), consisting mainly of poor IDPs women and households headed by the women, will benefit from the project. Each monthly voucher is worth US$ 50 and can be exchanged for food items in selected local shops. The implementation plan is based on the distribution of monthly vouchers to beneficiary families so that each family will benefit from six consecutive months of vouchers program.
For the 2265 targeted families, the vouchers mean guaranteed access to food every month. Beyond that, the project also gives them the chance to choose which foods will best meet their families&#x2019; needs.
For local sellers, the vouchers are creating hundreds of new customers, most of whom previously had difficulties affording to buy food in their shops.
Silk Road has developed a strong plan for the implementation, monitoring and evaluation of this program will start by pre-assessment of the target population aims to collect a quantitative data focused on project indicators (measuring all project indicators prior to intervention) and that will tack a place in the first month of the implementation.
In the next phase, Silk Road will select the beneficiaries of the program and the participating sellers as well also we will do verification of the selected beneficiaries. We will use clear and logical selection criteria in partnership and cooperation with the community (Through focus groups discussion that will be held) in order to ensure that all families understand why some were selected and why some other families were not eligible. We will use a separate team to verify the extent to beneficiaries meet criteria to ensure transparency and objectivity in selection. The priority will be to target at-risk groups the Newly IDPs families (Women-headed households) and GBV survivors to protect them from the adoption of negative coping mechanisms, as well as from other exploitative and unsafe situations, such as prostitution, transactional sex, early pregnancy, enlistment into armed groups, early/forced/child marriage.
Criteria for selecting Sellers:
1. Seller&apos;s ability to re-supply goods
2. The diversity of goods in the market
3. The accessibility of beneficiaries to the market
4. Number of days and hours working
5. The reputation of the seller in the region
6. Fees or commissions payable by the Organization if any
7. Cooperation with the organization and the seller&apos;s willingness to accept the terms and conditions of the payments
Also, within the first month of the project, we will conduct the sealers capacity assessment include the frequency of re-supply of goods focusing on the goods we plan to distribute, the availability of a warehouse close to the shop, notes by the team on the seller&apos;s skills in dealing with customers as well as the number of customers who came during the evaluation period, reputation and seller&apos;s interest in participating in the program and finally the financial capacity of the seller. Furthermore, we will update the assessment of prices, the current situation of the local market and the most requested goods by local population before identifying sellers.
In this project, we will use unconditional vouchers (Food for a fixed monetary value (value-based vouchers) in the selected shop) that allow sufficient flexibility for the beneficiaries, where they can buy whatever they need from the list of the items included in the voucher according to the voucher amount (Around 25 items).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-FSC-164533-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-23">799880.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-14999">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-23">799880.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304551498">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-01">479928.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304738308">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-16">319952.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
