<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA1/H-N/NGO/15009</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">responding to urgent health and nutrition needs in Idleb governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a matter of fact, this grant will address the variety of urgencies and dire health and nutrition needs on the ground by matching with the health and nutrition clusters strategic plan and approach. As such, this grant will support lifesaving primary health care services by providing medical staff financial remuneration and gap-filling facilities operational support and Scaling up integrated mother and child-centered nutrition life-saving interventions through Rapid Response teams. 

On the other hand, In line with the health Cluster and sector partners&apos; approach to expanding existing health facilities and to supporting critical one. THIS PROJECT WILL SUPPORT tow primary health care centers along with integration nutrition services through establishing one rapid response team with its OTP at PHC level. All of these two primary health care centers and RRT are located in underserved areas and heavily populated with IDPs and affected population.
This grant  through health and nutrition intervention will serve 71969 population based on the update of the IOM report divided as follow:
Balmis, 3,887    
Maalaqa - Bishlamon, 3,406  
Bsheiriyeh - Bello, 6,030 
Western Marj Akhdar, 9,000 
Eastern Marj Akhdar, 8,533
Torlaha: 4749
Kafr Aruq (co): 8670
Ras Elhisn: 10161
Htan: 5706
Barisha: 11828

Practically speaking, this project will support Meshmshan primary health care center, which is located in Idleb governorate, Jisr Alshogour sub-district, western marj Alkhader community. This PHC is level tow serving 9000 population as primary health care center. It will provide the outpatient primary health care services with temporary residency. This crucial PHC is providing its health services daily except Friday for those in need covering boys, girls, men and women. 
All the complicated cases will be referred to Al Rahma Hospital where we have already coordinated with them to receive the complicated cases. 
The second PHC is Barisha primary health care center, this health facility is located in area heavily populated with IDPs especially women, elderly and boys,and girls under five years. It is serving 41,113 population, 26177 out of them are IDPs. This PHC now is providing the child health care services and we are aiming through this grant to scale up this health services adding tow GPs to cover real gap in this area by providing the reproductive health services and internal medicine services including NCD and CD giving extra attention for those elderly and people with disabilities. Those added services will be provided daily except Friday at the health facility level.  The staff will refer the cases if needed to Bab Al-Hawa Hospital. 
Finally, the integration approach with nutrition sector will be clear by establishing one RRT linked to Meshmshan PHC which will provide the OTP services at the PHC level, this RRT will cover 30856 population - including 9000 targeted population through Meshmshan PHC- 5400 of them C5 and 2314 of them PLW.  This RRT will Screen boys, girls under five, and pregnant and lactating women for acute malnutrition and PSS cases. Also, they will refer boys, girls, pregnant and lactating women to the Meshmshan primary healthcare center if there is a malnutrition case and they will refer the cases needs PSS to Meshmshan center who have tow Qualified PSS. Along with disseminating IYCF-E messages among mothers of children under five (group sessions). And finally they will Facilitate IYCF-E campaigns. In addition to that, they will provide hygiene and health promotion and educate the mothers regarding the general danger signs for children under five years and refer the suspected cases. 
This grant will secure the required pharmaceuticals and medical consumables for these two health facilities and monthly running cost including fuel, maintenance and internet. 
Finally, all of these services will be reported to health and nutrition clusters coordination tools 4W and HERAMS and EWARN</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-HEA-164233-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-NUT-164243-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="77.97" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="22.03" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-18">186549.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-15009">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-18">186549.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304543229">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-26">186549.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
