<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/N/NGO/16346</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure Continuity, Increase Coverage and the Delivery of Life-Saving Nutritional Services in Areas of High-Need in NWS.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to ensure the continuity and increased the coverage of life-saving nutritional services, in high needs and remote locations through activating 10 Rapid Response Teams (RRTs), who will target areas of low coverage or have very high rates of acute malnutrition and therefore require urgent scale-up.
Those teams will introduce integrated nutrition, protection, health and WASH services to both host and IDPs, where two teams will cover one of the following five locations: Jisr-Ash-Shugur, Badama, Harim and Salqin sub-districts in Idleb, in addition to Qabasin in Al-bab sub-district in Aleppo.
Each team, consisting of a nutritionist, a nurse, and 2 community health workers, will introduce the following integrated services:
Nutrition: Screen Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW) and Children under 5 (CU5) to detect and refer the malnourished cases to health facilities, provide IYCF-E counselling for mothers with moderately malnourished children, distribute micronutrients for preventing of anemia and malnutrition among children,
pregnant and lactating women, disseminate oral messages on IYCF-E recommended feeding practices, and monitor distribution and use of breast milk substitutes, support health/nutrition inclusive education and promotion refer the needed cases and follow up the referred cases. Besides, 2000 Breast covers will be distributed to the PLWs to encourage them feeling more privacy and to raise the awareness   about the importance of exclusive breastfeeding even in the camps.
No group awareness sessions or hand-to-hand brochures will be distributed to the beneficiaries according to nutrition cluster task force to avoid the risk of COVID19, instead of that the project team will apply programmatic adjustments through raise the beneficiaries&#x2019; awareness via the social media, especially FACEBOOK and WHATSAPP awareness groups under control of field supervisors. Also, the RRT will roll out a family MUAC approach through training the caregivers to measure the MUAC of their children, in addition to strengthen household follow ups for SAM and MAM cases. All the RRT will be trained to take the right precautions during the work and the project will cover the PPE for the staff and beneficiaries (masks, gloves, sterilizers, big board for explaining the awreness messages).
Protection: identify and refer the cases exposed to abuse or violence via the visual signs on the children under five and PLWs&#x2019; bodies, where the discovered cases will be referred to the child protection CP or GBV case management teams in coordination with CP specialist in SEMA and field teams on the ground according to CP and GVB service map.
A half-day PSEA online training will be conducted to the nutritionists and supervisors, after that, they will convey and orient the CHWs to raise their awareness about how they have to provide the services in the right way and provide the beneficiaries with the compliant contacts numbers and emails in case any mistake resulted from the workers or supervisors.
Health: Detect and refer CU5 and PLWs with danger signs and Medical problems according to guidance developed in coordination with the nutrition cluster (paper and electronic templates), where the referred cases will receive the medical care under the supervision of specialized doctors such as pediatrician or general practitioner.
Furthermore, Messages about the RH module will be delivered to PLWs.
WASH including COVID19 awareness: support hygiene promotion and raise the awareness through providing key messages about the hand washing, mask use, social distancing, sterilizers use and food processing.
Using educational videos   and social media platforms, SEMA teams will increase the people aware about COVID19 infection ways, risk of infection and social contacts, the protective ways in coordination with local councils, camps management and other related stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-NUT-164714-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-04">140278.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-04">209268.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16346">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-04">349547.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667968">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">209728.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305612043">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-07">130380.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
