<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA1/NFI/NGO/16388</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing living conditions in Dana sub-district for the vulnerable conflict affected returnees, IDPs and Host communities through shelter rehabilitation for 500 household</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horan Foundation (HF) previously known as Ahl Horan Association (AHA) in this proposal intends to enhance the living conditions of the conflict-affected population living in Dana sub-district as the needs are still huge in that area based on the information provided by draft HNO 2020 and to the SA strategic paper for the First round. The action that HF will take is rehabilitation of 500 shelter units in  Hezreh, Termanin, Tilaada where the three communities are in Dana sub-district and support those communities in providing a life-saving and life sustaining shelter support through rehabilitation process within 8 months.

The idea of proposing this project came from the previous implementation of shelter rehabilitation for damaged houses and shelter units in Dana and Afrin cities by HF where the host communities and IDPs lives in a very bad condition and due to small amount of fund HF could only address 800 HHs for newly displaced with emergency shelter rehab, while the needs assessment showed that huge needs for most vulnerable population are still there and in need of shelter rehabilitation.

This suggested intervention will be, as you may see in the activities in line with Shelter Rehab Guidelines (SRG) of GRADE 2 damages houses, the design of program, considering protection issues, designing the activities and engaging the community, all was designed in line with SRG.

A focus on moderate damage (Grade 2) allows a maximization of impact, in order to assist as many beneficiaries as possible especially IDPs and returnees which their shelter units were damaged as a result of aerial/land attacks or unfinished units that needs basic rehabilitation to sustain their lives, windows and doors for instance as the needs assessment done by our teams and engineers showed that many of IDPs are living in very bad condition. Units targeted in the RNA was checked for the HLP issues and no major issues checked. In addition to the repair of small damages in walls, doors, broken windows, locks and plumbing services, HF will install one solar panel system in each targeted HHs (if not existed) to provide an alternative source of lighting in an energy scarce environment and to enhance privacy and decrease protection issues for women and children.

HF seeks to address the needs for the most vulnerable people in targeted locations and this definition of the needs came from needs assessment done by HF, Pictures of the damaged houses are attached in documents in addition to needs reports and calls for interventions from areas LCs. Our approach is toward more qualitative and sustainable response to Shelter repair, with the goal of improving livelihoods and promoting stability, reintegration of IDPs into host communities and a return to normalcy for all targeted HHs. In addition to enhancing physical stability and safety via Shelter repair of GRADE 2 damaged HHs.

The provision of shelter meets one of the basic survival needs of women, girls, boys and men and can strengthen protection in a physical sense this project aims to improve the shelter and living condition for approximately(Boys 600 Girls 650 Men 550 Women 700 Total 2500) of the hosts, returnees and IDPs population. For the HC the beneficiaries would be (Boys 336 Girls 364 Men 308 Women 392 Total 1386) while for the IDPs the numbers would be (Boys 204 Girls 221 Men 187 Women 238 Total 850)

HF will coordinate with the responsible organization of the served area to cover other needs to enhance the living condition that may include livelihood opportunities for the most vulnerable people.

This project will respond to the needs of different groups since the very beginning of the project will form a shelter committee that contains those groups especially women and girls and youth, and had taken into consideration to respond to their needs through providing lightning to prevent GBV and installing special latrines for the people with disabilities.
&#x2026;. to be continued in the comments..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-SHL-164593-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-02">454225.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-02">146444.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-16388">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-02">600670.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304667992">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-08">240268.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304913927">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-11">360402.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
