<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/RA1/CCM-P/UN/14987</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of Sheikh Bahr Reception Center and provision of emergency protection services to IDPs and host community members in northwest Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to support the CCCM and Protection response to the immediate needs of the most vulnerable displaced persons in northwest Syria (NWS) and has two main components:
First, IOM will establish a reception center with hosting capacity of up to 3,000 people at any given time in Deir Hassan, Dana sub-district, Harim district, Idleb Governorate. The project will provide newly displaced persons affected by the ongoing conflict with multisector assistance including temporary shelter, WASH, NFIs, food, health services through coordination with clusters, partners, and camp residents. IOM will work with Maram Foundation, a local NGO with the proven record and capacity of establishing and running reception centers in NWS. The project will target any person or household who requires a temporary shelter and humanitarian assistance. The project will construct key administrative and critical humanitarian infrastructure including the installation of 30 rub hall tents with concrete foundation, 12 family tents for office purposes, medical activities, and accommodation for people with disabilities, 12 water points, 60 solar lighting poles, 10 blocks of latrines and showers, sewage system, fence, warehouse, child friendly space, and drainage systems. This component of the project will provide temporary shelters and multisectoral assistance to an estimated 6,000 newly displaced persons     (960 men, 1,354 women, 1,864 boys, 1,822 girls) cumulatively, based on the assumption that the RC is at 50% capacity during its first four months of operations.

Second, IOM, in partnership with Shafak, will provide integrated emergency protection services to approximately 15,650 new IDPs and host community members in and around the planned Deir Hassan RC. This will include specialized and non-specialized services including child protection and gender-based violence (GBV) services, information dissemination, distribution of dignity kits, psychological first aid (PFA), psycho-social services (PSS) risk education and legal awareness raising, service mapping, referral to specialized services, and individual protection assistance (IPA) to the most vulnerable individuals. Age- and gender-representative community committees will be formed to ensure a participatory and contextualized approach. The project will also conduct protection monitoring to provide the Protection Monitoring Taskforce with timely information regarding critical protection concerns.
During the period of establishing Deir Hassan RC (estimated from 15 March&#x2013;15 June 2020), two mobile outreach teams will provide the full range of services around Dana sub-district. The focus will be on reaching new IDPs in underserved, informal IDP sites, with all case management activities conducted in Shafak&#x2019;s child-friendly space (CFS) in Deir Hassan. With the opening of the RC to IDPs in mid-June 2020, one outreach team will provide full-time on-site support. Case management will be conducted in a dedicated protection tent in the RC. The second team will continue outreach efforts in the adjacent communities throughout the project period. Both mobile teams and the protection team in RC will conduct activities throughout the project period. All activities will start in the first month. The distribution of dignity kits will commence after building community rapport and an overview of existing needs in month 2. The two community committees will be established in month 1 by mobile teams. Committee members will then support the incoming IDP members from the RC.
The total number of targeted beneficiaries for the project is an estimated 17,738 unique individuals, which includes an estimated 11,738 unique beneficiaries under the protection component (not including 3,912 people provided with protection services in the Deir Hassan RC and counted under the CCCM component), and the estimated 6,000 beneficiaries under the CCCM component who will be provided with shelter and multisectoral assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-CCM-164745-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-PRO;PRO-CPN;PRO-GBV-164655-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="84" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="16" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-01">1433584.59</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-14987">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-01">1433584.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304560716">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-09">1433584.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
