<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-20/3559/SA2/WASH-ER/NGO/17692</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated WASH and ERL response to the negative effects of the COVID 19 pandemic on the affected communities in NWS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our response will focus mainly on two sectors, WASH and ERL where we seek through this integrated response to reduce the risks of the Covid 19 pandemic among the already affected people. Our strategy depends on innovative intervention to confront the economic and social impacts of Covid 19 and limit its spread and its effects on the vulnerable people, where the water, sanitation and hygiene package is designed to limit the spread of the Covid 19 and change the wrong and unhealthy hygienic practices and provide the needed personal items that will protect people and enhance their personal hygiene, while the ERL packages will work to help vulnerable people to overcome the negative economic and social results left by the spread of the Covid 19 beside the Syrian crisis through the provision of short-term labour opportunities to skilled and unskilled workers supporting 180 HHs Who will mainly responsible for producing around 155520 reusable masks through the cash for work that will be implemented.
Silk Road will establish (3 ) workshops equipped with the necessary equipment to produce these masks as well as some women will participate from their homes if any (Women have a Sewing machine), while the organization will secure all other materials needed for the production of the masks. The workshops will be in Batenta, Maaret Elekhwan and Kafr Karmin and the main beneficiaries will be selected from these locations. Silk Road will seek to use existing workshops if any and in case it is not possible then we will go to establish new workshops knowing that this will not cost a lot and will not take a long time as well.
The produced masks beside soap that will be secured by the organization will be packed in boxes or bags and this package will be distributed to the beneficiaries in two ways (The first by the hygiene promoters when they visit the family and the second by the head of the family who can come to the workshop to pick up the package). The sewing machines will be handed over to the number of families after the project ends ( Kind of sustainability of the project under an agreement with women, standers and criteria for selection). Silk Road will select the most vulnerable women (Families with no income generation) in each targeted community and we will prioritize IDPs, women ith disabilities, and women-headed household also we will take into our consideration the size of the family and persons he has the ability to work if any. Silk Road will study each case before producing the final list and we will transparently work with the community. Also, once we select the women, we will sign an agreement with them to ensure the rights of each party.
The approach that we will follow in implementing WASH intervention to achieve the desired goals will be based on providing the needed safe drinking water to people as well as support and manage waste collection systems to maintain a safe and clean environment in addition to distributing hygiene personal supplies (Soap +Masks (4 per person) that helps reduce the spread of the Covid 19 epidemic, in addition to re-usable face masks that we will provide through early recovery activities that we will support. These activities will be accompanied by awareness-raising activities that will be provided by the hygiene promoters who will be assigned in each targeted communities(Two in each one). During this period of support (Operation of the water systems), a cost recovery system will be established to ensure continuous cash flow required for running the systems during and after the project (Only the first two months of the project will be supported 100% while the others will be partly supported), this will involve a study on a suitable tariff rate that takes into account the dwindling financial capacity of the benefiting population and will be based on focus group discussions with a representative group of the community including members of local councils of targeted communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-ERY-165411-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR20-WSH-164606-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="17" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="83" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-22">558093.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-17692">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-22">558093.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304860948">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">334856.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305032951">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-26">223237.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
