<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8620</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multiplaza Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Honduras : Camino Real - Multiplaza              Region    Latin America &amp; Caribbean        Sector       Project No008620   Projected Board DateJune 25, 1998   Company NameHillwood Investments jointly with Multiplaza de Tegucigalpa S.A. and Inversiones Real S.A.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The project is sponsored by Grupo Roble de Honduras a sister company of Inversiones Roble based in El Salvador, which ranks among the established business groups in Central America.  The groups main business is focused on hotel and real estate development and its main holdings include the Camino Real hotels in San Salvador, El Salvador; San Jose, Costa Rica and San Pedro Sula, Honduras.  The group also owns several shopping malls located in San Salvador, San Jose, San Pedro and Managua.      The Hotel will be managed under a contract with Grupo Real (the hospitality division of Grupo Roble) and Inter-Continental Hotels.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The estimated cost of the project including interest during construction and contingencies is US$40.12 million.  The proposed IFC investment includes a senior loan of US$10 million.     Location of project and Description of site    	The project will be located in the capital of Honduras - Tegucigalpa.  The project site which consists of 15.5 acres is situated in a corridor of rapid residential, commercial and other development and is bordered on the north by the Boulevard Suyapa and on the south by Boulevard Juan Pablo II.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The borrowers for the IFC loan will be Hillwood Investments and its two wholly owned subisdiaries - Multiplaza de Tegucigalpa S.A. and Inversiones Real S.A.  Multiplaza de Tegucigalpa will develop and operate the Mall while Inversiones Real will own the Camino Real Inter-Continental.    	The project consists of a mixed-use development including a 157-room hotel and an adjacent shopping mall in Tegucigalpa.  The proposed hotel - The Camino Real Inter-Continental - will be the first 5-star chain hotel in the city.  The Multiplaza which will be located at the same site will be one of the largest shopping centers with four anchors, a supermarket, local stores, a large food court and movie theaters.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a Category B project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental review procedures and key environmental, occupational health and safety issues of concern in the project include: land use; disposal of liquid effluents; solid waste disposal; CFCs; employee safety training and emergency response and fire protection measures.      	The Mall and hotel buildings will be fully equipped with sprinklers and an independent fire safety audit is being conducted to ensure that the project complies with the WOrld Bank guidelines on fire safety.  Wastewater and sewage from the project will be discharged to the city sewers.  IFC has required the sponsors to commit to building a wastewater treatment plant if the municipal system fails to invest in such a system by the time the project is complete.  Solid waste will be disposed off in the municipal dump.  The sponsors have assured IFC that the central air conditioning system and cold storage facilities are CFC-free.  The project will meet World bank Environmental, health and safety policies and guidelines as well as Honduran requirements.    The  is  May 15, 1998 from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     May 8, 1998      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multiplaza de Tegucigalpa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8620" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-02-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-06-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Honduras</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="HN-Honduras">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.0000000000 -86.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - City and Business Hotel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-02-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-02-18">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-02-18">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multiplaza de Tegucigalpa</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8620/multiplaza-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
