<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/SA1 2017/WASH/NGO/4571</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to safe water, sanitation and hygiene services for people affected by Acute Watery Diarhoea (AWD) /cholera and severe drought in Bay (Baidoa), and Lower Shabelle (Marka) regions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will support access to water sanitation and hygiene services for about 12,000 people who include (3,600 women, 2400 men, 3,120 girls and 2880 boys)  people affected by severe drought conditions and at risk of Acute Watery Diarrhea (AWD) / cholera outbreak in Bay and Lower Shabelle regions. The project will target Baidoa and Marka in the following breakdown Bay - 50%, Lower Shabelle 50%. The project will adopt an integrated humanitarian assistance delivery approach to improve efficiency, cost effectiveness and improved outcomes in WASH, education and health needs of the affected people. SYPD will adopt an integrated approach by using education and health facilities as entry points in the implementation of emergency water access, hygiene awareness creation, AWD/Cholera preparedness and improving sanitation facilities in the affected regions. 

The project will entail the following interrelated activities:

1. Emergency access to safe water: SYPD will support emergency access to safe water through water vouchers to support household water access, provision of water treatment supplies (aqua tabs), chlorination of common water sources (shallow wells), supporting operational and repair of strategic boreholes including provision of fast moving spare parts and fuel subsidies, rehabilitation and protection of shallow wells to promote preparedness and an exit strategy.

2. Support access to safe water for institutions (Schools and Health facilities): While water vouchers will provide households with water, surrounding health facilities (5) and schools (5) will be supported with vouchers for water trucking. Each institution will be provided with a voucher worth 8,000 liters per week for a period of three months. The support will complement other interventions such as school feeding for school children and medical services in health facilities. In addition, SYPD will provide 1 water tank / water bladder with a capacity of 10,000 liters to each school and health facility targeted by the support. 

3. Hygiene promotion campaigns: SYPD will use loud speakers, information materials and hygiene promoters to create awareness on appropriate hygiene practices, hygienic and safe water handling at the household level in order to reduce unhygienic handling and storage of water at the household level which creates additional avenues for contamination. The activity will be linked to the reduction of AWD / cholera risks and improve household capacity in preventing water borne diseases. SYPD will use schools as avenues for the delivery of messages and dissemination of information materials to teachers and school children to create an early start in hygiene awareness. 

4. Rehabilitation of institutional and household sanitation facilities: SYPD will prioritize AWD affected districts to rehabilitate or construct latrines and building new ones where they do not exist at the households and in institutions. The will support the improvement of sanitation facilities in schools and health facilities. 

5. AWD / cholera preparedness and Disaster risk reduction (DRR) activities: SYPD will promote Acute Watery Diarhoea (AWD) and other diarrheal diseases preparedness at the community level through the participatory approach for the control of diarheal disease by implementing the Participatory Hygiene and Sanitation Transformation (PHAST) step by step guide. The intervention will help communities members and particularly women who bear the greatest burden of diseases in identifying the common risk factors in the specific locations and actions that need to be take to prevent the disease outbreaks.

6. Capacity building /Sustainability: SYPD will mainstream sustainability of water infrastructure by training the WASH committees on general operation and maintenance.

7. Rehabilitation of water facilities: this will include the rehabilitation of shallow wells</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SYPD</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>sypdmog@yahoo.com</telephone>
   <email>Hassan Ali Hassan</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-02-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-01">270123</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-4571">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-01">270123</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302550132">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-17">216098.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305149260">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-19">45196.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
