<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/SA1 2017/Prot/NGO/4572</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote essential emergency GBV prevention  response, strengthen community, CSOs, Local authorities&#x2019; capacity to prevent and respond rights violations and contribute to protective environments for IDPs and other vulnerable groups in Hiran, Lower Shabelle and Banadir regions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian situation in Somalia continues to deteriorate with potential famine crisis that resulted from two consecutive seasons of poor rainfall in most parts of the country, According to UNHCR report in April 2017, drought related displacements are reported to be on the increase due food insecurity and limited services, which caused competition for resource such as food and water among affected people, which may have more negative impact on women and girls due to their vulnerability.  According to GBV IMS report about 1599 GBV incidents from January to February 2017. Out of the 1599 Incidents, 72 percent accounted for intimate partner violence, sexual assault accounted for 12 percent and rape 13 percent, psychological emotional abuse at 9 percent, physical assault at 52 percent, forced marriage at 4 percent and denial of resources and opportunities at 9 percent. Sexual violence, particularly rape within the drought hot spots account for 15 percent. 75 percent of the GBV survivors are IDPs and 97 percent of these are female.
Furthermore, the protection cluster has concerned that the protective environment for the IDPs and civilians affected by the drought remains weak and requires strengthening.to respond. Thus, WARDI is scaling up its GBB response in Hiran, Lower shabelle and Bandir regions. WARDI will address GBV prevention amp response through three interrelated sets of activities: prevention, response (survivor assistance) and coordination. 
1) The prevention activities include training Community Safety amp Awareness Mobilizers in approaches and methods to proper survivor-centered care, raising awareness in communities about available confidential services, referral networks and dignity kit distributions.  
2) The response activities of the project include provision of medical services quality to women and girls who are survivors of GBV through Three GBV one stop centers. (One in Belet Weyn Hospital, One in Wanla Weyn and one in km 7-13 of Mogadishu). WARDI will also apply the following principles &quot;privacy, confidentiality, safety of survivors and family&#x201D; while providing medical assistance to GBV survivors.
3) Since WARDI is focal point of Hiran GBV sub cluster, the organization will strengthen GBV coordination at national and Hiran sub cluster WG to improve coordination among partners, reporting and ensure that mainstreaming of protection across cluster and partners in the Hiran region. 
Further more, the project will also improve the capacity of service providers to provide quality services, strength resilience of the Internal displaced people (IDP) and poor host community through awareness raising campaigns.
4) WARDI will also provide awareness on GBV, health care services, and psychosocial support to GBV survivors.
 In summary, a total of 3,053 drought affected people will be provided life saving GBV services including medical support, psychosocial support, awareness on GBV prevention and capacity building for case workers and community members on GBV prevention and response in Hiran region, The project is complementary with WASH, health and Nutrition interventions that WARDI is implementing in the targeted locations.
Through this project , WARDI will also subcontract with three local partners  operating at regional and district levels in the areas at risk.  The partners have the capacity to implement multiple activities in both SRH and GBV in the same district/ region. With adequate resources, same partners will be able to reach most of the population in need through different modalities.the three partners will run 3 family centers/safe houses in 3 districts (Afgoi ,Dharkinley and Hodan )</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HINNA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OSPAD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SSC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WARDI Relief and Development Initiatives</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WARDI Relief and Development Initiatives</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hussein Abdi Isak</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chairman</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+262615501688</telephone>
   <email>wardiorg@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-24"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-08">199501.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-4572">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-08">199501.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WARDI Relief and Development Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302729226">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-19">159601.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WARDI Relief and Development Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303208403">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-05">39900.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WARDI Relief and Development Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
