<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/R/Shelter-CCCM-WASH-Prot/INGO/6289</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the protective environment for IDPs and other vulnerable groups in particular through enhanced integrated Protection, Shelter, CCCM and WASH interventions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is designed to contribute to Somalia HRP 2017 and DRC&apos;s efforts to support the drought-induced displacement affected populations (Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs)and host communities) in Bay and Banadir regions through integrated protection, CCCM, emergency Shelter and WASH interventions. The specific interventions to be implemented include: WASH component in Baidoa include construction of 165 VIP latrines and provision of sanitation tools, hygiene promotion targeting 1945 households, hygiene kits targeting the most vulnerable households (1945 kits). DRC also anticipates additional supply of hygiene kits through the WASH cluster which will bridge any gaps. The kits will be distributed during or after hygiene promotion. In Mogadishu/Kahda, DRC proposes some minimal WASH interventions, focusing mainly on hygiene promotion and distribution of hygiene kits to the most vulnerable, to complement the Shelter, CCCM and Protection interventions, considering the integrated nature of the project in the two regions. DRC will also train two community health volunteers in each settlement to disseminate health and hygiene messages in the community supported by Hygiene Promoters. The protection component will consist of: Provision of street solar lights to affected people in the newly established IDP settlements, protection kits to address urgent needs for the women and girls that are extremely vulnerable Child protection &#x2013; drought affected children have access to immediate medical, psychosocial, transportation, dignity kits, Non-food items (NFIs) in Kahda and Baidoa IDP settlements and children safe places housing land and property (HLP): focusing mostly awareness raising and capacity building activities on HLP Mine Risk Education (MRE) - Mine risk education awareness on existing explosive hazards, mapping of critical mass in the community based on selected communities, to identify key agents for change and community dialogue and MRE sessions and protection monitoring in IDP settlements to identify and analyze risks, incidents, and trends relevant to the protection and assistance of populations displaced due to drought to inform decision making, prioritization, advocacy and programme (re-)design in both settlements in Baidoa and Kahda. The shelter activities will involve distribution of Emergency Shelter, NFIs kits and some Cash assistance to1100 households in Kahda district, Banadir region and other 1100 households in the new IDP settlements in Baidoa town. The beneficiaries will be selected in a community driven process with a pro-poor and vulnerable approach, considering issues such as women headed households, child headed households, orphans, disabled, the old among and new arrivals. The CCCM component is aimed at the overall coordination through enhanced communication with communities, feedback mechanisms, information sharing on available assistance and services and improved coordination for service delivery during the project. 
The overall objective of DRC integrated approach in this project are: WASH component - to contribute to the reduction of AWD/Cholera incidences in Baidoa and Kahda through hygiene awareness and education, household water treatment and proper use of latrines and reduction of open defecation through construction of improved sanitation facilities in Baidoa Protection- to enhance protection of IDPs and vulnerable women, children and girls through protection mainstreaming in selected IDP settlements in Baidoa and Mogadishu through access to treatment, psychosocial support and material support, awareness creation on mine risk education and HLP CCCM - to ensure effective coordination, communication and equitable access to services and protection for Internally Displaced Populations in Baidoa and Mogadishu Shelter -to improve the living conditions and protection by providing emergency shelter kits/NFIs to the most vulnerable drought affected populations in Baidoa and Kahda district</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eliab Mulili</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 612522289</telephone>
   <email>E.Mulili@drcsomalia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simon Nzioka</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 254 722307125</telephone>
   <email>s.nziokah@DRCSOMALIA.ORG</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-29">819901.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-29">485468.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-6289">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-29">1305370.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302860131">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-05">783222.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303480594">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-14">501473.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
