<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/SA2/H-WASH-Nut/NGO/7413</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of an integrated multi-sectoral lifesaving services to drought affected IDPs and communities in Baidoa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is an integrated response around three complimentary directorial areas Health, WASH and Nutrition. It is intended to mitigate the physical and protection consequences of drought on populations and communities directly affected in Bay region, in particular, Baidoa town. The main objective of this project is to provide integrated life-saving emergency primary health, WASH and Nutrition services to 24,500 (Nutrition: 2500 Boys, 3000 Girls and 1500 PLW, for Health: 2,100 Boys, 3,000 Girls, 1,200 Women, 1000 men and WASH program: 3,200 Women, 2,000 Men, 2,200 Boys and 2,800 Girls) AWD/drought affected direct beneficiaries in ADC, North sites and east sites IDPs through the provision of 9 IERT teams for integrated services
HIDIG emphasis will be on maternal, neonatal and child health including emergency immunization to the host communities and IDPs as well as treatment of severe acute malnutrition, building the capacity of health workers through training on integrated management of acute illness IMCI, Cholera/measles case management and integrated  community case management iCCM which will be done to equip health workers with the required skills to deliver quality healthcare services. As part of WASH integration, HIDIG will carry out comprehensive Hygiene and sanitation promotion activities including distribution of 450  basic hygiene to 2700 vulnerable families with severely malnourished children in the IDPs. HIDIG will also distribute standard (IEC) materials for social mobilization, HIDIG will closely coordinate with Baidoa district Local MOH as well as Federal level MOH and social mobilizers, elders all involved in activities on mobilizing communities. To support increase access of sustainable and safe water, HIDIG through the trained hygiene promoters will conduct bucket  chlorination at the three constructed water kiosk in ADC IDPs water point to mitigate any occurrence of AWD. Through this IERT program HIDIG will strive to improve the sanitation services within the household as well as the MCH through construction/rehabilitation of two gender sensitive toilet with hand washing facilities as well as piped water in ADC and Mursal HIDIG MCH.it shall intend to construct 78 household  latrine to the main IDPs in ADC,Nort sites and east sites hence this shall ensure proper sanitation services. HIDIG will construct three number water kiosk one in each main IDPs in ADC IDPs  and shall connect this water kiosk through piping from wadajir Borehole thus this will ensures better protection or GBV related incident reduced. HIDIG will also distributes sanitation kits and as well intend to construct two main incinerators at ADC and Mursal MCH in Baidoa for better disposal of medical and none medical waste.
On the other hand the nutrition component intends to achieve the following, capacity building of nutrition staff on IMAM/IYCF services, infant young child feeding best practices (IYCF), as well as conduct caregivers infant and young child feeding practices, IYCF promotion session for better information dissemination to the caregivers in the project area. Referral of malnourished children with complicated cases will be done to the Outpatient Therapeutic Programme (OTP) centers integrated with primary health care services managed by HIDIG and other actors in the program areas thus providing more holistic opportunity to the target beneficiaries.
However, HIDIG endeavors to undertake health , WASH and Nutrition activities that will be integrated in the sense that under five children boys, girls admitted at the OTP sites will be immunized against measles and other communicable disease and as well the SAM complicated cases referred to the stabilization centers for proper medical treatment, on the same note the mothers visiting ANC/PNC at the mobile clinic will be provided both NHHP/IYCF-E and shall be integrated with hygiene promotions activities such as hand washing practices as well as distribution of hygiene kit</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hidig Relief And Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hidig Relief And Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daud Moalim Abdinur</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615532161</telephone>
   <email>dama09@hotmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="27" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="33" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-06">519949.87</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1704410098">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-01">535</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hidig Relief And Development Organization</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-7413">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-06">519949.87</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hidig Relief And Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303188896">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-16">415959.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hidig Relief And Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303853578">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-26">102822.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hidig Relief And Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
