<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/R/Shelter/NGO/6629</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve access to Emergency Shelter and NFIs and overall living conditions for 5,400 newly displaced people in Lower Shabelle (Afgoye corridor and K50 through unconditional cash vouchers (for ESKs  NFIs), distribution of Solar Lamps and CCCM</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will target an estimated 5,400 newly displaced people or 900 households who comprise 2,700 people or 450 households newly displaced in Afgoye corridor, and 450 households or 2,700 people K50. 

The project will target the most vulnerable people who have been displaced by prolonged drought conditions and conflict. To ensure that displaced people have a complementary package, the project activities will also include solar lamps,and dignity kits  This will ensure that the intervention enhances the protection of the internally displaced persons, promotes dignity and privacy of displaced people.
The project will be implemented through unconditional cash vouchers. SYPD will carry out a market survey at the initial phase to determine the market functionality and confirm the availability of appropriate supplies in the local market. Where appropriate and when the market survey confirms the availability of the appropriate NFIs and shelter materials in the local market, SYPD will distribute shelter and NFIs through unconditional cash vouchers. The cash transfer approach will promote local economy by pumping in cash.  

SYPD will give each household a cash vouchers of $200. This will provide beneficiaries with the freedom the choose from a variety of brands and NFIs from the local market. The voucher value will enable each household to purchase standard emergency shelter kit (timber/poles, wooden sticks, plastic sheets, nails, door, padlock, hinges, 2 kgs of Binding Wire, and rope) at $125 and NFIs kits (containing 2 blankets, 1 plastic sheet, 1 kitchen set, 3 sanitary towels, 2 soaps, 2 prayer mats and 2 Jerrycans with the capacity of 20 liters) at $75. 

To ensure quality control of materials, SYPD will guide household on the choice of appropriate material in the local market. 
Distribution of solar lamps and dignity kits will however be done through in-kind distribution since they are generally not available in the local market. This will also ensure quality control and value for money. 
SYPD will use an owner-driven approach in the construction of emergency shelters by training the IDPs on how to construct / assemble the shelter unit. SYPD will facilitate the construction of a demonstration unit at every site to show beneficiaries how to construct the shelters.

SYPD will also incorporate light training on camp safety, Disaster Risk Reduction, and site planning. This will promote sustainability of the project and empowerment of the beneficiaries. 
The project will integrate Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM) aspects by working with local authorities, other partners, ensuring settlement and site planning to promote safety against fires, proper drainage channels and provision for common space for basic services such as sanitation facilities, health posts, play grounds and access roads.
SYPD will undertake proper site planning and work with beneficiaries during the constructions to ensure appropriate access roads, children playing grounds and common facilities sites. In addition, proper site planning will also be undertaken to ensure effective mitigation of fires and avoid congestions.
SYPD will adopt a participatory and transparent approach with an age, gender and diversity lens by strengthening existing community mechanism to ensure  ensure access to information and services and improve accountability to affected populations 

Project committees will be formed and will hold meetings with SYPD staff on a weekly basis. The forum will provide a structured avenue for disseminating information on services and all-round feedback mechanism through which beneficiaries can communicate ideas and feedback on project activities to guide re-design and adjustments where necessary. The project committees will also provide a forum for complaints and dispute resolution, lessons learning and</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hassan Ali Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+25261-5521100</telephone>
   <email>director@sypd.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-08-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-07">210393.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-07">89702.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-6629">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-07">300096.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302877507">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-12">240076.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development  Peace Building Initiatives</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
