<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/SA1 2017/Nut/INGO/4663</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency integrated nutrition project aimed at reducing  morbidity and mortality related to severe acute malnutrition through  outpatient therapeutic feeding program(OTP) among in Kismayo district of south central Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kismayo was liberated in 2012 following a military offensive. Since then the town has continued to receive new people migrating in. These include natives that had fled due to insecurity, migrants from villages outside the town and neighboring districts who flee there due to both civil and food insecurity in their home villages and finally those repatriated from Daadab refugee camp in Kenya. The population has continued to increase from 166667 in 2005 (UNDP,2005), to 211387 in 2014(UNFPA, 2014) to 382215 in 2016 (Jubaland Ministry of planning et all). Majority of this population is however in need of many basic services which are limited within the town, and are easily affected by shocks that pushes them to crisis due to a number of factors. Kismayo town is also home to approximately 30690 IDP in the various zones in the town. Abdalla Birole is also home to approximately 1530 IDP (Ministry of planning 2016, UNHCR 2016) who are in critical situation and in dire need of health and nutrition services. About 90% of IDP in Kismayo come from the riverine Gosha community, most who hail from middle Juba, This community has been marginalized for long and still find it hard to easily integrate with Kismayo host population and enjoy equal work and business opportunities.(SAF UK, 2016).On 28 September, due to a worsening drought situation,the Jubaland authorities appealed for urgent humanitarian interventions in areas near Afmadow, Badhaadhe and Kismayo districts.In Kismayo the arrival of a large number of refugees returning from Dadaab in Kenya is also putting pressure on limited resources available in Kismayo town and IDP settlements (OCHA,2016).
SAF UK will implement the project through 1 mobile team covering the Abdalla Birolle settlement and 2 other fixed site in Farjano.Mobile OTP has been selected in addition to the fixed sites because it will increase access to services, and can cover a wider population compared to a fixed site, also considering the poor health seeking behaviour of the population. The targeted malnourished children aged 6-59 months and PLWs will be screened by screeners supported by CBW. Targeted severe acute malnourished boys and girls will be treated through OTP and followed up by CBWs.Treated uncomplicated SAM cases will be referred to Targeted supplementary feeding programs (TSFP) for continued treatment.Treatment of malnutrition as well as management of common diseases and micro nutrient supplementation for PLW will be conducted alongside promotion of IYCF, with emphasis on exclusive breastfeeding and appropriate complementary feeding by nutrition staff and CBWs .  15 nutrition staff (5 women and 10 men) will be trained on management of acute malnutrition (IMAM) and Infant and young child feeding(IYCF) promotion before they begin work.  20 (9 women and 11men) CBW will be trained on NHHP and community mobilization. 3 Peer support group for mothers with children less than 24 months with severe acute malnutrition, and none respondent cases will be formed,and conducted monthly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdiaziz Hashi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excecutive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254725449441</telephone>
   <email>info@safuk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-22">189886.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-4663">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-22">189886.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302571203">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-29">189886.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
