<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-17/3485/SA2/WASH-Nut-H/NGO/7476</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency Response Team for WASH, Nutrition and Health for crisis affected populations in Deynille and Kaxda camps.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wocca proposes an integrated humanitarian response project to intervene in 15 pre-selected IDP camps in Kaxda and Deynille. Wocca&#x2019;s WASH, Nutrition and health sectors backed up by the protection sector form an integrated emergency response team that plans to uplift the humanitarian conditions of 18,138 drought and crisis affected IDPs (3429 men, 4445 women, 4394 boys and 5870 girls). This project will ensure immediate access to nutrition, WASH and health services. More specifically, our WASH sector will ensure increased, equal and sustained access to safe and appropriate water, sanitation services and hygiene promotion by establishing two water pipes totaling 1272 metres from a borehole outside Kaxda and linking it two strategically located water kiosks which we will construct inside Guryasame /Mandeeq IDP camps with an extension to our proposed fixed nutrition center at Iskaashi IDP camp hence provide more affordable water to the community at a subsidized cost.  To improve sanitation in the IDP camps 80 gender sensitive latrines with hand washing facilities and locks from the inside will be constructed in the targeted schools, camps, and at the nutrition center as well as carry out comprehensive hygiene and sanitation promotion activities including distribution of basic hygiene kits to the most vulnerable households, students and patients discharged from health centers. The nutrition sector will ensure equitable access to quality life-saving nutrition services through systematic identification, referral, and treatment of acutely malnourished cases for PLWs and children under the age of five years by establishing a fixed nutrition center in Iskaashi IDP camp and at the same time run three outreach mobile teams, one for each selected camp areas, kaxda, Deynille and Afgooye corridor roving from one camp to another. Nutrition will emphasize on the following 3 segments:- (1). Community mobilization, to sensitize the population to the problem of malnutrition, how to identify it, in order to reach more children and at an earlier stage in their development of acute malnutrition, therefore increasing program coverage and recovery. Screening of children through assessment of Mid-Upper Arm Circumference (MUAC) and nutritional Oedema, mobilization of key leaders, education and sensitization, promotion of acceptance of the programme by the community and follow up of patients in programs that default or present a problem will constitute the major interventions under the community mobilization segment. -(2). Outpatient care - to treat patients with SAM who have a good appetite and no medical complications through weekly or biweekly distributions of Ready to Use Therapeutic Foods (RUTFs) and routine medicines, medical and nutritional monitoring of the patient. (3). Inpatient care - to treat patients with SAM who have poor appetite and/or medical complications through daily therapeutic milk and medical treatment in inpatient care centre. A referral system will be put in place to transfer patients from one component to the next (when the patient condition worsens), or to return to the previous one if the evolution of treatment is satisfactory. Wocca will also boost access to essential healthcare services in the IDP camps though a referral mechanism to Banadir hospital the doctor and nurses hired for the nutrition centers will provide first aid services and ambulatory services will be provided to Banadir hospital, emphasis will also be given to social mobilization campaigns to educate communities on common health issues and support implementation of community hygiene Promotion for epidemic outbreak Prevention. Wocca already has an ongoing protection project in these IDP camps running case identification, case management, material assistance and referral of victims to health facility, this protection project will complement this proposal and we will make use of the already hired case workers in GBV case management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joseph Mutunga</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">program officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0718 992246</telephone>
   <email>Livelihoods@woccaorg.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Robbert van der Steeg</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0734 775 122</telephone>
   <email>Robbert.vandersteeg@woccaorg.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarah Hassan Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">program officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0714796100</telephone>
   <email>nairobi@woccaorg.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="45" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-08">2465.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-08">297532.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-7476">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-08">299998.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303116750">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-18">179998.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304368543">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-10">96838.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
