<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-20-KG-S-IAA-1213-ISNNADR-5-KG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WMD Commodity Identification Training Instructor Training Workshop + Curriculum Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the global community&apos;s ability to safely destroy, store, apply safeguards to, and transport weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and secure related facilities and materials; control borders and territory to prevent illicit movement of WMD and related materials and technology and to prosecute and punish violators; prevent the proliferation of WMD and related materials, technology, and expertise to states or non-state actors of concern or to potential terrorists; comply fully with international obligations concerning arms control, nonproliferation, and WMD terrorism; deter and prevent WMD terrorism; and respond to a WMD terrorism event.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to strengthen the global community&apos;s ability to safely destroy, store, apply safeguards to, and transport weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and secure related facilities and materials. More specifically, this includes Commodity Identification Training (CIT) Instructor Training workshops seek to build a solid foundation of knowledge in nonproliferation export controls, control lists, and WMD-related dual use commodities and processes; increase the familiarity of trainers with CIT course materials, including delivery of practice presentations; and provide for active discussions of CIT curriculum development, implementation best practices and lessons learned. CIT National Course Development prepares the partner&#x2019;s CIT Working Group to undertake development and implementation of a CIT Program. The workshop lays the foundation for sustainably incorporating a CIT-based curriculum into the partner&#x2019;s regular training regimen and, as such, a critical goal of the workshop is development of a CIT Implementation Plan to guide course development..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Energy - Office on Nonproliferation and Arms Control</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>932010320</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-20" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Energy</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>National Nuclear Security Administration</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-11" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Energy</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>202-586-5000</telephone>
   <email>The.Secretary@hq.doe.gov</email>
   <website>https://energy.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1000 Independence Ave., SW Washington, DC 20585</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="KG">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kyrgyzstan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Kyrgyz Republic continues to consolidate its parliamentary democratic system since a popular revolution in 2010 led to the first democratic transfer of presidential power in Central Asia in 2011. International observers widely heralded the 2015 parliamentary elections as free and fair, further demonstrating the country&apos;s commitment to a democratic system. The presidential election in 2017 will be critical to democratic development, as the country remains fragile and faces myriad challenges, including lack of viable employment opportunities, widespread corruption, weak rule of law and law enforcement sector impunity (especially in terms of treatment of minority groups), a persistent energy deficit, and a deteriorating social service infrastructure. The Kyrgyz Republic needs to address these challenges and demonstrate that democracy can deliver a better quality of life to its citizens. The primary goal of U.S.~assistance programs is to partner with the government and civil society to foster a more stable and prosperous country. U.S.~assistance will focus on economic growth programs that can have a demonstrable impact on people&apos;s lives and provide market-based solutions to address the energy deficit, as well as programs that support continued parliamentary development, judicial reform, and an electoral process that continues to reflect the will of the citizens. U.S.~assistance will fight tuberculosis and support higher education and early-grade reading across the country. U.S.~assistance programs will support greater economic prosperity and promote increased cooperation of the Kyrgyz Republic with other states of Central Asia on economic connectivity, security, and counter-narcotics efforts. U.S.~assistance will also continue to support reforms and tackle corruption in law enforcement structures. U.S. assistance will build resilience and reduce vulnerability to Russian aggression, increase European integration, and provide continued support for enduring programs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-01">88337</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-27">14500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Nuclear Security Administration HQ: Fund Cite</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="1002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2012" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1075">Nonproliferation, Anti-Terrorism, Demining and Related Programs, International Security Assistance, State</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-27">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Nuclear Security Administration HQ: Fund Cite</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="1002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="11330" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
   </sector>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2013-02-15"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
