<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27409</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eurasian Minerals Inc.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eurasian Minerals Inc. (EMX or the Company),  is a TSX Venture Exchange listed junior mining company focused on early stage precious and base metal exploration in northern Haiti and Turkey. EMX also has equity or royalty interests in early stage projects in Eastern Europe and Kyrgyz Republic.  The Haiti prospects (Lamine, La Miel and Grand Bois) fall under a joint venture agreement with Newmont Ventures Limited, a subsidiary of Newmont Mining Corporation. The two main projects in Turkey, Sisorta and Akarca, fall under joint ventures with Chesser Resources Limited and Centerra Gold Inc respectively. Exploration in Haiti started in 2006 and the Company has not yet started drilling. The Company has started drilling at Sisorta and Akarca and has produced initial resource estimates. All EMX projects are early stage exploration and at this time it is not certain or possible to tell if any of the projects will actually proceed to mine development. Development of a mine, if it happens, is not expected to be completed for at least five or more years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed IFC investment in exploration stage projects would not result in any immediate incremental production and the development impacts during this stage are expected to be limited. Local employment in an extremely poor part of Haiti is expected to be the main direct development impact during this phase. Indirectly, the advancement of exploration projects in Haiti could also have a positive impact of attracting additional foreign investments to an underdeveloped but promising sector of the Haiti economy. Because the investment predates advanced exploration and feasibility studies, it is not yet possible to fully quantify or specify the potential development impacts during any possible mine development or production. If continued exploration eventually leads to mine development and production, the development impacts for Haiti could be substantial and include both revenues/foreign exchange contribution to the national economy and development of vital transportation/energy infrastructure that would improve possibilities for other economic activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eurasian Minerals Inc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27409" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-02-19" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-03-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. David M. Cole  President &amp; CEO   Eurasian Minerals Inc.    6624 Willow Broom Trail   Littleton, CO 80125  +1 (303) 979-6666 +1 (303) 973-0715</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haiti</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="HT-Haiti">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EMXs main projects are listed  below:  The Lamine copper exploration project is located in a remote mountainous area 15km south of the Atlantic Ocean and approximately 50km west of the port city of Cap Haitien.   The La Miel gold exploration project is located in a remote mountainous area adjacent to the Haiti-Dominican Republic border, approximately 50 km South of the Atlantic Ocean and 65 km East of Cap Haitien. The Grand Bois gold exploration project is located in a mountainous area 28km southwest of the port city of Cap Haitien, along the highway towards Port au Prince, Haiti.   The Akarca gold exploration project is located in a remote mountainous area in the Bursa province of Western Anatolia, Turkey.  The Sisorta gold exploration project is located in a remote mountainous area in the Sivas Province, in North-Central Turkey.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.0000000000 -72.4166720000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC - Copper</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.30 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-02-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-02-19">10300000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-02-19">10300000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eurasian Minerals Inc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27409/eurasian-minerals-inc">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
