<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-19/HSD20/SA1/H-N/UN/13038</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to integrated essential health and nutrition services for vulnerable communities in newly accessible villages in East Jabal Mara, South Darfur</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aim is to maintain the access to essential life-saving health, nutrition and WASH services and vital public health interventions for very-high vulnerable communities affected by conflict and displacement living in East Jabal Mara from the side of South Darfur State. The direct health service delivery through maintaining the functionality of the recently operationalized 7 public health facilities to cover around 242,000 IDPs and conflict affected communities. Intermittent access in targeted areas that were not accessible for several years had been obtained at the beginning of 2018. Through SHF (March 2018) WHO had initiated the re-activation of public health services through 7 clinics, including 1 Stabilization Centers (SCs) in Dirba. The heath facilities and the SC had been rehabilitated (basic repairs) and staff availability along with essential medicines and registration including SAM treatment protocol availability ensured. The present request for funding is to ensure the continuity of health, nutrition and WASH services addressing the pressing needs for high rates of malnutrition, and basic services delivery. There are no NGOs (except NIDO supported by WHO) and full hand over of responsibilities to the MOH in the present context of social unrest, economic crisis and disruption of public services is not feasible. Without continuation of support the services will be immediately discontinued. The project activities initiated in March 2018 were jointly agreed and planned with health and nutrition federal and state ministry of health, and the local communities. They are in line with sectors priorities and SHF allocation strategy. The implementation of some activities will be done through sub-granting to NIDO  (a WHO partner in the area present in one of the 7 targeted villages) and the state MOH.  The Deribat PHCC  stabilization center established by the WHO will continue to be supported to ensure the continuity of the management of Sever Acute Malnutrition (SAM) inpatient care. The functionality of seven clinics re-activated in the area will be continued with the provision of medical supplies, incentives for the medical staff and on the job coaching. The availability of qualified medical staff (including a doctor in Diribat) proved essential to ensure that the alerts of outbreaks are immediately investigated and response initiated before the joint state RRT team (MOH and WHO) are able to reach. The provision of free-of charge health services and medicines will be continued ensuring access to essential emergency health care for targeted population mainly composed of IDPs, returnees and host communities. The expansion of emergency health information system and public health early warning alert response systems (EWARS) in emergency for prompt identification and timely response to emergencies are critical for preventing the avoidable mortality and morbidity amongst targeted communities. The training of states&#x2019; and locality Rapid Response Teams (RRT) in charge of assessment and initial response to acute events such as outbreaks alert investigation and initial response was completed by WHO. Through the new request the operational support for investigation missions will be continued.  
The first ever stabilization center  (Liba SC) in Deribat area of East Jebel Mara locality in South Darfur state was established through previous funding and WHO will continue to support the staff availability, medical supplies and transport of nutritional supplies provided by UNICEF&#xAC;. The inpatient case load during 2018 is 320 living in East Jabal Mara locality . WHO will provide the required medicines and medical equipment and expansion of the inpatient area with one room  for the stabilization center.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yosif Mohamed Goma</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00249912178491</telephone>
   <email>gomaay@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.64886390 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-20">178264.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-20">321719.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-13038">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-20">499983.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SUD_2019_1000088">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-21">499983.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
