<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Administration and Control</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Accountable Entity&apos;s, the Millennium Challenge Account (MCA) Morocco, administrative costs, which include staff salaries, financial audits, and fiscal and procurement agent fees.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Morocco</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-09-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-ARTISN FEZ" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-ENTRPS SUP" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-FNCIAL SVS" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-FRUIT TREE" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0017" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0021" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0031" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0049" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0131" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN-0214" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-MAR-2750BXCOMD-SMALL FISH" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Delivery of a complete, correct and fully executed CIF Disbursement Request for the relevant CIF Disbursement Period.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">10) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after July 31, 2008, the Government shall have established a bid challenge system acceptable to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11) Submission to and approval by, MCC of a CIF Financial Plan and Quarterly Financial Report</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12) A CIF Procurement Plan, approved by MCC, is currently in force.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">13) Proof, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, that all Compact Implementation Funding shall be free from Taxes as anticipated by Section 2.7 of the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">14) Prior to each CIF Disbursement, MCA-Morocco shall ensure that an interim Environmental and Social Impact (ESI) director has been selected and remains engaged until a permanent ESI director is hired.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">15) With respect to any CIF Disbursement, MCC is satisfied, in its sole discretion, that the Government has committed funds for the initial census of occupants at Place Lalla Ydouna and for the urgent preliminary works during the CIF period at the Makina and the fondouks, as required under Paragraph D.7 of Annex I to the Compact.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">16) The Government shall cause the appropriate governmental ministry or body to issue one or more tax exemption letter(s) (or other appropriate documentary evidence) to the Accountable Entity evidencing such exemption from Taxes, as promptly as possible and in no event later than the date of the initial Disbursement of Compact Implementation Funding.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">17) Within ninety (90) days after the Effective Date of this Agreement, the Government will provide to MCC written evidence, satisfactory to MCC, of the existence of specific operational procedures the Government will use to ensure that each Tax MCC identifies in writing is not applied to the Section 2.7 Items, along with a description of the legal basis for Government use of such procedures.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2) MCC is satisfied, in its sole discretion, that (a) the activity being funded by such CIF Disbursement is necessary, advisable or is otherwise consistent with the goal of facilitating the implementation of the Compact, (b) there has been no violation of, and the use of requested funds for purposes requested will not violate, the limitations on use or treatment of Compact Implementation Funding, and (c) MCA-Morocco and the Government will have substantially complied with its obligations and covenants as set forth in the CIF Agreement (including all covenants set forth in Attachment II).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after March 15, 2008 MCA-Morocco is fully formed and in good standing under the laws of Morocco.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after April 15, 2008, MCC is satisfied, in its sole discretion, that MCA-Morocco is sufficiently mobilized (including, without limitation, having hired all key personnel as identified by MCC) in order for MCA-Morocco to be able to fully perform the obligations of MCA-Morocco as described in the CIF Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after sixty (60) days after MCA-Morocco is fully formed and in good standing under the laws of Morocco, a Bank Agreement has been executed and delivered by MCA-Morocco and TGR, and is in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed by MCC, and no material default has occurred or is continuing there under.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">6) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after sixty (60) days after MCA-Morocco is fully formed and in good standing under the laws of Morocco, MCA-Morocco has executed and delivered to MCC a contract with an individual to act as the chief financial officer of MCA-Morocco, which individual is subject to MCC approval and which contract must be in full force and effect and in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">7) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after thirty (60) days after MCA-Morocco is fully formed and in good standing under the laws of Morocco, a Fiscal Agent Agreement, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, has been signed by MCA-Morocco and a fiscal agent acceptable to MCC, and is in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed by MCC, and no material default has occurred or is continuing there under.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">8) With respect to any CIF Disbursement on or after July 31, 2008, a Procurement Agent Agreement, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, has been signed by MCA-Morocco and a procurement agent acceptable to MCC, and is in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed by MCC, and no material default has occurred or is continuing there under.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9) Prior to the deposit of any CIF Disbursement into the Permitted Account in accordance with an approved CIF Disbursement Request, MCC will have received satisfactory evidence of the establishment of the Permitted Account.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
