<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-585-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004262-MOU</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-585" secondary-reporter="0" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Centre for Migration Policy Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIGNING OF A MEMORANDUM OF UNDERSTANDING BETWEEN NIGER - ANLTP AND NIGERIA - NAPTIP ON COUNTERING TRAFFICKING IN PERSONS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MoU signing ceremony took place on 16 November 20215 hosted by the Nigeria Ministry of Foreign Affairs and well attended by over 70 individuals drawn from a cross session of the diplomatic community in Abuja after a Note Verbal inviting all members was sent by the ministry on behalf of the project.6 The signing was executed by both parties represented by the Director General of the ANLTP-TIM for Niger and the Director General of NAPTIP for the Nigeria side after series of goodwill messages were delivered by a roll-call of dignitaries including the representative of the distinguished Ambassador of the Netherlands.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004262-MOU" crs-channel-code="11000" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch MFA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004262-MOU" ref="XM-OCHA-585" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Centre for Migration Policy Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIGER - NIGERIA

REPORT OF THE SIGNING CEREMONY OF A MEMORADUM OF UNDERSTNDING BETWEEN THE FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF NIGERIA AND THE REPUBLIC OF NIGER ON STRENGTHENING CROSS-BORDER COOPERATION IN COMBATING TRAFFICKING IN PERSONS

Introduction
The process that culminated into the signing of a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) between Nigeria and Niger on strengthening cooperation in the fight against TiP began 16 to 18 April 2019, when ICMPD organized a first meeting between ANLTP/TIM of Niger and NAPTIP of Nigeria under the framework of the EU funded project FMM West Africa.  The aim of that meeting was to facilitate cooperation between the two institutions for better management of cross border trafficking in persons. At the end of the discussions, the two Directors General issued a communiqu&#xE9;,  calling for a series of short, medium and long-term actions including the signing of a bilateral agreement/ Memorandum of Understanding as well as the implementation of joint activities. 

The Netherlands is funding the ICMPD-led cooperation initiative between NAPTIP and ANLTP-TIM in a project titled: Strengthening Nigeria - Niger Cooperation on Countering Trafficking in Human Beings (NG-NR Project). The aim is to foster operational collaboration between the Governments of Nigeria and Niger through the instrumentality of a Joint Technical Working Group (JTWG) responsible for identifying common priorities and implementing joint coordinated interventions. The JTWG will identify and agree on minimum standard operating procedures pertaining to the management of cross border trafficking cases. The signing of a bilateral agreement between the two countries is critical to the proper functioning of all joint operations between the agencies (ANLTP and NAPTIP), providing a formal framework for cooperation.

At the launch of the NG-NR Project and during the field study for the project baseline assessment, a trip was organized to Agadez  given its importance as a transit route for victims of trafficking (VoT). The mission team visited local communities where migrants live; and majority of the people encountered were young Nigeria women and children. The field visit involved officials of both Nigeria and Niger who were members of the Joint Technical Working Group newly inaugurated during the project launch. Since the project inauguration, there had been a series of joint activities and consultations aimed at increasing the operational interface between the two lead agencies responsible for the execution of the MoU, i.e. ANLTP from the Niger side and NAPTIP from the Nigeria side. 

Context
Niger and Nigeria share a border of about 1500 kilometres. The communities living around these borders maintain relations based on economic, social and religious dimensions. However, the communities are also witnesses as well as victims of several forms of cross-border crimes, including terrorism. Communities located along the borders are affected by the smuggling of different counterfeit products, illicit firearms trafficking, smuggling of migrants, trafficking in persons as well as insurgency of terrorist groups.

Nigerians and citizens of other sub-Saharan African countries (economic migrants, refugees, asylum seekers, victims of trafficking) transit through Niger, to Algeria and Libya, and for some of them to Italy and Europe. Although majority of the migrants are men and boys, more and more young women and girls are being identified in Niger. For some time now, female migration has not receive as much attention in research as much as men. Today, female migration, as much as that of men, is a reality and a prioritised topic for analysis by the scientific community, particularly due to the observation of the evolution of the status of women in various west-African societies and their significant contribution to the purchasing power of their families in their countries of origin.

Niger is host country to many nationals of the West-African sub-region, and particularly many Nigerians. Numerous reports and testimonies received from Niger confirm that Nigerians remain the majority of migrants cared for or found in Niger. In most cases, migrant women and girls are victims of trafficking for sexual exploitation, others are sexually exploited, and others are involved in sex work/ prostitution in ghettos, brothels, during their transit in Niger. For many women and girls, this situation can last several years until they have gathered enough money to free themselves from their traffickers.

The Nigerien authorities have limited resources to take care of the flow of migrants who find themselves stranded in Niger, having run out of money to continue their journey. In most situations, the Niger officials are obliged to turn to international and humanitarian organisations, particularly IOM, to help take care of migrants, ensure their return, and support reintegration in their countries of origin.

Niger is facing many challenges to care for these vulnerable migrants, returned from Algeria and Libya, often victims of trafficking, and who stay in transit cities like Agadez, Arlit and Dirkou. Cases of sexual exploitation are detected in brothels, or situations of forced labour in ghettos. Children are also victims of all forms of exploitation, and are victims of stigmatisation by local communities.

The International Centre for Migration Policy Development (ICMPD) organised a series of consultations and capacity building workshop for criminal justice practitioners in Niger. Through the technical support of ICMPD a national referral mechanism for victims of trafficking in Niger was developed. This mechanism is an agreement between all actors for a comprehensive assistance and/or the reintegration of identified or potential victims of trafficking, with a clear division of roles and responsibilities for each of the actors.
On the Nigerian side, ICMPD also supported the Nigerian anti-trafficking actors and particularly the Nigerian National Agency for Prohibition of Trafficking in Persons (NAPTIP), through a programme to strengthen the training resources of the agency.

Consultations with the Niger authorities indicated that substantial efforts in international cooperation should be carried out, particularly with neighbouring countries like Nigeria, whose nationals are the most numerous, especially amongst victims of trafficking identified within Niger&#x2019;s borders. The Nigerian authorities also acknowledge the need to set up a collaborative platform between the two countries to better address different issues in relation with the prosecution of traffickers as well as the caring for vulnerable groups, in particular victims of trafficking on both sides of the border.

Hence, the need for cooperation between the authorities of Niger and Nigeria; to share information and good practices; to facilitate criminal justice cooperation, to investigate and dismantle criminal networks; and to aid and protect victims of trafficking as well as migrants in situation of vulnerability. When conditions are right, a safe return of victims to their homes in Nigeria, and in partnership with the civil society, through a transnational referral mechanism can be organized.

MoU Signing Ceremony
On 15 November 2021, a workshop was organized to review the MoU by participants from both the Nigerian as well as the Nigerien sides, including civil society organizations . On the same day, the 3rd JTWG meeting was held to discuss the activities of the JTWG since the last meeting, to plan new activities, and to setup subcommittees.  The MoU signing ceremony took place on 16 November 2021  hosted by the Nigeria Ministry of Foreign Affairs and well attended by over 70 individuals drawn from a cross session of the diplomatic community in Abuja after a Note Verbal inviting all members was sent by the ministry on behalf of the project.  The signing was executed by both parties represented by the Director General of the ANLTP-TIM for Niger and the Director General of NAPTIP for the Nigeria side after series of goodwill messages were delivered by a roll-call of dignitaries including the representative of the distinguished Ambassador of the Netherlands.  Other distinguished Ambassadors who delivered goodwill messages included the Ambassadors of Italy, Japan, Vietnam, Rwanda and Namibia, a representative of FIIAPP was also present at the signing. The visiting delegation from Niger included officials of the National Agency for the Fight against Human Trafficking; magistrates specialized in the fight against terrorism, officials of the Police/DST, a representative of the Office of Criminal Mutual Assistance and Judicial Collaboration, and representatives of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs as well as representative of the Niger Embassy in Abuja.

In his welcome remarks, the Director of Legal and Consular department, representing the Hon. Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Nigeria MFA expressed his deep appreciation to the diplomatic community for honouring the invitation to witness the event. In the same light, the NAPTIP DG noted the openness demonstrated by the delegation from Niger particularly during 3rd Joint Technical Working Group consultation process leading up to the validation of the draft MoU. In response, the DG ANLTP reiterated Niger&#x2019;s commitment to cooperate with its Nigerian counterpart in the fight against trafficking in persons. For ICMPD, the MoU signing was an achievement that signified the strong partnership it has with both countries.

The delegates where hosted to a private meeting by the Nigerian Minister of State for Foreign Affairs where on behalf the Government of Nigeria, he promised to advocate for resources to be made available for the implementation of the provisions of the MoU.
&#x2003;
Scope of the MoU
The MoU with its preamble and 18 articles outlines the key areas of cooperation to guide the activities of the Joint Technical Working Group (JTWG) set-up for the joint implementation of its provisions. The scope applies to the prevention and detection of trafficking in persons, protection, repatriation and rehabilitation of victims, in particular women and children, in the territories of the two countries. It has three objectives:
i.	Develop a common front to prevent and fight eradicating trafficking in women and children by sharing information and raising awareness in the two countries.
ii.	Protect, rehabilitate and reintegrate victims of trafficking in their environment of origin.
iii.	Promote friendly cooperation between the parties in order to achieve these objectives.

Conclusion
ICMPD will work with both parties to ensure that the provisions of the MoU are well implemented, including sourcing for additional funding to support the project beyond the funding period provided by the Netherlands. It is certain that COVID19 will further aggravate the problem of cross border TiP and reduce the ability of states to respond adequately to TiP issues. Nigerian victims count will continue to rise in transit cities such as Agadez, hence increasing the need to strengthen Niger Nigeria cooperation. 
The logical next step for this project is to develop a comprehensive repatriation program of Nigerians stranded in Niger who may not fit into the categories supported by the Assisted Voluntary Return and Reintegration (AVRR) programs, even though they may be willing to return.

Visibility

TV Reporting
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1taxGPfcVAM
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvfDckcxwHs

TV repoting with panel discussions
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JHBWMQ4HcpM
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dINhN6_bvYg

Newspaper Reporting
https://www.vanguardngr.com/2021/11/nigeria-niger-republic-move-to-tackle-human-trafficking/
https://www.theheritagetimes.com/nigeria-niger-sign-mou-on-eliminating-human-trafficking/

Twitter Posts
https://twitter.com/icmpdwestafrica/status/1460539174562537472?s=21
https://twitter.com/icmpdwestafrica/status/1460549161888231429?s=21</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <telephone>+43150446770</telephone>
   <email>ICMPDAbuja@icmpd.org</email>
   <website>https://www.icmpd.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <telephone>+43150446770</telephone>
   <email>icmpdabuja@icmpd.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15190" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
