<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27676</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Jacinto</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Help lower Nicaraguas dependence on thermal power:  Currently, renewable sources account for less than 30% of Nicaraguas effective installed generation capacity.  The successful completion of the Project will provide clean, low-cost power generated from a renewable resource to meet close to 20% of current power demand and allow for the possible retirement of old, inefficient and expensive thermal capacity. 

Development of Nicaraguas geothermal resources: To address the countrys current energy challenges, the Government of Nicaragua (GON) has put forth a strategy to develop its domestic renewable energy resources, including geothermal power.  Successful completion of the first large-scale greenfield private sector-led geothermal projects in Nicaragua would contribute directly, as well as indirectly through demonstration effect, to this objective.

Climate change: The Project is expected to displace thermal power generation, hence reducing the regions carbon emissions by approximately 361,901 tCO2 per annum (after project emissions of 39,167 tCO2 per annum).

Supporting the financial sustainability of the power sector: The Project will reduce Nicaraguas wholesale energy prices and dependence on oil, supporting the power sectors path towards financial sustainability.

Cost Efficiency:  The Project will help lower the cost of electricity and therefore help support a lower cost structure for industries and consumers in Nicaragua.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris Energy Nicaragua S.A. (PENSA, or the Company) owns the San Jacinto-Tizate geothermal concession covering a 40 km2 area near Le&#xF3;n, Nicaragua, that is estimated to have a geothermal resource of more than 200 MW capacity.  Since 2005, under the concession, PENSA has owned and operated 10MW generation capacity comprised of 2 x 5MW back-pressure turbines (B/P units).

The Company is in the process of expanding its operations by adding another 72MW of capacity through 2 x 36MW Fuji flash turbines supported by further steam resource development, after which the original less efficient B/P units will be decommissioned (the Project).  As is often the case with integrated (comprising both steam field and power plant) geothermal power plants, financing for the Project is being divided into phases to match the ramp up of geothermal development and the progress of construction.  For this project, financing for the Project is being divided in Phase I and Phase II that each correspond to 36MW addition of capacity to the Companys operations.  IFC has been asked to consider providing financing for Phase II.

The Project will utilize geothermal resources from a smaller area within the larger concession (Eastern Sector), which has been in development since the 1950s by various parties and is estimated to contain a geothermal resource sufficient for the Project.  The Company has been and will continue to sell its output to two utilities, both of which are subsidiaries of Union Fenosa, a large Spanish utility, under power purchase agreements (PPAs) whose term end in 2029.  The Company has deployed a group of the worlds leading contractors/suppliers to complement its own substantial in-house geothermal expertise: ThermaSource of the US in drilling, Construtora Queiroz Galvao of Brazil in construction, and Fuji Electric of Japan in turbine supply.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris Energy Nicaragua, S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27676" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-08-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greg Cardenas
Vice President Project Finance, Latin America 
POLARIS ENERGY NICARAGUA S.A.775.772.0904 
Email: gcardenas@ram-power.com | Website: www.ram-power.comc/o 6880 S. McCarran Blvd., Suite 1| Reno | Nevada 89509</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nicaragua</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="NI-Nicaragua">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is located 20 kilometers east of Le&#xF3;n.  The 40 square kilometer concession area is uninhabited, save for sparse subsistence farming in some peripheral areas.  The nearest village to the Projects site is San Jacinto, which is a small settlement adjacent to the base camp.  The project site has been under development for several years, and currently houses the existing B/P units and steam field development.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0000000000 -85.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BE - Geothernal - Renewable Energy Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $60.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-11-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-11-04">60000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-11-04">60000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris Energy Nicaragua, S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27676/san-jacinto">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
