<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012431-01-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SECURING CRITICAL WASH SERVICES WITHIN INFORMAL SETTLEMENTS AND IN RESPONSE TO COVID-19 OUTBREAK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il Libano &#xE8; attualmente caratterizzato da molteplici crisi, la cui azione congiunta ha provocato un progressivo aumento della vulnerabilit&#xE0; della popolazione locale e rifugiata, nonch&#xE9; delle istituzioni nazionali. Uno dei principali fattori di crisi &#xE8; costituito dalla presenza protratta di un numero ingente di rifugiati provenienti dalla Siria, la cui vulnerabilit&#xE0; &#xE8; ulteriormente aumentata a partire dal 2020, anche a causa dell&#x2019;aggravarsi della crisi finanziaria ed economica in Libano e delle conseguenze dell&#x2019;epidemia di COVID-19. L&#x2019;iniziativa oggetto della presente Proposta di finanziamento prevede un contributo all&#x2019;UNICEF di euro 1,5 M per la realizzazione di attivit&#xE0; finalizzate a garantire l&#x2019;accesso al diritto all&#x2019;acqua e a un ambiente salubre ai rifugiati siriani negli insediamenti informali, nonch&#xE9; all&#x2019;attuazione del Piano nazionale di risposta all&#x2019;epidemia di COVID-19. L&#x2019;iniziativa contribuisce al raggiungimento dell&#x2019;obiettivo strategico n. 2 del Lebanon Crisis Response Plan 2017-21 e all&#x2019;attuazione del Pilastro 6 (Infection Prevention Control) del Piano nazionale di risposta all&#x2019;epidemia di COVID-19. Le attivit&#xE0; previste comprendono l&#x2019;erogazione di servizi WASH (acqua e igiene) all&#x2019;interno degli insediamenti informali che ospitano i rifugiati siriani e nei centri di isolamento che ricevono casi sospetti o confermati di COVID-19. L&#x2019;iniziativa sar&#xE0; realizzata da UNICEF con il concorso di ONG nazionali e internazionali con precedente esperienza specifica.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon is characterized by multiple crises, which have increased the vulnerability of the local and refugee population, as well as of national institutions. One of the main factors is the protracted presence of a large number of refugees from Syria, whose vulnerability has further increased since 2020, also due to the financial and economic crisis in Lebanon and the consequences of the COVID-19 epidemic. The financial contribution to UNICEF allows the implementation of activities aimed at assuring access to water and a healthy environment for Syrian refugees in informal settlements, as well as the implementation of the National Response Plan to the COVID-19 epidemic. The programme contributes to the achievement of strategic objective no. 2 of the Lebanon Crisis Response Plan 2017-21 and the implementation of Pillar 6 (Infection Prevention Control) of the National Response Plan to the COVID-19 epidemic. The planned activities include the provision of WASH services within the informal settlements for Syrian refugees and within the isolation centers for suspected or confirmed COVID-19cases. The programme is implemented by UNICEF in partnership with national and international NGOs with previous specific experience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41122" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41122" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41122" ref="XM-DAC-41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - FONDO DELLE NAZIONI UNITE PER L&apos;INFANZIA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012431/01/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-25">1500000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-41122" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - FONDO DELLE NAZIONI UNITE PER L&apos;INFANZIA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-07">1500000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-41122" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - FONDO DELLE NAZIONI UNITE PER L&apos;INFANZIA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
