<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRAT &#x2013; Balkan Route: a welcoming transit</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto &#x201C;BRAT &#x2013; Balkan Route: Accoglienza in Transito&#x201D; si occupa del fenomeno migratorio in Bosnia e 
Erzegovina (BiH). BRAT &#xE8; una iniziativa triennale proposta da IPSIA (capofila) in ATS con Caritas Italiana e Croce 
Rossa Italiana, e avente come partner locali l&#x2019;associazione EMMAUS, Caritas BiH, e la Societ&#xE0; di Croce Rossa 
della BiH. 
La BiH &#xE8; attraversata dai flussi migratori lungo la Rotta Balcanica fin dal 2018. In questi anni il paese non &#xE8; 
riuscito a proporre efficaci politiche di gestione del fenomeno, n&#xE8; a mettere in piedi un adeguato sistema di 
accoglienza. Le istituzioni bosniaco-erzegovesi a livello nazionale e locale hanno finora organizzato 6 Campi di 
Transito per l&#x2019;accoglienza, con 5.000 posti letto complessivi, nei quali le condizioni sono molto precarie e non in 
linea con gli standard internazionali. Rimane inoltre ancora senza sistemazione un numero molto elevato di 
migranti (stimato in circa 3.000 persone) costretti a ripari improvvisati in squat, fabbriche abbandonate, rifugi 
nei boschi. Le condizioni di accoglienza dei migranti in BiH sono dunque estremamente preoccupanti, e 
sfociano ciclicamente in vere e proprie crisi umanitarie - come ad esempio la recente emergenza al campo di 
Lipa nel gennaio 2021. 
Questa situazione cos&#xEC; problematica &#xE8; causata da una molteplicit&#xE0; di fattori, che si possono riassumere in: 1. 
Debolezza istituzionale del paese in generale e della gestione della migrazione in particolare; 2. Malesse 
psicologico diffuso tra le diverse fasce della popolazione migrante; 3. Scarsit&#xE0; di accesso all&#x2019;assistenza sanitaria 
per i migranti stessi; 4. Carenza formativa degli operatori delle organizzazioni e istituzioni che si occupano di 
migrazione; 5. Atteggiamento ostile della popolazione locale verso i migranti. 
Il progetto BRAT vuole dunque intervenire a livello politico, culturale ed operativo, per contribuire a facilitare 
una migrazione ordinata, sicura e responsabile in BiH (obiettivo generale del progetto &#x2013; in linea con il target 
10.7 degli SDGs). E&#x2019; necessario cio&#xE8; introdurre nuove politiche, nuove narrazioni e nuove strutture per rendere 
la gestione del fenomeno nel paese piu sostenibile, efficace e in linea con gli standard internazionali. 
BRAT interverr&#xE0; nelle 3 aree del paese maggiormente interessate dal flusso migratorio: il Cantone di Tuzla, il 
Cantone di Sarajevo e il Cantone di Una Sana al confine con la Croazia. In queste aree il progetto si pone 
l&#x2019;obiettivo specifico di potenziare e diversificare i servizi di accoglienza per i migranti, migliorandone le 
condizioni sanitarie e psicologiche e favorendo la creazione di relazioni con la comunit&#xE0; di accoglienza. 
Per raggiungere tale obiettivo, viene proposta una strategia multilivello e multisettoriale, che prevede l&#x2019;utilizzo 
di vari strumenti: 
- a livello operativo: migliorando le condizioni all&#x2019;interno dei Campi di Transito (potenziamento dei Servizi 
Psicosociali in 4 Campi) e rafforzando le tutele per chi &#xE8; costretto a vivere all&#x2019;esterno dei campi (fornitura di 
Servizi sanitari di base). Il progetto avvier&#xE0; inoltre prassi innovative di accoglienza, in particolare i Servizi in 
comunit&#xE0; per i migranti piu vulnerabili (3 Safe Houses e 3 Centri diurni); - a livello politico e formativo: tramite azioni di Advocacy e tramite percorsi di formazione (Trainings e Study 
visits), BRAT vuole accrescere le competenze degli stakeholders nazionali e locali incaricati di gestire il 
fenomeno migratorio, oltre che introdurre nuove strategie decisionali che rispondano meglio alle sfide poste 
da questo tipo di migrazione nel territorio - facendo leva sulle buone prassi e sulle competenze sviluppate 
dai partner nel loro pluriennale lavoro di accoglienza in Italia; 
- a livello culturale e di opinione pubblica: BRAT aumenter&#xE0; le occasioni di conoscenza tra le comunit&#xE0; 
ospitanti e le comunit&#xE0; migranti tramite diversi Eventi di incontro; migliorer&#xE0; la narrazione rispetto ai 
fenomeni migratori con una specifica Campagna</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &#x201C;BRAT &#x2013; Balkan Route: a Welcoming Transit&#x201D; deals with the migration process in Bosnia and 
Herzegovina (BiH). BRAT is a 3-years initiative proposed by IPSIA (lead applicant) in partnership with Caritas 
Italiana and Italian Red Cross, and with the involvement of the local partners: association EMMAUS, Caritas BiH, 
and the Red Cross Society BiH. 
BiH is involved in the migration flow along the Balkan Route since 2018. In those years, the country was not able 
to propose efficient policies on migration nor to establish and adequate system for the hospitality of the 
migrants. The BiH institutions, both at national and local level, opened so far 6 Transit Camps for the hospitality, 
with an overall number of 5.000 beds available; the conditions within the Camps are extremely poor and not in 
line with the international standards. Moreover, there is still a large number of migrants (estimated in 3.000 
people) without accommodation, forced to sleep in squats, abandoned buildings, or even in the forest. The 
conditions for the accommodation of the migrants in BiH are extremely worrying, and they lead to cyclical 
humanitarian crisis &#x2013; such as the recent emergency situation at Lipa camp, in January 2021. 
This problematic scenario is produced by several factors, which can be summarized in: 1. Institutional 
weakness of the country, both in general and in the specific migration sector; 2. Largely spread psychological 
distress among the migrants; 3. Limited access to health care for the migrants; 4. Lack of competences among 
the staff of the institutions and organizations dealing with migration; 5. Hostile attitude of the local population 
towards the migrants. 
The project BRAT aims at impacting at political, cultural and operational levels, in order to contribute in 
facilitating a migration process in BiH that is better managed, safer and more responsible (general objective of the project &#x2013; in line with the target 10.7 of the SDGs). It is necessary to introduce in BiH new policies, new 
storytelling and new structures to make the management of the migration flow more sustainable, more efficient 
and more in line with the international standards. 
BRAT will be implemented in the 3 regions of the country most involved in the migration flow: Tuzla Canton, 
Sarajevo Canton, and Una Sana Canton at the border with Croatia. In those regions, the project has the specific 
objective to strengthen and diversify the accommodation services for the migrants, to improve the health and 
psychological conditions, and to promote better relationships between migrants and local communities. 
To achieve such a goal, a multi-level and multi-sector strategy will be in place, which can benefit from several 
instruments: 
- at operational level: improvement of the conditions within the Transit Camps (by strengthening the 
Psychosocial Services in 4 Camps) and of the protection for the people forced to live out of the camps (by 
providing Basic healthcare services). The project will also develop new hospitality experiences, in particular 
the Community-based Services for the most vulnerable migrants (3 Safe Houses and 3 Daily Centers); 
- at political and educational level: BRAT aims at improving the competences of the national and local 
stakeholders dealing with migration issues, through Advocacy actions and Educational programs (Trainings 
and Study visits). It will also introduce new decision-making strategies which can better respond to all the 
challenges created by this migration flow in the country, inspired by the good practices and the competences 
developed by the partners (through their long-term experience with the migration in Italy); 
- at cultural and public opinion level: BRAT will increase the number of opportunities for local and migrant 
communities to meet each other through several Events; it will improve the perception of the public opinion 
toward the migration through a specific Awareness Campaign;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/02/7" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitate orderly, safe, regular and responsible migration and mobility of people, including through the implementation of planned and well-managed migration policies</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce inequality within and among countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-09">3600000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">2160000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPSIA - ISTITUTO PACE, SVILUPPO, INNOVAZIONE ACLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
