<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASTE or RESOURCE? &#x2013; Enterprises and municipalities&#x2019;  environmental and social responsibility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;iniziativa &#x201C;RIFIUTO o RISORSA? - Responsabilit&#xE0; ambientale e sociale di municipalit&#xE0; e imprese&#x201D;, che durer&#xE0; 
36 mesi, &#xE8; stata proposta da CELIM insieme a Cesvi e Oxfam Italia, quali membri mandanti dell&#x2019;ATS, Oxfam GB, 
Ingegneria senza Frontiera Milano e Politecnico di Milano, quali partner internazionali o italiani, e le 
Municipalit&#xE0; di Hasbaya e Chebaa, come partner locali. 
Il progetto ha l&#x2019;obiettivo generale di contribuire a ridurre l&apos;impatto negativo su salute e ambiente dato 
dall&#x2019;inquinamento e dalla contaminazione di aria, suolo e acqua in Libano, in conformit&#xE0; con l&#x2019;OSS 3.9. Si 
prevede di avere tale impatto, sviluppando in 3 anni modelli di responsabilit&#xE0; ambientale e sociale con 
particolare riferimento alla gestione dei rifiuti solidi urbani nel Governatorato di Nabathiye e del Sud per 
12 municipalit&#xE0; e 20 MPMI e un totale di 42.056 beneficiari diretti (obiettivo specifico). 
Questo obiettivo verr&#xE0; conseguito grazie al raggiungimento di 3 risultati: il sistema di raccolta, il trattamento e 
lo smaltimento dei rifiuti solidi sono migliorati in 12 municipalit&#xE0; nel distretto di Hasbaya (R1; R2); produttivit&#xE0;, 
innovazione, produzione e consumo sostenibili e creazione di posti di lavoro dignitoso sono promossi per 20 
MPMI nelle filiere dei rifiuti nei distretti di Hasbaya, Saida e Tiro (R3).
R1: per rispondere al problema di una raccolta differenziata insufficiente e, dove esistente, di scarsa qualit&#xE0;, si 
introdurr&#xE0; un sistema di gestione di raccolta differenziata a Hasbaya e Chebaa, le due cittadine pi&#xF9; grandi del 
distretto, e si revisioner&#xE0; il piano di raccolta differenziata gi&#xE0; presente a Rashaya Al Foukhar. I nuovi piani 
verranno co-progettati, implementati e monitorati, assicurandosi sia un&#x2019;adeguata formazione tecnica e 
gestionale sia la fornitura di veicoli e contenitori. Affinch&#xE9; i sistemi di raccolta differenziata funzionino, si 
progetter&#xE0; e implementer&#xE0; una campagna informativa e di sensibilizzazione per la corretta separazione e 
conferimento dei rifiuti a livello domestico e commerciale. Infine, si elaboreranno e presenteranno piani di 
raccolta differenziata e organizzeranno formazioni peer to peer per le 9 municipalit&#xE0; non coinvolte 
nell&#x2019;implementazione del servizio per assicurarsi che abbiano tutti gli strumenti per implementare i piani.
R2: per migliorare il trattamento dei rifiuti, attualmente insufficiente, si realizzeranno 3 centri di compostaggio 
a Hasbaya, Chebaa e Rashaya Al Foukhar e 2 centri di separazione dei riciclabili a Hasbaya e Chebaa. I centri 
verranno progettati, costruiti ed equipaggiati con i macchinari necessari; si formeranno poi gli operatori a livello 
tecnico e gestionale e si svilupper&#xE0; un modello di gestione e un sistema di monitoraggio del funzionamento dei 
centri; verr&#xE0; infine istituito un fondo di dotazione per l&#x2019;avvio dei centri di Hasbaya e Chebaa. Per migliorare lo 
smaltimento dei rifiuti, che ad oggi &#xE8; inadeguato, si mitigheranno gli impatti ambientali delle discariche a cielo 
aperto esistenti a Hasbaya, Chebaa e Rashaya Al Foukhar: si conterranno e copriranno i rifiuti gi&#xE0; presenti per 
poi predisporre nuovi lotti e piani per la disposizione controllata dei rifiuti indifferenziati; gli operatori delle 
discariche verranno formati e monitorati perch&#xE9; implementino correttamente le nuove procedure ed analisi 
verranno svolte per valutare gli impatti ambientali. Infine, si elaboreranno e presenteranno piani di trattamento 
e smaltimento per le 9 municipalit&#xE0; non coinvolte nell&#x2019;implementazione dei servizi e si organizzeranno incontri 
formativi e di scambio tra le municipalit&#xE0;.
R3: per rispondere a sistemi di produzione limitati e inquinanti, caratterizzati da scarsit&#xE0; di investimenti 
sostenibili, le 20 MPMI selezionate saranno supportate economicamente con tre esborsi di contributi monetari, 
subordinati ad un processo di selezione e verifica di fattibilit&#xE0; dei piani di sviluppo e business da esse elaborati.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &#x201C;WASTE or RESOURCE? &#x2013; Enterprises and municipalities&#x2019; environmental and social responsibility&#x201D;, 
which will last 36 months, was proposed by CELIM together with Cesvi and Oxfam Italia, as ATS members, 
Oxfam GB, Ingegneria senza Frontiera Milano e Politecnico di Milano, as international or Italian partners, and 
the Municipalities of Hasbaya and Chebaa, as local partners.
The project has the overall objective of contributing in reducing the negative impact on health and the 
environment caused by air, soil and water pollution and contamination in Lebanon, in accordance with SDG 
3.9. This impact will be reached developing, in 3 years, models of environmental and social responsibility with 
particular reference to the management of municipal solid waste in the Governorate of Nabathiye and the 
South for 12 municipalities and 20 MSMEs and a total of 42,056 direct beneficiaries (specific objective).
This objective will be achieved thanks to the accomplishment of 3 results: the solid waste collection, treatment 
and disposal systems have improved in 12 municipalities in the Hasbaya district (R1; R2); productivity, 
innovation, sustainable production and consumption and creation of decent jobs are promoted for 20 MSMEs 
in the waste value chains in the districts of Hasbaya, Saida and Tyre (R3).
R1: to respond to the problem of insufficient or poor quality separate collection, a separate collection 
management system will be introduced in Hasbaya and Chebaa, the two largest towns in the district, and the 
separate collection plan, already present in Rashaya Al Foukhar, will be revised. The new plans will be codesigned, implemented and monitored, ensuring both adequate technical and management training and the 
supply of vehicles and containers. In order for the separate collection systems to work, an awareness campaign 
will be designed and implemented for the correct separation and disposal of waste at domestic and commercial 
level. Finally, separate collection plans will be developed and presented and peer to peer trainings will be 
organized for the 9 municipalities not involved in the implementation of the service to ensure that they will 
have all the tools to implement the plans.
R2: to improve waste treatment, which is currently insufficient, 3 composting centres in Hasbaya, Chebaa and 
Rashaya Al Foukhar and 2 recyclables sorting centres in Hasbaya and Chebaa will be built. The centres will be 
designed, built and equipped with the necessary machinery; the operators will then be trained at a technical 
and management level and a management model and system for monitoring the functioning of the centres will 
be developed; finally, an endowment fund will be established for the start-up of the Hasbaya and Chebaa 
centres. To improve waste disposal, which is currently inadequate, the environmental impacts of the existing 
open dumpsites in Hasbaya, Chebaa and Rashaya Al Foukhar will be mitigated: the waste already present will 
be contained and covered and new lots and plans will be prepared for the controlled disposal of unsorted 
waste; dumpsites operators will be trained and monitored to correctly implement the new procedures and 
analyses will be carried out to assess the environmental impacts. Finally, treatment and disposal plans will be 
elaborated and presented for the 9 municipalities not involved in the implementation of the services and 
training and exchange meetings between the municipalities will be organized.
R3: to respond to limited and polluting production systems, characterized by a scarcity of sustainable 
investments, the 20 selected MSMEs will be economically supported with three disbursements of monetary 
contributions, subject to a selection and verification process of the feasibility of the development and business 
plans drawn up by them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO LAICI ITALIANI PER LE MISSIONI ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/01/8" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="42" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small and medium-sized enterprises (SME) development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="58" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste management/disposal</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="15.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, combat desertification, restore degraded land and soil, including land affected by desertification, drought and floods, and strive to achieve a land degradation-neutral world</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, reduce the adverse per capita environmental impact of cities, including by paying special attention to air quality and municipal and other waste management</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially reduce the number of deaths and illnesses from hazardous chemicals and air, water and soil pollution and contamination</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="12.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially reduce waste generation through prevention, reduction, recycling and reuse</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End poverty in all its forms everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="12" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure sustainable consumption and production patterns</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implement nationally appropriate social protection systems and measures for all, including floors, and by 2030 achieve substantial coverage of the poor and the vulnerable</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrate climate change measures into national policies, strategies and planning</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Make cities and human settlements inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protect, restore and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt biodiversity loss</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Take urgent action to combat climate change and its impacts</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">3600000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO LAICI ITALIANI PER LE MISSIONI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">2160000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO LAICI ITALIANI PER LE MISSIONI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
