<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">EDU TOP - Educazione Tecnica e professionale per migliorare le  competenze, le Opportunit&#xE0; per il lavoro dignitoso e la Prosperit&#xE0;  per i giovani vuln</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto &#x201C;EDU TOP - Educazione Tecnica e professionale per migliorare le competenze, le Opportunit&#xE0; per il 
lavoro dignitoso e la Prosperit&#xE0; per i giovani vulnerabili del Libano&#x201D; presentato dal COMI con i partner, VIDES 
e ISF-MI, la controparte locale FMA MOR ed il partner locale SDA ha come obiettivo la promozione di un 
sistema di formazione professionale e tecnica di qualit&#xE0;, equa ed inclusiva, rispondente ai bisogni del mercato 
del lavoro, a favore di coloro che ne sono maggiormente esclusi. 
Il cambiamento che si intende generare con il progetto riguarda quindi la qualit&#xE0; della formazione 
professionale, l&#x2019;inclusivit&#xE0; dell&#x2019;accesso e la coerenza con i bisogni del mercato del lavoro per facilitarne 
l&#x2019;ingresso ai giovani. 
Questa strategia &#xE8; nata da una analisi dei bisogni effettuata dal partenariato in stretta collaborazione con la 
Direzione Generale dell&apos;Istruzione e della Formazione Professionale del Ministero dell&#x2019;Educazione (DGTVET) 
che ha evidenziato alcune importanti cause della disoccupazione giovanile.
1. La scarsa qualit&#xE0; dell&#x2019;offerta formativa professionale pubblica e la mancanza di coerenza tra i 
bisogni del mercato del lavoro ed i programmi della formazione professionale (skill mismatch) comportano scarse opportunit&#xE0; di impiego pure in settori in cui la domanda di lavoro &#xE8; alta.
2. Il gap di qualit&#xE0; tra la formazione professionale privata, con costi inaccessibili ai gruppi 
vulnerabili, e quella pubblica comporta una grave disparit&#xE0; di accesso a reali opportunit&#xE0; di 
lavoro per i gruppi vulnerabili, in particolare i rifugiati. Le donne inoltre partecipano al mercato 
del lavoro al 29% (rispetto al 72% degli uomini), evidenziando pure un problema di equit&#xE0; di 
accesso.
3. La quasi totale assenza di strumenti di supporto ai giovani nella ricerca di un impiego dignitoso, 
nonch&#xE9; di orientamento e formazione sullo sviluppo sostenibile nelle scuole professionali 
pubbliche taglia di fatto i giovani pi&#xF9; vulnerabili al di fuori delle opportunit&#xE0; di inserirsi 
professionalmente e partecipare ai grandi temi del dibattito sociale del loro tempo.
Il gruppo target &#xE8; stato perci&#xF2; individuato nei giovani pi&#xF9; vulnerabili: nel contesto locale identificati con i 
rifugiati (per lo pi&#xF9; siriani e palestinesi) e con le ragazze (in linea con l&#x2019;OSS 4.5).
Il progetto si occuper&#xE0; del rinnovamento dei curricula formativi, aggiornamento dei docenti ed allestimento 
dei laboratori didattici in 22 scuole pubbliche nei settori dell&#x2019;informatica, dell&#x2019;infermieristica e della 
gioielleria. I settori sono stati scelti sulla base dell&#x2019;alta domanda che li caratterizza da parte del mercato del 
lavoro locale e della loro appetibilit&#xE0; da parte dei gruppi vulnerabili targettizzati e delle donne. Le scuole 
beneficiarie sono state selezionate per coprire tutte e 5 le Regioni del Libano, in modo da garantire 
l&#x2019;inclusione anche delle scuole che si trovano nelle zone pi&#xF9; remote e sono state selezionate con il criterio 
della distribuzione dei benefici tra tutte i gruppi religiosi ed etnici che compongono la complessa societ&#xE0; 
libanese. 
Contestualmente saranno rafforzati 15 Guidance and Employment Office (GEO) che realizzeranno attivit&#xE0;, 
workshop, seminari, formazioni e bootcamp per formare i giovani alla ricerca di un impiego, creare situazioni 
di incontro tra i giovani e le imprese, orientare i giovani e le famiglie e combattere lo stigma sociale di cui 
soffre la formazione professionale. Sar&#xE0; creata una piattaforma di orientamento online ed un Portale 
Nazionale del Lavoro per il matching domanda &#x2013; offerta di lavoro. 
Infine, per far fronte alla mancanza di conoscenza delle tematiche relative all&#x2019;ECG e allo sviluppo sostenibile, 
si creer&#xE0; una piattaforma e-learning con moduli sull&#x2019;educazione allo sviluppo e alla cittadinanza globale e si 
realizzeranno formazioni dei docenti e degli studenti sulle stesse tematiche per rafforzare la consapevolezza, 
partecipazione e realizzazione dei giovani nella propria societ&#xE0;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &quot;EDU TOP - Technical and Vocational Education to Enhance Skills, Opportunities for Decent Work 
and Prosperity for Vulnerable Youth in Lebanon&quot; presented by COMI with its partners, VIDES and ISF-MI, the local counterpart FMA MOR and the local partner SDA aims at promoting a system of quality, equitable and 
inclusive vocational and technical education, responsive to the needs of the labour market, in favour of the 
most excluded ones. 
The change that the project aims to generate concerns the quality of vocational training, the inclusiveness of 
the access to training opportunities for vulnerable groups and the consistency with the needs of the labour 
market. 
The strategy came from a needs assessment carried out by the partnership in close collaboration with the 
Directorate-General for Education and Vocational Training of the Ministry of Education (DGTVET), which 
highlighted some important causes of youth unemployment.
1. The low quality of the public vocational training offer and the lack of coherence between the 
needs of the labour market and the vocational training programmes (skill mismatch) lead to poor 
employment opportunities, even in sectors where there is a high demand for labour.
2. The quality gap between private vocational training, which is unaffordable for vulnerable groups, 
and public vocational training leads to serious inequality in the access to real job opportunities 
for vulnerable groups, in particular refugees. Women also participate in the labour market at 29% 
(compared to 72% for men), also highlighting a problem of equity of access.
3. The almost total absence of tools to support young people in their search for decent 
employment, as well as guidance and training on sustainable development in public vocational 
schools, effectively cuts off the most vulnerable young people from opportunities to enter the 
labour market and participate in the major issues of the social debate of their time.
The target group was therefore identified as the most vulnerable young people: in the local context identified 
with refugees (mostly Syrian and Palestinian) and girls (in line with OSS 4.5).
The project will renovate training curricula, update teachers and set up teaching training in 22 public schools 
in the major of IT, nursing and jewellery. The sectors were chosen on the basis of their high demand from the 
local labour market and their attractiveness to targeted vulnerable groups and women. The beneficiary 
schools were selected to cover all 5 regions of Lebanon to ensure the inclusion of schools in the most remote 
areas and were selected on the basis of the distribution of benefits among all religious and ethnic groups that 
composes the complex Lebanese society. 
Beside, 15 Guidance and Employment Offices (GEO) will be strengthened. They will carry out activities, 
workshops, seminars, trainings and bootcamps to train young people on how to search for a job, create 
encounter situations between young people and companies, orient young people and families and fight the 
social stigma suffered by vocational training. An online guidance platform and a National Job Portal will be 
created to match job supply and demand. 
Finally, in order to cope with the lack of knowledge of issues related to ECG and sustainable development, an 
e-learning platform will be created with modules on development education and global citizenship, and 
training of teachers and students on the same issues will be carried out to strengthen the awareness, 
participation and fulfilment of young people in their own society. The project duration is 3 years. The Salesian counterpart&apos;s deep roots in the territory, its long and proven experience in the vocational 
training sector and the close collaboration with DGTVET will make the initiative extremely sustainable.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMI- COOPERAZIONE PER IL MONDO IN VIA DI SVILUPPO ONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/02/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="11231" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure that all learners acquire the knowledge and skills needed to promote sustainable development, including, among others, through education for sustainable development and sustainable lifestyles, human rights, gender equality, promotion of a culture of peace and non-violence, global citizenship and appreciation of cultural diversity and of culture&#x2019;s contribution to sustainable development</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-18">1775785.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMI- COOPERAZIONE PER IL MONDO IN VIA DI SVILUPPO ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">1065471.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COMI- COOPERAZIONE PER IL MONDO IN VIA DI SVILUPPO ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
