<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-209131-GB-CHC-209131-NF-BRA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRITISH COUNCIL</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton fund, Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021 the main local partners are: local state funding agencies from S&#xE3;o Paulo, Maranh&#xE3;o, Distrito Federal, Paran&#xE1;, Minas Gerais. Research institutions: Funda&#xE7;&#xE3;o Oswaldo Cruz, Funda&#xE7;&#xE3;o Get&#xFA;lio Vargas. NGO: Sempre Viva Organiza&#xE7;&#xE3;o Feminista. The partners do not contribute to the project financially.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional Links, Researcher Links and Newton Fund Impact Scheme calls provides grants for the development of research and innovation collaborations between the UK and partner countries. Grants facilitate research that tackles local development challenges such as extreme weather conditions, access to affordable health care, food and energy security. Increase policy impacts and user engagement.  Increase the number of collaborations between UK and Brazilian Institutions &#x2013; including in states where the UK has not previously had a strong presence. 
Increase the number of UK researchers undertaking placements in Brazil in order to support Brazil&#x2019;s internationalisation agenda.
Improve the international reach of Brazilian science &#x2013; in particular the number of joint papers and papers published in English.
Support the development of Brazil&#x2019;s innovation ecosystem by sharing UK expertise &#x2013; in particular commercialising technologies developed in universities and improves support for innovation of research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior and early career researchers, local vulnerable communities. Institutions: universities, research institutions and NGOs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The British Council has been operating the Newton fund in Brazil since its launch in 2014. After 7 years of constant engagement, the British Council has implemented over &#xA3;9 million (plus equal or higher match funding) through our Institutional Links, Researcher Links, Newton Fund Impact Scheme and Professional Development and Engagement Programmes. Our contribution to national research environment supports a wide range of in-country priorities, to strengthen institutional capacities for grantees, local partners and national systems. Impacts have resulted in research development in 22 of the 26 Brazilian states and in Distrito Federal with over 1,000 Early Career Researchers from Brazil and the UK coming together through scientific workshops and over 20 UKBR partnerships between science museums, social organisations and public agencies developing applied science and kick starting further bilateral collaborations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="2" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (BEIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <telephone>00441619577755</telephone>
   <email>IATI@britishcouncil.org</email>
   <website>https://www.britishcouncil.org.br/atividades/educacao/newton-fund</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-id code="34488439" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">S&#xE3;o Paulo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-23.3251 -46.3810</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Brazil is a national project and is delivered in one location, S&#xE3;o Paulo, covering the entire country.</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="11420" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">127883.22</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
