<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13708A0105-KHM-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU/PAT II 2021-2022: Parliamentary Centre for Asia, PCAsia, Cambodia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EU/PAT II 2021-2022: Parliamentary Centre for Asia, PCAsia, Cambodia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall purpose of the intervention is &quot;to improve the performance of the target Parliaments - Cambodia, Lao PDR, and Myanmar - by helping to strengthen the capacity of parliamentary staff, and by increasing the intensity of technical exchanges and experience-sharing among their regional peers&quot;. Sida Phnom Penh jointly with the EU under the PAT II programme will restrict the funding to services to the Cambodian parliament.

In order to achieve this purpose over time, the project has five main components:

1) providing input to draft legislation;

2) implementing their representation function;

3) fulfulling their oversight role particularly at the local level;

4) for ASEAN parliaments to use the services of PCAsia and engage in peer learning and exchanges (which part only will be financed by Sida Phnom Penh when there is Cambodian participation); and

5) build the capacity of PCAsia as a capacity strengthening institute in legislative and democratic development support in the region and internationally.

Throughout all activities PCAsia promotes core values such as integrity, neutrality, objectivity and non-partisan behaviour.

The immediate, direct beneficiaries of PCAsia&apos;s activities will be the Parliamentarians and parliamentary staff in Cambodia. The research staff of the parliament will be better equipped to conduct research, analyse and prepare research products requested by parliamentarians and the various parliamentary commissions. Consequently, parliamentarians will have objective and technically based research papers at their disposal to base their decision-making on.

In a longer perspective the intervention also aspire to benefit Cambodian citizens in general as a legislature able to pass laws based on better facts and with an improved outreach capacity eventually will create more efficient and a professional Parliament in closer contact with its constituents.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sida tillsammans med EU (genom en delegering) finansierar den kambodjanska organisationen PCAsias (Parliamentary Centre of Asia) genomf&#xF6;rande av Kambodja-delen av sin strategiska plan &quot;Parliamentary Centre of Asia, Activities 2021-2024&quot; under perioden 1 april 2021-31 december 2022. Huvudsyftet &#xE4;r att bidra till ett f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrat arbete hos det kambodjanska parlamentet, genom att st&#xE4;rka kapaciteten inom dess f&#xF6;rvaltnings-, och utredningsfunktioner, PCAsia &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; den avslutade organisationen PIC (Parliamentary Institute of Cambodia) som Sida st&#xF6;tt tidigare.

Insatsen &#xE4;r en del av den andra fasen av en st&#xF6;rre  finansiering fr&#xE5;n Sida/EU till programmet f&#xF6;r ansvarighet och transparens (Partnership for Accountability and Transparency, PAT II, GD.-beslut 2019-003682) som har som delm&#xE5;l att st&#xE4;rka efterfr&#xE5;gan p&#xE5; och tillg&#xE5;ngen till ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande i den offentliga sektorn genom instititutionell kapacitetsutveckling.

Den totala budgeten finansierad av Sida/EU f&#xF6;r perioden &#xE4;r SEK 11 900 000.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This initiative concerns joint Sida and EU support (delegated financing) to the Cambodian NGO ,Parliamentary Center of Asia, PCAsia, to implement its strategic plan &quot;Parliamentary Centre of Asia, Activities 2021-2024&quot; during the period 1 April 2021-31 December 2022. The support is a continuation of previous support to the newly closed organization PIC (Parliamentary Institute of Cambodia) with the goal to develop the capacity of the Cambodian Parliament and its support functions through training and research.

The Swedish support to PCAsia is a joint support between Sweden and the EU through the Partnership for Accountability and Transparency (PAT II) that is managed by Sweden. PAT II is focusing on good governance with improved accountability and transparency in the use of public funds.

The total budget jointly financed by Sida and EU is SEK 11 900 000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PCAsia/Parliamentary Centre of Asia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PCAsia/Parliamentary Centre of Asia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.a - Strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels, in particular in developing countries, to prevent violence and combat terrorism and crime.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.a - St&#xE4;rka ber&#xF6;rda nationella institutioner, bland annat genom internationellt samarbete, i syfte att bygga upp kapacitet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, i synnerhet i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE5;ld och bek&#xE4;mpa terrorism och brottslighet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13708_13708agreementPCA.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/asien/13708_CalloffdecisionEY.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Avrop fr&#xE5;n ramavtal revisionstj&#xE4;nster beslut om tilldelning</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13708_13708decisiononcontributionPCA.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Examples of results from 2021

1. Parliamentary staff has increased capacity to provide support to parliamentarians to input draft legislation.

PCAsia supports Cambodian parliamentary staff to provide national parliamentarians with knowledge on legislative issues on the agenda through reasearch products. 8 research products were deliverd by PCAsia&apos;s researchers. 15 parliamentary staff were trained on legal analysis and legislative drafting. 16 parliamentary staff were trained on parliamentary committee work and 6 were engaged in best practices exchange on parliamentary responsibilities. 11 parliamentary staff were trained on support for ASEP 11 (Cambodia was hosting the ASEP 11 - the 11th meeting of the Asia-Europe parliamentary partnership). There were also 6 parliamentary staff trained in parliamentary research techniques, and 3 were trained as trainers (ToT) for subjects related to parliamentary research.

The remaining activities that were not possible to carry out have been postponed due to restrictions during the Covid-19 pandemic or they have started to be carried out but are not ready and therefore moved to next year for finalization.

2. Parliamentary staff has improved capacity to provide support to parliamentarians to implement their representation function.

PCAsia supports parliamentarians and parliamentary staff to conduct public consultations on issues related to research products. 1 such public consultation has been held under PCAsia&apos;s quality control. Also one activity of the Cambodian Women&apos;s Caucases and WAIPA has been supported. The activity on improved digital communcation with citizens through e-Parliament has not been started but postponed to 2022. Staff of the Senate has travelled to attend training for e-Parliament. There have been less requests than planned received by the Budget Research Department, BRD, of the Senate due to Covid-19 restrictions and that many parliamentarians have worked from home.

3. Parliamentary staff has improved capacity to provide support to parliamentarians to fulfill their oversight role, in particular at the local level.

Parliamentary staff in Cambodia have increased their analytical capacity to support the oversight role of the Parliament on the state budget during the year through 12 staff that were trained on budget analysis, 9 trainees were mentored and coached on budget analysis from the BRD of the Secretariat of the Senate. BRD also produced 40 budget analysis research products under the mentoring and coaching of PCAsia&apos;s trainers. 76 parliamentarians (twice as many as targeted) increased their capacity to assess public policies through training on &quot;Autonomy of Parliamentary Assemblies&quot;.

4. The AIPA Secretariat (ASEAN Inter-parliamentary Assembly) uses PCAsia&apos;s services and engages in peer learning and exchanges.

There were no activities under this component in 2021 that concerned the Cambodian parliamentarians nor parliamentary staff. Such activities have been postponed to 2022 when travel restrictions may be further relaxed.

5. PCAsia is recognized as a valued partner as a capacity strengthening centre in legislative and democratic development support in the region and internationally.

PIC was closed at the end of March 2021 and its operations and the majority of its staff were successfully transferred to PCAsia that started its activities from 1 April 2021. Agreements for funding of PCAsia was signed with SDC, Sida PP, and an extension was signed with Sida Bkk. Landesa was also a new partner that signed a financing agreement with PCAsia.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13708" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
