<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5110010303-KHM-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU/PAT 16-19: National Audit Authority</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EU/PAT 16-19: National Audit Authority</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kambodja inledde &#xE5;r 2004 en reform med syfte att st&#xE4;rka den offentliga finansiella styrningen (OFS). Reformen har finansierats av flera givare, d&#xE4;ribland EU och Sida. I december 2015 fattade EU-kommissionen beslut om att l&#xE4;mna fortsatt st&#xF6;d till reformen. Beslutet inneb&#xE4;r st&#xF6;d genom tv&#xE5; olika finansieringsmekanismer; sektorbudgetst&#xF6;d till reformens genomf&#xF6;rande samt en delegering till Sida f&#xF6;r att finansiera insatser som kompletterar sektorbudgetst&#xF6;det. Det svenska st&#xF6;det kommer att riktas till akt&#xF6;rer/omr&#xE5;den som inte i tillr&#xE4;cklig omfattning inkluderats i tidigare st&#xF6;d till OFS-reformen, och som inte med automatik kan n&#xE5;s via EU:s sektorbudgetst&#xF6;d. L&#xE4;rdomar fr&#xE5;n tidigare st&#xF6;d visar att de mest relevanta omr&#xE5;dena f&#xF6;r additionellt och riktat st&#xF6;d handlar om anti-korruption, externrevision, statistik och extern granskning av budgeten. Dessutom har betydelsen av att &#xF6;ka skatteint&#xE4;kterna och effektiviteten i skatteadministrationen understrukits.

Det svenska st&#xF6;det kommer att omfatta f&#xF6;ljande kambodjanska myndigheter och organisationer: Statistikmyndigheten, Skattemyndigheten, Transparency International Cambodia, Riksrevisionen och Parliamentary Institute of Cambodia. Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r det program som ska genomf&#xF6;ras av Sida, Partnership for Accountability and Transparency (PAT), &#xE4;r 10,342 miljoner euro. EU:s bidrag uppg&#xE5;r till 7 miljoner euro. Det svenska bidraget uppg&#xE5;r till ca 32 miljoner kronor.

Denna insats avser st&#xF6;d och samarbete med Kambodjas Riksrevision, National Audit Authority (NAA). NAA f&#xE5;r sedan h&#xF6;sten 2011 svenskt st&#xF6;d genom svenska Riksrevisionen (RiR) inom ramen f&#xF6;r ett myndighetssamarbete, vilket finansieras genom RiR:s egna medel f&#xF6;r utvecklingssamarbete. RiR:s st&#xF6;d fokuserar p&#xE5; ett av de tre omr&#xE5;den som anges i den v&#xE4;gledning f&#xF6;r kapacitetsutveckling av ett lands riksrevision som tagits fram av International Organisation for Supreme Audit Institutions (INTOSAI), n&#xE4;mligen sj&#xE4;lva revisionsarbetet. Den insats som f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s i denna promemoria avses inriktas p&#xE5; de &#xE5;terst&#xE5;ende tv&#xE5; omr&#xE5;den som anges i INTOSAI:s v&#xE4;gledning: organisatorisk kapacitet samt kommunikation och relationer med externa intressenter.

I enlighet med NAA:s projektans&#xF6;kan, daterad den 12 maj 2016, kommer insatsen att omfatta st&#xF6;d till f&#xF6;ljande omr&#xE5;den: 1) utveckling och uppgradering av NAA:s IT-milj&#xF6;, 2) intern och extern kommunikation, inklusive relationer med externa intressenter, 3) genomf&#xF6;rande av Kambodjas ordf&#xF6;randeskap i ASEAN SAI, samt 4) framtagande av en ny strategisk plan f&#xF6;r perioden 2017-2021. 

Ut&#xF6;ver detta tillkommer finansiering av en extern medelhanteringsfunktion (fund manager) samt ett externt managementst&#xF6;d, vilket NAA beg&#xE4;rt i sitt projektf&#xF6;rslag. Dessa externa resurser kommer att handlas upp av ambassaden genom avrop fr&#xE5;n ambassadens ramavtal med KPMG samt genom en f&#xF6;rnyad konkurrensuts&#xE4;ttning under Sidas ramavtal med konsulter inom OFS-omr&#xE5;det. Insatsen kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras under perioden 1 juli 2016-30 juni 2019. Den totala budgeten uppg&#xE5;r till ca 7,1 miljoner kronor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to National Audit Authority to increase the organizational capacity, improve Communication and relations with external people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National Audit Authority (NAA) is Cambodia&#x2019;s Supreme Audit Institution (SAI). It is an autonomous institution which has the mandate to audit all government institutions. NAA was established in 2000 by the Audit Law and started to undertake independent external financial audit on entities of the RGC in 2002. In the recent Open Budget Survey (2017) Cambodia scores 55 out of 100 in terms of budget oversight and is thereby considered to provide adequate budget oversight. Under the law, NAA has full discretion to decide which audits they should perform; the auditor general is appointed independently from the executive and it has sufficient resources to fulfill its mandate. However, the 2015 PEFA assessment concluded that the capacity of NAA is limited, even though the audit coverage and the timeliness of submission of audit reports to the legislature have improved.
The overall objective of the intervention is stated as follows: NAA&apos;s capacity strengthened as the SAI of Cambodia through support to its information and communications infrastructure and its ability to partake and contribute in international cooperation. This objective will be achieved through the following four outcome objectives:1. A functional IT environment and intranet that supports internal and external communication and crucial office functions.2. A developed external communication policy and practice, Stakeholder Management.3. Active and professional chairmanship of the ASEAN SAI 2016-2017.4. NAA has a new long-term strategy from 2017 to direct the development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB (f d Orgut Consulting AB)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Audit Authority of Cambodia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">10986.3846198796</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">26208.6112086112</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">17094.1498665194</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">25537.8123711122</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">10986.3846198796</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">26208.6112086112</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">17094.1498665194</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">25537.8123711122</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">82749.722433</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">10986.4348740723</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-28">11690.3837603838</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">9061.6122616123</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">5456.6514566515</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">1186.9419129154</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">7313.7508054865</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">8593.4398876922</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">3605.2549202085</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">7036.1361689527</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-28">4235.3451284383</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">10661.0518300743</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective for the support under the PAT programme was &#x201C;improved effectiveness and transparency of external audit&#x201D;. In order to achieve this objective, the intervention focused on 1) a functional IT environment and intranet; 2) external communication and stakeholder management; 3) chairmanship of the ASEAN SAI and; 4) Strategic Plan 2017-2021.FCG Consulting has provided support to NAA throughout the implementation phase, particularly in the areas of IT and external communication. The support function form part of the overall intervention and the cost is included in the project budget.The cooperation with NAA was time consuming throughout the project life. This was likely a consequence of NAA not being used to working with donors and receive external support. As an institution NAA is also cautious in its approach, which partly can be explained by its complicated position of not being sufficiently independent from government while at the same time being expected to scrutinize and perform the role of watchdog over the same government
The following results have been achieved under the above noted focus areas number 1 -4:
1. Internal communicationAt the start of the intervention the IT environment within NAA was in a very poor state. In order to enable effective internal and external communication, it was essential to establish a proper IT platform. By providing support to an upgrade of the IT environment, the internal organisational capacity and work procedures would be strengthened, while at the same time a possible platform for communication with external stakeholders would be established.In the initial project proposal, it was planned to include the introduction of an intranet. Due to the delays in the project implementation, and particularly in procuring the IT equipment, NAA and Sida agreed to put the intranet on hold until the equipment was in place. Due to the delays in the procurement of equipment, there was insufficient time to also introduce an intranet during the activity period. However, five ICT-staff at NAA received training in administration and configuration of the network, which included web-site management and e-mail services, and the adoption of an ICT policy. Final approval of the e-mail server and domain within the government set-up was received in May 2020.
2. External communication, stakeholder managementA Stakeholder Engagement Policy was developed by NAA with the support of FCG. The policy builds on an Action Plan which was developed as part of a training on &#x201C;SAI Engaging with Stakeholders&#x201D; provided by INTOSAI Development Initiative (IDI) (free of charge for its member SAIs). The Stakeholder Engage-ment Policy has been consulted on widely within NAA and was approved by management in 2019 and is currently actively used. However, actual implementation of these tools remains. Together with members of the Second Commission from the Cambodian Parliament, NAA participated in a study visit to Sweden in October 2017. The aim of the visit was to increase the understanding of the respective roles and mandates of Parliament and the Supreme Audit Authority, in order to strengthen relations between the Cambodian institutions.
3. Active and professional chairmanship in ASEANCambodia chaired the ASEANSAI 2016 to 2017. During the last year of their chairmanship, Cambodia organised two major events for the other ASEAN SAIs which resulted in a signed protocol amendment on the establishment of ASEANSAI. During the Cambodian chairmanship the ASEANSAI signed an agreement with the World Bank on the Area of Establishment of ISSAI Facilitators POLL and a Memo-randum of Understanding with the Swedish National Audit Office on the support for ISSAI implemen-tation. Moreover, the ASEANSAI finalised their strategic plan for 2018-2021. The results of the Cambodian chairmanship in the ASEANSAI were documented in the book &quot;Spirit of Togetherness for Achieve-ment&#x201D;, published in November 2017.
4. New Strategic Plan 2017 &#x2013; 2021The Strategic Plan for 2017 &#x2013; 2021 is in place since 2017 and has been operationalised through the NAA Action Plan (NAA MAP 3-2018) and can be found on the website of NAA. It aims to form a basis for a more holistic and sequenced approach to capacity building and future organisational development. With the support of PAT, a Mid-Term Review was organised in August 2019 to follow-up on progress of the implementation of the Strategic Plan and draw up the 2020 Work Plan.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51100103" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
