<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10816A0101-KHM-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arbitration Council Foundation Cambodia 2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Arbitration Council Foundation Kambodja 2019-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">The Arbitration Council Foundation (ACF) har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering p&#xE5; 2,5 miljoner dollar (cirka 22,5 miljoner kronor) till Sida, representerat av den svenska ambassaden i Phnom Penh f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av program &quot;Strengthening Industrial Relations and Labour Market Conditions in Cambodia&quot; under perioden 2019&#x2013;2021. 

Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka arbetsmarknadens parter och arbetsmarknadsf&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llanden genom social dialog och en v&#xE4;lfungerade och trov&#xE4;rdig skiljedomsn&#xE4;mnd f&#xF6;r konflikthantering i Kambodja 1) konflikthantering p&#xE5; arbetsmarknaden, 2) partnerskap och att bedriva arbetet ut&#xE5;triktat med akt&#xF6;rer, 3) &#xF6;ka institutionell integritet och trov&#xE4;rdighet, och 4) f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning av institutioner och samarbete med arbetsmarknadsministeriet och resursmobilisering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Arbitration Council Foundation (ACF) has applied for funding to Sida, represented by the Embassy of Sweden Section Office in Phnom Penh, to carry out the Programme, &quot;Strengthening Industrial Relations and Labour Market Conditions in Cambodia&quot; for a period of 2019-2022. 

The proposed intervention aims at strengthening industrial relations and labour market conditions through social dialogue and well-functioning, credible labour dispute arbitration system in Cambodia by 1) labour dispute resolution, 2) partnership and outreach with stakeholders, 3) increased institutional integrity and credibility, and 4) institutional strengthening and collaboration with the Ministry of Labour and resource mobilization. 
In 2021 additional funding was provided to further support the scale up of ACF&apos;s work on enhancing effective and accessibility of individual labor dispute resolution services. This contribution is a continuation from previous support and Sweden has been supporting the foundation since 2014.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this contribution is to strengthen industrial relations and labour market conditions through social dialogue and well-functioning, credible labour dispute arbitration system.&#xA0;
Moreover, three specific objectives under the overall objective that the intervention seeks to achieve are as follows:
1. To enhance effectiveness and accessibility of labour disputes resolution services in which the stakeholders have confidence;
2. To increase capacity of industrial relations stakeholders to participate in dispute prevention and resolution and social dialogue to effectively address their disputes;
3. To strengthen industrial integrity and sustainability of the Arbitration Council, Arbitration Council Foundation and their services.&#xA0;
4. Specific objective (major amendment): To enhance effectiveness and accessibility of individual labour dispute resolution services in which the stakeholders have confidence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF/Arbitration Council Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF/Arbitration Council Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.8" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.8 - Protect labour rights and promote safe and secure working environments for all workers, including migrant workers, in particular women migrants, and those in precarious employment.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.8 - Skydda arbetstagarnas r&#xE4;ttigheter och fr&#xE4;mja en trygg och s&#xE4;ker arbetsmilj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r alla arbetstagare, inklusive arbetskraftsinvandrare, i synnerhet kvinnliga migranter, och m&#xE4;nniskor i otrygga anst&#xE4;llningar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">264385.1986590383</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">271452.92463381</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">264385.1986590383</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">271452.92463381</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-06">528770.397318</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-28">264385.1986590383</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">271452.92463381</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_10816AgreementAmendmentIofContributionArbitrationCouncilFoundationCambodia2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Amendment I on Core Support to Arbitration Council Foundation Cambodia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_10816AgreementAmendmentIIofContributionArbitrationCouncilFoundationCambodia2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Amendment II on Core Support to Arbitration Council Foundation Cambodia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_Scannedagreementamendment2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement amendment no. 3</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_10816AgreementofContributionArbitrationCouncilFoundation2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement on Core Support to Arbitration Council Foundation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_10816DecisiononAmendmentIofContributionArbitrationCouncilFoundationCambodia2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment I of Contribution to Arbitration Council Foundation Cambodia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_10816DecisiononAmendmentIIofContributionArbitrationCouncilFoundationCambodia2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment II of Contribution to Arbitration Council Foundation Cambodia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_DecisiononAmendmentofContribution(10816).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment of Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10816_10816DecisiononContributionArbitrationCouncilFoundationCambodia2019-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution to Arbitration Council Foundation Cambodia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The assessment of results achievement for this year&apos;s Conclusion on Performance is based on the annual report for 2019 and the Skype meeting held on 19 May 2020 between the Embassy and ACF. These results are summarized as follows:

Component 1 - Resolution of labour disputes

2019 saw double increase of dispute cases resolved by the Arbitration Council (AC) compared to 2018 in which a total of 59 cases were handled. A total of 117 labor dispute cases were resolved by the AC (vs the target at 50 cases) with a success rate of 75%, which is slightly higher than the target of 74%. This benefited a total of 41,906 worker beneficiaries, of whom approximately 80% were women, under the set target of 57,500 workers, from the AC&apos;s arbitration services. The number of total beneficiaries couldn&apos;t be controlled by ACF but rather depending on the number of complainants of each dispute case.  

Out of the 117 cases, 48% were the recorded cases from Phnom Penh whereas 52% were cases collected from several provinces. The capacity of arbitrators and ACF staff was developed and improved through various training courses and opportunities concerning the new labour-related regulations issued by the Ministry of Labour (for example, workers&apos; representative status in collective bargaining and resolving collective labour disputes, seniority payment), conciliation skills, arbitration models in Myanmar, Vietnam, China and the United States, and strategic plan development.

The increase of the cases handled by the AC during 2019 compared to 2018 was explained by ACF with two main possible reasons. First reason was the Ministry&apos;s new ministerial directive/Prakas 303 to allow &quot;minority&quot; trade unions to represent their members in collective dispute resolution. This new Prakas has been considered as a supplementary legal framework that loosens strict requirements under the Trade Union Law of 2006 that requires the &quot;most representative status&quot; of trade unions to be able to bring cases to the AC, thus having an impact on the case increase. Second reason was that improved registration of unions by the Ministry of Labour in the post-2018 election year, thus enabling the unions to forward cases to the AC for resolution. 

Component 2 - Partnership and stakeholder outreach and training

The ACFs partnership with labour dispute resolution actors have maintained and increased not least with the Ministry of Labour, Cambodian Federation of Employers and Business Association (CAMFEBA), Garment Manufacturing Association of Cambodia (GMAC), American Center for International Labour Solidarity (ACILS or Solidarity Center), International Labour Organisation (ILO) and various union federations and confederations as well as local and international organisations. Partnership in this context is referred to ACFs collaborative efforts with labour actors, human rights organisations wand others whose roles are essential to enabling an effective and credible labour arbitration system and upholding labour rights in Cambodia.

ACFs publications in relation to arbitral awards, digest books, quarterly newsletters, Q&amp;A booklets, complication of labour law and regulations, trade union law and other information brochures were disseminated via ACFs website and social media (Facebook, Twitter and Youtube), and distributed in hard copies to relevant partners working on the labour market, which made it accessible to those most interested. For example, the ACFs social media reached over 36,000 viewers against the target of 10,000.

14 stakeholder outreach activities and trainings were carried out by ACF targeting partners in public and private sectors such as the employers, unions, lawyers, students, civil servants and CSOs to increase their understanding in labour dispute resolution and arbitration process. A total of 791 trainees, of which 48% were women, participated in and all of them came from Phnom Penh.

Component 3 - Institutional integrity and sustainability

ACF has established and maintained numerous formal structures and activities since many years such as Board of Directors and the Representative of AC, General Arbitrator Meeting, Regular Arbitrator Meeting, Annual Arbitrator Retreats and Arbitrator Working Group Meeting to increase its institutional credibility, integrity and sustainability. ACF has worked with the Ministry of Labour to work and recruit new arbitrators with procedural proposal to enable new choices for the disputing parties but no update since then.

ACFs sustainability is on a good move as the currently adopted multi-source funding model used by ACF to institutionally and financially sustain. In 2019, USAID through its partner- the Solidarity Center- supported ACF with a total grant of 1.5 million USD for the period of 2020-2024 under the Labour Rights in Cambodia Project. This is a positive contribution in terms of ensuring financial sustainability of ACF/AC as the continued Swedish support for additional two years 2020-2021 was also made with ACF through the agreement extension. Apart from these two major donors, ACF also received some small grant from the Cambodian government and the brands for implementing certain activities.

Gender equality

ACF reported that gender equality was mainstreamed in the programme activities and decision-making with disaggregated sex data such as for staff recruitment, ACs hearings, capacity building sessions, and stakeholder trainings. For example, 60% of the total ACF staff (25) are women, whereas 17% are female arbitrators (out of 30). 36% were female participants attended the 151 ACs hearings. ACF had a gender focal point but she left the position and the new person would be on board in 2020. The current gender equality work implemented by ACF can be improved; therefore, the gender equality consultancy with proper gender analysis and response was agreed to be conducted in 2020.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10816" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
