<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10483A0101-KHM-11110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF Inclusive Education II 2017-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNICEF Inclusive Education II 2017-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Programmet bygger p&#xE5; tidigare UNICEF program inom utbildningssektorn i Kambodja riktade mot barn och ungdomar (PlanIT 51100073, UNICEF - Inclusive Education Support 2014-2016, 30 MSEK). Programmet har ett tydligare fokus p&#xE5; l&#xE4;rande &#xE4;n f&#xF6;reg&#xE5;ende fas, inklusive kunskapsutv&#xE4;rdering och genomf&#xF6;rande av det kvalitetsutv&#xE4;rderingssystem som initierades i samarbete med svenska Skolinspektionen (PlanIT 51100054 Education Quality Assurance 2013-2016, 16,5 MSEK). Programmet har fortsatt tyngdpunkt p&#xE5; insatser f&#xF6;r barn fr&#xE5;n etniska minoritetsgrupper, barn som lever med funktionsneds&#xE4;ttningar och andra utsatta grupper. J&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet i olika former, inklusive insatser f&#xF6;r att motverka skolrelaterad k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld, samt WASH (vatten, sanitet och hygien) har en mer framtr&#xE4;dande roll i denna programfas j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;rt med tidigare. Ett nytt inslag i programmet &#xE4;r arbetet med klimat och milj&#xF6;fr&#xE5;gor. Sammantaget har d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r det nya tre&#xE5;rsst&#xF6;det en &#xF6;kad total avtalsvolym (57 MSEK) j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;rt med tidigare fas (30 MSEK).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed programme is to a certain extend a continuation of the Sweden funded programme  - UNICEF - Inclusive Education Support 2014-2016 (51100073). The proposed new phase will have stronger focus on children&#x2019;s learning, including learning assessments and the operationalisation of the quality assurance system that was initiated in twinning cooperation with the Swedish School Inspectorate.  The programme will maintain important equity interventions for children from ethnic minorities, children with disabilities and over-aged children. This phase of the proposed programme will have clearer focus on gender issues &#x2013; including school related gender based violence and WASH. A new part of the programme is a emphasis on climate change and environmental issues.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of UNICEF&#x2019;s Inclusive Education programme 2017-2019 is to support Cambodia in providing and assuring more equitable provision of quality education services. This is expected to be achieved by fulfilling four outcomes, which include support for research, data and coordination, tailored programmes to increase boys&#x2019; and girls&#x2019; participation in education with a component on climate change adaptation, strategies to strengthen the quality of the teaching and learning process including learning assessments, life skills and the implementation of the external and internal inspection framework.  1. By 2019, there is strengthened capacity for policy development and coordination in education. 2. By 2019, there is increased capacity and accountability to provide access to inclusive basic education particularly amongst indigenous minorities and children with disabilities including in emergencies. 3. By 2019, there is strengthened capacity of education authorities at national level and in targeted districts to provide quality and measurable primary and lower secondary education. 4. There is sustained UNICEF technical support to the education sector with a focus on the most marginalised children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="111" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Level Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.1 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar fullbordar avgiftsfri och likv&#xE4;rdig grundskole- och gymnasieutbildning av god kvalitet som leder till relevanta och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga kunskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">4095004.0950040948</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1150695.0197919542</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1269048.9535633838</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">4095004.0950040943</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1150695.0197919547</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1269048.9535633838</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-103773.6245030256</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">6669006.669006</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">4095004.0950040948</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">1150695.0197919542</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">1269048.9535633838</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">-103773.6909606035</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The indicators for the different expected outcomes show that the results of the programme have been in general very positive and have been achieved. Some of the main outcomes and setbacks for the different areas can by summarised such:
Outcome 1: Strengthened capacity for policy development and coordination in education
UNICEF has been supporting the NGO Education Partnership (NEP) to play an active coordination role among international and local NGOs working in the education sector to effectively participate in the education reform process. The intended outputs have however not been achieved and thus this result area has not contributed to the expected outcome as planned.
There were significant achievements in strengthening EMIS data management and use during the UNICEF-Sida partnership. The inclusion of indicators relating to Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 4, such as water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH), children with disabilities, and ethnic minorities has made the EMIS more comprehensive and inclusive. Anecdotal evidence shows increased use of EMIS data by national and sub-national education managers to inform planning, operational decision making and reporting.
Outcome 2: Increased capacity and accountability to provide access to inclusive basic education
Children with disabilities have a fundamental right to education. The UNICEF-Sida partnership has continuously raised awareness and built the capacity of key actors and implementers in the delivery of inclusive education services. The intended results for this area were achieved as planned. The ongoing capacity building of teachers and MoEYS officers at national and sub-national levels has contributed to changing teachers&#x2019; perceptions of including children with disabilities in their classrooms. The creation of a pre-service inclusive education training course is a milestone that can transform how children with disabilities can learn and participate in the education system. Teachers have improved their knowledge and skills in relation to children with disabilities and inclusive education through this pre-service training and through in-service interventions.
Indigenous ethnic minority teachers are essential for effective education service provision to children from indigenous minority communities. Where there is a lack of teachers, access to education is hindered. The UNICEF-Sida partnership contributed to increasing the number of pre-school and primary teachers fluent in indigenous languages, enabling more indigenous minority children to access education in a familiar language, essential to optimise their learning experience. Results under this area have been consistently achieved and the UNICEF-Sida partnership contributed to the current positive trend in Multilingual Education (MLE). Enrolment in the MLE programme of indigenous minority children keeps increasing.
The Special Education Diploma course produced Cambodia&#x2019;s first ever cohort of specialised teachers for children with hearing and visual impairments. To ensure long-term institutional capacity, an institutional development plan for National Institute of Special Education (NISE) was developed, guiding priorities and actions for the next five years. This investment in training specialised teachers will enhance the inclusiveness of the Cambodian education system and will greatly benefit children with disabilities to access quality inclusive education.
The planned results for primary school teachers trained in positive discipline and effective classroom management have been consistently achieved each year of the programme. Positive discipline training for teachers and school directors has helped reduce the incidence of violence in target schools. Programme visits and survey results suggest positive behaviour change in teachers, away from corporal punishment and towards improved learning environments, as reported by students.
Outcome 3: Capacity building at national and sub-national levels
The planned results for local life skills education was partly achieved during the UNICEF-Sida Partnership. The targets were adjusted due to delays in operationalising the programme at central level. However, local life skills syllabi and learning standards have been developed for Grades 4&#x2013;9. This programme is attempting to introduce a major shift in pedagogy. It promotes participatory problem-based learning approaches as opposed to traditional rote learning methodologies. This has increased the quality of the Cambodian education system in the selected districts and the likelihood of improving learning outcomes for children in school.
School inspection plays a crucial role ensuring the quality of education at the school level, as the inspection findings provide an external view and assessment of school performance. The planned results under this area of work were partly met, and the provincial-based quality assurance inspection system (PQAIS) progressed slowly. The operational guidelines for the PQAIS embedded external and internal inspection and were developed and aligned with the child-friendly school checklist and school inspection tools. Since the introduction of the PQAIS system, POE directors pay more attention to school self-assessments and inspection findings of inspectors and DTMTs. The POE management teams have increasingly used inspection findings to inform planning and monitoring.
Outcome 4: Sustained UNICEF technical support
UNICEF continued to play a lead role in policy dialogue and harmonisation in the education sector and to ensure strong knowledge management systems within the Education Sector Working Group (ESWG). The UNICEF-Sida partnership strengthened the harmonisation of development partners in the education sector and their alignment with MoEYS policies, systems and major education reform processes. During the UNICEF-Sida partnership, UNICEF continuously played an active role in education sector coordination, as chair of the ESWG, vice chair of the Joint Technical Working Group (JTWG-Education), coordinating agency for the Local Education Group, and grant agent for the Global Partnership for Education III Variable Part programme. Policy-informing research was conducted and disseminated. At the sub-national level, UNICEF zone officers continued support to strengthen coordination and alignment of partners at sub-national level. Sone officers helped facilitate planning and coordination processes with POEs and NGOs, especially through the provincial ESWG and JTWG forums.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10483" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
