<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12442A0101-KHM-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khmer Rouge history education by Documentation Center of Cambodia 2018-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Utbildning Khmer Rouge, av Documentation Center of Cambodia 2018-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">DC-Cam (the Documentation Center of Cambodia) har ins&#xE4;nt en projektans&#xF6;kan till ambassaden som syftar till f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra utbildningen om R&#xF6;da khmerernas folkmord i Kambodja samt st&#xF6;d till f&#xF6;rsoningsprocessen under en period av ett &#xE5;r mellan juni 2018 och maj 2019. Projektet har tv&#xE5; huvudsakliga komponenter: en teaterupps&#xE4;ttning , &quot;Breaking the Silence&quot; samt uppdatering och publicering av en uppdaterad textbok i historia om det Demokratiska Kampuchea. 

&quot;Breaking the Silence&quot; &#xE4;r en teaterpj&#xE4;s som fokuserar p&#xE5; &#xF6;verlevares vittnesm&#xE5;l f&#xF6;r att bidra till dialog och f&#xF6;rsoning och sattes upp f&#xF6;rsta g&#xE5;ngen 2010. Den uppdaterade textboken avser bidra till och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;tra undervisningen om det Demokratiska Kampuchea samt R&#xF6;da khmertribunalens (Extraordinary Chambers in the Courts of Cambodia, ECCC) arbete. Nuvarande textbok har inte uppdaterats sedan 2007. De uppdaterade b&#xF6;ckerna kommer att anv&#xE4;ndas i skolundervisning och utbildningsinsatser om folkmordet i DC-Cam:s regi.

Insatsen f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;tts kunna &#xF6;ka kunskaperna om R&#xF6;da khmerernas folkmord i samh&#xE4;llet och st&#xF6;dja den fortg&#xE5;ende f&#xF6;rsosningsprocessen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Documentation Center of Cambodia (DC-Cam) has submitted a project proposal to the Embassy to implement a Project that aims to support eductaion on the Khmer Rouge genocide and healing in Cambodia for a one-year period from June 2018 to May 2019. The project has two main components: a theatre play &#x201C;Breaking the Silence&#x201D; and publication of an updated history textbook on the Democratic Kampuchea. 

&quot;Breaking the Silence&quot;, which was earlier performed in 2010, is a theatre play based on survivors&#x2019; testimonies to promote dialogue and reconciliation. The history textbook would contribute to genocide education as well as the legacy work of the Khmer Rouge Tribunal (Extraordinary Chambers in the Courts of Cambodia, ECCC). The current history textbook has not been updated since 2007. The updated history textbooks will be used in mandated public schools and genocide education events of DC-Cam.  

It is expected that the contribution will increase the public&apos;s knowledge about the Khmer Rouge genocide and support the continued reconciliation process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this intervention is aimed to support education on the Khmer Rouge genocide and healing in Cambodia for a one-year period. The intervention has two main components: (1) a theatre play &quot;Breaking the Silence&quot; and (2) the publication of updated History on the Democratic Kampuchea textbooks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DC-CAM/Documentation Center Of Cambodia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">131179.2322562828</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">131179.2322562828</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-8643.6040261898</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-16">131179.232256</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">131179.2322562828</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-28">-8643.6431154109</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The agreement with the cooperation partner DC-Cam came to an end on 31 August 2021. The final report was submitted to the embassy and the assessment of the results is based on the reports and exchange of communication with the cooperation partner at the last conclusion periods.&#xA0; Throughout the project period, the achieved results both expected and unexpected are summarized&#xA0;as follows:&#xA0; Achieved results - The History of Democratic Kampuchea textbooks was approved by the Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports to be published and disseminated to their targeted high schools and universities in Phnom&#xA0;Penh&#xA0;and provinces.&#xA0; - The knowledge amongst&#xA0;the target groups, particularly women and youth on the Democratic Kampuchea (the history of Khmer Rouge) and comparative genocide (the holocaust) has increased. Numbers of dialogue on healing processes, new permanent exhibition panels as well as&#xA0;theatre play performance,&#xA0;&quot;Breaking the Silence&quot;&#xA0;were conducted in various locations such as Phnom&#xA0;Penh, Battambang, Kampong&#xA0;Cham, Kandal, Prey Veng, Uddor&#xA0;Meanchey, Siem&#xA0;Reap and Takeo.&#xA0;&#xA0; -&#xA0; The permanent exhibitions (18 panels vs plan of 10) related to the revised History of the Democratic Kampuchea have been installed at different regional training centers and high schools in Cambodia which could eventually reach to 22,500 visitors. This result achievement was additionally contributed by the publication of Heidi Fried&apos;s holocaust experiences, which was translated into Khmer by a young Cambodian woman and distributed to the targeted schools and groups.&#xA0; - During the launch of the &quot;Breaking the Silence&quot; theater play performance in Phnom Penh in 2018, Swedish Ambassador Maria Sargren gave a speech acknowledging the Swedish support to DC-Cam&apos;s project which aimed at contributing the education of the young generation about the Khmer Rouge past history, healing and reconciliation process in Cambodia. This launch event was participated by the Under-Secretary of State of Ministry of Education, Youth and Sport, some diplomats, and hundreds of students at&#xA0;&#xA0; the National Institute of Education, international audience, and general public from several The total audiences attended the &quot;Breaking the Silence&quot; performances in Phnom Penh and four other provinces are at least 2,500 audiences. - For gender equality, the project applied a gender ratio of 50% male and 50% female for the activity implementation and events. For example, the project targeted 50/50 split between men and women for &quot;Breaking the Silence&quot; performers and for the participants as well. The project also provided the chance for women and girls to demonstrate their capacity and express voices because DC-Cam believed it was essential that all activities considering of maximum diversity and empowerment to the marginalized groups. Unexpected Results - The publication of Heidi Fried&apos;s book, it was not actually planned in the original project document. However, during the activity period DC-Cam requested to have such publication with remaining fund to increase more knowledge of Cambodian young people about comparative genocide education from Heidi Fried&apos;s work, &quot;Questions I am Asked about the Holocaust&quot; by translating the original text into Khmer language. It was successful as many readers, especially Cambodian students, expressed their interest in the translated book in relation to the comparative genocide in Europe and in Cambodia during the Khmer Rouge regime with a hope to end such atrocities from happening again.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12442" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
