<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5110007301-KHM-11110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF - Inclusive Education Support 2014-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNICEF - Inclusive Education Support 2014-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att st&#xF6;dja genomf&#xF6;rande av centrala delar av den kambodjanska regeringens utvecklingsplan f&#xF6;r utbildningsomr&#xE5;det 2014 &#x2013; 2018. Detta g&#xE4;ller s&#xE4;rskilt de delar som syftar till att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla alla barns r&#xE4;tt till skolg&#xE5;ng, utbyggnad av system f&#xF6;r inkluderande utbildning med s&#xE4;rskilt fokus p&#xE5; barn fr&#xE5;n minoritetsgrupper och andra utsatta grupper, samt f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning och utbyggnad av flerspr&#xE5;kig utbildning f&#xF6;r barn fr&#xE5;n minoritetsgrupper. Insatsen har ytterligare som syfte att st&#xF6;dja kapacitetsf&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning hos relevanta myndigheter f&#xF6;r att kunna axla ett decentraliserat ansvar f&#xF6;r utbildningsystemet liksom att &#xF6;ka medvetenhet, deltagande och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande hos f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ldrar och lokalsamh&#xE4;lle f&#xF6;r utbildningskvalitet och resursanv&#xE4;ndning. Insatsen kommer dessutom att st&#xF6;dja f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttringar och teknisk utveckling f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla tillg&#xE5;ng till relevant statistiskt underlag f&#xF6;r reformbeslut. Insatsen best&#xE5;r av fyra komponenter: inkluderande utbildning, st&#xF6;d till utvecklingsdialog och koordinering, f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkt deltagande och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande genom anv&#xE4;ndande av multimedia, samt tekniskt st&#xF6;d p&#xE5; central och decentraliserad niv&#xE5;. Prorgrammets total budget &#xE4;r 30 miljoner kronor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention supports central parts of the Cambodian Government&#x2019;s Education Strategic Plan 2014-2018 with a special focus on the parts that  relate to education for all, including the expansion of a system for inclusive education with focus on children from minority groups and other marginalised groups as well as multilingual education for children from minority groups. The intervention will also support capacity strengthening within relevant government authorities to undertake responsibilities for the education system at decentralised level and increased demand for accountability for quality education from parents and local communities. The intervention will also support improvements and technical development to ensure quality data collection and analysis for education reform. The intervention consists of four components: inclusive education, support to dialog and coordination, increased demand and accountability through the use of multimedia, and technical support and central and sub-national levels.
The total budget is SEK 30 million.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Childrens&apos; Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="111" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Level Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1457747.197481013</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1457747.197481013</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-13907.4150787075</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">4373241.592443</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-28">1457747.197481013</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">-172448.0355680356</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">172448.0355680356</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">-13907.440393998</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Throughout the implementation period UNICEF has continued to engage with and support the Ministry of Education, Youth and Sport (MoEYS) on priority areas of the intervention and continued to align its support with national policy, adding particular value on areas of equity, learning and inclusion. At the national level, UNICEF continues its engagement with the MoEYS, via the Child-Friendly Schools Steering Committee and, as the Chair and Secretariat of the Education Sector Working Group (ESWG), helps to support harmonization of development partners in the education sector and their alignment with the MoEYS&#x2019; policies and systems. At the sub-national level, UNICEF continues its support to provincial planning and coordination fora, with support from zone office colleagues outside of Phnom Penh.     During the implementation period of the intervention, a number of results related to the intended outcome have been achieved.    The inclusive early childhood education (ECE) programme has been expanded to 176 state pre-schools by the school year 2016-17 &#x2013; a significant increase from 30 state pre-schools in the SY2013. An additional 41 community pre-schools also provide Inclusive ECE by the SY2016/2017. Simultaneously in 2016, the Multilingual ECE programme has expanded from 20 community pre-schools to 83 pre-schools. This success is largely the result of increased government ownership as reflected in the Multilingual Education National Action Plan (MENAP) (2016-2018). The plan, the first of its kind in Cambodia and South-East Asia, includes projections on enrolment data, the number of teachers needed and plans for provincial-level expansion of Multilingual Education (MLE) in pre-school and primary school.  By the end of 2016, all MLE community schools in the northeast of the country had been transformed into government schools.     The intervention supported the MoEYS to develop an in-service teacher training package on positive discipline, aimed to foster secure, child-friendly and non-violent relationships between teachers and their students, drawing from national and international experiences and best practices. The positive discipline programme was scaled to 172 primary schools across the three target provinces to the benefit of approximately 51,145 children.     As part of this initiative, the MoEYS and UNICEF have also worked with the Royal University of Phnom Penh (RUPP) to conduct a knowledge, attitude and practices survey (baseline and endline) on disciplinary methods to help measure the impact of the training package. This survey shows that teacher attitudes and practices toward classroom management have changed as a result of the training, including significant differences in acceptance of corporal punishment and changes in approaches to anger management. As such, corporal punishment and physical violence has decreased as a result of the training. Students also expressed greater access to teachers able to listen to their problems, greater numbers of student councils, greater attention to child rights in school, and guidelines in place to protect them from violence in schools.     In 2016 a joint formative evaluation was conducted examining the implementation of the Cambodian Child Friendly School (CFS) policy. Because of the known challenges around school inspection, a particular focus was placed on the internal monitoring and inspection processes of District Training and Monitoring Teams (DTMTs). The evaluation found that the CFS policy has been instrumental in promoting a broad understanding of overall school improvement criteria as well as strengthening inclusiveness, gender responsiveness, community participation, health and protection.      In 2016, the joint UNICEF-MoEYS Out-of-School Children study for Cambodia was finalized for launch. The report, which is part of a global initiative jointly supported by UNICEF and the UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS), is designed to provide analysis on the scope of school exclusion and policies and strategies to address inequalities in school opportunities. The report analyses the key supply and demand side issues affecting children&#x2019;s participation in education including a review of policies, governance and financing of the sector. Based on the findings, recommendations are made for strengthening participation in pre-school focusing on young children&#x2019;s holistic developmental needs, on primary school attendance for the most vulnerable children aged 6-11 years and for promoting attendance in lower secondary education through social protection measures. The report also focuses recommendations on teacher education reform efforts and in strengthening the management and financing of equity-oriented programmes.     These marked achievements to education in Cambodia are largely tied to the Inclusive Education Support Programme in Cambodia which has enabled UNICEF to continue its strong support to the MoEYS in national policy and programming with a focus on the areas of equity, learning and inclusion.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51100073" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
