<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13404A0101-KHM-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU/PAT II, 2020-2022: Transparency International Cambodia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EU/PAT II, 2020-2022: Transparency International Cambodia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida jointly with the EU under a delegated support contributes to Transparency International Cambodia for implementing its, &quot;Strategic Plan 2020-2022, Collective Action Against Corruption (CA2C)&quot; during the period 2020-2022. The main objective of TIC&apos;s strategic plan is to strengthen demand, participation and capacity of key stakeholders in Cambodia to fight corruption. Stakeholders that will be able to contribute to reduce, prevent and reduce corruption include youth groups, civil society organisations, citizens, public sector institutions and businesses. 

The intervention aims to achieve a society that is free from corruption contributing to the overall goal established for the PAT programme (Partnership for Accountability and Transparency, PAT II, GD decision 2019-003682) &#x201C;Strengthened demand for and supply of public transparency and accountability through institutional capacity development&#x201D;, : 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget financed by EU/Sida is SEK 25 500 000.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sida tillsammans med EU (genom en delegering) finansierar TICs (Transparency International Cambodia) genomf&#xF6;rande av sin strategiska plan &quot;Strategic Plan 2020-2022, Collective Action Against Corruption (CA2C)&#x201D; under perioden 2020-2022. Huvudsyftet med planen &#xE4;r att bidra till &#xF6;kat ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande och transparens genom fr&#xE4;mjande av dialog. Deltagare &#xE4;r civilsamh&#xE4;llets organisationer, ungdomsgrupper, medborgare, institutioner i den offentliga sektorn och f&#xF6;retagare.Insatsen &#xE4;r en del av den andra fasen av en st&#xF6;rre  finansiering fr&#xE5;n Sida/EU (Partnership for Accountability and Transparency, PAT II, GD-beslut 2019-003682) som har som delm&#xE5;l att st&#xE4;rka efterfr&#xE5;gan p&#xE5; och tillg&#xE5;ngen till ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande i den offentliga sektorn genom instititutionell kapacitetsutveckling.

Det totala budgeten som finansieras av Sida/EU &#xE4;r SEK 25 500 000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TI Cambodia&#x2019;s vision is for all Cambodians to live in a society that is free from corruption.
TICs programme has four Components with their own set of expected results including impact, outcomes, output and activties:&#xA0;
1. Public Sector engagement and coalition building programme &#xA0;
Expected Programme&#x2019;s Impact: Enhanced public service delivery at national and sub-national levels and increasing accountability and transparency of fiscal governance.
Outcomes:
1. Enhanced public service delivery at national and sub-national levels
2. Increased public understanding and demand for fiscal transparency and accountability
3. Strengthened effectiveness of alternative reporting mechanisms on corruption cases through the Advocacyand Legal Advice Centre (ALAC) and enhanced the anti-corruption legal and regulatory frameworks
Citizen and youth empowerment programme&#xA0;
Expected Programme&#x2019;s Impact: Increased public demands for anti-corruption and enhanced civic participation by allcitizens in decisions that affect their lives
Outcomes&#xA0;
1. Increased women, youth and citizens understanding and knowledge of good governance, integrity,transparency and corruption and its effects on their lives and society
2. Enhanced participation by youths on anti-corruption and increased demands for positive reforms&#xA0;
Business Integrity Programme&#xA0;
Expected Programme&#x2019;s Impact: Increased accountability, integrity and transparency in business practices
Outcomes&#xA0;
1. Policies adopted for a more level playing field through increased advocacy from business associations andgovernment dialogue.
2. Responsible Business Conduct (RBC) principles, including business integrity, adopted and implemented byCambodian businesses.
3. Increased research and advocacy on relevant private sector issues, including RBC and business integrityleading to raised awareness amongst the broader private sector of these topics.
4. The Business Integrity Consultancy continues to operate and provide services for the private sector, CSOs,and DPs.
5. Enhanced transparency and accountability in the award of mining sector permits, licence and contracts
Governance foundation and capacity development&#xA0;
Expected Programme&#x2019;s Impact: Enhanced capacity of TIC&#x2019;s staff and increased its members and their commitmentin the fight against corruption.
Outcomes&#xA0;
1. Enhanced governance structure and capacity of TIC to effectively manage and deliver results onanti-corruption at both national and sub-national levels.
2. Increased members for TIC and increased their commitment among citizens/youth/institutionsto promote integrity and take actions against corruption.
1. Enhanced knowledge and understanding of corruption, accountability, transparency and its effects through evidence-based research and studies.
Research and advocacy programme&#xA0;
Expected Programme&#x2019;s Impact: Well-informed anti-corruption stakeholders and publics on the state of governance,sector-based studies on corruption issues that affect the lives of people/business community, and addressed emergingcorruption cases or abuse of power.
Outcome&#xA0;
1. Enhanced knowledge and understanding of corruption, accountability, transparency and its effectsthrough evidence-based research and studies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21033" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21033" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">433781.7735648284</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">433781.7735648283</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-11">433781.773564</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">306198.8989869377</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">6447.2816704127</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">121135.592907478</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13404_13404agreementTIC.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement on Core Support</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13404_13404decisiononcontributionTIC.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Example of results

The overall goal of TIC&apos;s strategic plan 2020-2022 is to increase public accountability and transparency through demand-driven advocacy and dialogue. There are five outcome objectives linked to the overall goal that Sida supports together with EU under PAT II. The fifth goal is capacity building of TIC&apos;s own organization as the support by Sida/EU is a core support.

TIC can contribute to the PAT&apos;s indicators in particular on improved budget comprehensiveness and transparency and enhanced accountability.

Goal 1 - Public sector engagement and coalition building programme (budget utilization 40%)

Enhanced public service delivery and increased public understanding and demand for fiscal transparency together with strengthened effectiveness of alternative reporting mechanisms on corruption cases through the ALAC and enhancement of the anti-corruption legal and regulatory framework. The project has contributed to this through:

- 15 actions (12 planned) that were taken by the government and the local administration to become more accountable, transparent and responsive in public service delivery. Some examples of actions are that an assessment was carried out of what challenges provincial and district ombudsmen were facing. As a result two official notifications were issued by the government on strengthening their roles and responsibilities and advising local governments to provide greater support to ombudsmen&apos;s offices. It was also reported that the local government had trained commune healthcare centre staff on not to discriminate patients based on their socioeconomic or political status, encouraging staff to receive and treat them first and letting them process payments later.

- 29 (12 females) Trainers of Trainers (ToT) at Ministry of Interior (MoI) that received training and with capacity building of 626 (193 females) sub-national officials to enhance the effective performance of their roles. 73% of the surveyed officials have reported applying their skills to enhance transparency, accountability and responsiveness in their duties after the training.

- 37 (planned 180) (14 females) clients that received legal advice from the ALAC lawyer. ALAC reached around 408 (54% females) youth and citizens through its trainings (17 trainings carried out - 14 planned). 4 corruption cases were received (related to traffic police and court) but none (planned 7) was referred to the anti-corruption unit (ACU) as they lacked sufficient evidence.

Goal 2 - Citizen and Youth Empowerment Programme (budget utilization 23% mainly due to holding virtual meetings instead of physical gatherings/meetings)

Increased women, youth and citizens understanding and knowledge of good governance, integrity, transparency and corruption and its effects on their lives and society and enhanced participation by youths on anti-corruption and increased demand for positive reforms. Also, to enhance the effectiveness of TIC&apos;s provincial presence in 5 regional provinces. The project has contributed to this through:

- Five virtual forums on social accountability, good governance, and women and youth leadership that were carried out with 513 people from five provinces attending.

- 102 (66 females) youth that participated in the virtual youth camp that took place 2021. 10 youth led initiatives were developed afterwards.

- Through the partnerships with MoI, capacities of more than 600 public service officials at sub-national levels were enhanced. 

- 24 youth led inititiavies have been initiated which have contributed to further increase the awareness among the public and youths on importings issues (corruption, good governance, accountability, public service, women and youth empowerment etc.). 

- Most of the gatherings were hold virtually which reduced the costs for holding the various meetings and youth camp and provincial forums. The annual youth debate and mock-parliament were delayed to 2022.

Goal 3 - Business Integrity Programme (61% utilized)

Among the outcomes were to adopt policies for a more level playing field through increased advocacy from business associations and government dialogue. It was also to lead to the implementation of more responsible business conduct (RBC) principles, including business integrity, adopted and implemented by Cambodian businesses. Training on this has taken place but it is not possible to measure yet if RBC has been implemented/adopted. It is also to lead to increased accountability, integrity and transparency in business practices and enhanced transparency and accountability in mining sector. The project has contributed to this through:

- In partnership with CWEA (Cambodian Women Entrepreneurs&apos; Association) there have been two capacity trainings to their potential provincial chapters. In partnership with FASMEC (Federation of Associations for Small and Medium Enterprises of Cambodia), workshops with SMEs have been carried out in six provinces with the purpose of building SMEs&apos; capacity to do business with effectiveness and integrity.

- TIC has opened space for civil society to impact indigenous communities through community consultations. For instance, vulnerable mining communities are encouraged to participate in and be active in the EISEI (Extractive Industry Social and Environment Impact) Network. The project also supported direct activities with a range of indigenous communities affected by mining projects. 

- There have been workshops carried out in Preah Vihear, Kratie and Ratanakiri with 78 community people participating to raise their awareness of Environmental Impact Assessment and Fair, Prior Informed Consent principles and processes. 

- A training on new mining legal framework was also conducted with the community people in Preah Vihear.

- The policy papers on non-fiscal revenues and on rapid assessment of mining policy framework has been completed.

- 20 media outlets and CSOs attended a series of virtual training on the financial investigation for journalists which were jointly conducted by TIC and CamboJa. The training was delivered by trainers from the Centre for investigative journalism CIJ based in UK. 

Goal 4 - Research and Advocacy Programme (63% utilized)

The expected impact is to have well-informed anti-corruption stakeholders and public on the state of governance, sector-based studies on corruption issues that affect the lives of people/business community, and addressed emerging corruption cases or abuse of power. Evidence-based research and studies are tools used under this component together with a more effective M&amp;E mechanism and evidence-based impact assessment of the programmes. 

- In cooperation with the Southeast Asia Globe, an online media outlet, 19 publications were collected and uploaded to TIC&apos;s E-library. A landing page on their website was created to accentuate issues along with practical solutions concerning good governance and anti-corruption in Cambodia. 2 articles were produced and published on the landing page. One was titled &quot;the changing face of Cambodian leadership&quot; and onother &quot;Cambodian healthcare system facing a dual practice dilemma&quot;.

- A study on Leadership of Women and Youth in Cambodia was carried out and launched on 19 March 2021. The study was to further explore how Cambodian women navigate their leadership paths and career ladders despite bureaucratic hurdles.

- An external consultant was commissioned to undertake a study on &quot;Beneficial Ownership in the Land and Property Sector of Cambodia&quot;. A first draft report is ready and now being reviewed by and advisory group.

- A parallell report on UNCAC implementation in Cambodia for the second review cycle has been produced. The report is intended as a contribution to the UNCAC implementation review process. The report was finalised and publicly distributed on 25 November 2021 via social media channels.

- Two new proposals were sent to donors for financing. One worth USD 100,000 was accepted and the other worth USD 200,000 is under review by UN Democracy Fund.

- TIC&apos;s M&amp;E framework, plan and database have been developed and is in place. M&amp;E tools such as sampling method and questionnaires for pre-test, post-test and survey, monitoring report template, activity tracking and indicator tracking table were also developed and used. An evaluation to sub-national authorities who were trained on good governance and GRPS was conducted and was intended to evaluate whether they have applied their knowledge after the training (see the results under Goal 1, first point, above).

- TIC conducted at least 12 digital campaigns during 2021 (e.g. Citizen Budget Handbook, Anti-corruption Law and combatting corruption, whistleblower protection), a number launches and joint digital campaigns, participated in the working group of anti-corruption, the working group for digital rights, and the budget working group as some examples.

Goal 5 - Governance Foundation and Capacity Development

In addition to the four goals, TIC is also reporting on how it has strengthened its own organizational capacity and its commitment in the fight against courrption:

Outcome 1 Enhanced governance structure and capacity of TIC to effectively manage and deliver results on anti-corruption at both national and sub-national levels.

Outcome 2 Increased members for TIC and increased their commitment among citizens/youth/institutions to promote integrity and take actions against corruption

- 25 in-house trainings were conducted covering project management, reserach skills, communication, data driven advocacy, good governance, anti-corruption legal framework and tools, budget process, gender responsive publc service etc. All staff participated in various trainings.

- The staff retreat was postponed to 2022 due to the corona travel and meeting restrictions prevailing.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13404" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
