<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13640A0102-KHM-43082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum II 2020-2022 Policy research</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Future Forum II 2020-2022 Policy research</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum is an independent Cambodian think tank that focuses on research, analysis and public policy. The think tank was established in 2015. The main objective of the think tank is to encourage independent social scientific research and thinking and through that positively influence the Cambodian policy narrative and stimulate an evidence-based policy debate. Future Forum is also set up to respond to the need for more independent analysts and researchers that can conduct objective policy research. The think tank strives to include a wide number of actors in its operations and activities, including different political parties, the government, the state administration and civil society. Young people and students are an important target group. A special effort is made to include groups that are not always heard in policy and social debate, such as women, grassroots groups, and ethnic, religious and social minorities.
The first phase of Swedish support to Future Forum was implemented during the period 1 July 2017 to 30 June 2020. The Swedish support amounted to SEK 3.3 million in total (54% of the total budget). The support was provided as core support for Future Forum&apos;s operations.
Future Forum has submitted a program proposal for a new implementation period from 1 July 2020 to 31 December 2022. Expected Swedish support amounts to SEK 5.5 million.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Future Forum &#xE4;r en oberoende kambodjansk tankesmedja, etablerad 2015. Huvudsyftet med tankesmedjan &#xE4;r att genomf&#xF6;ra oberoende samh&#xE4;llsvetenskapliga studier av h&#xF6;g kvalitet, stimulera en evidensbaserad politisk debatt och d&#xE4;rmed p&#xE5;verka den kambodjanska politiska diskursen p&#xE5; ett positivt s&#xE4;tt. Ambitionen &#xE4;r vidare att inkludera ett brett antal akt&#xF6;rer i arbetet, inklusive politiska partier, regeringen, statsf&#xF6;rvaltningen och det civila samh&#xE4;llet. Tankesmedjan har ocks&#xE5; som ambition att utbilda och tr&#xE4;na blivande forskare och analytiker. Ungdomar och studenter &#xE4;r en viktig m&#xE5;lgrupp. En s&#xE4;rskild satsning kommer ocks&#xE5; att g&#xF6;ras f&#xF6;r att f&#xE5; med grupper som inte alltid h&#xF6;rs i debatten, s&#xE5;som kvinnor, gr&#xE4;srotsgrupper och etniska, religi&#xF6;sa och sociala minoriteter. 

Den f&#xF6;rsta fasen av det svenska st&#xF6;det till insatsen genomf&#xF6;rdes under perioden 1 juli 2017 till 30 juni 2020. Det svenska st&#xF6;det uppgick till 3,3 miljoner kronor (54 % av den totala budgeten). St&#xF6;det l&#xE4;mnades som k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till Future Forums verksamhet. 

Future Forum har inkommit med ett programf&#xF6;rslag om en ny genomf&#xF6;rande period fr&#xE5;n 1 juli 2020 till 31 december 2022. Det f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade svenska st&#xF6;det uppg&#xE5;r till 5,5 miljoner svenska kronor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum&#x2019;s overall objective is to encourage intellectual research and thinking, to positively influence the policy narrative in Cambodia at a local, national and international level, employing evidence-based policy debate, analysis and recommendations in order to contribute to democratic, political and socio-economic change that will benefit all peoples of Cambodia. A special focus is on outreach to youth, women, grassroot communities and minorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A to be procured</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">54290.584926762</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">54290.584926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">54290.584926</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13640_13640AgreementFF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13640_13640DecisiononcontributioFF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The narrative report covers the whole year 2020, i.e. the last half year of the first Sida support 2017-2020 and the first half year of Sida&#x2019;s second support period 2020-2022. This is assessed to be reasonable as the support is provided in the form of a core support and that the institution follows a calendar year plan and implementation.
The year 2020 proved to be a big challenge for Future Forum as for most activities globally. &#xA0;The impacts of Covid-19 on the organisation&#x2019;s ability to deliver planned activities and outputs were fundamental.
Due to the pandemic, between March and July, all staff, students and researchers worked from distance including the training and other learning activities, using Zoom and Skype as an instrument. From July, the premises were gradually opening, and some lectures and activities were delivered in person, by implementing a range of strict health and safety measures recommended by the World Health Organisation. But most of the activities were conducted online and on distance for the rest of the year. An important part of the training programmes, the planned institutional visits and site observations to various public locations, government agencies, and development partners were cancelled or postponed due to their office closures or practice of social distancing. &#xA0;
However, the outbreak of the pandemic brought about some learning opportunities for the organisation, including the practice of a wide range of safety and health measures. The organisation also increased the use of and integrated online learning and platforms such as Zoom, Skype, Google Classroom, and other online tools to supplement the traditional mode of learning delivery.
The fieldwork did also take on another shape using creative ways to obtain required data for analysis including interviewing sources by phone, social media platform, or video conference device, and administering online surveys through Survey Monkey or Kobo Toolbox. &#xA0; In spite of the challenges brought by the pandemic the staff and trainees published 11 op-eds and commentaries in English (some including translated Khmer versions) and 20 were edited in-house for publication in 2021 in various local and international media outlets (including The Phnom Penh Post, Southeast Asia Globe, and Nikkei Asia Review). &#xA0;
Twelve final draft research papers were completed, revised and went through final editing and quality check by Future Forum&#x2019;s academic advisors. These papers will be published in the soon to be launched Journal of Future Cambodia.
As part of the capacity building program 40 research, policy, and academic writing lecture series were conducted in 2020. &#xA0; Future Forum engaged in one big regional project as the Cambodian partner in the Center for International Private Enterprise&#x2019;s&#xA0;(CIPE) &#x2018;Corrosive Capital&#x2019; project on investment that doesn&apos;t seek economic benefits, but political influence in Asia. &#xA0;
Future Forum in cooperation with Angkor Research Cambodia undertook in 2020 an economic impact study on Covid-19. The study will continue in 2021 and maybe beyond. The project is studying the economic impacts of COVID-19 on farmers, wage workers, and families with micro-enterprises.
The volumes 1 and 2 of Cambodia 2040 were launched in 2020. Volume 3 of Cambodia 2040 will be launched in early 2021. Young political analysts in training at Future Forum have worked with Southeast Globe&#x2014;on joint articles on the futures of Cambodia, altogether 8 articles and an independent webpage.
Future Forum did also participate in joint podcast production of 15 thirty-minute Khmer language podcasts called &#x201C;envision Cambodia&#x201D; produced by VOA Khmer. VOA Khmer service has more than 7 million followers on Facebook. Envision Cambodia is also on iOS and Android platforms as well as on VOA Khmer. 8 of the podcasts went live in 2020 and 8 will be broadcasted in early 2021.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13640" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
