<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12147A0101-KHM-43060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITP DRM MSB &#x2013; Disaster Risk Management.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ITP DRM MSB &#x2013; Styrning, kontroll och organisation av katastrofhj&#xE4;lp.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International capacity development programme related to crisis management and risk management.

Government disaster risk management organisations, civil society and academia organisations having participated in the ITP will have increased cooperation and information sharing in relation to disaster risk management information and experience sharing. Organisations will have key individuals that have strengthened capacity (increased knowledge, skills and changed behaviour) to support strengthened organisational performance and outputs for disaster risk management.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Internationellt kapacitetsutvecklingsprogram inom krisberedskap.

Statliga myndigheter, civilsamh&#xE4;llet och akademin (verksamma inom f&#xF6;ljande omr&#xE5;den: f&#xF6;rebyggande/f&#xF6;rberedelser innan olycka och kris, reducerande &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder under olycka och kris samt &#xE5;teruppbyggnad efter olycka och kris) kommer efter genomf&#xF6;rt program att ha utvecklade f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r integrerat samarbete och effektiv informations- och erfarenhetsdelning. De nyckelpersoner fr&#xE5;n organisationerna som kommer att delta i programmet kommer dessutom att ha &#xF6;kade f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r snabb och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenlig kommunikation med individer som arbetar inom andra organisationer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSB has developed an ITP with disaster risk management as the overall thematic focus. Organisations will have strengthened capacity to manage disaster risk through increased flow and sharing of risk and vulnerability assessment data on different levels. Should a disaster strike the different stakeholders will share response information and needs assessment data and participate in coordination mechanisms. Recovery will be designed and implemented considering disaster risk by the organisations who having participated in the ITP. Gender and environment will be mainstreamed to informing decision making in disaster risk management.
Government disaster risk management organisations, civil society and academia organisations having participated in the ITP will have increased cooperation and information sharing in relation to disaster risk management information and experience sharing. Organisations will have key individuals that have strengthened capacity (increased knowledge, skills and changed behaviour) to support strengthened organisational performance and outputs for disaster risk management.
More specifically, the ITP will contribute to the vision and mission by supporting ITP participants and their organisations in achieving the below listed outcome statements.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSB/Myndigheten f&#xF6;r samh&#xE4;llsskydd och beredskap</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MSB/Myndigheten f&#xF6;r samh&#xE4;llsskydd och beredskap</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.17" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.9 - Enhance international support for implementing effective and targeted capacity-building in developing countries to support national plans to implement all the Sustainable Development Goals, including through North-South, South-South and triangular cooperation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.9 - &#xD6;ka det internationella st&#xF6;det f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av effektiv och riktad kapacitetsuppbyggnad i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna till st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r nationella planer f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra alla m&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling, inklusive genom samarbete nord&#x2013;syd och syd&#x2013;syd samt trepartssamarbete.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">361318.2362146737</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">108581.169853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">116592.2419522205</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">387469.6218913594</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">365716.261119985</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">361318.2362146737</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">108581.1698535242</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">116592.2419522207</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">387469.6218913593</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">365716.2611199851</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-01">1334806.222958</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">361318.2362146737</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">108581.169853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/capdev/12147_007569-19TillaggtillSidassarskildavillkorforbidragtillMSB(tillaggsavtal)2424527_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Agreement, MSB (amendment)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/capdev/12147_038071-18AvtalombidragtillMSBmellanSidaochMSB2372116_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Agreement, MSB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/capdev/12147_005187-19Beslutomandringavinsats,2018till2023,MSB-Styrning,kontrollochorgani2412161_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on contribution, MSB (amendment)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/capdev/12147_036864-18BeslutominsatsMSB-Styrning,kontrollochorganisationavkatastrofhjalp2366303_1_1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on contribution, MSB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Please refer to the following documents: 014676/20, 011905/20, 005961/20, 038549/19 and 021048/18 (file: 17/001364 MSB  ITP Disaster Risk Management). 

The first programme set will be concluded in spring/summer 2020. Due to the COVID-19 pandemic the foreseen start-up of two additional programme sets in 2020 will be delayed. Hence, this conclusion on performance will primarily report on the Asia-set that started in 2019. The programme set included participants representing civil society (including the Red Cross/the Red Crescent), government agencies and academia from Bangladesh, Nepal and the Philippines. Due to difficulties in finding suitable candidates and change initiatives Cambodia was excluded from the first programme set. MSB will be re-structuring the recruitment process in the future. This concretely means drawing on an extended network in Cambodia in order to fill the Cambodia slot with relevant participants with potential to achieve institutional change.

Regarding Bangladesh the Director General of Health Services has focussed on preventing gender-based violence, initially concretely forming governmental regional committees to organise women-friendly spaces in case of disaster. The only joint change initiative from Bangladesh is a collaboration between the Cyclone Preparedness Programme of the Ministry of Disaster Management and Relief and the United Nations Population Fund (in Bangladesh). The expected outcome of the change initiative is improved access to information on early warning and life-saving services by women and girls and reduce gender-based violence risk in disaster prone districts in Bangladesh. The Red Cross/the Red Crescent plans to develop a financial framework that will support vulnerable people during a disaster. A pilot will be carried out in 2020. The change initiative by the Centre for Natural Resource Studies aims to create a better capacity for the most vulnerable households to cope with climate change. About 50 training sessions have been carried out so far among households in the selected villages in order to increase knowledge and capacity for preparedness, response and recovery to natural disasters. The BRAC University change initiative focus on training communities in the area of disaster risk management. Part of the training package developed capacity building sessions on first aid, fire and collapsed buildings.

Regarding Nepal the Ministry of Home Affairs has worked on a change initiative to integrate vulnerability information in a geographic information system platform in the disaster management portal of Nepal. Vulnerability indicators have now been identified with relevant stakeholders. As a result, the consultations with local government representatives have also increased the awareness about the special needs of vulnerable groups. The Disaster Management Division of Nepal Police has a change initiative focussing on strengthening the capacity at different levels by creating curricula and courses to train staff, but also create awareness amongst the population. The National Network of Community Disaster Management has trained local governments and local communities to conduct vulnerability and capacity assessments. The Disaster Preparedness Network in Nepal has carried out a similar programme at municipality level. Greenhood Nepal has worked with a change initiative to support community radio stations to produce public service announcement on disaster related issues in local languages. The Institute of Crisis Management Studies change initiative focus on reducing womens vulnerabilities and increase their resilience during disasters. Trainings on disaster risk management have been conducted on the community level focussing on disaster reduction methods and fire safety. The Central Department of Environmental Science of Tribhuvan University has worked on developing and revising the higher education curricula of their master programme on environmental science. A three-credit masters degree course on disaster risk reduction has been fully developed, based on national and international practices, which include 17 course modules. The module will be thought to approximately 120 students and 20 faculties. The work has also led to that other faculties at the university have been informed of new dimensions of disaster risk reduction.

Regarding the Philippines the Office for Civil Defence change initiative aim to improve the quality of the trainings delivered within the organisation. This is achieved by developing minimum qualification standards for the subject matter experts to ensure that only those who have the necessary training, experience, and competencies will be allowed to facilitate disaster risk reduction trainings (both on central and regional levels). The Development Academy of the Philippines has identified a gap regarding guidelines and management plans for post-disaster waste. The change initiative is to develop and provide framework-guidelines for post disaster waste management for the local government units to enhance and consolidate post-disaster waste management practices, standard operational procedures, and initial training design for the post-disaster waste management. The change initiative of the Department of the Interior and Local Government is about improving the support to local level by better coordination and support from regional and national level. This is obtained by coordinated information and data management on local disaster risk reduction and institutionalised convergence of capacity building providers. The Centre for Disaster Preparedness change initiative aims to promote the inclusion of persons living with disabilities in planning, budgeting, and other development processes of local government units and other agencies, specifically in disaster risk reduction and management. The Philippine Disaster Resilience Foundation work with improving private sector coordination in emergency response and resilience work. The objective with the change initiative is to develop an information system to support its operations centre to improve early warning and analysis of anticipated impact for earlier action.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12147" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1130103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="0" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Capacity development, partnership and methods that support Agenda 2030 for sustainable development 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kapacitetsutveckling, partnerskap och metoder som st&#xF6;der Agenda 2030 f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar utveckling 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
