<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10524A0101-KHM-11110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Capacity Development Partnership Fund III 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 Capacity Development Partnership Fund III 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Den givargemensamma fonden, Capacity Development Partnership Fund (CDPF), skapades 2011 f&#xF6;r att finansiera centrala delar av Utbildningsministeriets plan f&#xF6;r kapacitetsutveckling. Fondens f&#xF6;rsta fas p&#xE5;gick under 2011 &#x2013; 2014 med en andra fas 2015 &#x2013; 2017. Fondens tv&#xE5; f&#xF6;rsta faser har finansierats gemensamt av EU delegationen i Phnom Penh, UNICEF och Sverige. Sveriges st&#xF6;d uppgick till 30 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2015-2016 (PlanIT 51100074) och till 21 000 000 SEK f&#xF6;r 2011-2014 (PlanIT 51100002).

Ordf&#xF6;rande i fondens styrelse &#xE4;r Utbildningsministeriets statssekreterare och vice-ordf&#xF6;rande &#xE4;r EU:s representant. &#xD6;vriga medlemmar i fondens styrelse &#xE4;r Undervisningsministeriets avdelningschefer samt den svenska ambassadens representant. UNICEF administrerar fonden i enlighet med organisationens egna regler och f&#xF6;rordningar. 

CDPFs &#xF6;vergripande syftet &#xE4;r &quot;att fr&#xE4;mja ett effektivt ledarskap och ledning av utbildningssystemet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er genom systematisk kapacitetsutveckling, f&#xF6;r att d&#xE4;rmed bidra till genomf&#xF6;randet av utbildningssektorns strategiska plan, &#x201D;Education Strategic Plan (ESP) 2014-2018.&quot; M&#xE5;let med denna plan &#xE4;r i sin tur att st&#xE4;rka utbildningssystemets kapacitet f&#xF6;r planering, budgetering, revision och finansiell uppf&#xF6;ljning samt utv&#xE4;rdering, f&#xF6;r att effektivt kunna genomf&#xF6;ra &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r &#xF6;kad j&#xE4;mlikhet, samt &#xF6;kad kvalitet i undervisning och l&#xE4;rande samt bidra till en effektivare administration. De effektm&#xE5;l som ska uppn&#xE5;s genom CDPF baseras p&#xE5; ministeriets &#xF6;vergripande kapacitetsutvecklingsplan f&#xF6;r perioden 2014-2018. Denna plan kommer att uppdateras under 2018 parallellt med framtagandet av den nya strategiska planen f&#xF6;r utbildningssektorn 2019-2022. Effektm&#xE5;len &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande:

1. Att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka Utbildningsministeriets kapacitet f&#xF6;r planering, uppf&#xF6;ljning samt offentlig finansiell styrning f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra reformer inom sektorn.

2. Att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka kapaciteten p&#xE5; provins- och distriktniv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att planera, styra och f&#xF6;lja upp effektivt genomf&#xF6;rande av insatser f&#xF6;r h&#xF6;gre utbildningskvalitet, tillg&#xE5;ng till utbildning och &#xF6;kad j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet inom utbildningssystemet. 

3. Att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka skolors kapacitet f&#xF6;r lokal planering, finansiering och uppf&#xF6;ljning med syftet att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra undervisning och l&#xE4;rande och involvera lokalsamh&#xE4;llet i &#xF6;kad utstr&#xE4;ckning i styrning och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. 

Fonden f&#xF6;rvaltas av UNICEF och finansieras med bidrag fr&#xE5;n EU, Sverige och UNICEF.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
The Capacity Development Partnership Fund (CDPF) was established in 2011 to support key parts of the Cambodian Education Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports&#x2019; (MoEYS) strategic plan for capacity development. The first phase of the fund was operating in 2011-2014 and a second phase in 2015-2017. The two first phases were jointly funded by the EU Delegation in Phnom Penh, Unicef and Sweden. 

The steering committee of the CDPF consists of the State Secretary of the MoEYS, directors of the Ministry&#x2019;s different departments and representatives from the donors. UNICEF together with MoEYS Department of Planning acts as the secretariat of the fund and UNICEF is the fund manager.

The overall objective of the CDPF is to enable effective leadership and management of the education sector through systematic capacity development thereby enabling implementation of the strategic plan for the education sector&#x2019;s development. 

The Policy priorities are: 
1. Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all 
2. Ensure effective leadership and management of education staff at all levels 

The sub-objectives the CDPF Phase III aim to contribute: 
1. To strengthen MoEYS capacity in policy formulation, planning, financing and management of reforms for improved sector performance. 
2. To strengthen capacities at provincial and district levels to plan, manage and monitor education service delivery. 
3. To strengthen school leadership and capacity in relation to planning and management in order to increase participation and learning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the CDPF is to support the implementation of MoEYS Capacity Development Strategic Master Plan (CDMP). The CDMP is based on an analysis of the capacity deficit to implement the Education Strategic Plan (ESP) 2014-2018. A new ESP, aligned to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) will be created during 2018 to guide the development of the sector 2019-2022. In order to implement this new plan a renewed CDMP will be constructed. The Theory of Change for the CDPF III is that by focusing on building capacity in MoEYS policy development, planning, financing, personnel, inclusive and accountable education service delivery and gender equitable leadership the education system will be strengthened to deliver equitable, inclusive and quality education services.
The overall objective of the CDPF is to enable effective leadership and management of the education sector at all levels through systematic capacity development thereby enabling the implementation of the ESP.
The three sub-objectives of the CDPF Phase III aim to contribute:
1. To strengthen MoEYS capacity in planning, monitoring, public financial management, policy implementation and management of education reforms for improved sector performance;
2. To strengthen capacities at provincial and district levels to plan, manage, monitor and ensure effective implementation of policies for improved education service delivery; and
3. To strengthen school-level capacity and accountability in relation to planning, financing and management in order to increase participation and learning.

Six intermediate outcomes of the intervention are expected:
1. Legislation, policy development and implementation are based on research and policy dialogue
2. Development, implementation and monitoring of education plans and budgets at all levels is results-based and of high quality
3. Financing of quality education is equitable, efficient and accountable
4. Human resource planning, deployment and performance management at all levels is of high quality and gender-equity is promoted
5. Education service providers are increasingly committed to, and accountable for, education service delivery that is inclusive, equitable and of enhanced quality and relevance
6. Organisational and technical leadership is gender-equitable</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="111" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Level Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.1 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar fullbordar avgiftsfri och likv&#xE4;rdig grundskole- och gymnasieutbildning av god kvalitet som leder till relevanta och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga kunskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3510003.51000351</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3510003.5100035095</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-21">7020007.020007</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">3510003.51000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">1628717.5478028602</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10524-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/10524-decision-on-contribution-to-cdpf-iii-2018-2021.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution, Capacity Development Partnership Fund III 2018-2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida together with EU, USAID, GPE (Global Partnership for Education) and UNICEF have jointly supported the CDPF III from 2018. During 2020 the CDPF showed progress towards in achieving its objectives and even more importantly the ability to adapt to drastic changes due to the Covid-19 pandemic.

The Covid-19 pandemic has disrupted education as well as other parts of Cambodian society during 2020. All schools were closed from March until the end of the year and most of the staff at central, province and district levels were working from home, to the extent possible given the limited access to online technology for many. The work plan for 2020 for CDPF III had therefor to be adapted and reoriented to a large degree. Some activities planned have not taken place, either postponed or cancelled. A substantial part of the budget has been reallocated to deal with the closure of schools and the instructions not to physically gather teachers or other Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports (MoEYS) personal. Instead a number of activities financed through the fund have taken place through online interactive media.

An emergency assistance was mobilised by the fund to support the MoEYS comprehensive response to the Covid-19 pandemic in the education sector. This nationwide support provided children with the means to continue learning despite school closures; and to prepare schools to re-open and operate safely in the context of the pandemic.

One of the most significant achievements of CDPF in 2020 was the finalisation of the MoEYS functional review, a comprehensive and rigorous process, which provided key advice on how MoEYS could evolved at an organisational level to more efficiently realise its key functions.

Another major contribution made to the education sector by the CDPF was the Joint Education Sector Needs Assessment examining the impact of the pandemic on children, including multi-dimensional impacts, the level of access, quality and effectiveness of distance learning and the capacity development needs of teachers. As an initial response to the pandemic, the funds resources were drawn upon to provide support to MoEYS for the production of inclusive continuous learning materials through the production of video lessons/e-lessons. As the impact of the pandemic in Cambodia deepened, resources from the fund together with other resources, were used to deliver a back to school initiative. This enabled the provision of basic school cleaning and hygiene supplies to all public schools and to conduct a nationwide awareness campaign encouraging good hygiene and pandemic preventative measures. 

Under CDPF Phase III, the activites are organised under six strategic outcome areas, five of which are reflected in the current MoEYS Capacity Development Master Plan (CDMP). The sixth is aiming at increased gender balance at upper management levels. Despite the challenges of the pandemic many of the key education reforms kept slowly progressing with the support of CDPF both at national and subnational levels, including teacher training and in-service development, school-based management, curriculum development, student assessment and inspection, and public financial management (PFM).

The capacity of the Ministry of Education, Youth and Sport (MoEYS) officials to develop and implement policy; the use of financial management systems, and the use of human resource management systems at national and sub-national levels was strengthened through training, mostly online. The capacity of school principals, administrators and teachers on school-based management (SBM), financial management, human resource management, inclusive education, science, technology, engineering and mathematics (STEM) teaching skills, multilingual education (MLE) teaching skills, and minimum quality standards on community pre-school (CPS) curricula were strengthened to effectively manage schools and classrooms. These investments, among others, are helping to improve the quality of education service delivery in Cambodia, helping to create ongoing education opportunities for all Cambodias children. The effect of the Covid-19 pandemic was however that essential parts of the planned activities towards achieving the outcomes in the programme were constrained.

Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 1 on policy and research is constrained.Progress under this strategic outcome was constrained in some areas such as identifying and completing priority research topics. However, CDPF funding allowed MoEYS and the Department of Policy to support building a better and more resilient education system through Covid-19 response and recovery efforts. Undertaking the pandemic Joint Education Needs Assessment, funded by CDPF, was a major collaborative effort between MoEYS, UNICEF, Save the Children and the Education Sector Working Group (ESWG). This assessment generated evidence from over 15,000 survey respondents to better understand the situation of students, caregivers, teachers, school directors, local and subnational officials, teacher trainees and teacher trainers in relation to education attainment in the context of the pandemic. Importantly, the assessment also provided constructive recommendations on how to improve education services to children during this difficult time to curb learning loss.

Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 2 on planning was mostly on track.Much support under this outcome focused on building the knowledge and skills of MoEYS education planners at national and sub-national levels on results-oriented planning and analytical reporting. Furthermore, significant efforts were made to develop the Capacity Development Master Plan (CDMP) 2020-2024 in support of the Education Strategic Plan (ESP) implementation.

To increase the knowledge and understanding of results-based management at the subnational levels, the Department of M&amp;E conducted a series of mentoring and coaching activities in which education managers from provincial and district offices of education built their skills in using results-based management approaches to monitor and evaluate implementation. CDPF continued to support and strengthen the Department of Education Management Information System (EMIS) to improve the availability of timely, accurate, accessible, relevant, reliable and meaningful quality data for making informed decisions.

Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 3 on financing is constrained. Progress under this strategic outcome was constrained in some areas due to Covid-19 prevention measures such as; systematic budget-policy linkage across MoEYS central departments; target provinces using fully functional scholarship data management systems for reporting; and for more complex reasons in other areas such as the transfer of educational functions to subnational levels. In 2020, CDPF continued to strengthen the capacity of MoEYS Department of Finance to improve the Education Financial Management System (EFMS). In particular, investments were made in improving the capacities of national and sub-national budget entities in budget preparation, execution, monitoring and timely reporting. Good gains were made in improving the equity and efficiency of MoEYS national scholarship programmes.

Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 4 on personnel is constrained. Progress under this strategic outcome was constrained in some areas due to Covid-19 prevention measures such as; finalisation and application of the Human Resources Management Information System (HRMIS) quality assessment tool; training of teacher trainers; and delayed for the more complex reason of issues experienced due to inter-ministerial collaboration in areas such as the operationalisation of staff appraisal system at the provincial and central levels. With CDPF support, MoEYS Department of Personnel mobilised technical assistance to support the development of the HRMIS Master Plan, which was completed during the year. This Plan aims to improve the efficiency, effectiveness, equity and fairness of staff management and deployment.

MoEYS conducted functional review of thirty-four technical departments and seven directorates at central level with financial support from CDPF. The review supported the identification and delivery of improvements in the allocation of both functions and capacities across departments and units in MoEYS at central level. The recommendations include actions such as: to review and revise departmental summaries to clearly identify all functions and associated competencies; to link management functions to job descriptions and performance management; to equip departments to adopt the updated organisational structure and; in recognition that managerial capacity must be addressed, use CDPF funding to examine competency needs and use the information to identify suitable mentoring and training to develop the desired level of competency in those individuals.

Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 5 on equity and quality service delivery is constrained. Progress under this strategic outcome was constrained in some areas such as: reaching the target for the number of schools where staff are trained to fully implement school-based management; development of new or updated multilingual education (MLE) teaching and learning materials for five ethnic minority languages and; the adoption of standardised learning assessment guidelines for provincial school inspection teams.

School-based management (SBM) training was conducted online with some restrain although it was estimated through participant surveys that the training was more focused and efficient the the workshop model. The continuation of CDPF support in 2020 for the Multilingual Education Plan (MEAP) enabled MoEYS Special Education Department to operationalise the plan in coordination with stakeholders at sub-national levels, development partners and civil society organisations. Collaboration, funded by CDPF, between the department, UNICEF and CARE resulted in the preparation of a detailed concept note, with recommendations including key steps needed to establish a pre-service MLE teacher training course at Steung Treng Regional Teacher Training College and clear steps on how to revise the existing curriculum and to extend it to accommodate to the addition on a further ethnic minority languages. CDPF supported the development of a teacher training curriculum for educating children with intellectual disabilities and autism.

Work conducted on Strategic Outcome 6 on gender-equitable leadership is constrained. Progress under this strategic outcome was constrained due to Covid-19 prevention measures particularly in the area of launching a professional development programme targeted at women leaders throughout the central and subnational levels of MoEYS. Promoting gender-equitable leadership within MoEYS focuses on integrating gender equity at an institutional level so that gender is considered throughout all aspects of planning, human resource polices and implementation. An important part of this work is also the development and implementation of professional development training and networking opportunities for women at national and sub-national levels of the ministry. Targeted capacity building to promote gender awareness and gender equitable staff management for senior and middle managers was somewhat constrained in 2020 with the postponement of a programme that was expected to benefit 70 women in leadership positions at the national and subnational levels. However, training with the International Training Centre during the last quarter of 2020 resulted in the MoEYS gender master trainings building their competencies and knowledge base of gender equality, gender mainstreaming and organizational change; and how these areas can complement each other.

Work on integrating gender equity at an institutional level focused on a gender audit of MoEYS, which began in the last quarter of 2019. The audit, which concluded in the first quarter of 2020, was a participatory process that promoted organizational learning on mainstreaming gender practically and effectively. As part of this process a wide range of government and non-government stakeholders were consulted. CDPF also provided technical and financial support for the development of MoEYS Gender Mainstreaming Strategic Plan 2021-2024.

. ..

The challenges of reacting and adjusting to the COVID-19 pandemic for the Cambodian education sector were huge as were its impacts on the originally planned capacity building work through the CDPF in 2020. MoEYS took the decision to close all its schools from March 2020 for a period of around six months but was extended to the end of the year. The school closures resulted in disruptions to learning in all of Cambodias estimated 13,482 schools, from pre-school through to upper secondary schools, with an estimated 3.2 million students affected.

The impacts of school closures and social distancing COVID-19 prevention measures on the operations of CDPF and its implementing partners were twofold: (i) by necessity, CDPF turned to respond to this emergency and to support education stakeholders during school closures and students safe return to school; and (ii) previously planned 2020 activities had to be revised, reprioritised and in many cases postponed to ensure the safety of all participants. An important lesson learned from this experience, was if circumstances demand, the CDPF as a mechanism has the ability to respond quickly and comprehensively to sector needs. All these re-focusing and re-planning was done in close cooperation with the donor organisations, Sida, GPE, USAID and UNICEF as fund trustee, and MoEYS different levels.

A persistent challenge in the work of CDPF and MoEYS is the effective development and implementation of result-based planning. The highly centralised planning that occurs within MoEYS, often leads to less locally relevant plans and poor implementation at local levels. In addition, capacity constraints of education staff at all levels to use EMIS data and education statistics to analyse, interpret and explain education issues and report on implementation progress, remains a challenge.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10524" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1000000000" strategy-end-date="2018-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Cambodia 2014-2018</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kambodja 2014-2018 (utfasning till 2022)</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
