<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14659A0102-KHM-43082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodian Development Resource Institute (CDRI) 2021-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Cambodian Development Resource Institute (CDRI) 2021-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia Development Resource Institute (CDRI) is a leading research institution in social science and economy in Cambodia. The institute was established in the beginning of the 1990&#x2019;s and has developed from mainly being a training institution for civil servants to become an independent academic institution and think tank providing civil society, media, the political opposition and the Government with important knowledge and understanding. 
The social science research that the institute conducts in various fields is considered to be extremely important for efforts to increase respect for human rights, a process of democratisation and compliance with the rule of law. 

Sida has contributed to the Cambodia Development Resource Institute (CDRI) since the early 1990s. The contribution is provided in the form of a core support to the research institution with a focus on five main themes: agriculture, economics, education, environment and administration. CDRI&apos;s evidence-based research results are of high quality and can thus contribute with evidence-based basis for policy decisions, reforms and advocacy work at both central and local level, not least via civil society.

With background and for reason stated below, it is decided:

- That Sida shall contribute to the Cambodian Development Resource Institute from 1 July 2021 to 31 December 2023 with the following allocation, SEK 2,500,000 for 2021, SEK 5,000,000 for 2022, SEK 5,000,000 for 2023. In addition, Sida will finance audits up to a value of SEK 500,000 during the activity period.
- That SEK 2,500,000 shall be allocated for this purpose from appropriation item 1: 1.6 Asia financing code 104050301 in 2021.
- That SEK 10,500,000 for coming years for this purpose shall be allocated from the framework for outstanding commitments, with an indicative distribution according to Sida&apos;s budget per year as above.
- That the Head of Development Cooperation on behalf of Sida shall sign the intervention agreement with the Cambodian Development Resource Institute in main accordance with the attached draft agreement.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Cambodia Development Resource Institute (CDRI) &#xE4;r ledande forskningsinstitut inom samh&#xE4;llsvetenskap och ekonomi i Kambodja. Det har funnits fr&#xE5;n b&#xF6;rjan av 1990-talet och har utvecklats fr&#xE5;n ett tr&#xE4;ningsinstitut f&#xF6;r offentligt anst&#xE4;llda till att bli ett frist&#xE5;ende akademiskt institut och tankesmedja som bidrar med viktig kunskap f&#xF6;r civilsamh&#xE4;lle, media, den politiska oppositionen liksom f&#xF6;r beslutsfattare. 

Den samh&#xE4;llsvetenskapliga forskning som institutet bedriver inom olika omr&#xE5;den bed&#xF6;ms vara synnerligen viktiga f&#xF6;r str&#xE4;van f&#xF6;r &#xF6;kad respekt f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, arbete f&#xF6;r en demokratisering och f&#xF6;r efterlevnad av r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer. 

Sida har bidragit till institutet sedan b&#xF6;rjan av 1990-talet. St&#xF6;det ges i form av ett s&#xE5; kallat &quot;k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d&quot; (verksamhetsst&#xF6;d) till forskningsinstitutionen med fokus p&#xE5; fem huvudteman: jordbruk, ekonomi, utbildning, milj&#xF6; och f&#xF6;rvaltning. CDRI:s evidensbaserade forskningsresultat h&#xE5;ller h&#xF6;g kvalitet och kan d&#xE4;rmed bidra med evidensbaserade underlag f&#xF6;r policybeslut, reformer och p&#xE5;verkansarbete p&#xE5; b&#xE5;de central och lokal niv&#xE5; inte minst via civila samh&#xE4;llet.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention as it is presented in CDRI&apos;s proposal is based on five fundamental principles that are expected to contribute to Sida&#x2019;s three priorities in Cambodia - human rights, democracy and rule of law:
? The promotion of democratic governance through a rights-based approach to development.? A &apos;demand-driven&apos; approach to development programmes and projects with clear local ownership.? Long-term institution-building and transparent public engagement.? The integration of gender and vulnerable population and resilience as a cross-cutting issue; and? A focus on local human resource capacity development.
The overall theme for CDRI&#x2019;s research focus for this proposed period will be the on-going dynamics of change affected by the global pandemic and its aftermath impact. The main objectives for CDRI activities during this proposed period to achieve this are:
a) Research: To generate high quality development policy research by the 5 research centers related to Agriculture, Economy, Education, Environment, Governance, and crosscutting themes on democracy, poverty, climate change, digital technology and gender equality.
b) Outreach Communication: To publish and disseminate research knowledge in key local policy forums and in leading regional and international publications
c) Partnership: To strengthen national, regional and international collaborative research, partnerships and networks
d) Capacity Development: To contribute to Cambodia&#x2019;s development research capacity, evidence-based policy making culture, and informed participation of ordinary Cambodian women and men the government&#x2019;s development priorities and performance
e) Institutional Strengthening: To build a more sustainable future for CDRI as Cambodia&#x2019;s leading development policy research institution through institutional strengthening, systematic implementation of capacity development and research career, and effective resource mobilisation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDRI/Cambodia Development Resource Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDRI/Cambodia Development Resource Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">582961.2097611025</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">582961.2097611025</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">470333.1040352575</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">695589.3154869475</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">1165922.419522</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-28">235290.6061630659</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/14659_14659AgreementCDRI.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/14659_14659DecisiononContributionCDRI.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the 2021 CDRI continued to conduct important research projects. A total of 42
projects of research were undertaken, five of which funded under the CDRI-Sida
Resource Partnership. Capacity building for research was provided in 17 training
seminars. CDRI hosted 23 workshops on different topic and participated in 28 external
workshops providing presentations. The institute continued to publish a variety of inhouse publications including working papers, policy briefs, The Annual Cambodia
Development Review.
A major highlight was flexibility in mobilising resources and responding swiftly to both
challenges and opportunities as the global coronavirus pandemic unfolded. The different
research centres reacted quickly, securing new research opportunities and collaborations
to contextualise and understand the multifaceted impacts of Covid-19. The research and
assessments quickly informed Cambodias policy responses to Covid-19.
Some of the research highlights are:
A survey on the impact of COVID-19 pandemic on Cambodian Households:
- investigating the effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on socio-economic wellbeing on
Cambodia&apos;s rural households and the government&apos;s cash transfer to mitigate shock on
rural poor.
- Strategic Covid-19 assessment: a three-year (2020-2023) project of research for
conducting a rapid assessment of the pandemic impact on women&apos;s socio-economic
welfare and vulnerable groups. It also assesses micro, small and medium-sized enterprises
to investigate pathway solutions for government to consider and use for the efforts of
addressing a long-term post pandemic recovery.
- The State of Gender Equality and Climate Change in Cambodia: raising awareness of
the benefits, advantages, and needs for gender responsive climate action by analysing
gendered impacts of climate change and suggesting ways to enhance and mainstream
gender equality into climate relevant sectoral policies</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14659" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1040504" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2750000000" strategy-end-date="2026-12-31" strategy-start-date="2022-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Asia and Oceania 2022-2026</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Asien och Oceanien 2022-2026</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
