<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13640A0102-KHM-43082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum II 2020-2023 Policy research</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Future Forum II 2020-2023 Policy research</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum&#x2019;s overall objective is to encourage intellectual research and thinking, to positively influence the policy narrative in Cambodia at a local, national and international level, employing evidence-based policy debate, analysis and recommendations in order to contribute to democratic, political and socio-economic change that will benefit all peoples of Cambodia. A special focus is on outreach to youth, women, grassroot communities and minorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Future Forum &#xE4;r en oberoende kambodjansk tankesmedja, etablerad 2015. Huvudsyftet med tankesmedjan &#xE4;r att genomf&#xF6;ra oberoende samh&#xE4;llsvetenskapliga studier av h&#xF6;g kvalitet, stimulera en evidensbaserad politisk debatt och d&#xE4;rmed p&#xE5;verka den kambodjanska politiska diskursen p&#xE5; ett positivt s&#xE4;tt. Ambitionen &#xE4;r vidare att inkludera ett brett antal akt&#xF6;rer i arbetet, inklusive politiska partier, regeringen, statsf&#xF6;rvaltningen och det civila samh&#xE4;llet. Tankesmedjan har ocks&#xE5; som ambition att utbilda och tr&#xE4;na blivande forskare och analytiker. Ungdomar och studenter &#xE4;r en viktig m&#xE5;lgrupp. En s&#xE4;rskild satsning kommer ocks&#xE5; att g&#xF6;ras f&#xF6;r att f&#xE5; med grupper som inte alltid h&#xF6;rs i debatten, s&#xE5;som kvinnor, gr&#xE4;srotsgrupper och etniska, religi&#xF6;sa och sociala minoriteter. 

Den f&#xF6;rsta fasen av det svenska st&#xF6;det till insatsen genomf&#xF6;rdes under perioden 1 juli 2017 till 30 juni 2020. Det svenska st&#xF6;det uppgick till 3,3 miljoner kronor (54 % av den totala budgeten). St&#xF6;det l&#xE4;mnades som k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till Future Forums verksamhet. 

Future Forum har inkommit med ett programf&#xF6;rslag om en ny genomf&#xF6;rande period fr&#xE5;n 1 juli 2020 till 31 december 2022. Det f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade svenska st&#xF6;det uppg&#xE5;r till 5,5 miljoner svenska kronor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The core support to Future Forum aims to contribute to the implementation of a programme entitled &#x201C;the Young Researchers Programme&#x201D; (2020-2022). Future Forum is an independent Cambodian think tank that focuses on research, analysis and public policy. The think tank was established in 2015. 

The main objective of the think tank is to encourage independent social scientific research and thinking and through that positively influence the Cambodian policy narrative and stimulate an evidence-based policy debate. Future Forum is also set up to respond to the need for more independent analysts and researchers that can conduct objective policy research. The think tank strives to include a wide number of actors in its operations and activities, including different political parties, the government, the state administration and civil society. Young people and students are an important target group. A special effort is made to include groups that are not always heard in policy and social debate, such as women, grassroots groups, and ethnic, religious and social minorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A to be procured</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">58296.1209761103</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">58296.1209761103</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-11">54290.584926</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13640_13640AgreementFF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/cambodia/13640_13640DecisiononcontributioFF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Forum had two core programs in 2021: (1) the Young Researchers Training Program (YRP) and (2) Research Partnership. In addition, Future Forum had two cross-cutting arms to support the successful proliferation of our mission and vision: (3) the Research Community and (4) The Hub.

The biggest challenge for Future Forum during 2021, just as for the world in general, was the continued impacts of Covid-19 on the ability to deliver all planned activities and outputs. For example, in the context of the Young Research programme (YRP), three of the fellows contracted Covid-19 and therefore needed an extended timeframe to complete their respective research projects. An additional four fellows dropped out from the program due to their health, urgent family commitment, and personal development concerns. Due to the requirements to minimise interaction, some program activities including major annual fieldwork and institutional visits at Embassies, government offices (National Assembly, National Institute of Statistics), NGOs, and other research institutions were cancelled.

To accommodate to the challenges of the pandemic the organisation had to create and operate hybrid model to ensure that work was being undertaken and meeting deadlines. For this several ways to deliver planned technical capacity development activities were identified. Rooted in the Learning by Doing philosophy, Future Forum saw that class-time lectures were kept at a minimum-efficient level and streamlined for the most relevant and quality content. This allowed for more time and space for discussion and application interactions. To cater to this, the program implemented a blended learning module with flipped-classroom strategies to supplement the traditional mode of learning delivery in a more structured and systematic way.

Future Forums flagship training program is the YRP. From the very beginning of the organisation in 2015 training of young researchers was seen as essential. The form for this has however changed considerably and has now found its form as the YRP.  Beginning operation in 2018, the YRP is an intensive, one-year policy training and coaching program designed for recent Cambodian graduates and young professionals. Through individualised training and mentoring, the YRP aims to empower the fellows to become competent in policy research and analysis with the intention that they can influence and contribute to shaping public policy discourse by serving in government, civil society, tertiary education, or research institutions. The program is primarily a learning-through-doing exposure to policy research, designed around lectures, seminars, and the writing of peer-reviewed academic journal-quality original research, policy briefs, and commentary articles for national and regional media. There are about 20 young research fellows enrolled in the YRP per cohort.

During 2021 the fellows in the YRP conducted a number of research and published articles and papers in a variate of fields.  Four policy research papers in the area of urban studies, public health, tourism and future currency, have been reviewed and will be published in the Journal of Future Cambodia (JFC) to be released in the mid-2022. The continued impacts of Covid-19 have otherwise challenged. Three research projects had to adjust their methodology due to the pandemic and are in the process of completing their papers as should also be ready for publication in the JFC journal.

Ten policy-related op-eds and commentaries written by the young fellows have been published at various local and international media outlets, including the Phnom Penh Post, Diplomat, SEAGlobe, VOD, and RealEstate News over the course of six months. Additional 19 articles are awaiting editorial review and publication in the first half of 2022.

The Research Partnership program is the research centre of the organisation and is cross-cutting along programmatic and study area lines to support the development of policy-oriented solutions through multiple mediums of publication and in collaboration with multiple donors and partners specifically the Community of Researchers.

Some of the research programmes that Future Forum participated in 2021 were:

- BRI Monitor a collaborative effort by five civil society organisations in Southeast Asia and the Pacific (CIPE, IDEAS, ADRi, SGI, and INA) to promote transparency and accountability in major infrastructure projects funded through the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) in the region.
- The third volume of Cambodia 2040 was published in 2021. Future Forum has, in partnership with the Konrad Adenauer Stiftung, engaged Cambodian researchers and authors to address important issues for the possible development of the country until 2040.  Three edited volumes have been published, examining 28 different areas of socio-economic development, ranging from monetary policy to the fourth industrial revolution to ecological diplomacy.
- Future Forum, for the Asia Foundation, together with Angkor Research and Consulting did a study called Covid-19 Economic Impact Study. Unpacking the results.
- Future Forum is undertaking research and analysis of the Cambodian microfinance industry in the wake of the Covid-19 pandemic. Ongoing from 2020 and will be finalised in 2022.
- In order to support civic engagement towards a peaceful, inclusive, and equitable society through expanding opportunities for inclusive civic engagement, using dialogue and analysis Future Forum is conducting a project called Research Design through a Social Inclusion Lens.
-The first volume of the book The World We Want (Digital Futures) brought together a collection of local experts to examine over 25 different topics exploring Cambodias opportunity in the global order.

Future Forum is actively, and on an ongoing basis, building a community of researchers who are focused on public policy issues. The community of researchers is a network of both internal and external researchers who engage in opportunities to network with other members of the community and work in collaboration with other members of the community.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13640" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
