<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27016</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WBG Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Development Impact of this project is likely to be high.  The specific development impacts of this project would be:

Significant improvement to the enabling environment for the creation of a viable housing finance market in West Bank.  Institutional and legal constraints today create major obstacles to mortgage lending.  It is expected that the removal of such obstacles particularly registration of titles, difficulty of foreclosures will encourage lenders to come into the market and scale up their lending programs.

Access to finance for middle and low income individuals.  The project will make affordable, long term home finance available to a significant number of people in the low and middle income brackets.  The homes financed will help improve the living standards of the borrowers as they get access to safe and more spacious housing as compared to the overcrowded and cramped conditions they currently face.  The longer term of the mortgages to be provided under the program will play a major role in making homes more affordable by reducing the monthly payments to a level that could be serviced by a broader segment of the population.

Boost to the construction sector:  Although the program is intended to fund only mortgages and not construction, the creation of effective demand by the financing available under the program will encourage developers to take a more active approach in developing their projects as the risk to them will be reduced by an increase in the number of  potential buyers.  The program may include financing of progress payments for booking of units in multifamily housing developments in the construction phase.

Restarting the mortgage market.  As the program will be making mortgages under a difficult environment, it would be sending a positive signal to other institutions.  The success of the project would encourage other entities to come into this market and help build a more sustainable housing finance market in West Bank.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project would establish a program for affordable home loans to lower and middle income segments of the Palestinian Population initially in the West Bank and when conditions permit, in Gaza. The initiative takes a long, term programmatic approach to improve the lives of Palestinian families living in unsafe, substandard or severely cramped housing conditions in West Bank and Gaza.   The program would combine the provision of technical assistance for the development of the overall mortgage market in Palestine and the availability of long term mortgages that would be designed to make home ownership affordable to target segments of the Palestinian population. A mortgage servicing company AMAL would be formed to perform certain master servicing and other functions related to the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFFORDABLE MORTGAGE AND LOAN CORPORATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27016" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-04-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Robert Drumheller
Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC)
Vice President of Structured Finance,
1100 New York Avenue, NWWashington, D.C. 20527
Telephone: 202 336 8480</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank and Gaza</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-West Bank and Gaza">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project shall operate initially in the West Bank. Commencement of the project in other geographic areas otherwise eligible for support, such as Gaza, shall be subject to the unanimous agreement of the Lenders.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.0000000000 35.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA - Primary Mortgage Institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $75.40 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-04-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-04-13">75400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-04-13">75400000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFFORDABLE MORTGAGE AND LOAN CORPORATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27016/wbg-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
