<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011808-01-6</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water knowledge: Egyptian- Italian Water training Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Con un focus geografico sull&apos;Egitto e sui Paesi del bacino del Nilo, l&apos;iniziativa mira a migliorare le conoscenze specifiche e professionali e una visione condivisa sull&apos;acqua come contributo prezioso per migliorare un approccio integrato di gestione delle risorse idriche a livello istituzionale attraverso lo sviluppo delle capacit&#xE0; istituzionali, l&apos;intervento infrastrutturale, il potenziamento della rete, miglioramento della qualit&#xE0; della formazione. L&apos;obiettivo di cui sopra, pienamente pertinente sia con la cooperazione italiana che con le priorit&#xE0; del governo egiziano, sar&#xE0; raggiunto attraverso il raggiungimento dei 2 seguenti risultati: Risultato 1: l&apos;infrastruttura fisica e tecnica e le attrezzature di RTSWRI sono migliorate per ospitare un innovativo centro di servizi di addestramento in acqua nella regione. Questo risultato contribuisce a raggiungere l&apos;obiettivo del progetto garantendo un adeguato supporto fisico e metodologico unito a un miglior livello di erogazione della formazione per l&apos;RTSWRI. Risultato 2: la qualit&#xE0; del sistema di addestramento RTSWRI nel campo acquatico &#xE8; migliorata rispettivamente in termini di metodologie di insegnamento e abilit&#xE0; manageriali per i formatori e acquisizione di conoscenze / leadership per i tirocinanti. Questo risultato contribuisce a costruire un centro di formazione flessibile ed efficiente in Egitto e nella regione. Corsi di formazione di alto livello in Egitto e in Italia saranno erogati a 20 giovani impiegati egiziani, 60 funzionari egiziani di diversi ministeri chiave per la gestione dell&apos;acqua a diversi livelli, 20 funzionari regionali dei paesi del bacino del Nilo e 20 istruttori egiziani, 2 tecnici di laboratorio, per un totale di 142 diretti beneficiari. Inoltre, attraverso l&apos;e-learning una stima n. di 700 beneficiari potrebbero essere raggiunti. L&apos;iniziativa rientra nella strategia nazionale egiziana 2030 per lo sviluppo sostenibile e avr&#xE0; una durata complessiva di 24 mesi. L&apos;agenzia esecutiva &#xE8; CIHEAM Bari, che funger&#xE0; anche da agenzia esecutiva, in collaborazione con Hydroaid.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With a geographical focus on Egypt and Nile Basin Countries, the initiative aims at enhancing specific and professional knowledge and a shared vision on water as valuable contribution to improve an integrated water management approach at Institutional level through institutional capacity development, infrastructural intervention, network enhancing, training quality improvement.The objective above, fully relevant both with the Italian Cooperation and Egyptian Government priorities, will be attained through achievement of the 2 following results: Result 1: The Physical and technical infrastructure and Equipment of RTSWRI is enhanced to host an innovative water training services hub in the region. This result contribute to reach the project objective by ensuring proper physical and methodological support to an improved level of training delivery for the RTSWRI. Result 2: The RTSWRI Training system quality in the water field is improved respectively in terms of teaching methodologies and managerial skills for trainers and knowledge/leadership acquisition for trainees.This result contribute to reach the project objective, aiming to ensure a flexible and efficient training hub in Egypt and in the region. High level trainings in Egypt and in Italy will be delivered to 20 youth Egyptian employees, 60 Egyptian officials of several key ministries for water management at different level, 20 regional officials from Nile Basin countries and 20 Egyptian trainers, 2 Lab technicians, for a total of 142 direct beneficiaries. Furthermore, through e-learning an estimated n. of 700 beneficiaries might be reached. The initiative falls within the national Egyptian strategy 2030 for Sustainable Development and will have a whole duration of 24 months. The executing Agency is CIHEAM Bari, who will act also as implementing Agency, jointly with Hydroaid.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="47019" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="47019" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="47019" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIHEAM - CENTRO INTERNAZIONALE DI ALTI STUDI AGRONOMICI MEDITERRANEI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011808/01/6" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="11430" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advanced technical and managerial training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14081" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education and training in water supply and sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially increase the supply of qualified teachers, including through international cooperation for teacher training in developing countries, especially least developed countries and small island developing States</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially increase water-use efficiency across all sectors and ensure sustainable withdrawals and supply of freshwater to address water scarcity and substantially reduce the number of people suffering from water scarcity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-10">2268838</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIHEAM - CENTRO INTERNAZIONALE DI ALTI STUDI AGRONOMICI MEDITERRANEI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
