<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-GCRF-GCRF-INTPART-UKSA-GCRF-INTPART-CALL-2-UKSA_C2_07ab</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EcoProMIS 2.0</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The project will create a data analytics system &#x201C;EcoProMIS&#x201D; to transform data into affordable, accurate and actionable knowledge and decision support for land management in Colombia. The focus is on how to preserve biodiversity and reduce greenhouse gasses in crops and ecosystems including rice, palm oil, tropical savannah, forest and wetland systems.  Currently rice and oil palm compete for land and resources (e.g. water) with tropical savannah, forest and wetland systems; individual decisions taken by farmers at the local scale mean that optimum allocation of land and resources is typically not achieved, increasing negative environmental impacts and making farming less sustainable in the long term. Providing local decision makers with clear, comprehensive regional data will enable them to make informed land use choices and will help to ensure that the incomes of smallholders and farmers, which are dependent on rice and/or oil palm, are sustainable.
The international collaboration facilitated by this project allows Colombia to draw on UK expertise, whilst in turn helping the UK partners develop new marketable services for the longer term.  The project will deliver benefits for the sustainable development of land management in Colombia, for the first time drawing on UK expertise in the interpretation of satellite data.  The benefits for the international project participants are:
&#x2022;	Cenipalma represents palm oil growers and Fedearroz represents rice growers in Colombia and both therefore have a direct interest in facilitating more sustainable production systems.
&#x2022;	CIAT, Colombia, works across 53 countries in the tropics and will use the ouputs from the project to assist its work in Colombia and other countries which grow rice and palm oil where there are similar challenges in relation to both crop productivity and the links between farming and environmental stewardship.
&#x2022;	The project will provide CIAT, Fedearroz, Cenipalma and Solidaridad with additional sources of free data to support their work with stakeholders in Colombia and therefore build their capacity to run research, extension and support programmes with land managers, farmers and smallholders.
The benefits for Colombia are:
&#x2022;	The integration of farming and natural habitat management so that a profitable farming industry can co-exist with climate change programmes and policies to protect the natural environment, ensuring that biodiversity is preserved and greenhouse gas emissions are managed in the long term (SDG13).&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricompas</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-EA31" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Space Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="43041" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-31">111035.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="70">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricompas</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-31">205446.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="70">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricompas</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
