<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BRA576</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISA/CIR - Cruviana Project - Alternative Energy solutions for indigenous communities in the Amazon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy sources in isolated systems in the Amazon are based on burning of fossil fuels, with high carbon emissions which are highly pollutant. In 2010 around 1.3 billion litres of diesel oil were burnt to keep these systems running in the Amazon , the same region where plans to build large dams for energy &apos;export&apos; to urban centres prevail. Without suitable alternatives, they depend on supply of diesel oil, transported along hundreds of kilometres of roads or waterways, under a local scheme controlled by agents or authorities that exploit local populations through abusive trade and transport arrangements. Therefore there is a need to seek permanent energy solutions for the Amazonian populations that live far from the grid, in indigenous communities or small urban centres. 
The abundance of solar radiation, forests and rivers in the Amazon provides great potential for renewable energy sources such as biomass, solar, water or wind in the case of the indigenous land, Raposa Serra do Sol. This project aims to research the viability of renewable energy solutions that are decentralized, autonomous, efficient and easy to operate, which can lead to a decrease in fossil fuel energy dependence of indigenous communities and small urban centres in the Amazon. The results of this research will be used for advocacy purposes with the federal government to incorporate in its long term energy expansion programme &#x2018;Luz para Todos&#x2019; (Light for Everyone). The areas selected are the regions where ISA is established at the local level, namely: Xingu, Raposa Serra do Sol and Upper Rio Negro. ISA started this project &#x2018;Cruviana&#x2019; in March 2010, and has been working with CAFOD partner, CIR to assess wind energy potential in the indigenous land, Raposa Serra do Sol. This next phase of the project will involve: installation of two hybrid energy generation systems in two indigenous communities financed by the governmental programme Light For All, the inclusion of 8 indigenous communities in the same programme and other public policies, a new study of wind/solar energy potential in two indigenous communities, and training community members on risk management and to advocate for their rights to sustainable energy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA576" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA576" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto SocioAmbiental</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BRA576" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="23030" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-01">24000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="49269">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-22">24000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="63628">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-22">24000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto SocioAmbiental</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
