<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BRA630</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Brasileira Floods response - Bahia and Minas Gerais - phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the second phase of the BRA626 emergency response. It aims to scale up support to affected families that have been impacted by a tropical cyclone that hit Minas Gerais and Bahia states in Brazil very badly in December 2021, and has since caused landslides, severe flooding and dam breaks causing many more thousands to be made homeless and without access to their basic needs. Caritas Brasileira intends to increase its target group from 110 to 186 of the most vulnerable families in the municipalities of Ilheus (Bahia) and Palmopolis (Minas Gerais) to distribute further cash transfer cards for three monthly payments of BRL450 (c. &#xA3;64.30 @ 7) totalling BRL 1350 (&#xA3;193 @ 7) to these 76 additional families. Please see the people and communities section of BRA626 for more information. 

In both municipalities, many communities (hundreds of families) remain invisible and abandoned by the public authorities and have been forgotten by national media. Caritas Brasileira staff report that both Ilh&#xE9;us and Palm&#xF3;polis have areas that are completely unassisted by either local government or NGOs. Families impacted by the rains report minimal support from the local parish in the form of a basket of donated goods. But donations have decreased considerably, and urgent needs of affected communities continue to be drinking water, food, clothes, mattresses, nappies for children and sanitary items for women/older people, medicines and hygiene items. 

An extratropical cyclone that formed in the Atlantic Ocean, caused by low pressure on the southern coast of Brazil has led to torrential rains and extreme floods in the south of Bahia and the Jequitinhonha valley of Minas Gerais. By 18/2/22, flooding, landslides and dam breaks had affected more than 900,000 people. In total, 311 municipalities declared a state of emergency (166 in Bahia and 145 in Minas Gerais). According to Civil Defence Authorities, a total of 103,848 people were forced to leave their homes due to flood damage in both states. In Bahia, a total of 86,705 people had to be relocated, of which 26,606 people needed emergency shelter and 60,099 people were able to move temporarily to family or friends&#x2019; house. In Minas Gerais, a total of 17,143 people had to be relocated, with 3,409 people living in temporary shelters and 13,734 people currently living with family or friends. It is expected that 20% of the homes from the relocated families have been destroyed and need to be rebuilt, but official data is not yet available. The heavy rains were responsible for the deaths of 35 people (26 in Bahia and 9 in Minas Gerais).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA630" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BRA630" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xE1;ritas Brasileira</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BRA630" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-01-03">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55786">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-03">30000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70627">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-03">30000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xE1;ritas Brasileira</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
