<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-180138</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support food safety through capacity building along food value chain in Quzhou, China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Being a major supplier of the food and agro-products in the region of south-east China and honored to supply food to the G20 Summit taking place in Hangzhou in September 2016, Quzhou has the potential of sustainable agricultural production in the region and to serve the huge demands for safe food and agro-products in the adjacent areas such as the Yangtze River Delta, Pan-Pearl Delta and Western Side of Taiwan Strait Economic Zone. With also the vision of targeting better compliance with international standards and accessing to international markets, the initiative keen on developing the agricultural clusters in Quzhou and establishing a World Food Safety Innovation Demonstration Zone, launched and supported by the Government of Quzhou, is seeking technical cooperation with national and international agencies working under relevant mandate as experienced and reliable service partners.
The Zone located in Qujiang District, Quzhou City aims to effectively promoting sustainable development of food nutrition and health integrating validated knowledge transfer, scientific research and innovation, policy making and agenda setting, compliance with regulation and standard, development of manufacturing and processing, commercial activities and trade, promotion and leisure entertainment. Five functional zones will be established in the core area of the Zone to build a food safety management system covering the entire value chain from farm to fork and food industrial development, seeking to be eligible for a national food safety and quality demonstration base, encourage compliance and consumer trust, and contribute to international recognition and trade.

UNIDO received the request for technical support and cooperation on food safety, nutrition and health in the framework of the Zone, which accommodates the consistency with UNIDO&#x2019;s mandate of promoting sustainable food systems that deliver food and nutrition security without compromising economic, social, and environmental bases to generate food security and nutrition for future generations. UNIDO identifies, develops and manages programmes to improve the competitiveness of the agro-food processing sector through access to support services, markets and trade opportunities, and contributes to the capacity-building of food system support institutions and skill development agencies through its advisory and convening activities.
Food safety is also top-highlighted on the agenda of the cooperation between UNIDO and China. Both the &#x201C;UNIDO-China Strategic Cooperation Framework 2018 &#x2013; 2021&#x201D; and the &#x201C;UNIDO Country Programme for China 2016-2020&#x201D; signed between the Ministry of Commerce of China and UNIDO recognize food safety as one of the key emphases of the UNIDO-China cooperation. This project will reflect the food safety approach of UNIDO leading to safer food for sustainable and resilient business, and highlight the intervention as well responding to the requirements and demands of the Zone when envisaging to create a Food Safety Service Center with multiple operational duties, through which UNIDO&#x2019;s core functions as of technical cooperation, policy analysis and advice, norms and standards and convening and partnerships, could be confirmed towards achieving the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust Fund for Increased Food Security through Agribusiness</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-180138" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.320412 104.187418</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quzhou</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.95944 118.86861</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">9934.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">6780.14</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="180138-0-01-01-2018-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">9934.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="180138-0-01-01-2018-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">9643.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="180138-0-01-01-2019-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">6780.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="180138-0-01-01-2019-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">6823</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
