<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing the energy, water, food and climate nexus through organic waste to energy solutions in the Metropolitan Region of Recife</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is based on an official request of the Government of the State of Pernambuco. It aims to lay the foundation for a larger project to be implemented in partnership with the Government, private sector and with support of international climate finance. The project addresses the sensitive energy, water, food and climate nexus in the Metropolitan Region of Recife (RMR) by promoting the use of organic waste to energy solutions (WTE).

The project is of cross-sectoral nature and contributes to the implementation of several federal, state-level and urban policies and regulations, such as the Solid Waste Plan of RMR, the State Plan for Solid Residues of Pernambuco, the Recife Sanitation Plan, the Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC), as well as the recently adopted 2050 National Energy Plan with its ambitious renewable energy targets. Solid waste management, water and sanitation, energy security and climate change adaptation are major interrelated concerns of the Metropolitan Region of Pernambuco (RMR), which includes 15 municipalities, provides livelihood for around 4 million people and hosts major industries in the region.

The overall objective of the project is to address the energy, water, food and climate nexus by promoting the use of organic waste to energy (WTE) solutions in the Metropolitan Region of Pernambuco (RMR). The project comprises a 16 months preparatory phase, which foresees the development of relevant assessments for two pilot projects and the formulation of a project document for the main phase. The preparatory phase includes the following results:

1. Assessment  of the Camaragibe landfill and recommendations for environmental improvement, including the identification of investment opportunities for organic WTE;
2. Assessment  of organic WTE investment opportunities (e.g. biogas, biomethane) on the island of Fernando de Noronha;
3. Formulation of a project document for the main phase and mobilisation of climate finance for the implementation;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210120" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-09-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-9.781292 -53.880595</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recife</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-8.05389 -34.88111</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">39823</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
