<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200274</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scaling up resource optimization for technical cooperation in UNIDO departments</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A task force on Resource Optimization for Technical Cooperation (ROTC) was established to design and pilot new modes of TC delivery along the project cycle with the aim to more efficiently use regular budget and voluntary contributions available to the Secretariat.
On 8 March 2019, the Executive Board decided to pilot the application of the new ROTC business model in the Department of Agribusiness and requested the Department to report regularly on progress.
In response, the Department of Agribusiness identified five areas of focus for the optimization of resources in the TC cycle. Working with colleagues in CMO/PRO, CMO/HRM, CMO/ITS, CMO/FIN, ODG/IOD, and the directors of the different technical departments, the concepts and their pilot implementation were further refined. The piloting commenced in April 2019 with the preparation of the standardized modules; establishing and training teams for shared procurement and recruitment services; and preparing standard operating procedures for the new shared services.
The first draft of the standard operating procedures for shared services was finalized in December 2019 and the beginning of January 2020. Extensive briefings to the technical departments, CMO and the Field Offices were undertaken and regular briefings to the EB on the ROTC pilot progress were also provided, the most recent in June 2020. Nine briefings for senior managers of TC departments were conducted, wherein feedback was obtained and further clarifications given.

In August 2020, EB approved to proceed with scaling up/expansion (with focus on fine-tuning department-related matters), Mobilize continued support of relevant departments/divisions with an approved amount of 100,000 EUR from regular programme of technical cooperation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200274" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">36809.82</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
