<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-180055</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Low-Carbon Infrastructure Framework and Implementation Guidelines for the Belt and Road Initiative</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) is a major development strategy led by China since 2013. A large component of the BRI is large scale infrastructure investment, with total investment estimates in the range 1 to 2 trillion USD. This volume represents a large opportunity to create unprecedented economic growth along the BRI, however, if implemented without sufficient regard for sustainability and climate impacts, the initiative may also pose unprecedented environmental risks. Given the long life spans of the infrastructure being implemented and the high capital cost, there is a very real risk that inaction now will lead to a lock in to unsustainable and high carbon infrastructure for decades to come. As many projects along the BRI are in advanced stages of development time to influence their design is very limited. Several initiatives exist that are aiming to improve environmental, social and governance (ESG) aspects along the BRI. Despite these efforts, there remains a lack of uptake of sustainability standards along the BRI. Key reasons for this include: a lack of incentive for contractors to implement high ESG standards; a lack of clarity as to which standards should apply; additional cost and time implications perceived by project planners, developers and procurers; a lack of capacity of planners and procurers; and a high degree of complexity related to the diversity of project types as well as socio-political and regulatory landscapes along the BRI.

This project will accelerate the uptake of carbon neutral standards through the development of a Carbon Neutral Infrastructure Framework and Implementation Guidelines. The framework and guidelines will be developed through a multi-stakeholder process and would complement existing efforts to green the belt and road. The proposed approach would build upon existing standards and focus on making these standards appropriate for implementation along the BRI, whilst working to build clear incentive structures for their rapid uptake.

Once implemented, the approach will: reduce greenhouse gas emissions from BRI infrastructure; boost resilience against future climate change impacts; ensure infrastructure is compliant with international sustainability standards and creates co-benefits; and ultimately assist to improve creditworthiness of improved projects and participating governments thereby attracting additional infrastructure investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-180055" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="C6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">16166</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">7331.96</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="180055-0-01-01-2018-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">16166</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="C6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="180055-0-01-01-2018-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">15756.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="C6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="180055-0-01-01-2019-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">7331.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="C6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="180055-0-01-01-2019-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">7199.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="C6" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
