<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190365</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arab Food Safety Initiative for Economic Integration</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Since 2014 UNIDO has been successfully implementing the Sida-funded project &#x201C;Enhancement of regional trade capacities in food through harmonized regional conformity assessment and food safety systems&#x201D;, called the SAFE initiate. For this regional programme the donor approved only in November 2019 an extension of additional nine months, meaning it will eventually close in September 2020. The remaining time is being used to enable the conduct of the final independent evaluation of the project and to continue full support to the effective implementation of planned sustainability interventions.

2) UNIDO held throughout 2019 regular consultations with Sida to jointly explore options to further strengthen the fruitful cooperation and to build on the organizations&#x2019; common efforts of enhancing food safety and regional trade capacities in food in the region. Overall, Sida&#x2019;s commitment to strengthening regional economic integration in this field in the Arab region has been strongly embedded in their development cooperation strategy 2016 &#x2013; 2020, and it will also be an important pillar in their new strategy that will commence in 2021. Accordingly, Sida strongly encouraged UNIDO to keep actively engaging with relevant partners at regional and international level until the start of the new strategy. Furthermore, Sida also expressed its clear aim to reduce the number of agreements concluded with partners towards a more coordinated effort between implementing agencies under a &#x201C;one package&#x201D; offer, and therefore encouraged UNIDO to foster and steer consultations on the advancement of regional economic integration in the Arab region with potential implementation partners.

3) Besides Sida there are also other potential donors, such as the World Bank (WB) and the Islamic Development Bank (IsDB), which expressed their interest in joining forces with UNIDO in advancing regional economic integration in the Arab region by further upgrading legislative and institutional food safety capacities and through the upgrading of selected food value chains/trade corridors. While the World Bank has directly approached UNIDO and expressed their willingness and readiness to promote a large Food Safety Programme in the MENA region, it is one of the project&#x2019;s main counterparts, namely the Arab Industrial and Mining Organization (AIDMO), which in parallel has initiated discussions with the Islamic Development Bank. The latter has expressed strong interest to support a regional food safety initiative under the IsDB&#x2019;s regional cooperation and integration operational strategy that was launched only in December 2019.

4) Aiming at eventually preparing such a large-scale programme, a preparatory assistance project shall hence be launched in 2020, and get implemented in full complementarity with the already approved extension of the Sida-funded project. Official requests for support in the formulation of a fully-fledged technical assistance programme were also officially submitted to the DG of UNIDO by the DG of the Arab Organization of Agricultural Development and by the Assistant Secretary General of the League of Arab States. Both organizations officially approached UNIDO to express their full satisfaction with the achievements made by the SAFE programme, and to request for UNIDO&#x2019;s assistance in the design of a follow-up phase. The latter shall aim at the consolidation and scaling-up of what has been achieved to date, and support already initiated sustainability efforts (see the attached official request letters dated 8th November and 19th November 2019).

5) Against the above, the purpose of this preparatory assistant request is hence to further pave the ground for the implementation of a large-scale food safety initiative in the Arab region as of 2021, called the Arab Food Safety Initiative for Economic Integration. Aiming at establishing a fundamental basis for such a programme and to facilitate required policy dialogue with concerned decision-makers in the region, as well as negotiations with possible additional donors, it is essential to obtain clear data on the economics of food safety in the region and to establish a collaboration mechanism among all relevant partners. Therefore, it is proposed to use the requested UNIDO PA funding mainly for the conduct of an economic impact assessment in regard to food safety in the Arab region, for facilitating continuous consultations with relevant stakeholders at regional (i.e. LAS, AIDMO, AOAD) and international level (i.e. WB, FAO, UNDP), and eventually for the formulation of a large-scale programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190365" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">76318.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">29100.58</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">25549.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1 - Economic Impact Assessm.</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">26212.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1 - Economic Impact Assessm.</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">2606</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1 - Economic Impact Assessm.</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">3452.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1 - Economic Impact Assessm.</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-02-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">50768.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2 - Consultations</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-02-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">53674.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2 - Consultations</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">26494.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2 - Consultations</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190365-0-01-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">25346.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2 - Consultations</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M5" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
