<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-140211</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting ISID in Europe and Central Asia region: UNIDO#s input to the regional conference on industrialization in the 21st century</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the first UNIDO Regional Conference on Industrial Parks held in Baku, Azerbaijan, in 2012, and the 15th UNIDO General Conference in Lima, Peru, in 2013, the Ministry of Economy and Industry of the Republic of Azerbaijan (MEI) requested UNIDO to collaborate on the organisation of a conference on Industrialization in the twenty-first century: The main trends, modern approaches and best practice experiences, with a focus on
industrial parks and zones, to be held in Baku on 26-27 November 2014. The conference will be organized within the context of the 2014 &#x201C;Year of Industry&#x201D; in Azerbaijan, as decreed by the President of Azerbaijan. The main objective of the conference is to review the main industrialization trends in the 21st century, with a focus on Azerbaijan, and modern approaches and best practice experiences on using various instruments, including industrial parks and zones and investment partnership models, for pursuing inclusive and sustainable industrial development. The conference, as an example of UNIDO&#x2019;s convening and dissemination function, will bring together experts, practitioners and government officials from the Europe and Central Asia region to share experience, knowledge, know-how and best practices.

The conference builds on the discussions and recommendations of the UNIDO General Conference in Lima in 2013 and UNIDO forums on pursuing inclusive and sustainable industrial development in 2014. During the first
UNIDO global forum on 23-23 June 2014, participants engaged in a strategic dialogue on strategies and policies to pursue inclusive and sustainable industrial development as a response to new development challenges; the role of business infrastructure, such as industrial parks, zones, cities and districts, as an integral part of strategic and targeted planning, and as a concrete and well-circumscribed instrument and an area of rapidly growing demand for UNIDO services; and on leveraging the power of partnerships for resource mobilization and implementation of strategies and policies. Member States recommended that, in addition to the global approach, UNIDO should also provide a regional focus and organize similar conferences at the regional level.

In addition, the conference also builds on UNIDO&#x2019;s Europe and Central Asia Regional Programme on Industrial Parks and its first conference in Azerbaijan in 2012, which was supported by the governments of Azerbaijan and Slovenia. Following the first conference, the Government of Slovenia requested UNIDO to establish a platform for regional dialogue and cooperation on industrial parks and within this framework the second regional
conference was held in Ljubljana, Slovenia, on 8-9 April 2014, with a focus on science, industry and technology parks. The conference in Azerbaijan will therefore contribute to this platform for promoting inclusive and sustainable industrial development in the Europe and Central Asia region using instruments such as industrial parks in their various forms.

Following consultations with the MEI, it was agreed that UNIDO will support the Ministry&#x2019;s initiative as a partner together with GIZ and will co-organize a conference, including the preparation of the aide memoire, advice on the selection of participants, panellists and moderators, substantive contributions and presentations in sessions on industrial parks and partnerships, transcription of conference discussions and recommendations, design of the conference logo, press releases, conference video, and a final summary report. For this purpose, the MEI committed to allocate &#x20AC; 84,750 to the UNIDO IDF.

The MEI invited the Director General of UNIDO to open the conference and sign the Framework Programme of Cooperation between UNIDO and the Government of Azerbaijan. The Programme defines primary areas of
cooperation with the purpose of contributing to sustainable development of the industrial sector of the economy of Azerbaijan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azerbaijan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-140211" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="AZ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azerbaijan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.404542 47.696938</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">19864.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">38522.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">29244.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-303.3</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2014-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-31">19864.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2014-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-31">17884.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2015-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-31">38522.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2015-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-31">33818.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2016-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-31">29244.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2016-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-31">29446.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2017-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">-303.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140211-1-01-01-2017-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">-359.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to conference organization</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="AZ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
