<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200321</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scaling up Cocoa-based Food Systems, Land Use and Restoration / Transformative Innovations in C&#xF4;te d#Ivoire (SCOLUR-CI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The present GEF project aims to promote deforestation-free cocoa value chains and restore degraded cocoa-forest landscapes in C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire. The project envisages action under four overall components: (i) integrated landscape systems for planning and management; (ii) cocoa production best practices and value chains (iii) conservation and restoration of natural habitats, and; (iv) knowledge sharing and dissemination. The activities of these areas will be implemented via three GEF agencies: FAO, UNIDO and UNDP under the leadership of FAO.

Three project landscapes have been selected, in close consultation with CFI partners. Two of the landscapes are located in Western C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, while a third is located in the east, bordering on Ghana. Briefly, the individual landscapes are as follows: Cavally landscape, Gu&#xE9;mon landscape and Ind&#xE9;ni&#xE9;-Djuablin/La M&#xE9; inter-regional landscape.

The component 2 of the project is aimed at achieving improved efficiency, responsibility and sustainability of the cocoa value chain as a key element in ensuring improved livelihoods, maintenance of ecosystem services and global environmental benefits related to land degradation, biodiversity conservation and climate change mitigation. Activities under this component will take place within, or otherwise be designed to benefit, the three target landscapes introduced above. The intention is to stimulate transformative change for livelihoods and landscapes, including benefiting the surrounding classified forests and protected areas, while also serving as important demonstrations for further uptake across the regions in question.

The Output 2.4 &#x201C;Sustainable cocoa standards and certification systems developed and tested&#x201D; of this component will be implemented by UNIDO in partnership with the REDD+, which deals with the issue of traceability of cocoa and certification.

Under this output, sustainable cocoa standards and certification systems will be tested at two levels. First, existing or ongoing standards such as ISO 3410 or national standards for C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire and Ghana will be promoted in order to increase the quantities of certified product being sourced from within the target landscapes. Second, innovative approaches to certification of the landscapes themselves, or sub-units thereof, will be examined and piloted.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GEF - Global Environment Facility</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200321" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CI" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8 -5</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">108689.75</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
