<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of a fully-fledged project document on Industrial Policy and Capacity Development for Enhanced Productivity and Competitiveness in Mauritius</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of this preparatory assistance is to develop a project, with a view to support the Ministry of Industrial Development, SMEs and Cooperatives, Government of Mauritius. The planned assistance concerns designing industrial policies and strategies with a view to achieve growth in the manufacturing sector, as well as developing capacities for government staff. Lately, the manufacturing sector has lost international competitiveness and the new government program (2020-2024) outlines a strategy for reviving the sector. The baseline scenario demonstrated that the share of medium- and high-technology manufacturing has declined over time, which is in line with the need to sharpen technology-focused industrial policy.

To achieve its goal the government seeks to upgrade the sectors technologically, getting as close as possible to the world technology frontier, and thereby increase sectoral productivity growth and competitiveness. Importantly, this is not to be accomplished by erecting trade barriers or other means of protection, but through technologically advanced investment machinery and equipment, enhanced skills of labor and innovation. In other words, technological prowess is to be achieved through an upgrade of the production process and  sophistication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200127" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MU" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="MU" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mauritius</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.261277 57.550058</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">6134.97</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
