<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-170081</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO-AIESEC global partnership</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Joint Declaration was signed by the President of AIESEC Global and UNIDO&#x2019;s Director General in November 2016 to formalize the mutual intent to actively engage young women and men in inclusive and sustainable development. The Declaration has provided a strong basis for further cooperation in engaging young women and men on a global level, particularly in the areas of employment and entrepreneurship, including social entrepreneurship, and for joint advocacy of their critical role as leaders and agents of change towards sustainable economic and social development. Since then, the engagement between UNIDO and AIESEC has continued to deepen, particularly in the areas of entrepreneurship skills development targeted at young women and men and education on sustainable development.  This is in line with UNIDO&#x2019;s mandate to promote ISID, as well as with the request by Member States to engage young women and men in the process, as per the Lima Declaration of 2013. This was  confirmed in the 17th session of UNIDO&#x2019;s General Conference (e.g. in GC.17/10) as well in the latest Medium Term Programme Framework (2018-2021), which amongst other things, highlight the importance of reducing poverty by promoting more inclusive patterns of industrial development, including by removing obstacles that impede local entrepreneurship, particularly for young women and men.
Based on the above, the proposed global partnership between UNIDO and AIESEC seeks to effectively increase the meaningful engagement of young women and men in achieving sustainable development, by realizing their potential to contribute to the achievement of the SDGs, with particular focus on SDG 9 as an enabler of all Goals. In the long run the project will strengthen the local entrepreneurial ecosystem in which young women and men operate, through (1) entrepreneurship skills development, capacity building of young women and men and peer-to-peer support (2) empowerment of young women and men to actively participate in key processes to achieve ISID and the SDG, and through (3) joint outreach to mobilize young women and men and increase their engagement. This in return, will empower young women and men to realize their potential as innovative and driven agents of change towards achieving inclusive and sustainable industrial development. Pilot activities between UNIDO and AIESEC have proven to effectively foster y engagement and entrepreneurship led by young women and men and thereby strengthen the ecosystem. A number of young women and men participating in pilot activities continued onto pursuing entrepreneurial ambitions, by creating their own enterprise or by building linkages within their local ecosystem, thereby creating jobs for their peers and contributing to long-term social and economic development.
UNIDO will leverage AIESEC&#x2019;s networks to ensure maximum effectiveness in reaching out to young women and men and mobilizing them to take action towards the achievement of inclusive and sustainable industrial development. It foresees increasing the opportunities for quality skills development and building the entrepreneurial capacities of young women and men, building on the evidence that their responsiveness to current social, economic and environmental challenges and entrepreneurship led by young women and men are critical drivers of sustainable development. To this end, the project will deliver the jointly developed state-of-the-art entrepreneurship training toolkit, Start and Grow, on an online and offline basis. The toolkit adopts an innovative approach by applying the language and tools that respond to the challenges and needs that young entrepreneurs face today, and has been successfully piloted in Ethiopia and Austria. Furthermore, jointly promoting entrepreneurship led by young women and men will significantly increase outreach to and by existing and aspiring entrepreneurs, and will thus support entrepreneurship led by young women and men in the countries of operation.
Finally, an action plan to engage young women and men will be developed in line with UNIDO&#x2019;s programmatic objectives, which will leverage on the presence and networks in the countries of operation to adequately address their engagement at country level. The action plan seeks to address how best to serve young women and men as beneficiaries, and how to engage them in UNIDO activities and initiatives to adequately address the challenges and needs they face.
The project approach allows for a phased implementation of activities in accordance with the funds mobilized. The ideal scenario comprises nine countries in total: three pilot countries in year 1 (phase 1), and six additional ones in year 2 and 3 (phase 2). Funds mobilized by UNIDO will be allocated to phase 1, which will be crucial to mobilize further funds for phase 2 (negotiations are on-going with OFID) to allow further scale up of activities in years 2 and 3. The results achieved in phase 1 will be instrumental in proving the feasibility of the project approach, and on the significant added value of a partnership between UNIDO and AIESEC. In addition to the outreach and engagement of young women and men, the proposed project expects to train 50 trainers, and 600 young women and men over the three years. In the first year (phase 1), the project expects to train 20 trainers and 200 young women and men.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust Fund for Youth Employment</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-170081" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">5620.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">7328.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-8.11</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-01-2017-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">5620.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-01-2017-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">6292.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-01-2018-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">872.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-01-2018-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">869.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">-8.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">-8.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-02-2018-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">6455.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="170081-0-01-02-2018-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">6658.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
