<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210039</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industrial Deep Decarbonization Initiative</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In January 2019 at the preparatory meeting for the CEM10, the need to increase the CEM work on energy efficiency and clean energy in industry was expressed by a few CEM members (India, Finland, EU, China, UAE, UK).  UNIDO prepared a background paper and a side event at the CEM 10 meeting in Vancouver in May 2019 to present the findings and discuss the gaps and interests of member states.

During the side event, the members agreed that UNIDO and the CEM Secretariat should run survey to identify common areas of interest among the CEM members.  The outcomes of the survey were presented at the CEM11 preparatory meeting in Riyadh in February 2020.   The members agreed that the initiative should focus on energy intensive industries, primarily steel and cement as there are already existing efforts under the industry transition track of the climate summit and some gaps to help create the demand in the market for green commodities like steel.

UNIDO convened a side event co-lead with India during the CEM11 meeting in September 2020 during which the UK and Canada announced support for the new initiative on industrial decarbonization.  UNIDO in close cooperation with the UK, India, Canada and Sweden developed the attached proposal for a new initiative on industrial deep decarbonization and presented the proposal at the CEM12 preparatory meeting in February 2021.   Germany, IRENA, the World Bank and other partners expressed interest to join the initiative. Discussions are underway with China, Chile and Brazil to join the initiative.

The project will enable UNIDO to animate and coordinate a global initiative for industry deep decarbonization in partnership with the CEM Secretariat.  The initiative aims to deliver concrete actions in support of developed and developing countries&apos; efforts towards decarbonizing the hard to abate sectors and net zero targets by 2050.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210039" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">93925.16</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="210039-0-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-01">93925.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">project document formulated and approved</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="210039-0-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-01">40825.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">project document formulated and approved</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
