<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210019</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Program - Burundi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government of Burundi, through H.E. Minister of Commerce, Industry and Tourism, addressed UNIDO on 7 March 2019 via an official letter requesting the Organization to formulate a Country Programme (CP) for Burundi. The Government highlighted industrialization as one of its key priorities to accelerate and diversify economic growth and support the implementation of Burundi&#x2019;s National Development Plan 2018-2027.
The interest in the development of a CP was further reiterated by H.E. Minister of Commerce, Industry and Tourism in a bilateral meeting with UNIDO Director General at the margins of the Eighth UNIDO Ministerial Conference of the Least Developed Countries held in November 2019, in Abu Dhabi. At this occasion, H.E. also indicated the tentative priority areas for the CP, namely: (i) agri-business: leather value chain; fruits and vegetables value chains; fishery sector on the Lake Tanganyika; coffee and tea; (ii) quality and standards; (iii) energy and environment and (iv) tourism. An additional letter from H.E. Minister of Commerce, Industry and Tourism was addressed to UNIDO on 27 January 2020 confirming Burundi&#x2019;s readiness for receiving a CP formulation mission with technical experts in order to effectuate a country diagnostic and discuss further orientations.
The Burundi Country Programme will be aligned with the relevant national development priorities, notably the National Development Plan 2018-2027 which was developed to accelerate the achievement of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and the National Policy for Industrialization 2019-2027. The CP will be also aligned with the Burundi Vision 2025, including in terms of timeframe. It will also take into account regional and international strategic and policy instruments, including the ECA policies, the Africa Union Agenda 2063, the programmes of action for Least Developed Countries and Landlocked Developing States, as well as the Burundi UNDAF and all of the UNIDO policies and regulations, including the mandates on Inclusive and Sustainable Industrial Development (ISID) and the Third Industrial Development Decade for Africa (IDDA III).
Burundi and UNIDO have fruitful long-standing working relations where the Government of Burundi has always been a reliable partner to the Organization. Burundi&#x2019;s governmental counterparts will further liaise with the UNIDO Representative and Director of the Regional Office Hub in Ethiopia (covering Burundi) as well as with the Regional Coordination Division- Africa for coordination support (PFC/RFC/AFR).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Budget</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210019" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-04-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BI" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bujumbura</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.3822 29.3644</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BI" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burundi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.431481 29.910427</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">41865.02</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="210019-0-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">20409.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="BI"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="210019-0-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">1064</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="BI"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="210019-0-01-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">10989.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="BI"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="210019-0-01-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-01">9641.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.2</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="BI"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
