<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enterprise Risk Management 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aimed at developing and implementing UNIDO&#x2019;s general risk management strategy framework with a view to integrating Enterprise Risk Management (ERM) as a decision making management tool and taking active measures for addressing and mitigating the adverse impact of identified risks on the Organization while identifying and capturing opportunities.
The Risk Management Committee is of the view that a well-established and widely integrated ERM framework will drive all three management priorities. Namely,

&#x2022; informed decision making with proper consideration of risk and opportunities will support integration and scale up in the global context (priority 1) by closely aligning undertaken programmes and initiatives with broader Organizational objectives, specifically as they relate to SDG 9;
&#x2022; through integration of risk management into the management process and the application of mitigation measures and controls, if and when required, UNIDO becomes a more efficient UN Organization as its activities become even more aligned with its mandate and management objectives, including the MTPF, yielding effective implementation and innovation (priority 2);
&#x2022; championing a comprehensive risk management framework will elevate UNIDO&#x2019;s status in the UN system and support profiling UNIDO as a modern UN organization in support of its Member States. As a result, UNIDO will become a more transparent and hence, more effective and efficient UN Organization fueled by strengthened partnerships with MSs, donors and the private sector (priority 3).
Director of External Relations acts as UNIDO Risk Focal Point and Chair of the Risk Management Committee (RMC) with ETR/OD acting as the RMC Secretariat in support of this function. The Risk Focal Point leads an enhanced Organization-wide transformation of the Enterprise Risk Management (ERM) framework vis-&#xE0;-vis the RMC to develop and implement UNIDO&#x2019;s general risk management strategy to comprehensively address all major risks faced by the Organization.
Following recommendations of the Joint Inspection Unit (JIU), External Auditor (EA), Audit Advisory Committee (AAC), and calls from Member States to integrate risk management in operational processes of UNIDO, and in line with management priorities and the maturity model of the High-Level Committee on Management (HLCM) Cross-Functional Task Force on Risk Management (HLCM RM), UNIDO should make every effort to enhance and solidify its standing as regards to ERM.
It is in the view of the Risk Focal Point and the RMC that advancements made in 2018 towards identifying and aligning top perceived risks in UNIDO (bottom-up approach) with the MTPF provides a solid foundation for enhancing the ERM framework in 2019 and provide guidance form senior management (top-down) on the ERM process and integration. From the work carried out by the RMC in 2018, the RMC has concluded that UNIDO maintains an ad-hoc and highly fragmented risk management framework, having a more advanced and structured processes embedded in Finance and IT functions.
Viewing the 2018 work plan as an internal evaluation period of the maturity of UNIDO&#x2019;s ERM framework, the 2019 work plan proposed herein focuses on setting-up key ERM principles for operationalizing UNIDO&#x2019;s ERM policy for achieving a more systematically aligned and integrated framework.
Specifically, the 2019 work plan focuses on validating the identified risk profile, defining risk tolerance and risk appetite, updating and/or instilling controls and mitigation measures, assigning risk ownership and responsibilities, developing risk identification and reporting guidelines, expanding RMC reach through engagement of the Risk Liaison Officers function and harmonizing UNIDO&#x2019;s wide understanding of ERM principles through knowledge sharing and training.
The RMC concluded at its 21 February 2019 meeting that to effectively implement the RMC endorsed 2019 work plan and with the view to build on momentum gains in 2018, establishing an ERM project (the Project) should be considered by the Executive Board (EB). In its recommendation, the RMC further emphasizes the need for a resource endowment to the Project, including establishing a one full-time position embedded in the RMC Secretaria and a provision for external consulting to assist the RMC secretariat, the Risk Focal Point and the RMC in managing the ERM project.  In line with its mandate, the RMC has requested the Risk Focal Point to submit the its recommendation that would support advancing and operationalizing UNIDO&#x2019;s ERM policy in 2019 and enhance maturity of the framework.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190082" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">11478.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">97977.67</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-01-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">3870.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advance general risk assessment</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-01-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">3824.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advance general risk assessment</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-01-03-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">3756.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Corporate Risk Register</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-01-03-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">3712.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Corporate Risk Register</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-01-02-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">3756.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preliminary report on top 10-15 risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-01-02-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">3712.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preliminary report on top 10-15 risks</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-02-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">15092.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Liaison Officer functions</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-02-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">6121.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Liaison Officer functions</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-02-03-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">45766.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Liaison Officers, risk owners, and</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190082-1-02-03-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">12428.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Liaison Officers, risk owners, and</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
