<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210056</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing income and employment opportunities in Liberia through a market system and cluster development approach in agro-industry value chains</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Embassy of Sweden invited UNIDO and other organizations to submit a concept note to design a program proposal, which should build on the lessons learned and act as a continuation of the current Program financed by SIDA &#x201C;Markets and value chains in agriculture (GROW Liberia)&#x201C; that has been implemented in 2013-2021.

The Call for Concept is for an inception phase only, for which an agreement will be signed. The inception phase is expected to be initiated in the last quarter of 2021 and should be completed within a period of 12 months from the date of signature of the agreement. The end outcome of the inception phase will be a well-thought through program proposal, based on an in-depth market system analysis (MSA), market system development (MSD) program design and partnership set-up, addressing the development of sustainable agricultural productivity, value chains and markets in Liberia. The budget for the inception phase is maximum 8 MSEK.

Subsequently, (not included under the agreement) the intention is to sign an additional agreement in 2022 for the implementation of the 4-year MSD program. This phase is not included in the Call for Concept.

The Embassy of Sweden foresees that this new intervention will integrate a Market Systems Development approach and target small-scale farmers, by closely collaborating with Ministry of Agriculture and other Liberian partners. The development of agricultural markets and value chains has a potential to contribute to a process of inclusive and sustainable economic growth that reduces poverty in Liberia. With a majority of the poor living off agriculture, inclusive and sustainable growth in the agricultural markets and value chains that matter most to them and where they are most involved would stimulate activities and employment that generate income for women, men and youth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210056" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="LR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.344812 -9.429833</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">22085.89</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="210056-0-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-01">22085.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="LR"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="210056-0-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-01">15230.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="LR"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
