<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190099</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional support and skills development for a dam safety programme to enable sustainable management of hydraulic infrastructure in Iraq</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq&#x2019;s prosperity and stability largely depend on the sustainable management of its water infrastructure network, which mainly relies on the Euphrates and Tigris rivers.

The Mosul Dam, on the Tigris River, is the largest dam in Iraq, and one of the largest dams in the Middle East. Managing the Mosul Dam in a sustainable manner is key for three major reasons: i) to cope with the rising energy demand necessary for industrial development and population growth; ii) to provide downstream irrigation in the Ninewa basin, whose population&#x2019;s largely depend on agriculture; and iii) to mitigate the increasing risk of floods due to the dam&#x2019;s instability. The Mosul Dam has structural instability problems due to the geology of the site. The Mosul Dam&#x2019;s infrastructure has seriously deteriorated over the past years due to poor maintenance and the recent conflict in the region.

The proposed UNIDO-led intervention aims at supporting Iraqi authorities to safely manage the Mosul Dam and, in the long-term, to efficiently and safely manage the Iraqi national hydraulic infrastructure.
This will be done through an integrated skills development and technology transfer programme, designed to strengthen governmental capacities.  Once trained, Iraqi operators, technicians and decision makers will be able to take informed-decisions and will operate the Mosul Dam in the most sustainable, safe and efficient manner.  They will be able to regularly monitor operating conditions and to carry out any required rehabilitation and remediation efforts of damaged infrastructure.  They will also be able to anticipate and mitigate risks, including man-made and natural catastrophe. The intervention will also pave the way for a National Dam Safety Skills Development Program covering the whole of Iraq&#x2019;s national hydraulic infrastructure.

The programme is designed to deliver on two major outcomes: 1) The Mosul Dam Monitoring Unit is established and can effectively monitor the Mosul Dam, ensuring adequate maintenance and risk mitigation. 2) The National Dam Safety Planning Unit &#x2013; Baghdad is established and works in synergy with the Mosul Dam Monitoring Unit, and the conditions are met to roll-out a National Dam Safety Programme.  In terms of the long-term impact, the project will contribute to ensuring a safe and predictable water supply in Iraq. The provision of basic services such as water and electricity is crucial for state-building, and for industrial and agricultural development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Italy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190099" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IQ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.577183 43.667107</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">510116.75</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="190099-1-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-01">239721.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IQ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190099-1-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-01">98437.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IQ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190099-1-07-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-01">270395.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IQ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190099-1-07-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-01">9454.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="IQ"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
