<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme for Country Partnership (PCP) Zambia 2021-2025</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia became a UNIDO Member State in 1985 and since then 216 projects have been implemented for the country by UNIDO. UNIDO&#x2019;s portfolio in Zambia over the past decade has been focused mainly on renewable energy and environment (SHP &amp; Montreal Protocol) and trade capacity building (TCB). In addition, there were two regional projects that covered Zambia among other countries, namely to support SMEs (SPX &#x2013; regional) and a regional cotton sector study. The funding for these projects has come largely from the Government of Zambia (30%), the global Environment Facility (34%), Norway (28%), and the Montreal Protocol Multilateral fund (4%), with the remainder coming largely from UNIDO&#x2019;s programmable resources. Currently UNIDO is implementing 4 projects of technical cooperation in the country, in the areas of renewable energy, environment (Montreal Protocol) and agribusiness, and the Country Programme (CP) Zambia 2017-2021 with a total budget of USD 2,387,600  and has an increasing portfolio of pipeline projects, including the planned inclusion of Zambia as a beneficiary country in the regional SADC Forestry Project.

The ongoing CP Zambia was signed in 2015 and launched in 2016 with the initial timeframe 2015-2018. The implementation period was however amended to 2017-2021, so as to be aligned with the UN Sustainable Development Partnership Framework (UN SDPF) (2016-2021) instead of the former UN Development Assistance Framework (UNDAF) (2011-2015) for Zambia. The CP Framework was also aligned with national strategies and priorities as defined in the revised sixth National Development Plan (RSNDP) (2011-2016) and the Strategy Paper on Industrialization and Job Creation (2013-2018) which endeavour to attain Zambia&#x2019;s Vision 2030, that conceives Zambia as a &#x2018;prosperous middle-income nation by 2030&#x2019;.

In addition, a Donor Roundtable was organised in 2017 by UNIDO and the Government of the Republic of Zambia (GRZ). The CP Implementation Unit was established in August 2018. Zambia was subsequently selected as a Programme for Country Partnership (PCP) country in October 2018 and since then three missions have been conducted to the country in order to carry out country monitoring and facilitate the transition from CP to PCP by inter alia briefing the government counterparts on PCP requirements and prepare the upcoming UNIDO DG mission to the country in August 2018.

Since 2017, there has been a significant increase in the number of government requests for UNIDO&#x2019;s technical assistance and advisory services, enlarging thus the country&#x2019;s pipeline projects portfolio. Strong government commitment and solid relationships with donors and partners, including UN resident agencies, DFIs, the private sector, civil society and academia are key for UNIDO&#x2019;s Programme for Country Partnership (PCP) approach and will build a base for the initiation of the PCP Zambia. In addition, new sources from the Global South such as China and South Africa &#x2013; including the large foreign mining investors &#x2013; could be much more thoroughly engaged in the current climate that is conducive to new approaches.

Zambia&#x2019;s economy during the period 2000 to 2005 grew at an annual average of about 5.8% while the 2006 to 2015 period saw an upward and sustained growth averaging 6.9% per annum. Growth was driven by investments in the mining sector with spill-over effects into construction, transport, communications, wholesale and retail. Growth was furthermore facilitated by favourable copper prices, underpinned by demand from China, and increasing trade with neighbouring countries. Economic turmoil in the global economy has had limited effects on the Zambian economy, mainly with regard to its relative dependency on the copper and cobalt industry that are vulnerable to commodity price fluctuations. Relatedly, between 2007 and 2009 the falling prices of copper in the global market by 28% led to a corresponding FDI fall of 47%. Despite the post-2000 policy initiatives to diversify the economy by building stronger manufacturing and agriculture sectors, mining still remained the dominant sector. While the agriculture sector yielded positive growth rates over the 2000 to 2014 period, its contribution to Gross Domestic Product (GDP) declined from 23.8% in 2000 to 6.8% in 2014. The share of mining increased from 4.2% to 14.6% between 2000 and 2014 . In addition, the agriculture, manufacturing and tourism sectors necessitate a higher influx in FDIs.
Although the country recorded steady economic growth during the period 1990-2015, poverty trends suggest that the pattern of economic growth in Zambia is highly unequal and has not increased the incomes of the poor rapidly enough to lift them out of poverty. This is mainly due to three reasons. Firstly, economic growth has historically been concentrated in capital-intensive industries such as construction, mining and transport. Secondly, urban areas have gained more than rural areas and thirdly, economic growth has not been associated with labour-intensive sectors in which the poor tend to work, such as agriculture.
Due to the strong prevalence of poverty and social inequality, Zambia&#x2019;s first ever long-term plan Vision 2030, adopted in July 2006, aspires towards the goal of becoming a prosperous middle-income, dynamic industrial nation that provides opportunities for improving the well-being of all, embodying values of socio-economic justice, underpinned by the principles of: (i) gender responsive sustainable development, (ii) democracy, (iii) respect for human rights, (iv) good traditional and family values, (v) positive attitude towards work, (vi) peaceful coexistence and (vii) private-public partnerships.
Zambia has had three development plans since the re-introduction of the medium-term development planning process in the early 2000s, namely the Fifth National Development Plan, 2006-2010 (FNDP), Sixth National Development Plan, 2011-2015 (SNDP) and the Revised Sixth National Development Plan, 2013-2016 (R-SNDP). These Plans were formulated with a view to meeting the national aspirations as articulated in the Vision 2030. These aspirations are to transform the country from a primary product-dependent economy to a strong, dynamic middle income industrialised country by 2030. Following the expiry of the Revised Sixth National Development Plan in 2016, the Government spearheaded the formulation of the Seventh National Development Plan (7 NDP) covering the period from 2017 to 2021. The Plan represents the key national strategic framework for industrialization and sustainable economic development providing relevant guidelines for the planned PCP. Its five pillars are: Economic diversification and job creation; Poverty and Vulnerability Reduction; Reducing Development Inequalities; Enhancing Human Development; and Creating a Conducive Governance Environment for a Diversified Economy. The Plan departs from sectoral-based planning to an integrated (multi-sectoral) approach under the theme &#x201C;Accelerating development efforts towards Vision 2030 without leaving anyone behind&#x201D;. The goal of the 7NDP is to create a diversified and resilient economy for sustained growth and socio-economic transformation driven, among others, by agriculture. The Plan aims to bring about inclusive development and achieving more with less resources through integration and coordination of development efforts while also taking into account regional and global development agendas, including the Regional Indicative Strategic Development Plan (RISDP), a comprehensive development and implementation framework guiding the regional integration agenda of the Southern African Development Community (SADC) over a period of fifteen years (2005-2020), the African Union (AU) Agenda 2063, Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), and the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa (COMESA) protocols.
The planned PCP will be aligned to goals, strategies and principles of the 7NDP as well as the current United Nations Sustainable Development Partnership Framework (UNSDPF) (2016-2021) for Zambia, notably with the focus on the outcomes of the pillars 2 and 3 thereof. The three pillars of the 2016-2021 Zambia-UNSDPF (inclusive social development, environmentally sustainable economic development, and governance and participation) seek to address pervasive inequalities and ensure inclusiveness of interventions through eight outcomes. The current political and business climate in the country and the potential for cooperation presented to UNIDO, notably through the number of various requests for UNIDO&#x2019;s technical assistance that have been received, is promising for cooperation at the meso (institutions and business development plans) and macro levels (policy and strategy development and implementation support), working with associations, institutions, and decision-making bodies.
Thus, the PCP Zambia will also be largely based on the currently ongoing Country Programming Framework Zambia (2017-2021) and its six components; UNIDO&#x2019;s experience in the implementation of TC projects in Zambia; as well as the heretofore received government requests for UNIDO&#x2019;s assistance that build the core of the current UNIDO project pipeline for Zambia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190132" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ZM" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lusaka</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-15.40669 28.28713</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ZM" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-14.608141 27.82704</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">76426.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">123573.44</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">67983.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1 PCP doc formulated</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">67983.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1 PCP doc formulated</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">23016.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1 PCP doc formulated</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">18307.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 1 PCP doc formulated</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-02-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">8442.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 2 Investment promotion</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-02-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">8442.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 2 Investment promotion</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-02-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">63857.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 2 Investment promotion</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-02-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">52577.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 2 Investment promotion</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-04-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">13400</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 4 Financ. partnerships</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190132-0-01-04-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-01">7092.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PA Output 4 Financ. partnerships</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="ZM"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
