<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210090</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO strategic frameworks for partnering with and supporting the least developed and landlocked developing countries beyond 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the genesis of the LDC group, UNIDO has continuously implemented action-oriented technical and advisory services for inclusive and sustainable industrialization of the LDCs, as requested by the United Nations General Assembly, in 1971 (UNGA A_RES_2768(XXVI)_E). As of May 2021, Least Developed Countries (LDCs) represent 44 Member States at UNIDO while Landlocked Developing Countries (LLDCs) represent 31 of its Member States.

International development pursuits have reached a crossroad of utmost importance for Least Developed Countries (LDCs) and Landlocked Developing Countries (LLDCs). The year 2021 represents:
a) the last year of implementation of the Istanbul Programme of Action (IPoA) for LDCs 2011-2020 (extended to 2021 because of COVID-19) and the preparatory year towards the Fifth UN Conference of the LDCs, expected to be held in Qatar, in January 2022 (UN LDC5),
b) the last implementation year of UNIDO Operational Strategy on LDCs 2012-2020 (extended to 2021 in line with the IPoA),
c) the last 4 years of implementation of the Vienna Programme of Action (VPoA) for LLDCs 2014-2024 and the UN Roadmap for Accelerated Implementation,
d) the 50th anniversary of the creation of the LDC category, in 1971
e) the first of the last 5 years of implementation of the Third Industrial Development Decade for Africa (IDDA III), 2016-2025, and
f) the first implementation year of the last Decade of Action for the implementation of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development.

Therefore, this project is initiated to effectively link UNIDO&#x2019;s technical assistance with the policy and normative dimension to support LDCs and LLDCs Member States to achieve the Inclusive and Sustainable Industrial Development (ISID) and lasting industrial and economic development as part of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, beyond 2021. The eradication of poverty is among the most prominent of the Sustainable Development Goals, and the challenge of poverty eradication is the greatest for the least developed countries, where almost half of the population still lives in extreme poverty. UNIDO pursues ISID to harness industry&#x2019;s full potential to contribute to lasting prosperity for all, based on the recognition (Lima Declaration, 2013) that poverty eradication &#x201C;can only be achieved through strong, inclusive, sustainable and resilient economic and industrial growth, and the effective integration of the economic, social and environmental dimensions of sustainable development.&#x201D;
The project&#x2019;s strategized outputs are as follows:
1) A developed UNIDO Strategy and Implementation Plan for LDCs 2022-2031 with MR&amp;E tools, including through UNIDO Integrated Results Performance Framework (IRPF), and in alignment with the next programme of action for LDCs to steam from the UN LDC5 Conference, in January 2022.
2) A developed Feuille de Route with MR&amp;E tools, including through UNIDO Integrated Results Performance Framework (IRPF), for the operationalization of the UN Roadmap for Accelerated Implementation of the Vienna Programme of Action for LLDCs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210090" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">110429.46</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
