<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190022</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIDO eighth Ministerial Conference of the Least Developed Countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date and location: 2 November 2019, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates.

The UNIDO eighth Ministerial Conference of the Least Developed Countries was first initiated in 2007. Since then, the Conference has always been celebrated as a biennial event, preceding the UNIDO General Conference and has reached its eighth edition this year.
UNIDO plays a key role in orchestrating and coordinating the events pertaining to the LDC Ministerial Conference given its mandate and expertise, experiences and commitment in providing technical cooperation (TC) to the 47 countries in the LDC category: 33 in Africa (including North Africa), 13 in Asia and the Pacific and 1 in Latin America on industrial/economic development related issues. Through its ongoing TC activities, UNIDO advances the global debate on LDCs&#x2019; major industrial development challenges and their viable solutions towards their path to graduation.
At the 46th session of the Industrial Development Board, 26-28 November 2018, UNIDO strongly reaffirmed its commitment to support LDCs&#x2019; graduation through its mandate of Inclusive and Sustainable Industrial Development (ISID), as adopted in the Lima Declaration in December 2013 (GC.15/Res.1). The United Nations Programme of Action for the LDCs, the Istanbul Programme of Action (IPoA), was approved during the Fourth United Nations Conference on the LDCs (LDC-IV) for the period 2011-2020 which took place from 9 to 13 May 2011 in Istanbul, Turkey. The participation of the UNIDO Director General at the IPoA Midterm Review, held in Antalya in May 2016, reaffirmed UNIDO&#x2019;s key position as one of the main contributors to structural transformation and sustainable economic growth in LDCs. This commitment was also underpinned by the fact that UNIDO develop its own Operational Strategy on LDCs in response to the IPoA.
This year&#x2019;s Eighth (8th) UNIDO LDC Ministerial Conference is foreseen to take place on 2 November 2019, prior to the Eighteenth Session of the UNIDO General Conference (GC), to be held from 3-7 November 2019 in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates.
This year&#x2019;s tentative theme is entitled: &#x201C;Accelerating industrialization in LDCs: Lessons learnt and innovative approaches &#x201D;. The event will focus on best practices and case studies of industrialization for replication and upscaling, agreed in cooperation with the UN Office of the High Representative for the Least Developed Countries, Landlocked Developing Countries and Small Island Developing States (UN-OHRLLS), which was designated by the UN General Assembly as the coordinator of the LDC-V process.
In prior consultations, member states have expressed high interest to learn about the practical &#x201C;how&#x201D; of industrialization, innovative case studies and partnership approaches &#x2013; such as the UNIDO Programmes for Country Partnerships (PCPs) &#x2013; and how these can be replicated. Conclusions from these lessons learnt are also expected to provide momentum for the preparations of the next Programme of Action and LDC-V conference and UNIDO&#x2019;s own review exercise of the LDC Operational Strategy which is currently being launched.
The 8th UNIDO LDC Ministerial Conference will take place at a special time for the United Nations Programme of Action for the LDCs. The LDC-V process including the evaluation of the IPoA and the negotiations of the UN Programme of Action for the LDCs for the next decade will be launched towards the end of the year 2019. This process will culminate in the Fifth United Nations Conference (LDC-V) on the LDCs to be held in Doha, Qatar, in 2021. The outcomes of the 8th UNIDO LDCs Ministerial Conference, as a pre-LDC V Conference event will feed into the process of elaborating a new Programme of Action. This offers UNIDO a unique opportunity to have ISID/SDG 9 and IDDA III reflected in the new measures and strategies that will be adopted for the sustainable industrial development of the LDCs in the next decade 2021-2030 and their efforts of economic diversification.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Budget</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-190022" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">33455.31</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="190022-1-02-03-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">22419.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministerial Declaration</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190022-1-02-03-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">23114.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministerial Declaration</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190022-1-02-01-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">11035.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Showcasing and advancing UNIDO#s work</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="190022-1-02-01-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">11587.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Showcasing and advancing UNIDO#s work</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
