<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-140408</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building for the Green Industry Platform in China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China is in the phase of fast industrial development, but the dual pressures of resources and energy constraints and serious ecological damage have taken a heavy toll on the current industrial development and the national economic sustainable development. On the one hand, High energy-consuming industrial enterprises drive the economic growth, on the other hand they become a major source of energy consumption and environmental pollution. Adjustment of domestic industrial economic structure, changing the way of industrial development, and finding a path of sustainable growth in the industrial development have become the top priorities in China. The Chinese government has put the ecological civilization up to an unprecedented strategic level and into the five-in-one national development goal. The Chinese government demands acceleration of the establishment of a completely systematically ecological civilization system. Meanwhile, in &#x201C;the Thirteenth Five-Year Plan for National Economic and Social development&#x201D;, the Chinese government made specific requirements on energy conservation and achieving green, low-carbon and environmentally friendly development in the industrial sector, in order to comprehensively improve environmental awareness and resource efficiency in the industrial sector, and to promote the green industry. Green industry is the first priority to achieve sustainable industrial development, which has become a global consensus. In June 2012, at the &#x201C;Rio +20&#x201D; Summit, under the joint initiative of UNIDO and UNEP, the &#x201C;United Nations Green Industry Platform&#x201D; was established. GIP linked the main promoters of governments, businesses and community groups in the field of green industry from every member country and promoted cleaner and more competitive regional industrial development through the joint commitment and action. China, as the world&#x2019;s largest developing country, plays an important role in the global industry and manufacturing. To achieve the green and sustainable development in China, GIP focuses on the real situation of Chinese industrial development, and has taken a regional approach, in order to help the Chinese public and private sectors achieve green capacity building, to enhance the relevant departments&#x2019; understanding of the green industrial development, and to take the necessary support for green industrial development. At the Third Green Industry Conference held in 2013 in Guangzhou, China, UNIDO and Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) of China signed a Memorandum of Understanding to promote the development of green industry and beyond. In November 2014, the Chinese government and UNIDO concluded a strategic cooperation framework for 2014-2016, aiming to carry out economic and technological cooperation in the follow areas, namely resource-saving and low-carbon industrial production, renewable energy for production, air pollution reduction, food safety improvement, the implementation of multilateral environmental agreements, high quality and compliance infrastructures, investment-driven and demand-driven technology promotion and others. The key fields focused on green industry and food safety. In the pursuit of green industrial paths, the Chinese public sectors need the help from international societies and resources in the fields of green industry concepts, green industrial system and supervision design, green industrial operation specifications and green technology innovation incentive system, and the provision of successful cases of international relevant supporting policies, in order to help central, provincial and municipal governments and other green industry regulators to strengthen capacity building. Domestic green private sector faces a bottleneck when approaching international green resources and lacks of convenient channels of communication in technical communication and information exchange. The private businesses hope to understand the international forefront green concepts, consult the relevant policies and regulations of the international society, through practicing and learning with international organizations, in order to help develop and implement their own capacity building. The information exchange between public sector and private sector of domestic green industry need to be enhanced. The platform can be used effectively to help the private sector timely access to relevant changes in domestic green industrial policies, to assist the public sector to keep abreast of relevant information, and to fully integrate social resources and better promote domestic green industry, through promoting the communication and cooperation between the two sectors.
UNIDO approach In cooperation with UNEP, UNIDO launched the Green Industry Platform (GIP) at the Rio+20 Conference in June 2012. The Green Industry Platform is a global, high-level, multi-stakeholder partnership and forum to catalyze, mobilize and mainstream action on Green Industry around the world. It provides a framework to bring governmental, business and civil society leaders together to secure concrete commitments and action in support of the Green Industry agenda, i.e. greening the manufacturing process and creating green industries for production of goods and services for domestic use or export. Currently, GIP is still at the early stage of its establishment and needs to be vigorously promoted and popularized. China, as an emerging industrialized nation, has a huge demand for green transformation. Therefore, GIP needs more support from relevant domestic green units, in order to achieve greater efficiency and impact. The information of the GIP needs to be shared with domestic members timely. GIP needs more specific and comprehensive information on the Chinese businesses that have the willingness to join the platform, and also needs basic information and proofs provided by the domestic authority. At the same time, the members of the GIP signed a three-year statement, so the evaluation on these businesses should be carried out, in order to evaluate their leading and pilot role in the green industrial field and to decide whether to renew their commitment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-140408" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beijing</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>39.9075 116.39723</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.320412 104.187418</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">175076.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3532.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">29336.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">34920.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">-226.65</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-01-2016-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-31">60000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of GIPPMO strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-01-2016-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-31">60000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of GIPPMO strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-01-2017-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">30</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of GIPPMO strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-01-2017-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">30</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of GIPPMO strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-01-2018-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">30</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of GIPPMO strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-01-2018-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">30</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of GIPPMO strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2016-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-31">115076.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2016-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-31">115076.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2017-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">3502.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2017-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">3502.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2018-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">29306.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2018-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-31">29306.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2019-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">34920.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2019-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">34920.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2020-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">-226.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="140408-1-01-02-2020-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">-226.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">System of indexing/ranking/certification</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-country code="CN"></recipient-country>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
