<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operationalization of the UNIDO strategic framework for partnering with middle income countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The adoption by Member States of a UNIDO strategic framework for partnering with middle-income countries (MICs) at GC.18 through resolution GC.18/Res.9 demonstrated that partnering with MICs is essential to UNIDO&#x2019;s goal of achieving Inclusive and Sustainable Industrial Development (ISID) globally.

The referred resolution included a request for the Director General to prepare a workplan for the implementation of the strategic framework. At IDB.48 Member States adopted IDB Decision IDB.48/Dec.7 requesting Director General to finalize the work-plan for the operationalization for the UNIDO strategic framework for partnering with MICs &#x201C;ensuring the inclusion of recovery efforts in the context of the aftermath of the COVID-19 pandemic&#x201D;.

The mandate arising from IDB.48/Dec.7 comes to reinforce UNIDO&#x2019;s role as key facilitator of ISID in MICs. This project will operationalize UNIDO&#xB4;s strategic framework for partnering with middle-income countries by identifying specific measures aimed at accelerating the achievement of ISID and the attainment of SDG-9 in MICs. Such measures include, in addition to the workplan for partnering with MICs, the establishment of regional task forces to define strategic, programmatic, partnership and design investment strategies in MICs, in oordination with the field, together with organization of conferences and events to ensure visibility and global endorsement to these strategies, policies, and visions as reflected in the respective outcome documents.

The operationalization of the UNIDO strategic framework for partnering with MICs will also look at ensuring consistency with the strategy for UNIDO&#x2019;s activities in Small-Island Developing States (SIDs) or the UNIDO strategy for post-conflict situations. The operationalization of the strategic framework is also expected to rely heavily on the UNIDO policy on South-South and Triangular Industrial Cooperation (DGB/2019/09) as a key means for implementation of the workplan for partnering with MICs. Being a mandate from Member States emanating from IDB Decision IDB.48/Dec.7, it is extremely relevant that the workplan responds to the expectations of countries included in the MICs category (up to 103 UNIDO Member States according to the latest update by the World Bank from June 2020).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-210014" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="M0" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">149693.25</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="210014-1-01-01-2021-1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-01">149693.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="210014-1-01-01-2021-4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-01">25741.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.1</narrative>
   </description>
   <recipient-region code="M0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://open.unido.org/download/iati/unido-region.csv"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
