<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-16/3420/2SA 2016/Health-Nutrition/INGO/4272</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated Health and Nutrition services by running 4 mobile clinic teams supported by a network of Community Health Volunteers(CHVs) and by granting support to referral health facilities in Ibb governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at reducing morbidity and mortality of most vulnerable conflict-affected populations with focus on children under 5 and pregnant and lactating women through the provision of life saving emergency health and nutrition services by running mobile clinic teams supported by a network of Community Health Volunteers(CHVs) and by granting support to referral health facilities (including emergency services). 
The project will focus in two frontier districts of Ibb (Dhi-As-Sufal and As Sabrah that border Taiz. The two districts are the gateway to the worst conflict-affected governorate (Taiz) and home to many IDPs that are escaping violence in the neighboring Taiz. These districts are in severe need of emergency assistance and have been identified as extremely vulnerable by UN agencies and the MoPHP with high concentration of IDPs mainly from Taiz. The project builds on INTERSOS&#x2019; prior and on-going experience of INTERSOS in Sana&#x2019;a, Ibb, Taiz, Hadramout and Aden implementing similar projects funded by OCHA YHPF, UNICEF and WHO.
The proposal follows on the priorities set by the Health and Nutrition Cluster and MoPHP for emergency health and nutrition interventions: integrated health and nutrition services provided though 4 mobile clinics supported by a network of 24 CHVs.  Through this project, a total 112,720 IDPs and host community individuals in the two selected district of Ibb governorate will have access to a package of Emergency Primary Health Care (EPHC) integrated with nutrition services. The Integrated Health and Nutrition Package includes Reproductive Health/Maternal, Neonatal, Child Health (RH/MNCH), incl.g antenatal, deliveries and postnatal care for mothers newborn care, immunization (for both routine and supplementary vaccines), deworming, vitamin A supplementation, screening for malnutrition, treatment for SAM cases, health education, Outpatient Consultation and treatment for common aliments for both adults and children. INTERSOS will integrate components of IYCF in nutrition treatment and prevention.
The mobile teams will run an Outpatient Therapeutic Program (OTP) applying Community-Based Management of Acute Malnutrition (CMAM). This will enable mobile teams supported by CHVs to identify and initiate treatment for children with acute malnutrition before they become seriously ill. Mobile teams will provide treatment for the majority of children with SAM in the home using Ready-to-Use-Therapeutic Foods (RUTF) and routine medical care. When necessary, severely malnourished children who have medical complications or lack an appetite are referred to in-patient facilities for more intensive treatment. CMAM integrates health education for prevention and sustainability.
The project will support 2 functioning referral health facilities (1 per district) with medicines and equipment to improve their capacity. The 2 referral health facilities will be the focal point for receiving referrals from both mobile clinics and CHVs. Adding basic ambulance equipment to the mobile clinics vehicle converts it to a Basic Life Support (BLS) ambulance. The BLS ambulance will provide the referral services from the districts of the target locations to the two supported referral health facilities,  ensuring rapid transportation of critical cases to secondary health care level (priority will be given to U5 children and pregnant women). The project will establish an efficient outreach and referral mechanism from community level to primary health services and for primary to secondary health services. This will be achieved through a network of CHVs and through the BLS capacity of the mobile clinics for the transport/stabilization of critical patients.  
While the proposal is a multi-sector programme (Health-Nutrition), the project ensures attention for protection and gender mainstreaming, aimed at ensure sufficient awareness among health staff on protection and gender/SGBV related risks and referral pathways available.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evelyn Lernout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 (0) 715 555 00</telephone>
   <email>yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.05521633 44.26319019</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-30">52816.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-30">640845.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-30">56338.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6304269439">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-11">9944.76</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400252813">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-11">214.94</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-4272">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-30">750000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302349339">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-08">600000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303261908">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-05">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
