<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-52957535-4-ZW-SP</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News Is Bad News: Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) to improve the quality of journalism, (2) to empower citizens to have a voice and (3) to enable others to tell their stories and circumvent censorship by using online platforms to spread information on events happening in other areas in Zimbabwe.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Further coordination and clarification with European Journalism Centre, who is in the lead for this country, will need to take place in order to create synergies. Funding for the Zimbabwe activities of FPU needs to be secured from its overall Africa budget under the Strategic Partnership, which would not be a problem in 2016 given that FPU will only spend limited funding in Nigeria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The present situation is Zimbabwe is rather grim. The last elections in 2014 seem to have wiped away the opposition from the political arena entirely. Following the last electoral victory the economy has come to an almost standstill, due to which poverty has risen and unemployment skyrocketed affecting all sectors, including the media where even the state media has had to retrench large number of people. Zimbabwe&apos;s media landscape and sector is highly polarised. The print media sector is the most developed yet very small, with few independent players who have difficulty reaching readers outside of the 2 main cities (Harare and Bulawayo). Its radio and television sector is predominantly state owned despite some newcomers in the radio sector. Yet the latter are mostly owned by either other state companies or companies close to the state. Due to this situation, there are no true independent local and licensed radio or TV stations. Journalism education is of poor quality and lacks necessary equipment due to which graduates lack both theoretical as well as practical knowledge. It is very common for a TV journalism graduate not to have used a camera during his/her study. However, with internet spreading, mainly through mobile telephony, new opportunities for improving quality of journalism as well increasing and strengthening freedom of expression have arised. Free Press Unlimited wants to strengthen these developments, in partnership with Mobile Community Zimbabwe (MCZ). MCZ engages with local NGO&apos;s through a variety of boundary partners ranging from local media freedom and other ngo&apos;s, local media (licensed and unlicensed, independent and state) and journalism faculties and other local training institutes. To train it uses mobile telephones and Storymaker, it showcases content produced by its trainees through a website, which at the same time offers a simulation for journalism students and citizen reporters what it is like to work for a media outlet. More over, it shows the situation in the country, raises awareness about what goes on in the country and therefore has a direct engagement with advocacy activities. Since it partners with local ngo&apos;s, the website provides an advocacy and lobby platform to them, as they are able to show what their work is about. Working with local tertiary journalism institution has enabled direct change within what are commonly perceived very anti-reform institutions closely aligned with the state. Exposing lecturers and subsequently their students to new ways of conducting journalism, has led to the adoption of MCZ&apos;s curriculum by 2 tertiary institutions so far, which could be considered a form of indirect lobby that has led to change and improvement of journalism curricula. So far a lot of effort has been made to convince local organisations and participants that the project is not political and does not aim to change the regime, which was the initial perception of the project when it was piloted in 2013. Increasing efforts in the field of advocacy and lobby in a highly polarised country like Zimbabwe can be easily perceived to be political or anti-regime. Something to be wary of, as it might unnecessarily jeopardise the project and the people associated with it.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobile Community Zimbabwe (MCZ)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and Quality</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and Quality Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kqc@freepressunlimited.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">423166</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">239600</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">86315</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-4-ZW-SP-16" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">108878</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-01">149038</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitments to partner. Aggregated for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-4-ZW-SP-16" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">423166</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-4-ZW-SP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">239600</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">120166</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">114532</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">36617</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-DA" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
