<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-52957535-SP-IP</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News is Bad News: International Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">-Free Press Unlimited, European Journalism Centre and the Ministry will develop advocacy capacity with local partners to end impunity and increase the safety of journalists in relevant multilateral bodies such as UNESCO, the Office of the High Commisioner of Human Rights, the United Nations-General Assembly. -Free Press Unlimited will provide leadership and support to the international network of emergency safety assistance organisations through the Reporters Respond fund and the coordination mechanism of the Journalists in Distress Network. -Free Press Unlimited will coordinate in fragile states with international and local media actors through Global Forum for Media Development to ensure donor coordination &#x2013; add value and synergy to international efforts to increase freedom of expression and media freedom &#x2013; strengthen the local actors capacity to cooperate and advocate jointly. -Free Press Unlimited will strengthen the international advocacy for access to information within the sustainable development goals, strengthen implementation of freedom to access information laws and as well as for a free open and secure Internet with the Global Forum for Media Development, the World Wide Web Foundation and Article 19. -Free Press Unlimited will research malware proliferation and provide tool kits for circumvention technologies and conduct training for partners in the target countries. FPU will provide public access to learning about digital safety tools in cooperation with the network of digital safety training institutions through the Internet Protection Lab.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited and the European Journalism Centre (EJC) will work within the Strategic Partnership on lobby and advocacy in order to ensure that the information needs as well as research and monitoring efforts of local (media) actors will be highlighted at the relevant international stage to ensure connectivity between local, regional and international discussions. Relevant focus for the international programme are safety of reporters, gender equality and increased understanding for the role of the media in international development efforts. A link to EJC&apos;s report on these activities can be found under &apos;related activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order for the lobby and advocacy strategy to work, Free Press Unlimited believes there is also a strong necessity to develop an international program. On the one hand, lobby and advocacy efforts are immensely effective when and if international (diplomatic and media) pressure is applied to persuade government and authorities to improve and change their behavior and enabling environment. This is especially true in the area of safety. On the other hand, global networks of peer organizations can leverage learning, research and development efforts by other actors. Coordination can also foster collective attention to issues and especially help and improve harmonization of intervention efforts and aid effectiveness.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and Quality</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and Quality Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kqc@freepressunlimited.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1005978</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">1017425</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">53790</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aggregated for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Freedom House, GFMD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-31">548108</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovation (prototypes, netaidaidkit, malware analysis, censorship analysis) and International Lobby &amp; Advocacy. Aggregated for 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">445589</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovation (prototypes, netaidaidkit, malware analysis, censorship analysis) and International Lobby &amp; Advocacy. Aggregated for 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-IP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1005978</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">1017425</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">59767</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-IP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GFMD, Freedom House and Manifesta</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">93660</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GFMD, Freedom House and Manifesta</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">150000</value>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-4-RR-SP-16" ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporters Respond Budget</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">46000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">33499</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">43660</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">565647</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">111100</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">98999</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">737804</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">89750</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">17000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">975874</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-52957535-4-RR-SP-16" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-52957535-SP" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NetAidKit</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited has developed and continuous to improve the NetAidKit, a tool to increase digital security of journalists and activists. The Netaidkit is used in several countries in the context of the No News is Bad News Program to support digital safety.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amount of NetAidKits distrubuted to organisations or persons involved in the Strategic Partnership program</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intermediate Outcome 1: An enabling environment for the media is established, conducive to freedom of expression, pluralism and diversity</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited seeks to support the enabling environment for free and pluralistic media through it&apos;s international lobby and advocacy activities. These support and enable success in our other objectives.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relevant policy makers and legislators establish legal and regulatory frameworks</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Human Rights Council discusses the human rights situation in all UN member states, including freedom of the press, in the Universal Periodic Review. When a country in which Free Press Unlimited is active or has a network is under review, Free Press Unlimited drafts recommendations and background information on issues related to press freedom in that country, and offers these to the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs as input for the review. There is an active participation of Free Press Unlimited country experts in groups working on shrinking space for civil society and in the development of scenarios and policies. There are ad-hoc lobby and advocacy efforts by Free Press Unlimited when issues come up in countries in which we work, for instance by providing information to inform the Dutch government&apos;s position and policy.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperation between Free Press Unlimited and the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs on certain countries is starting to be developed, but for an actual partnership in this field more coordination is needed. A group of 8 Strategic Partnership consortia has been formed to work jointly on the issue of shrinking space for civil society which confronts all partners. The current plan is to identify 4/5 Strategic Partnership countries where the shrinking space for civil society is a pressing issue and to start doing joint analysis and scenario planning, to be able to better react to different developments and to operate in times of shrinking or increasing space for civil society to operate.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="99">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recommendations by Free Press Unlimited are incorporated into the Dutch interventions during Human Rights Council sessions. Transparency on policy choices is achieved so we are able in the end to work fully complementary on improving the press freedom and media environment. Workable scenarios are developed for 4/5 countries which assist in coping with the shrinking space for civil society and models are created to be used in other countries where this issue is present as well.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society Organisations lobby and advocate actively for journalist safety</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited shares information on safety violations of journalists from civil society organisations in our network with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, so that they can use it in the Universal Periodic Review of the Human Rights Council and as a policy and advocacy tool generally. UNESCO reports on the safety of journalists and the danger of impunity, based on information provided by member-states; Free Press Unlimited requests and facilitates partners in non-reporting countries to reach out to the responsible authorities to request information about the status of legal investigations into the unresolved cases of killed journalists in their country and to encourage the authorities to report to UNESCO. Free Press Unlimited lobbies for more support for safety of journalists through international networks on an international level and individually or in a network on a national level.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision-makers are not fully aware of international standards and norms for press freedom, and therefore can be persuaded by pressure through (inter)national lobbying and advocacy. A cooperation with Ministry of Foreign Affairs on this in certain strategic partnership countries will be developed.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="99">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recommendations by FPU on (impunity of) violence against journalists are incorporated into the Dutch interventions during the Universal Periodic Review process. Transparency on policy choices is achieved so we are able in the end to work fully complementary on improving the press freedom and media environment.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society Organisations support and defend the enabling environment for Media as a condition for Lobby &amp; Advocacy</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitor multilateral organisations active on press freedom and safety of journalists (UNESCO, UNHRC, UNGA, OECD, OSCE,EU). Document commitments and where relevant interventions that can be used for advocacy on national level. Provide local Civil Society Organisations with information on commitments made by their governments at multilateral level and assist them in identifying the right avenues and contacts within government.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the majority of countries where Free Press Unlimited is active Civil Society Organisaions lack the knowledge on avenues to engage with their governments.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="99">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society Organisations are enabled to identify the right avenues and contacts within government to influence the policy and legislation relevant to the enabling environment for the media. Focus areas are safety of journalists, gender equality and increased understanding of for the role of media in international development efforts.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Censorship analysis</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are already some countries in which internet censorship is monitored, but what exactly is measured differs. Free Press Unlimited wants to make the measurement of internet censorship more structured, widespread and comparable across countries. To do so, we want to: develop a standard for the measurement of internet censorship ; build a database of existing censorship monitoring data based on this standard; develop new tools to monitor and analyse internet censorship based on this standard; expand the number of countries in which this is being monitored; make the resulting data available and intelligible and bring it to the attention of Civil Society Organisations and decision-makers.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">We still need to develop an indicator to monitor progress on this activity.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Journalists and media actors work professionally and are effective and sustainable</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media are sustainable organisations: Media deal effectively with safety and security threats (physical, digital, psycho-social, legal)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited seeks to improve the digital safety of journalists through innovations that are developed and shared across the countries of the No News Is Bad News program.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anecdotically, we know that many journalists and activists face digital threats: being cut off from vital digital infrastructure to communicate and share their news or having their communication monitored, threatening their (ability to engage with) sources. Specific measurements will follow over the course of the program to map the scale of the problem and specific needs.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="99">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Journalists have safe and secure digital communication channels and can protect their information from breaches.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
