<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-52957535-H-KO-52-14-06</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowering Kosovo&apos;s Media Pioneers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The media practice in Kosovo is determined by the existence of mainly Prishtina-based powerful private television stations, several politicized dailies with a total circulation of around 30.000, and a public broadcaster that is effectively controlled by the Government. Being a journalist in Kosovo is often considered as a transitory phase before getting to the real power.

Public polls (UNDP Public Pulse project) show that Kosovo&#x2019;s population has little trust in democratic institutions, including media, with the majority believing that Kosovo media does not enjoy freedom of expression. The coverage of the local elections of 2013, following the April 2013 agreement among Kosovo and Serbia, was done exclusively in ethnic lines. Media did not inform the public accurately and did not cover the local dimension of the political agreement. Independent media is a rarity in Kosovo, and even more so for critical media operating outside Prishtina.

This project focused on two main aspects of the problem:
-News from/about the regions &#x2013; strengthening of regional media
The last decade saw the birth of several local radio stations, but not of local newspapers. Evidence shows that national and local radios tend to be less sensational and more mature than television and online portals. An audience research carried out by KMI few years ago has also shown that local radios have a significantly larger share of audience in comparison to national radio (69.76% compared to 33.54%). However, the number of stations and their popularity does not translate into a meaningful quantity and quality of information provided to local communities: regional media is staffed with untrained journalists, and re-broadcasting and copying from other media is a common practise. 

-A paradigm shift &#x2013; from eminence-based to evidence-based journalism 
Kosovo lacks a strong critical media, which would not rely on the Government or political parties for funding or support. Most outlets focus mostly on covering press conferences, pre-arranged media events and breaking news, rather than embarking on difficult investigative reports targeting corruption and providing detailed analysis. This is due to many media organisations&#x2019; reluctance to take on powerful individuals, as well as a lack of resources and skills.

Thankfully, the media sector has also seen the growth and development of a number of promising initiatives during the last few years:  

Kosovo 2.0
Primarily an online platform that pulses with voices unfettered and unafraid. Interactive blogs, articles and multimedia bring the untold stories Kosovo in the open, giving voice to the country&#x2019;s silenced, disfranchised majority: young people. Kosovo 2.0 also publishes a thematic biannual print magazine. Kosovo 2.0 reports in three languages Albanian, Serbian and English.
Kosovo Center for Investigative Journalism (KCIJ) 
An initiative of the Organization for Democracy, Anticorruption and Dignity &#x2013;  &#xC7;OHU. KCIJ was born out of discontent with the level of investigative journalism in Kosovo, bringing evidence and analysis about sensitive issues such as abuse of political power and corruption. It produces the bi-monthly PretPortr investigative report. KCIJ has its own website where all the research is published and also cooperates with daily newspapers Koha Ditore and Z&#xEB;ri, where Preportr issues are published. 
INC &#x2013; Local Radio Network 
10 stations operating throughout Kosovo. It includes Albanian, Serbian and one Romani language stations. INC is an initiative of Urban FM radio. 
Institute for Policy and Development (INDEP) 
A think tank and an advocacy center that provides independent research-based policy solutions, focusing on strengthening democratic governance and playing the role of public policy watchdog.

The project put into practice the recommendations of earlier evaluations of practices, which had pointed to the need for intense cooperation among all partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the proposed project is to promote freedom of expression and independent media as a pillar for the development of a democratic society in Kosovo. The focus lies on the ability of the partners to produce investigative reports, online/multimedia content, and to provide media coverage of regional stories and issues in an investigative way &#x2013; promoting investigations.  

1) Quality local news and investigative stories are produced and distributed cross-platform at local and national levels;
The 10 local stations that are currently on air (the INC network) and Kosovo 2.0 are thin and lean operations that will benefit greatly from joint program production and distribution. Instead of considering them in isolation, the action aims to bring key bloggers, talented journalists from the regions, representing different communities and generations, to report and produce multimedia local stories cross platform. 

2) Strengthened capacity of INC&#x2019;s local radio network and the Kosovo Centre for Investigative Journalism (KCIJ). 

3) Increased public awareness about the role of local media, freedom of speech and investigative reporting.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INC radio network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Development Policy (INDEP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Centre for Investigative Journalism</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="MEDIA AND ACCOUNTABILITY" percentage="100" vocabulary="99"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-01">114938</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-10-01">114938</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds reserved to be allocated within MFS2 Kosovo budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-01">5450</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shared costs. Kosovo 2.0 coordinates the program in Kosovo and is responsible for the cooperation between the four Kosovar organisations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-01">31250</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-01">10000</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INDEP</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-01">40750</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KCIJ</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-09-01">27488</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exchange between the Partnership and the Croation Journalists Association</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">An exchange between the Partnership and the Croation Journalists Association will strengthen the links between the organisations and their network in the region.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Exchange</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The representatives form the Croation Journalists Association meet with all four partner organisations. The local project coordinator will produce a day-to-day overview of the activities of the representatives from the Croatian Journalists Association and give and indicate which organisations they have met and when.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The exchange visit with CJA has not been arranged, it was replaced with two travel visits from Kosovo 2.0 and INC Network.

The first visit was in January 2015 in Basel/Switzerland, in which Besa Luci (Project Coordinator and Executive Director of Kosovo 2.0) and Sokol Loshi (Sales and Event Manager at Kosovo 2.0) have presented and promoted the releasing of the Migration magazine issue, and the launching campaign of the Sports magazine issue which was out in March 2015. 

The travel was used as exchange between media in Serbia and Kosovo 6 Journalist/Editors, of INC visited Belgrade (some of the institution visited, Media Center, Helsinki for Human rights, RTV Kragujevci, Harte Fact &#x2013; Center for Investigation journalism). This exchange, with journalists and editors, is particularly important because of their ability to penetrate different social groups, ordinary people whose life is the most affected by the daily politics and governments&#x2019; decisions taken in each of the two countries and now decisions made over the talks between Kosovo and Serbia facilitated by the EU. 

The newly created situation, although could not be predicted in time of project preparation, gives to the project even a greater importance since this exchange could contribute to better understanding of the situation, aims of each government in resolving the situation and provide the general public with the realistic and objective report. The project has a long term importance for the normalization of the relations between Kosovo and Serbia.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awareness-raising campaigns</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the project period the media coalition will organize 3 awareness-raising campaigns on the importance of free and independent media, using the right to Information to demand transparency and as a way to fight corruption. Specifically, INDEP will organise 3 seminars to raise awareness, including the preparation and organizing of World Press Freedom Day (May 3th).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">awareness-raising campaigns</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="20130"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased cooperation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased cooperation between the partner organisations will ensure that relevant issues raised and analysed by one partner will be followed up by the whole Partnership.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concrete cases of cooperation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concrete cases of cooperation: reports produced by one of the partners adapted by several partners to publish in their respective formats and for their audiences. Indicated in monitoring reports by the project coordinator and demonstrated by the partners.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">yes (1)/ no (0)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preportr</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KCIJ continues to produce 3 editions of &apos;Preportr&apos;, a quarterly investigative publication, online and in print.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 editions of &apos;Preportr&apos;</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first Preportr issue  was published in December 2014. This issue dealt will political patronage in Kosovo. 

The second Preportr issue, which was published on January 2015, was about cytostatic contraband and how these illegal medicines ended up in public health clinics.

The last Preportr issue  was dedicated to war veterans and their problems including the missing law and receiving no funding or any institutional support.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multimedia productions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0 will make at least 40 multimedia productions and distribute them online and offline.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0 will make at least 40 multimedia productions and distribute them online and offline.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="40"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0 print magazines</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0 will publish two print magazines (ranging from 120-160 pages).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo 2.0 print magazines</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The &#x201C;Migration&#x201D; issue 

&quot;Sports&quot; issue</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Radio programs</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular radio programs will be produced and distributed by all INC members and the broader INC/FPU network (also online).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of radio programs</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of programs per week/ month: 5 and 22, respectively, as indicated in monitoring reports by the project coordinator and demonstrated by the partners (INC).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="200">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Listeners of 9 different local radio stations were informed about illegal immigration, freedom of media, importance of having intra-ethnic and regional cooperation, more informed about gender discrimination, problems and discrimination that members of LGBT community face, discrimination that minority ethnic groups face especially Roma, Ashkali and Egyptian community face but also about different social and cultural issues as well as about successful stories (finally Kosovo is part of International Olympic Committee; a series of editions were produced and broadcast on internationalization of sport in cooperation with the special edition of Kosovo 2.0 on this issue).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training program</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ten journalists working for print, radio, television, on-line outlets from various regions in Kosovo will be trained as investigative journalists by KCIJ. The trainees will produce in-depth investigations which will be reformatted and published by all the partners and the respective media where they work.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ten journalist will have finished the training program and work as investigative journalists publishing in key media.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
