<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-52957535-4-BD-BB-19</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protecting Independent Media for Effective Development (PRIMED)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PRIMED is a consortium project led by BBC Media Action in partnership with Article 19, DW Akademie, Free Press Unlimited, Global Forum for Media Development, Global Voices, International Media Support (IMS), Media Development Investment Fund, The Communication Initiative and Wits University.
The PRIMED consortium will work to strengthen independent media to produce trusted public-interest journalism and provide avenues for constructive public debate. As public-interest media around the world face increasing economic and political pressures, a major component of the project is a flagship learning initiative that will generate evidence about what works in strengthening media viability and sustainability. PRIMED is funded by the UK Department for International Development.

Within the PRIMED programme, Fee Press Unlimited (FPU) works on the global level and in Bangladesh. Globally, FPU is responsible for developing and reporting on PRIMED&#x2019;s overall approach to gender and contributes to the global the learning agenda. It develops various tools- and indicators and provides thematic support and advice related to gender and media. In Bangladesh, FPU focuses on the inclusion of women in the media sector and gender sensitive media content with South Asia Center for Media in Development (SACMID). FPU also provides thematic support and advice related the safety and security for journalists and organizes regional learning initiatives on both gender and safety in cooperation with Freedom Forum (Nepal) and Tuwindi (Mali).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1076235-GB-8700" crs-channel-code="21000" ref="GB-CHC-1076235" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBC Media Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-GOV-1-300550-101" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reception</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0031208000400</telephone>
   <email>info@freepressunlimited.org</email>
   <website>https://www.freepressunlimited.org/en</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within the PRIMED programme, Fee Press Unlimited (FPU) works on the global level and in Bangladesh. In Bangladesh, FPU focuses on the inclusion of women in the media sector and gender sensitive media content with South Asia Center for Media in Development (SACMID). FPU also provides thematic support and advice related the safety and security for journalists and organizes regional learning initiatives on both gender and safety in cooperation with Freedom Forum (Nepal) and Tuwindi (Mali).</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within the PRIMED programme, Fee Press Unlimited (FPU) works on the global level and in Bangladesh. Globally, FPU is responsible for developing and reporting on PRIMED&#x2019;s overall approach to gender and contributes to the global the learning agenda. It develops various tools- and indicators and provides thematic support and advice related to gender and media.</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="75" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="22030" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">126113</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">126113</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-31">19345</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
