<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-52957535-4-RR-SP-16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News Is Bad News: Reporters Respond</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Along with press freedom, the safety and security of journalists and media workers is worldwide under pressure. Especially local journalists are exposed to violence and (online and offline) oppressive acts. At the same time, conflicts in countries like Syria, Iraq and Congo have caused the number of casualties amongst media practitioners to skyrocket. For many of these poignant casualties nobody has ever been convicted. The lack of security for media workers worldwide has caused many to end up in situations of distress during their career. For example; they need to flee their country, have lost their equipment or suffered the physical consequences of violence and oppression. During these periods of distress, media professionals are often unable to do their work and risk losing their job forever. It is important that media workers have access to effective support mechanisms; to contribute to a sustainable enabling environment in which they can continue expressing their pluralistic and diverse voices. FPU&#x2019;s Reporters Respond programme aims to be such a support mechanism. Via Reporters Respond, FPU has extended emergency assistance to over 200 organisations and media workers over the past four years. To coordinate its activities internationally, FPU has co-founded information exchange networks like the Journalists in Distress network (JID), its East African sister network (EAJID) and the encrypted Syria Response Group (SRG).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Criteria: To achieve the objective and supply support to media workers in distress Reporters Respond selects cases according this mandate and will only be able to provide support if the following conditions are met: The crisis event, and subsequent need for support, is a direct result of being a media worker. The crisis event resulted in a direct disruption of (the ability to) work. The case has to be presented to Reporters Respond within a three month period of the related crisis event. The case is of temporary nature and the applicant aims to get back to work as soon as possible. The case needs to be confirmed by at least two trusted sources. When these condition are met, Reporters respond will be able to provide financial support in the following categories: Equipment replacement. Medical costs Legal costs Short-term living expenses This support is meant for media workers in its broadest definition: Primary target group: Media activitsts, people employed by big media, presenters and newsreaders, travelwriters, news/factual actors, people employed by small media, publishers, bloggers, investigative journalists, satirical/comedy newsmakers, unpaid journalists that work daily, cartoonists, media owners, specialist reporters, media volunteers, media dissidents, part-time reporters, student reporters/media, watchdogs, general reporters, photographer, IPL target groups and whistleblowers. Secondary target group: Media lobbyists, media trainers, media campaigners, media financiers, writers/authors, state employees, eye witness media, Sales people , PR persons/ &#x201C;spin doctors&#x201D; . Never eligible: Advertisers/marketing, opinion leaders, propagandists, extremists, paparazzi, religious leaders, family, friends and acquaintances of a media worker</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited aims to have media and journalists as independent players in civil society, constitute a diverse and professional media landscape and function as change catalysts. This means that even under difficult circumstances as armed conflicts or oppression, journalists should be able to provide accurate, balanced, timely and relevant information. However, often the minimal conditions that allow media and journalists (local or in exile) to gather information or reach their audience are not met. Journalists are confronted with vandalism, violence and intimidation because of their job and sometimes unable to continue their work because of it. Reporters Respond is an emergency fund for journalists meant to help journalists who have been confronted with vandalism or intimidation get started again as soon as possible. Reporters Respond contributes to this objective by providing financial aid to journalists, producers and cameramen and women who are at risk because of their profession. Reporters Respond aims to give support as soon as possible. This fast, small scale, financial support can help prevent more serious damage and enables journalists, producers and cameramen and women to continue to do their job. In addition to its emergency fund, Reporters Respond is also able to provide training, coaching and support on the subject of digital, physical and psychological safety. Media practitioners who identify an immediate need can apply to receive a training tailored to their situation. This way Reporters Respond contributes to the provision of training, equipment, toolkits and available research that can help media practitioners and organizations ensure their safety and security. Last, Reporters Respond aims to contribute to the safety of journalists by being an instrumental and leading member of the Journalists in Distress network and the Syria Response Group. With these networks Reporters Respond ensures that information on media practitioners in distress is vetted, shared, collected and coordinated within an efficient international network dedicated to the safety of journalists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Journalists</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-52957535" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and Quality</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and Quality Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kqc@freepressunlimited.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-IP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Free Press Unlimited</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">136688</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535- 4-RR-SP-16" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">164325</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-IP" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">18440</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-31">137287</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">14310</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">15000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">14737</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">195529</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">155000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">223497</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">220000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">17000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">17000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">317502</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-IP" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Successful applications to emergency fund</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Successful applications to emergency fund in 2019</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no target number of grants. Successful applications vary in the size of the grant and will be awarded based on the assessed need and impact and on the availability of the budget.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-10-28" value="40" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between January 1st and December 31st 2020, Reporters Respond received 353 applications (67% men, 26% women, 7% organisations), of which 113 were accepted, 11 successfully referred and 229 declined. Accepted applications from the following regions: MENA 43, Eurasia 14, Americas 21, Sub-Saharan Africa 24, Asia 4, Europe 5, North America 2. Due to COVID 19, the fund was opened to safeguard secure media operations applications. 97 applications were made, 8 were accepted, 2 were referred to other organisations. A total of 3113 journalists have received protection materials.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="37">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Out of a total of 163 applications between January 1st and December 31st 2019, 69 successful applications were made from: Sub-Saharan Africa: 19; Middle East and North Africa: 25; Eurasia: 5; Americas: 16; Asia-Pacific: 4. 52 applicants were male, 13 female, 0 non-binary and 4 organisations (Countries classified into regions according to Freedom House classification)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Successful applications to emergency fund in 2016</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no target number of grants. Successful applications vary in the size of the grant and will be awarded based on the assessed need and impact and on the availability of the budget.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="40" year="2015"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Out of a total of 194 applications. Successful applications were made from: Sub-Saharan Africa: 30; Middle East and North Africa: 11; Europe: 1; Eurasia: 5; Americas: 2; Asia-Pacific: 1. (Countries classified into regions according to Freedom House classification. )</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Successful applications to emergency fund 2018</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is no target number of grants. Successful applications vary in the size of the grant and will be awarded based on the assessed need and impact and on the availability of the budget.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="43" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="65">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Out of a total of 190 applications between Q1-Q4, 73 applications were successfully made from Americas: 9; Asia-Pacific: 7; Eurasia: 15; MENA: 23; Sub-Saharan Africa: 19 (Countries classified into regions according to Freedom House classification)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Successful applications to emergency fund 2017</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="50" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="43">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Out of a total of 154 applications. Successful applications were made from: Sub-Saharan Africa: 11; Middle East and North Africa: 22; Europe: 1; Eurasia: 1; Americas: 4; Asia-Pacific: 4. (Countries classified into regions according to Freedom House classification. )</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
