<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9862</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEF CASPI Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caspi Ltd. is located in the town of Atyrau, one of the sites of extensive oil exploration in western Kazakhstan. The Company owns Chagala Hotel, a three-star hotel in Atyrau, and a small guesthouse in settlement Bautino, south of Atyrau and close to the Caspian oilfields, a site of the marine-supply base constructed by Offshore Kazakhstan International Operating Company (OKIOC).    The proposed project consists of the expansion and development of the Chagala Hotel and of the guesthouse in Bautino. The hotel and guesthouse offer rooms in $80-$120 range and the target market is oil workers and associated staff involved with the oil exploration and development work in the Caspian.  This will be IFC&apos;&apos;s first investment in this strategically important area of Kazakhstan, which is expected to be the prime driver of growth for the next twenty years.  The expansion of the Chagala Hotel will meet the growing needs of the international oil companies and related support companies that are developing the new Kashagan oilfield in the Caspian Sea, which is estimated to have reserves several times that of the North Sea.  Following this discovery, neither the Chagala Hotel nor the Bautino guesthouse can meet demand.    IFC has a strong role to play in this project through the provision of long-term funding.  Term financing is practically unavailable in Kazakhstan and IFC&apos;&apos;s financing will enable the company to expand the Chagala Hotel and Bautino guesthouse to meet the needs of international clients.  IFCs participation in the project is also expected to facilitate the company&apos;&apos;s future access to international borrowing.  The expansion of the Chagala Hotel and the Bautino guesthouse is a vital component of the business infrastructure in Western Kazakhstan as foreign businessmen require such accommodation to operate.  As such, this expansion and development work will contribute to attracting foreign investment into Kazakhstan.  The project will provide direct employment to the company&apos;&apos;s employees and indirectly to hundreds of workers providing goods and services to the company.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CASPI Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9862" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-10-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-12-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tim Abson, General Director, Caspi Ltd.   K.Ismagulov Str., #1, Atyrau, 465002, Kazakhstan   Tel: (7-31222) 54033   Fax: (7-31222) 54034</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kazakhstan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="KZ-Kazakhstan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The principal locations of the project are in town of Atyrau and small south-western settlement Bautino in Western   Kazakhstan, which is the main oil and gas producing area of the country.  The oil and gas export revenues, combined with the Caspian Sea sturgeon contribute about 22% to the country&apos;&apos;s GDP.  According to Economist Intelligence Unit, the oil and gas sector alone accounts for 44% of total exports and 85% of total FDI flow of Kazakhstan.  The region&apos;&apos;s enormous oil and gas reserves have attracted scores of foreign oil and gas companies (Chevron, Shell, British Gas/Petroleum, Total, Agip and others) since the country gained independence from Soviet Union in 1991.  However, the region&apos;&apos;s basic infrastructure and services are under-developed and exploration work is a real challenge for foreign oil and gas companies.  To address the shortage of export capacity, a consortium led by Chevron is in the process of building a $2.3 billion pipeline, that will transport Caspian Sea oil to the Black Sea.  An agreement has been signed for another pipeline project which would connect the western Kazakhstan fields with Mediterranean Sea.  These projects will clearly boost Kazakhstan&apos;&apos;s oil and gas production and facilitate developments of new fields, but they will also create an urgent need for accommodation for workers in the oil and gas industry .  As the only incumbent Western hotel, the Caspi Ltd. is well placed to capitalise on this opportunity.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.0000000000 68.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - City and Business Hotel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $2.50 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-10-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-10-04">2500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-10-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-10-04">2500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CASPI Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9862/sef-caspi-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
