<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10558</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Astana Tower Business and Shopping Center</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project involves the development of a greenfield business and shopping center in view of the anticipated demand for quality office and shopping space in Astana. In 1998, Astana became Kazakhstan&apos;&apos;s new capital and most of the national government administration has since been moved from Almaty to Astana.  Businesses and foreign investors have also started to establish their presence in the capital city.  However, the lack of quality business infrastructure has been an impediment to more rapid movement of businesses to Astana, and has hindered Astana&apos;&apos;s emergence as a fully developed new capital.  Astana Business and Shopping Center (ABS, or the company) responds to this growing need for modern business and office space in the emerging capital city of Kazakhstan.  In Astana, ABS is the first business and shopping center built to international standards.     ABS is located in a busy area of Astana at the intersection of one of the citys busiest avenues leading to  government, city administration, and diplomatic quarters.  The project was designed by Turkish architects and has been developed by Ahsel Group, which has been active and known in Kazakhstan, most notably through its Regent Ankara Hotel in Almaty.  ABS consists of a 20-floor office/ residential tower and a 3-floor shopping area, which is connected to the tower at the ground floor.  The building is suitable for international companies and is equipped with modern facilities, including a fitness center, central heating and air-conditioning, security systems, information technology network, communications systems, fire/ smoke detectors and sprinklers.       Development Impact   :  The projects developmental impact is expected to be significant since the project will help upgrade the local business environment, introduce modern business practices, and provide shopping facilities in the local community.  The project will help attract private businesses and foreign capital to Astana and help develop the new capital of Kazakhstan.       IFC Role:     The project is in line with the Kazakh government&apos;&apos;s priority to rapidly establish the city as the nation&apos;&apos;s capital by encouraging influx of private businesses in Astana as well.  Astana is likely to attract more businesses to relocate from Almaty if the currently available business and office infrastructure is upgraded to meet required international standards.     IFC&apos;&apos;s investment would signal confidence in the development of private sector activity in Astana and private investment in Kazakhstan.  IFC will provide the company with long-term financing, which is not available in the local market.  Furthermore, IFC has introduced Ahsel Group to the World Trade Center organization, which is seeking to extend its network into Kazakhstan and is considering locating their operation in Astana Tower.  This is likely to significantly benefit Kazakhstan&apos;&apos;s integration with overseas markets.  Finally, IFC will work with the sponsors to increase their awareness of international safety and construction standards, which is expected to result in consistent application of these standards in other Ahsel tourism and residential development projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Astana Business and Shopping Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10558" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-05-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-07-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mrs. Guzide Tumer, Member of Ahsel Board   Bilkent Plaza A3, Ankara, Turkey.   Phone: 90 312 266 0030   Fax:  90 312 266 7207</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kazakhstan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="KZ-Kazakhstan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a greenfield development located in Astana, the new capital city of Kazakhstan.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.0000000000 68.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AE - Other (Including Restaurants, Amusement Parks, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $5.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2003-05-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2003-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-05-08">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2003-05-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-05-08">5000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Astana Business and Shopping Center</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10558/astana-tower-business-and-shopping-center">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
