<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/2RA 2017/Health-WASH/INGO/6280</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Cholera Response in Amran Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the children is proposing to implement a three month emergency cholera response project that will significantly contribute to the containment and reduction of the spread of cholera and related deaths in Amran Governorates through timely implementation of integrated Health and WASH interventions. 

Health: the project is aiming to contribute to the reduction of cholera morbidity and mortality, as well as contribute to the reduction of cholera transmission through increasing hygiene practices awareness and Oral Rehydration Salt (ORS) preparation and use in the targeted communities through trained volunteers in Amran governorate. The project will achieve these objectives by providing support to 3 diarrhea treatment centers (DTC) in addition to 15 Oral Rehydration Therapy (ORT) centers located in the catchment area of the DTC (5 per each DTC). 
The project will support the DTC through provision of incentives for the medical staff, provision of running cost for daily consumable items, provision off cholera medication and medical supplies so as to be able to receive cholera cases and provide quality management. The project also will also establish and support 15 ORT corners at community level and corners will be run by trained community health workers. These centers will lead in the detection of the suspected cases, provide ORS to all diarrheal cases and refer the critical cases to the DTC. 
The project will increase the capacity of health workers at DTC and community health workers at working at ORT corners. The training will cover the following topics: surveillance system, case definition and case management, health education and community mobilization and referral. The project will help in referral the critical cases and submitting samples for suspected cases to the central lab for confirmation.
The project will be implemented with full integration with WASH sectors by targeting the same communities and complement the prevention measures with curative measures for better control and management of the crisis. All the WASH activities will be within the DTC/Health facilities.

WASH: SC propose to conduct the following activities: rehabilitation of water, sanitation and hand washing facilities at targeted 03 health clinics/DTC, distribution of cleaning toolkits to the targeted health facilities, distribution of water storage buckets, water purification tablets and WASH Cluster standard basic hygiene kits to the affected beneficiaries who come to the targeted DTCs for services. The project will also conduct cholera hygiene awareness sessions in the Health facility/DTC and key topics that will be discussed will include: safe water chain, proper use and maintenance of latrines,  avoid open defecation, hand washing with soap at critical stages, solid waste management and cleaning campaign, use of Cl2 tablets and chlorinated water, Jerry can cleaning campaigns at households and water points, door to door campaign for chlorination of household water storage tanks, personal hygiene issues like menstrual hygiene management and other hygiene management mechanisms. As specific focus on Cholera outbreak, the project will educate the beneficiaries coming to the DTC on cholera prevention, symptoms, cases referral including information about health facilities/DTC. Planned community awareness sessions will be conducted jointly with community health workers. Health project will complement other WASH activities that will be implemented with an integrated approach (messaging, campaigning of WASH and Health together). The integrated project will focus on the catchment population of 03 targeted health facility/DTCs under Amran. WASH activities will mainly focus on the prevention of Cholera activities by addressing some of the underlying risk factors such as inadequate poor quality water supply, poor sanitation and hygiene practices while Health intervention will mainly focus on the surveillance of the Cholera outbreak with curative treatm</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awards Management</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>dahir.ahmed@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Dahir Ahmed</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Development  Quality</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Muhsin.siddiquey@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Muhsin Siddique</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amran</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.35709040 43.87269369</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-14">450000.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6304280944">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-18">36755.22</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400253635">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-15">1164.86</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6280">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-14">450000.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302741162">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-23">450000.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
