<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/2SA 2017/Health-WASH/NGO/7080</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scaling up the Emergency Integrated Cholera Response in Taiz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The scaling up emergency cholera outbreak response in Taiz aims to reduce the morbidity and mortality in the most affected people in (Maqbanah, Al Wazya&apos;ah, Al Muka, Sharab Ar Rawnah, At Tazya&apos;ah, and Jabal Habashy) districts within 6 months by strengthening the control and prevention of the outbreak in particular the hard to reach communities through integrated approach (Health and WASH). The project targets 73,000 of the affected people and the internally displaced persons (12387) men (12502) women ( 13659) boys (20040) girls who are exposed to the outbreak and the areas with potential effect to the epidemic  in the following sub districts (At Tazya&apos;ah :Al Gandiah Al Ola&apos;ah  and Al Sha&apos;abaniyah,  Maqbanah: Al Malaheda&apos;a and Al Mawg, Sharab Ar Rawnah: Sharqi Hemyar  and Al Hayagem , Al Wazya&apos;ah: Al Ahyouk and Al Bawkarrah , Al Muka: Al Goma&apos;ah  and Al Zahari, Jabal Habashi: Al Barriaha and Belad Al Wafi). The project is a complementary response for&quot; IYCY Cholera Outbreak Response Project in Taiz&quot; held in July 1st 2017 to 1st October 2017.It goes in line with HFP Allocation Strategy under envelope 3 where IYCY scaled its  existing response, and strategically fit to the cholera integrated response plan 2017. The project consists of health and WASH components. Health activities are related to defined and timely disease surveillance and reporting, early detection of the suspected cases in the community and the effective treatment on the DTC level in 15 health facilities (As Shaheed Abduljalil, Al Hurriah, Al Ahtoob, Al Zarari, Al Amaqi, Albarh, Zogal, Al Ahyouk, Al Guma&apos;ah, As Shaheed Al Durra, Yafros, Al Nasr ) at the six targeted districts. The health facility will be provided with the essential medical supplies. On the other hand, WASH part focuses on prevention infection and control of the epidemic in the affected communities and the areas with potential to the outbreak through distribution of the hygiene kits, jerry cans, acqutabas and hygiene promotion sessions in the communities and DTC level. In addition, IYCY will dedicate the efforts on assessing the water, sanitation and hygiene in the communities in order to support the cluster with the integrated gaps for YHRP 2018. As this project is designed to strengthened DTCs functionality in supporting the health personnel and provision of medical supplies, IYCY, in coordination with UNICEF, is responding to the essential DTCs WASH needs in terms of water trucking, latrines rehabilitation, strengthening IPC practices, and medical and no-medical stuff waste management. Noting that, this response is completing the first project implemented between July 1st to October 1st, 2017. Therefore, interrelated response is taking place for alleviation the outbreak conduct the activities based on the IYCY polices and implementation guidelines accompanied with great commitment OCHA operational and financial policies and regulations. IYCY maintains a very good access to the targeted districts since the previous cholera response. IYCY is maintain a very good relationship with government officials and local communities. As this project is designed to strengthened DTCs functionality in supporting the health personnel and provision of medical supplies, IYCY, in coordination with UNICEF, is responding to the essential DTCs WASH needs in terms of water trucking, latrines rehabilitation, strengthening IPC practices, and medical and no-medical stuff waste management. Noting that, this response is completing the first project implemented between July 1st to October 1st, 2017. Therefore, interrelated response is taking place for alleviation the outbreak conduct the activities based on the IYCY polices and implementation guidelines accompanied with great commitment OCHA operational and financial policies and regulations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr.Abduljabbar Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967772636531</telephone>
   <email>abduljabbar.hassan@iycy.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-22">459461.21</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-7080">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-22">459461.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303103769">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-04">229730.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303325305-311">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-11">229730.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
