<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/1SA 2017/Health-Nutrition/INGO/6165</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated Health and Nutrition services by running 4 Fixed Health facilities supported by a network of Community Health Volunteers(CHVs) for community outreach in Ibb governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at reducing morbidity and mortality of most vulnerable conflict-affected populations with focus on children under 5 and pregnant and lactating women through the provision of life saving emergency health and nutrition services by running 4 partially functioning health facilities and establishing a network of Community Health Volunteers(CHVs) that would provide community outreach services. 
The project will focus two peripheral districts in Ibb (Far Al Udayn and Hamz Al Udayn) where the health facilities have nearly collapsed. The selection of the health facilities was done with consultation with Ministry of Public Health and Population(MoPHP) as per attached letter. INTERSOS would run 4 health centre level facilities which are nearly non-functional. These districts are in severe need of emergency assistance and have been identified as extremely vulnerable by UN agencies and the MoPHP with significant concentration of IDPs mainly from Taiz. The project builds on INTERSOS&#x2019; prior and on-going experience of INTERSOS in Sana&#x2019;a, Ibb, Taiz, Hadramout and Aden implementing health and nutrition funded by OCHA YHPF, UNICEF, DEC and WHO.
The proposal follows on the priorities set by the Health and Nutrition Cluster and MoPHP for emergency health and nutrition interventions: integrated health and nutrition services provided though 4 fixed health facilities supported by a network of 24 CHVs. Through this project, a total 114,640 IDPs and host community individuals in the two-selected district of Ibb governorate will have access to a package of Primary Health Care (PHC) integrated with nutrition services. The Integrated Health and Nutrition Package includes Reproductive Health/Maternal, Neonatal, Child Health (RH/MNCH), include antenatal, deliveries and postnatal care for mothers newborn care, immunization (for both routine and supplementary vaccines), deworming, vitamin A supplementation, screening for malnutrition, treatment for acute malnutrition cases, health education, Outpatient Consultation and treatment for common aliments for both adults and children. INTERSOS will integrate components of Infant and Young Child Feeding (IYCF) in nutrition treatment and prevention. In addition, with the current ongoing Cholera outbreak, each health facility would also run an Oral Rehydration Corner(ORC) and refer severely dehydrated cases to the nearest Diarrheal Treatment Centre(DTC). 
The health facility will run both Outpatient Therapeutic Program (OTP) and Supplementary Feeding Program(SFP) for the Management of Severe Acute Malnutrition(MAM) and Moderate Acute Malnutrition (MAM). This will enable health facilities supported by CHVs to identify and initiate treatment for children with acute malnutrition before they become seriously ill. The health facilities will provide treatment for most children with SAM/MAM in the home using Ready-to-Use-Therapeutic Foods (RUTF) and routine medical care. When necessary, severely malnourished children who have medical complications or lack an appetite are referred to in-patient facilities for more intensive treatment. The nutrition program will integrate health education for prevention and sustainability. Nutritional supplies for the will be obtained from UNICEF (SAM supplies) and WFP(MAM supplies).
The project will establish an efficient outreach and referral mechanism from community level to primary health services and for primary to secondary health services through Basic Life Support(BLS) ambulances that transport cases to referral health facilities in the district or Ibb city. Each district would have one BLS ambulance and can be activated by CHVs at the community level or staff at the health facilities. While the proposal is a multi-sector programme (Health-Nutrition), the project ensures attention for protection and gender mainstreaming</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Unshur</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 715 555 004</telephone>
   <email>health.coord.yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mirela Kuljanin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 715 555 001</telephone>
   <email>yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.05521633 44.26319019</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-12">375410.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-12">560038.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6165">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-12">935449.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302774316-321">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-19">748359.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303452728">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-24">187089.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
