<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/1SA 2017/Health-Nutrition-WASH/INGO/6012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, Nutrition and WASH live saving intervention in Hajjah governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children (SC) aims to respond to the urgent needs of the conflict affected communities in two districts (BaniQais, Al shaghadrah) of Hajjah governorate in Yemen. An integrated one-year project will be implemented to reduce child and maternal mortality, and to strengthen protection for children whose lives are being threatened by the ongoing and current humanitarian crisis in the country
This will be achieved through a life-saving intervention in health, nutrition and WASH. Health will focus on provision of newborn health, child health and maternal health at fixed primary health care facilities while nutrition will focus on treatment of Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM) and moderate acute malnutrition (MAM) for children and Targeted Supplementary Feeding Programme (TSFP) for Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW), and promotion of optimal Infant and Young Child Feeding Practices (IYCF) targeting caregivers of children aged 0-23 months old. The project will provide safe water, sanitation and hygiene promotion, inclusive of Gender Based Violence (GBV) awareness within the health facilities and safe water for households that are highly exposed to cholera, also receiving comprehensive hygiene and GBV messaging. Addressing WASH needs will impact on the reduction of malnutrition, through the reduction of disease in infants and young children. 
At national Level SC will engage an IYCF in Emergencies Expert to support the nutrition cluster partners and MoPHP to develop and operationalize the IYCF in Emergencies response plan as this was identified a priority from the cluster. At community level, the project will strengthen community participation in all interventions. Community volunteers (CV) will carry out malnutrition and IYCF screening, referral of acutely malnourished children to the health facilities, community awareness raising on IYCF and health and hygiene promotion. CVs will conduct follow up activities for children in Outpatient Therapeutic Program (OTP) and TSFP activities. At the health facility, staff will deliver newborn, child health (Integrated Management of Childhood Illnesses -IMCI), reproductive health (Minimum Initial Service Package- MISP), immunization, treatment of minor injuries, and treatment of SAM, MAM and IYCF counselling. 
The project will support 10 fixed health facilities (Al Nwaerh, Al Mokhabel,  Bani Hafej,  AlDHher ,  Al-Tor, Mashrafah ,  Almarw,   Al-mearg Alsawalmh,  AlHakymeh and AlBagalieh) with minor rehabilitation and maintenance, provision of medical supplies, medicines, operational costs, technical training and the health system through strengthening the health information and drug management systems. Implementation will be in close coordination and cooperation with Ministry of Public Health and Population (MoPHP) at national, governorate and district levels including the national and sub national Health and Nutrition Clusters. 
WASH, SC proposes temporary water trucking  for 200 IDP households for  60 days(until key water points are rehabilitated- an exit strategy for water trucking), safe water quality by chlorinating the water source (the rehabilitation of 10 water points i.e. piped water points or unprotected dug wells), rehabilitation of WASH facilities at health clinics, distribution of water storage PVC tanks with taps, water ceramic filters (testing the performance of 1%  Ceramic filter), and the distribution of water purification tablets for one month to targeted households at high risk of cholera exposure and distribution of basic hygiene kits with impregnated mosquito nets since Hajjah is a malaria prone and the summer season is approaching. Hygiene promotion awareness will focus on safe water chain, options for sanitation to avoid open defecation, hygienic latrine use, hand washing with soap or ash at critical stages, solid waste management, food hygiene, HH water treatment methods, cholera prevention messages, drainage and vector control issues like prevention of malaria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhsin Siddiquey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programme Development  Quality</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 737 789 138</telephone>
   <email>Muhsin.Siddiquey@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dahir Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awards Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967735201486</telephone>
   <email>dahir.ahmed@saveechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="24" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="36" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-07">1106044.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-07">1093956.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6012">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-07">2200001.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302767916">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-13">1760001.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303866844">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-11">438976.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
