<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/2RA 2017/Health-WASH/NGO/6265</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IYCY Scaling up Integrated Response to Chorea Outbreak in Taizz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is intending to scale up the ongoing integrated cholera response in Taiz with focus to the coastal districts Sharab Ar Rawanh, Maqbanah, Al Wazya&#x2019;ah, Jabal Habashy, Al Muka and At Ta&apos;iziyah districts in Taizz. The overall objective of this project is to reduce the occurrence and to minimize morbidity and fatality of cholera and AWD through effective prevention and timely response in three months. The project targets 58,005 individuals men (12744 ) women (13961 ) boys (15409 ) and girls (15891)  the most vulnerable affected people by the new cholera outbreak in the target districts. The project goes in line with cholera integrated response plan 2017 that outlines the emergency health, WASH and communications interventions to contain and prevent further spread of the outbreak in the high risk districts through an integrated approach of WASH and health. The project is going to provide integrated package outreach program of Health and Wash services for the most vulnerable affected people in 6 target districts.
The project consists of two main components health and WASH components. Health components entails the following provision package outreach program of Health services for the most vulnerable affected people in the 6 target districts through supporting 3 DTCs already established and set up, support and strengthen the functionality of 8 Cholera Treatment Units (DTUs) and 45 Oral Rehydration Corners (ORCs) to provide specialized care and treatment, and support the target health facilities with inpatient beds and supplementary supplies and drugs to support the treatment of AWD and cholera cases, building the capacity of the health workers through training for 45 health workers from DTCs and DTUs on cholera treatment guidelines and effective case management. In addition Support and capacity of the Community based surveillance 45 CHVs in order to establish the ORCs targeted priority areas on case definitions, reporting tools, outbreak detection and first responder rules and procedures to respond to the areas affected by the cholera is strengthened as well as distribution of IEC material and ORS to the patient and referral of cases to DTCs and DTUs.
WASH component is to provide WASH Emergency Response for most affected vulnerable communities by the cholera outbreaks in targeted areas of Taizz governorate. WASH intervention aims to provision a minimum package of access to clean drinking water and sanitation, improve Hygiene promotion/awareness raising campaigns, improve waste management and improve infection prevention and control at DTC/DTUs in affected areas through supporting the 3 DTCs and 8 DTUs with required WASH facilities, chlorination of water sources, piped network and private water trucks, distribution of consumable hygiene kits, and jerry cans for households with cases and immediate surrounding households, infection of household water storage containers, distribution of chlorine tablets for water treatment at household level with proper instructions on use of the tablets, in affected locations. Carry out hygiene promotion sessions, raise awareness to HHs, communities and to the patients discharged from DTCs and DTUs, communication and mass awareness raising, including production and dissemination of IEC materials, community mobilization and cholera awareness messages, advocacy to waste management to support the AWD and cholera outbreak response under the strategic objectives of the Health and Wash clusters. IYCY works for the project in a very consideration to the coordination with key stakeholder and partners including local authorities, governorate public offices, UNICEF, WHO, other NGOs worked in the same areas and the affected people in the local communities ensuring the effectiveness response. IYCY established qualified team to implement the aforementioned activities in addition to the strong monitoring and reporting mechanisms for each activities with close coordination to the affected communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abduljabbar Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967-772636531</telephone>
   <email>abduljabbar.hassan@iycy.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-10-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-14">505476.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1107489449">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-31">62489</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6265">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-14">505476.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302743347-353">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">202190.45</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302851288-294">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-25">303285.68</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Youth Council - Yemen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
