<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/1SA 2017/FSAC/UN/6005</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Food security and Nutrition sensitive response to the most vulnerable households with malnourished Under five (U5) children and Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW) in Hodeida and Abyan Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO proposes to implement an Integrated Food security and Nutrition sensitive response to the most vulnerable households with malnourished under five (U5) children and pregnant and lactating women (PLW) in Hodeida and Abyan Governorates. This project will be complementary to WFP supplementary feeding, which will be targeting the same under five children and PLW, enrolled in the CMAM feeding programs within specific governorates. The intervention addresses the priority criteria as defined by the allocation strategy amp FSAC in terms of:
(-Highest priority geographical location (Hodeida and Abyan Governorate are among the priority 1 governorates according to FSAC and Nutrition Clusters) and also with highest % of food insecure population (IPC Phase 4- March 2017 IPC analysis). The two governorates account for 117,312 of individual IDPs (19,552 HHs), among the IDP HHs, 1,704 HHs are hosted within the community in Abyan and 2,932 HHs in Hodeida. 
-Activities - production of highly nutritious vegetables for households&#x2019; improved dietary diversity amp food intake 
- Training amp capacity development of vulnerable households (with a PLW and/or a malnourished U5 child admitted in a CMAM program) on production techniques of highly nutritious vegetables. The project intends to target a total of 21,000 households (HHs) equivalent to 147,000 individuals including U5 child or PLW enrolled in a Community Management of Malnutrition (CMAM) program. This will translate to reaching directly to 39,690 men, 38,220 women, 35,280 boys and 33,810 girls. A total of two districts in Abyan Governorate (Ahwar and Khanifar) and two districts in Al Hodeida Governorate (Al-Suknah and Bayt Al Faqeel) will be targeted in line with the FSAC amp Nutrition cluster priority districts as stipulated in the YHPF and FSAC 2017 Strategy Paper&apos;s targets.

An able bodied member drawn from targeted households will be selected for training on the cultivation of highly nutritious vegetables. This cultivation will help address underlying causes of malnutrition as well as ensuring households have some extra vegetables for sale and in return to purchase other foods for the household. The overall outcome of the cultivation of highly nutritious vegetables will be to diversify the diets and improve food and nutrition outcomes. 21,000 trainees (Hodeida - As Sukhnah, 10,636, Abyan- Khanifar - 5,727, Al Hodeida - Bayt-Al-Faqial - 3,182, and Abyan- Ahwar- 1,455)  will benefit from training program which will be divided into two sessions - 1) General training on Nutrition and Linkages between food insecurity and malnutrition and 2) Land preparations, crop production and management, harvesting, processing and marketing. The sessions will be sequenced in a manner that each household representative trainee will receive the trainings and thereafter receive the seeds for cultivation. 

The targeted households will receive a set of vegetable seeds containing 5 different types of vegetable according to preferences per district. Vegetable seeds will include Okra, Onions, Pepper, Tomatoes and green leafy vegetables. Post-distribution follow-up/monitoring will be done after training sessions and seed distribution. The project will have direct impact on preventing further deterioration of already malnourished children and PLW. Through, enriching and diversifying the diet of most food insecure households by providing immediate and sustainable sources of vitamins and minerals to supplement staple food production, reducing economic burden on host communities, rebuilding of stocks and productive assets and preventing families resorting to negative or harmful coping strategies. This project will be further complemented by WFP and UNICEF supported nutrition program who will be providing supplementary and therapeutic feeding commodities to the targeted households with U5 children or PLW enrolled in the programs where the beneficiary list of households will be drawn.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abu Mousa Al Ashary  Social Charitable Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mayar Foundation for Development (MFD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Development Hodeida Girls Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Women Union (YWU)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salah Hajj Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO Representative in Yemen</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 967-736600</telephone>
   <email>Salah.ElHajjHassan@fao.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Etienne Peterschmitt</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Representative in Yemen</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 967-737890</telephone>
   <email>etienne.peterschmitt@fao.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.69554850 46.50340692</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-07">802631.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-07">1197368.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6306052041">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-01">95513.89</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6005">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-07">2000000.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302771079">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-18">2000000.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
