<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/1SA 2017/FSAC/NGO/6132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Life-Saving Food Assistance to the Most Vulnerable Conflict Affected People in Hamdan District of Sana&#x2019;a governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed address the immediate causes of food insecurity and malnutrition through improving the availability of food and access to food for the most vulnerable affected by the conflict in Hamdan district of Sana&#x2019;a Governorate. Whereas this project contributes to prevent the increase of food insecurity and malnutrition level through the provision of life-saving assistant by providing equitable access to food baskets confirming to FSAC/Sphere standards for 1625 HHs (2230 men, 2321 women, 3344 boys and 3481 girls) in Hamdan district of Sana&#x2019;a Governorate. The project consider AAP commitments endorsed by FSAC-Yemen. Stakeholders (including beneficiaries of women and men, marginalized group (if any) and local authorities&#x2026;etc.) participate in the project design, implementation and monitoring. For example, they were consulted through the need assessment conducted by the YLDF. During implementation, regular update of the project progress, needed project indicators to be achieved challenges/how the challenges are dealt with, result of BCFM and how they were handled, levels of achievement will be shared with that stockholders. They will be represented in the project stockholder committees, effective Beneficiaries Complaint and Feedback Mechanism will be clear to all stakeholders and with instruction how (women, men, people with special needs (if any)) can convey their complaints to the project management. Local authorities and stockholder will be informed (including women and men) of humanitarian principles, lows, standards &#x2026;etc. through informative session. Selection of beneficiaries is nondiscriminatory based on clear beneficiaries selection criteria that include the ones endorsed by FSAC-Yemen prioritizing the most vulnerable of women, men, boys and girls. Also, the project has been designed based on recent need assessment conducted by the YLDF and its sub implementing partner (Resilient Communities Organization) and the NRC. The YLDF will implement this project in partnership with Resilient Communities Organization as sub-implementing partner (SIP). Resilient Communities Organization has been selected by the YLDF as sub partner due to that they are youth led organization (which is in line with the YLDF partnership policies with local NGOs). The SIP has participated in conducting the need assessment in targeted district for this project. Food security is part of their main strategic programs, also, they have an ambitious and highly qualified (from the perspective of education) team who has previously worked in humanitarian assistant limited Shelter through UNHCR partnership however, they need more experience to learn on FSA side. being the YLDF SIP in this project will give them the chance to learn, grow and contribute to securing their contribution in the humanitarian sphere with sustainability. All in all, other parts of the proposal highlight more details about the rules of both the YLDF and its SIP. The SIP will be attending FSAC meetings/events. They already sent a request to join the cluster and waiting for the response. 

The project summery is that: 
1625 HHs of most vulnerable affected by the conflict in Hamdan district will have 3 times equitable access to provided food assistant (confirming to FSAC standards) through general food assistant (voucher) approach considering associated protections, gender, risks and other considerations.  


In this proposal, the YLDF partner with the resilient community organization (RCO) who is a local partner that will deliver assistant in two camp with clear coaching and monitoring and capacity building from the YLDF.  The project in line with the fist standard allocation strategy objectives including envelop 2 objectives, FSAC objectives and RCO instructions. other parts of the project explain more details including attached risk matrix, grant justification...etc..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilient Communities Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nawal Dobais</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excutive Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>735790177</telephone>
   <email>ndobais@yldf.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="23">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sana&apos;a</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.12394358 44.78727759</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">566670.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">182696.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6132">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-27">749367.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302766339-345">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-12">299746.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303005107-13">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-16">224810.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303778805">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-14">132066.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Leadership Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
