<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-17/3420/2SA 2017/WASH-FSAC/INGO/6983</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated WASH and Food Security Response in Hajjah Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action over a period of 12 months will assist an estimated 120,939 war affected, women, men, girls, and boys, in Abs district,  Hajjah govern-orate, with improved access to food and WASH services. Oxfam and MSF have sustained access to the district currently hosting over 58,880 IDPs (48%) living in open desperate condition in the informal settlement while 63,700 (52%) IDPs reside with host communities. The project action has specifically targeted this district based as it has the highest security scores both in food security and WASH related needs and among the cholera hot-spot. On the other hand Oxfam has high level of acceptance, established infrastructure and tested modality for WASH and EFSVL programming of up to &#xA3;7.5 million/year in Hajja and neighbouring govern-orates  while at the same time recognising the lack of humanitarian support from other actors
 
The project design is based on rapid needs assessment conducted on 21 Sept. 2017 by Oxfam and the ever-changing conflict context, humanitarian gaps, and priorities based on community needs. The project aims to ensure that IDPs and host communities have access to basic WASH services and food through integrated intervention, with a well-thought approach to address specific needs of women, children, elderly, people with disabilities and vulnerable groups while ensuring their participation in planning, implementation, and monitoring of interventions.
 This project will contribute to the YHRP food security objectives (1) improve the availability of food and access to food for the most vulnerable and objective (3) improve food security by supporting agricultural, livestock and fishery systems and assets. This will also contribute YHRP WASH objective (1) Restore or maintain sustainable water and sanitation systems to improve public health and resilience, and Objective (2) Provide emergency WASH assistance to the most vulnerable so as to reduce excess morbidity and mortality. The project is closely linked to protection cluster objectives and will contribute significantly to the achievement of its objectives (3, 4, and 5). This is also in line with Oxfam Yemen Country Strategic objective, Saving Lives and Resilience Building and Oxfam Strategic goals of saving lives.
 Under emergency food security intervention 7,750 beneficiary households (30% HHs will be women and house households with PWDs) will receive food assistance through three different interventions i.e. 5,500 households will benefit from the unconditional cash transfer (UCT), 1,250 households with cash for work (CFW) and 1,000 households will receive conditional cash grant (CCG) for livelihood protection and restoration.  The UCT and CFW will aim to meet the immediate food needs while conditional cash grants are aimed to protect and restore productive assets and to improve livelihood activities of men and women.
 Under WASH 107,300 individuals will benefit from access to safe water through rehabilitated 8 water supply systems in Abs district. To complement water provision, Public Health promotion campaign targeting 120,939 targeted people to adopt safe hygiene practices. Access to safe sanitation inside the IDPs camp will be supported through the provision of emergency latrines to 1,000 households giving priority for women, disabled and children headed household. It is also planned to conduct solid waste management campaigns at the community level and also in the urban cities in coordination with cleaning fund at district and govern-orate level.
Oxfam will be responsible for direct implantation for food security components, WASH, gender and protection while local partner Yemeni development Network (YDN) will be engaged in implementing public health promotion activities. The project will maintain support and coordination with General Authority for Rural Water Projects (GARWAP), Local Water Corporation at govern-orate level, Health Office, cluster and other actors in the targeted areas</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Development Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taha Alraeeini</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Funding Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739705557</telephone>
   <email>talraeeini@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-13">247252.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-13">2752747.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400329765">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-19">7964.07</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-6983">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-13">3000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303068503">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-20">2400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304081913">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-08">175798.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
