<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14592A0101-UKR-15113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Development of Transparency International Ukraine</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kapacitetsutveckling av Transparency International Ukraine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society backed and supported mainly by international donors, has played an important role throughout the events in the post-Maidan period and significantly contributed to the number of reforms.
During the Ukrainian Revolution of Dignity in 2014, TIU was seen by foreign and national stakeholders as an important and objective source of information of what was happening. Its stakeholders still see this as an important reason for supporting and cooperating with TIU. Since then, TIU has worked to develop and improve anti-corruption infrastructures (with the creation of anti-corruption bodies), with the reform and monitoring of public procurement in Ukraine (developing and then transferring the digital tools of ProZorro, ProZorro.sale and eHealth to the state).
In this regard, Transparency International Ukraine (TI Ukraine), although functioning for some 20 years now, but enquiring its current name in 2014, is especially seen to be still well positioned to respond to the challenges of post-Maidan, societal and political developments.
In 2019, TI Ukraine has engaged in a dialogue with the Embassy of Sweden regarding a potential support, while submitting a specific proposal soliciting funding for the i) institutional development as well as ii) the Prozorro.sale instrument enhancement.
The Project&apos;s general objective is to strengthen the potential of Transparency International Ukraine as an organization and enhance efficiency in its strategy implementation as well as increase capacity of Prozorro.Sale and develop a civic monitoring infrastructure around it.
As part of Sweden&#x2019;s risk management, it was decided to carry out a Systems-Based Audit (SBA) in order to obtain recommendations as a basis for a decision to either provide project-based support, or to provide other funding (core support funding of TI Ukraine) in pursuing the overarching goal of lowering the level of corruption in Ukraine.
According to the Strategy of Transparency International Ukraine for 2019-2021, there are 3 strategic mainstreams to reduce corruption levels:
Prevention: Mitigate corruption risks at the national and the local level by increasing transparency and accountability in authorities&#x2019; work. Engagement: Engage the maximum number of participants and create conditions enabling them to unite into effective networks by providing them with regular support. Punishment: Ensure an effective system of punishment for corruption-related violations
Within this intervention, TI Ukraine will implement its strategy in three priorities in the areas of Business Integrity; Anti-Corruption Policy Development and Analysis; Raising Awareness and Change of Perception Among Citizens, Betterment of the Perception of Ukraine Among Foreign Stakeholders.
Inherting a post-soviet economic system of governance Ukraine still to date has substantial assets in public ownership at all adminstrative levels. While a process of privatisation has to date had mixed results, and mispricing and misuse of state property has historically been a huge issue.
The lack of transparency has typically benefitted a small group of allied rent-seekers in the private and public sphere. Within the perimeters of the contribution in question, the team with work with the State-Owned Enterprise Prozorro.Sale to make the advancement of IT solutions and establish monitoring and oversight of state assets sale and lease. This will reduce corruption and enable effective use of state assets by transparent transactions between the state and the private sector (and in particular SMEs).
TI Ukraine&#x2019;s Legal Department shall contribute to the implementation of organization&#x2019;s strategic priorities supporting the bodies of Anti-Corruption infrastructure (NABU, SAPO, NACP, HACC, ARMA) to ensure an effective system of investigation, prosecution and justice for corruption-related offenses and recovery of assets obtained in result of crime. In particular, our legal experts closely cooperate with the National Agency for Corruption Prevention, conduct assessment of the anti-corruption infrastructure bodies of Ukraine to enhance their work, develop the capacity and improve the legislation on the Asset Recovery and Management Agency, monitor work of the High Anti-Corruption Court.
In addition, TI Ukraine aims at implementing a Business Integrity Program (BIP) to reduce corruption levels through improved transparency, accountability and integrity in business practices. TI Ukraine will undertake actions to increase the number of businesses in public and private sector operating without corruption.
This will be achieved as a result of better business regulations on a country level, well-developed internal anti-corruption and ethics procedures and practices, as well as through establishment of a new platform for experience exchange and support. Within the course of the project, TI Ukraine will conduct research on transparency in public reporting (TRAC), carry out a Business Integrity Country Agenda (BICA) assessment report, establish cooperation with at least three selected state-owned enterprises, as well as launch a Business Integrity Forum (BIF).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International Ukraine (TI Ukraine), with over 20 years&#x2019; track record of work to enhance public integrity, boost transparency of public finances usage and fight against corruption is well positioned to respond to the challenges of post-Maidan, societal and political developments.

To tis end, TIU has worked to develop and improve anti-corruption infrastructures (with the creation of anti-corruption bodies), with the reform and monitoring of public procurement in Ukraine (developing and then transferring the digital procurement tools of ProZorro, ProZorro.sale and eHealth to the state).

In 2019, TI Ukraine has engaged in a dialogue with the Embassy of Sweden regarding a potential support, while submitting a specific proposal soliciting funding for further institutional development of the TI Ukraine CSO.

Within this intervention, TI Ukraine will enhance its institutional capacities, while implementing its strategy in three priorities: 1) in the area of Business Integrity; 2) Anti-Corruption Policy development and analysis; and 3) raising awareness and change of perception among citizens, betterment of Ukraine&#x2019;s image among foreign stakeholders, while enhancing its organizational capacities.

The proposal put forward by TI is relevant for the current &quot;Results strategy for Sweden&#xB4;s reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2020&quot;, and in particular results areas 1 and 2.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Transparency International Ukraine (TIU) har arbetat i &#xF6;ver 20 &#xE5;r f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka transparensen av offentliga finanser och f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa korruption. Organisationen &#xE4;r v&#xE4;l l&#xE4;mpad att m&#xF6;ta de utmaningarna som Ukraina st&#xE5;r inf&#xF6;r efter V&#xE4;rdighetsrevolutionen, samt de politiska och samh&#xE4;lleliga utvecklingarna som sker i landet.

TIU har arbetat f&#xF6;r att utveckla och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra infrastrukturen f&#xF6;r korruptionsbek&#xE4;mpning (genom inr&#xE4;ttandet av organ f&#xF6;r korruptionsbek&#xE4;mpning). De har &#xE4;ven arbetat med reformering och &#xF6;vervakning av processer f&#xF6;r offentlig upphandling i Ukraina (de har utvecklat och &#xF6;verf&#xF6;rt de digitala upphandlingsverktygen ProZorro, ProZorro.sale och eHealth till den ukrainska staten).

Under 2019 har TIU inlett en dialog med Sveriges ambassad om eventuellt st&#xF6;d, samtidigt som de l&#xE4;mnat in ett specifikt f&#xF6;rslag som beg&#xE4;r finansiering f&#xF6;r vidare institutionell utveckling av TIU.

Inom denna komponent kommer TIU att st&#xE4;rka sin institutionella kapacitet och samtidigt genomf&#xF6;ra sin strategi inom tre omr&#xE5;den: 1) f&#xF6;retagsr&#xE4;ttr&#xE5;dighet; 2) utvecklande och analys av antikorruptionspolicy; och 3) &#xF6;ka medvetenheten och f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndra uppfattningen bland medborgarna, f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra bilden av Ukraina bland utl&#xE4;ndska motparter. Allt detta samtidigt som TIU:s organisatoriska kapacitet f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttras.

F&#xF6;rslaget fr&#xE5;n TIU &#xE4;r relevant f&#xF6;r den nuvarande &quot;Resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r Sveriges reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2020&quot;, och d&#xE5; s&#xE4;rskilt resultatomr&#xE5;dena 1 och 2.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21033" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21033" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15113" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anti-corruption organisations and institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">571195.0704800102</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">571195.0704800101</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-01">571195.07048</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">279821.3806853292</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">291373.689794681</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/14592_DecisiononContributionCapacityDevelopmentofTIUkraine14592_sca.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution Capacity Development of Transparency International Ukraine</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/14592_GrantAgreementsignedwithoutannexes14592Sida-TIUkrCapacityDevelopment_scan.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement Capacity Development of Transparency International Ukraine</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14592" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
