<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11415A0102-UKR-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MPTF for Peacebuilding and Recovery in Ukraine</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">MPTF for Peacebuilding and Recovery in Ukraine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka den ukrainska statens kapacitet att genomf&#xF6;ra &#xE5;teruppbygnadsinsatser i &#xF6;stra Ukraina inom ramen f&#xF6;r &#x2019;State Targeted Programme for Recovery of the Eastern Regions of Ukraine&#x2019;. F&#xF6;reslagen insats ska fungera som en plattform f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja &#x2019;Ministry of Temporarily Occupied Territories and Internally Displaced Persons&#x2019; med kapacitetsuppbyggnad, analys samt samording av aktiviteter p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;det fredsbyggande och &#xE5;teruppbyggnad i linje med ovan n&#xE4;mnda &apos;State Targeted Programme&apos;

Insatsens huvudsakliga m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att bidra till att m&#xF6;ta de samh&#xE4;llsekonomiska behov som den konfliktdrabbade befolkningen i Ukraina har. Huvudsakliga aktiviteter best&#xE5;r av:
- Att tillhandah&#xE5;lla analytiskt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att identifiera de sektorer som kan bidra till ekonomisk &#xE5;terh&#xE4;mtning i &#xF6;stra Oblast p&#xE5; medell&#xE5;ng och l&#xE5;ng sikt
-  Att st&#xF6;dja nationella och lokala myndigheter med fredsbyggande och &#xE5;teruppbyggnad
- Att etablera en plattform f&#xF6;r dialog mellan parter som arbetar med ekonomisk &#xE5;teruppbygnad 
- Finansiering av pilotprojekt med syfte att stimulera ekonomisk utveckling och relevanta statliga initiativ

Avtals- och aktivitetsperioden &#xE4;r 4 &#xE5;r.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution aims to strengthen the government&apos;s capacity to engage in reconstruction in eastern Ukraine in conjunction with  the &apos;State Targeted Programme for Recovery of the Eastern Regions of Ukraine&apos;. The Contributions shall function as a platform to support the Ministry of Temporarily Occupied Territories and Internally Displaced Persons&apos; with capacity building, analytical support and coordination of activities in peace-building and recovery in line with the governments &apos;State Targeted Programme&apos;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall development objective is: &apos;to help meet the socioeconomic needs of conflict-affected populations in Ukraine - including but not limited to conflict-affected populations, IDPs, returnees, former combatants and host communities&apos;  As for the indicators related to the development objective these are as follows:  1. MPTF finances socio-economic projects targeting conflict-affected populations of Ukraine 2. Decreased data gaps and increased empirical evidence of socio-economic impacts of conflict and displacement in Eastern Ukraine and economic recovery programming through the generation and dissemination of knowledge products 3. The Ministry of Temporarily Occupied Territories and IDPS (MTOT)and other national stakeholders and local administration has increased capacity for design, coordination and implementation of national, bilateral and international programming recovery and peace building initiatives in Ukraine in line with the recommendations in the RPA and as outlined in the State Targeted Programme. This includes effective targeting of interventions to support vulnerable groups (e.g. women, elderly and extremely poor)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/11415_DecisiononContribution_MDTF_Nov2017.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution &quot;MPTF for Peacebuilding and Recovery in Ukraine&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/11415_MPTFAASweden.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement contribution &quot;MPTF for Peacebuilding and Recovery in Ukraine&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The major project results achieved so far are the following:
- elaboration and approval&#xA0;of the Project Engagement&#xA0;Strategy&#xA0;for 2018-2020 with a purpose to support the GoU&#xA0;in establishing coordination platform on peacebuilding&#xA0;and recovery and to deliver select pilots in the areas defined as critical&#xA0;gaps and with a potential to be expanded;
- the design and launch of the Collaborative Leadership for Resilience and Development dialogue series,&#xA0;which brought together diverse representatives from Ukrainian Ministries and local authorities from eastern Ukraine to promote cross-Governmental communication, strategy, and joint action in response to the continued conflict;
- in partnership with Government of Ukraine, UN Office of the Coordinator for Humanitarian Affairs, UN Resident Representative&#x2019;s Office, and a Ukrainian Mapping Institute, further development and dissemination of a geocoded Data Portal on Peacebuilding and Recovery that brings together humanitarian and development data into one interface to support recovery strategy and coordination;
- design of a GoU-led Coordination Platform on Peacebuilding and Recovery based on national and international consultations including a GoU-convened event that gathered over 50 representatives of national Ministries, regional authorities, non-governmental organizations, and international agencies to solicit lessons regarding coordination efforts to date and the way forward;
- implementation and finalization of a pilot on psychosocial support to conflict-affected populations including field training and counselling delivered in Luhansk and Donetsk oblasts; and lessons learned and coordination events on pilot results to promote future scale-up and expansion of activities;
- Based on recommendations of Ukrainian officials at the CL4RD event, the launch of a new MPTF-financed study on Economic Recovery of the Donbas to create an evidence-based analysis to drive future policies and investments in socio-economic recovery of the region. 2019 was a year of political transition in Ukraine, and the new Government team has placed a priority on policies and programming to promote recovery and reintegration of eastern Ukraine. MPTF team efforts focused on developing the Bank&#x2019;s relationship and work program in coordination with the newly merged Ministry of Temporarily Occupied Territories and Internally Displaced Persons (MVTOT) as a new Government counterpart for MPTF activities; and on aligning MPTF activities with new administration priorities. Dialogue with broader range of national stakeholders and inter-government structures leading conflict-recovery efforts was also continued;
- The World Bank, at the request of the Presidential Administration at the Mariupol Investment Forum in October 2019, invested in exploring the development of a possible Partnership Fund on Recovery and Reintegration that would build on the current MPTF and focus on the Government&#x2019;s new recovery and reintegration priorities. Discussions with MPTF donors and other international partners have not resulted in any concrete output, and would have probably lead to further discussions and coordination among the key donors working in the area without involvement&#xA0;of the WB. The first question to answer is what is to be done, and than who can do that the best (WB is one of the options);
- Due to lengthy&#xA0;discussions about the possible strategy to utilize the remaining&#xA0;MPTF&#xA0;balance (at the moment 530 00 USD),&#xA0;the next meeting of the MPTF Executive Board is postponed. The meeting shall review progress of MPTF activities to date and&#xA0; consider additional proposals for funding with remaining MPTF financing.
- Lack of full staff to work with MPTF&#xA0;in Kyiv has negatively impacted the development and implementation of the project. Canada and Sweden&#xA0;have raised this issue with the WB on several occasions, however the World Bank does plan to expand its office / presence in Ukraine.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11415" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
