<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12686A0101-UKR-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Policy and Advocacy Initiative for Ukraine</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Milj&#xF6;policy och Advocacy Initiative f&#xF6;r Ukraina</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching goal of the EPAIU is to improve the quality and inclusiveness of environmental policy making and implementation in Ukraine by means of:
(a)&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; strengthening the influence of Ukrainian non-governmental environmental organizations on processes of designing, advocating, implementing and monitoring of environmental policies and practices at the national, regional and local levels;
(b)&#xA0; based on the NGOs&#x2019; work, building a broad public awareness of, and demand for a problem-relevant, more inclusive, rights-based and conflict-sensitive approach to environmental policy and decision-making.&#xA0;
The outcome objectives are:
(a)&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; to strengthen the environmental movement by means of fostering institutional development, policy, advocacy and communication&#xA0; capacities of a new cohort of environmental NGOs and think tanks;
(b)&#xA0; to improve public policy debate on the environmental protection as a cross-cutting issue of economic development and implementation of the Association Agreement between Ukraine and the EU;
(c)&#xA0;&#xA0; to contribute to raising public awareness of the environment as a value and public good;
(d)&#xA0;&#xA0; to develop and expand networks of public and private-sector stakeholders that collaborate on mainstreaming environmental protection.
The immediate objective (purpose) of EPAIU is to support the creation and development of a cohort of institutionally capable, transparently governed, accountable and publicly recognized environmental organizations that will engage in environmental policy-making, implementation and monitoring and build a broad and inclusive constituency. Through ongoing work and influence of these NGOs the programme strives to achieve a new quality of national and regional / local environmental policy and to grow&#xA0; informed public demand for policies and practices that ensure the environmental background.
Output objectives:
(a) Selection, through a competitive procedure and a nation-wide call, a cohort of 10-15 new environmental NGOs to take part in the Environmental Policy and Advocacy Initiative for Ukraine (EPAIU);
(b) Design and implement comprehensive governance, organizational management, strategic planning, policy research, advocacy, and communication capacity development program;
(c) Roll out institutional grant program to a circle of the selected and trained environmental NGOs and think tanks;
(d) Create an efficient network of NGOs working in the field of development and implementation of national and regional / local environmental policies;
(e) Create infrastructure for policy dialogues between environmental organizations, governmental agencies and socially responsible businesses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Denna insats syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra den offentliga debatten kring och genomf&#xF6;randet av milj&#xF6;-, klimat- och energipolitiska initiativ i Ukraina och &#xF6;ka medvetenheten kring dessa fr&#xE5;gor. Dessa m&#xE5;l uppn&#xE5;s genom en starkare milj&#xF6;r&#xF6;relse och st&#xE4;rkt inflytande f&#xF6;r ideella ukrainska milj&#xF6;organisationer i fr&#xE5;gor r&#xF6;rande utformning, fr&#xE4;mjande, inf&#xF6;rande och uppf&#xF6;ljning av milj&#xF6;politiska initiativ och praktiker p&#xE5; nationell, regional och lokal niv&#xE5;. M&#xE5;len uppn&#xE5;s &#xE4;ven genom att skapa nya och ut&#xF6;ka befintliga n&#xE4;tverk av akt&#xF6;rer fr&#xE5;n offentlig sektor, privat sektor och civilsamh&#xE4;llet som arbetar med att lyfta milj&#xF6;skyddsfr&#xE5;gor och &#xF6;ka allm&#xE4;nhetens intresse och efterfr&#xE5;gan av relevanta, inkluderande, r&#xE4;ttighetsbaserade och konfliktk&#xE4;nsliga perspektiv p&#xE5; milj&#xF6;politik och beslutsfattande.

Programmet, som lanserats av International Renaissance Foundation, kommer genom en konkurrensutsatt process utse en grupp p&#xE5; 10-12 ideella milj&#xF6;organisationer och hj&#xE4;lpa dem f&#xF6;rvandlas och v&#xE4;xa till institutionellt handlingskraftiga, transparent styrda, ansvarstagande och allm&#xE4;nt k&#xE4;nda ideella milj&#xF6;organisationer som kommer utnyttja de m&#xF6;jligheter som uppst&#xE5;r genom frihandelsavtalet mellan EU och Ukraina samt andra internationella och nationella instrument f&#xF6;r att lyfta milj&#xF6;politiskt t&#xE4;nkande och praktik. De utvalda organisationerna kommer att: genomg&#xE5; individuellt utformade program f&#xF6;r &#xF6;vergripande styrning, organisationsledning, strategisk planering, policyforskning,  p&#xE5;verkansarbete och utveckling av kommunikationskapacitet; ha m&#xF6;jlighet att delta i program f&#xF6;r institutionell / organisatoriskt st&#xF6;d; delta i skapandet av ett effektivt n&#xE4;tverk av ideella f&#xF6;reningar som arbetar med utvecklande och genomf&#xF6;rande av nationella, regionala och lokala milj&#xF6;program.
Vidaref&#xF6;rmedling av medel fr&#xE5;n samarbetspartnern till de valda implementeringspartnerna kommer att g&#xF6;ras i form av projektst&#xF6;d.

Budgeten f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r 35 miljoner kronor mellan 2018 och 2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This intervention aims to improve environment, climate and energy public policy debate and implementation in Ukraine and to contribute to better public awareness of these issues. These goals will be achieved by the strengthened environmental movement and influence of Ukrainian non-governmental environmental organizations on processes of designing, advocating, implementing and monitoring of environmental policies and practices at the national, regional and local levels. And also by creating and expanding networks of public, civic and private-sector stakeholders that collaborate on mainstreaming environmental protection issues and build a broad public awareness of, and demand for a problem-relevant, more inclusive, rights-based and conflict-sensitive approach to environmental policy and decision-making.

The program, implemented by the International Renaissance Foundation, will select through a competitive process a cohort of 10-12 environmental NGOs and oversee their transformation and growth into institutionally capable, transparently governed, accountable and publicly recognized environmental non-governmental organizations that will use opportunities opened by the reforms enabled by the Association Agreement between the European Union and Ukraine, other international and national instruments, to mainstream environmental policy thinking and practice. Selected organisations will: go through individually designed comprehensive governance, organizational management, strategic planning, policy research, advocacy, and communication capacity development program; have an opportunity to participate in comprehensive institutional support financing program; participate in building an efficient network of NGOs working in the field of development and implementation of national and regional / local environmental policies.
The transfer of funds from the Cooperation Partner towards the selected Implementing Partners will be made in the aid modality of project support.

The budget for this contribution is 35 MSEK for the period of 2018-2022.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRF/International Renaissance Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.3 - F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra utbildningen, medvetenheten och den m&#xE4;nskliga och institutionella kapaciteten vad g&#xE4;ller begr&#xE4;nsning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarna, klimatanpassning, begr&#xE4;nsning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarnas konsekvenser samt tidig varning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.3 - Improve education, awareness-raising and human and institutional capacity on climate change mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879313</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-14">4027432.569271</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/12686_12686GrantAgreementSigned.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement with Charitable Foundation International Renaissance Foundation Project Environmental Policy and Advocacy Initiative for Ukraine (EPAIU)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/12686_12686SignedDecisiononContribution2018-12-14.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution to Charitable Foundation International Renaissance Foundation Project Environmental Policy and Advocacy Initiative for Ukraine (EPAIU)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2020 the&#xA0;Environmental Policy and Advocacy Initiative for Ukraine (EPAIU) has moved from the assessments and capacity building of the small grants winners&#xA0; to the implementation of the large institutional grants:
-&#xA0;Based on the initial small projects of 16 organizations, the EPAIU team and grantees were able to identify individual organizations&#x2019; strategies of further development. At least 9 out of 16 showed a good potential for growing into expert groups (or even think tanks), able to combine policy advocacy with thematic expertise. Ten NGOs began to integrate gender issues into their main topics.
-&#xA0;All 16 organizations started their strategic planning, and at least 90% of the grantees designed strategic plans. While working on the strategy, the Public Control Platform NGO team span off their mature environmental component &#x2013; the Save Dnipro initiative &#x2013; into an independent NGO. The team used the small grant opportunity to prepare institutionally and registered officially new Save Dnipro NGO on 02.01.2020. The new entity was equipped by strategic plan and necessary basic internal policies, and so was ready to participate in Phase 3 of the EPAIU instead of the Public Control Platform NGO.
-&#xA0;Partner CSOs with wider missions: the Teple Misto (Warm City), Plast, and Crimean Tatarian Resource Center, successfully integrated environmental context into their strategies, respectively: a circular urbanistic economy, eco-scouting, and monitoring of the damage caused to the ecosystems of occupied Crimea. Two of the grantees launched special Expert Councils for the environmental activity and launched dedicated environmental pages at their sites.
-&#xA0;Despite improving financial systems during the small-grant period and establishing appropriate internal financial controls, one of the grantees was unable to report for the use of the initial installment of the grant in time and appropriately and, therefore, did not receive the second tranche. The IRF learned the lesson and enhanced the financial management component in the updated capacity-building program.
Phase 3 of the EPAIU competition was conducted in April-May 2020.&#xA0;The Selection Board (Competition Committee) met on 28 May, 2020, and selected 13 grantees for the main institutional grants in total amount of USD 1,630,000.&#xA0;Selected grantees work on a variety of environmental issues. Three of them (Plast, Warm City, CTRC) are not purely ecological, but actively integrate the ecological component into their main themes &#x2013; eco-scouting and promoting environmental education programs for young people, environmental urban planning and circular economy, protection of environmental rights of community and monitoring of a harm to ecosystems in the occupied Crimea. All organizations are very diverse in experience and their strategic activities. Two-thirds of this cohort are &#x201C;new-generation&#x201D; CSOs. All are strong defenders of the environment and environmental justice. The NGOs seek to influence the implementation of environmental policies and programs at all levels. Many of them work on both local, regional and national levels; their representatives take part in expert civic councils under several public authorities. They are known and respected by their stakeholders. Many of the grantees build partner networks and are known for their activities across Ukraine and abroad.&#xA0;
The capacity building program was organized in two parts: (1) the conclusion of the basic program for 16 small grantees in January-March 2020, and (2) a program for recipients of main institutional grants started in June 2020.&#xA0;In total 152 participants (118? or 78%, 34? or 22%) took part in the January-March program and 135 participants (119? or 88%, 16? or 12%) took part in the online capacity-building events for the institutional grantees.
Ten of EPAIU&#x2019;s institutional grantees (77%) have renewed their websites or launched new websites, others are working on their new websites.&#xA0;All 13 grantees hired communication managers in their teams; Ecoaction, Plast and CTRC have in-house PR units. Four (31%) CSOs approved their communication policies (two of them contain a crisis communication component), other grantees will catch up shortly. 11 grantees (85%) conducted advocacy actions in 2020 based on their own research findings (77%) and/or other partner CSOs&apos; materials (23%). Some of the topics included a gender component.&#xA0;In 2020, the EPAIU cohort produced 192 pieces of analytical products of different formats and thematic focus, including a gender component:
- Recommendations on urban waste management, elaborated and communicated by the Zero Waste Lviv in cooperation with Ecoltava within a framework of the Covid and Waste research;
- Kirovograd oblast administration started drafting a 2021-2024 Program on protecting the population from ionizing radiation of radon thanks to the expert inputs and communication of the Flora NGO;
- Lviv became the first city that signed an agreement for obtaining a Zero Waste City certification and charter &#x2013; such was the result of the Zero Waste Cities campaign conducted by the Zero Waste Lviv NGO in cooperation with their European colleagues;
-Special project &#x201C;The Second Breath&#x201D; of the Ecoaction NGO focused on building awareness of environmental rights to clean air. The campaign provided templates &amp; samples of appeals to officials, which people could download and use to defend their rights to clean air in a city.
- The most visible information campaigns by the Zero Waste Lviv were &#x201C;Brand Audit&#x201D;, &#x201C;EnvironMentsrual Week&#x201D;, and &#x201C;Polyethylene Free&#x201D;, which explained many simple things about eco-behavior and promoted eco-thinking.&#xA0;
- Ecopark Osokorky NGO launched an information campaign for awarding a status of an urban nature reserve to a wide nature spot in Kyiv, based on the findings of a comprehensive assessment of this territory, made in cooperation with scientists.
- Ecogvalt NGO successfully involved Kolomyya town residents in fundraising for a plastic waste press for Ecogvalt&#x2019;s social enterprise and raised UAH 26,000 in donations.
- &#x201C;Enough Poisoning Kryvyy Rig&#x201D; (with the NED support) produced a series of videos about environmental troubles in their city. The use of data and clear communication to local residents about the violation of their environmental rights allowed mobilizing people for action and strengthened the NGO&#x2019;s position in negotiations with the polluters about &#x201C;greening&#x201D; the industry.
- Ecoclub highlighted a lawsuit it had brought to the court in order to set a precedent of cancelling an illegal decision of the Rivne Oblast Department for Environmental Protection and Natural Resources under the environmental impact assessment procedure (EIA) issued for the Kronospan plant construction in the town of Horodok. The case will help highlight existing gaps in the EIA procedure and advocate for adjusting it at the national level.
In 2020 the EPAIU&#xA0;provided&#xA0;the grant support for analytical &amp; advocacy activity of the institutional grantee cohort:
- Consortium of Zero Waste Lviv, Ecoltava, and Fama social agency. The team analyzed the situation and practices of waste management during the quarantine period in 4 Ukrainian cities (Lviv, Truskavets, Poltava, and Myrhorod), compared them with European practices (in a partnership with Zero Waste Europe), and produced practical recommendations for the waste management system and other stakeholders to mitigate the harmful effects on the environment.
-&#xA0;Expert study of negative impacts of the uranium mining industry and natural radiation on the environment and health in the Kirovohrad region. Analytical review and advocacy points for an advocacy campaign for adoption of a &#x201C;Comprehensive Program for Protection of Population of the Kirovohrad Region from Ionizing and Radon Exposure. 2021-2025&#x201D; by the Kirovohradska Regional Council (implemented by Flora in partnership with the Eastern Mining &amp; Processing Plant and the Department of Ecology, Natural Resources and Fuel &amp; Energy Complex of Kirovohrad Regional State Administration).
-&#xA0;Analysis of an impact of climate change on water resources of Ukraine, development of potential mitigation solutions, adaptation options. Prognosis and arguments for the Ministry of Environment to include in the Adaptation to Climate Change Strategy, and for other relevant governmental agencies to consider in other documents related to the water management issues. The analysis seeks to intensify actions at the national and local levels to respond to the climate change, as well as actions aimed at reducing greenhouse gas emissions (implemented by Ecoaction in partnership with the Ministry of Environment and the Kyiv National Taras Shevchenko University).
-&#xA0;Identifying green areas in Kyiv for assessing adaptive conditions of the city in the context of climate change. Analysis of management, legal and information resources for making an inventory of green areas in Ukraine and the city of Kyiv.&#xA0;(Implemented by the Green Wave in partnership with Kyivzelenbud municipal company, the Department of Ecology of the Kyiv City State Administration, and the Davey Tree Expert Company).
-&#xA0;Study of practices of collection and utilization of fallen leaves and other waste of plant origin in industrial cities and towns (a case of Kryvyy Rig). Analysis of risks of influence of the wastes incineration on the residents&#x2019; health.&#xA0;(Implemented by Enough Poisoning Kryvyy Rig in partnership with the Department of Ecology and Natural Resources of Dnipropetrovsk Regional State Administration, the Media Platform Expert-KR, the Professional Ecological Community #ECODIIT, the Public Air Quality Monitoring Project &quot;EcoCity&quot;).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12686" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
