<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10416A0101-UKR-22030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ISK granskning av Ukrainas Nationella Television (public broadcaster)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisational and financial audit of the National Public Broadcaster of Ukraine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project goal: evaluate governance, key processes and internal control system, examine financial statements; provide recommendations and step-by step roadmap for further transformation of NPBU on the way to becoming and efficient and competitive public broadcasting organization.&#xA0;
Objectives:
1) Evaluate governance and provide recommendations for its improvement based on leading practices;
2) Examine key processes and procedures; identify areas for improvement in terms of efficiency and effectiveness;
3) Analyze HR activities, policies and practices, behaviors, risks and internal controls;&#xA0;
4) Validate the financial statements as at 31 December 2017 and for the period then ended (including the opening balances).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 2017 television remained the key source of information about social and political processes for the majority of Ukrainian population (86% according to December 2016 poll of Kyiv Institute of Sociology). More than 80% of the broadcast media market has been owned and controlled by four domestic oligarchs. According to December 2015 GfK values study among the TV audience, 49% of Ukrainian televiewers could not identify a Ukrainian TV channel that would meet the criterion of independence (either from government or oligarchs). The appetite for truth and fair information in the society has increased dramatically after 2014 Euromaidan, while the Ukrainian broadcast media market concentrated in the hands of a few oligarchs remained the same. In 2014-2016 the legal framework for establishing a public broadcasting system has been finally put in place by Parliament and government under strong pressure of civil society. In the first six months of 2017 the legal entity National Public Broadcaster of Ukraine has been established and its governing bodies have been formed. The newborn public broadcaster of Ukraine has a challenging task to become an efficient and competitive media organisation, which would gain public trust by providing a fair and objective alternative to the existing mainstream oligarch media.

The establishment of a genuine public broadcasting system in Ukraine has been one of the three media-related criteria of the EU-Ukraine Association Agenda. When the environment for technical implementation of this reform became enabling in 2017, EU Delegation in Ukraine prepared to launch a four-year technical assistance programme aiming to substantially modernize the public service broadcaster facilities in the capital. 

The National Public Service Broadcaster of Ukraine is being established on the basis of former national state television and radio as well as 26 regional and local TV and radio stations. The audit is to comprehensively map out how the NPBU operates. The recommendations provided will be the basis for further transformations in NPBU, as well as for an assessment of entity&#x2019;s budget needs and a subsequent reallocation of funds within the approved state funding. The deliverable of this audit should be a detailed report on findings and a roadmap for the use of the Supervisory Board, Management Board, and other parties engaged into the reform of public broadcasting in Ukraine and NPBU operations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Under 2017 hade en majoritet av Ukrainas befolkning (84% enligt en unders&#xF6;kning fr&#xE5;n Kiev Institute of Sociology 2016) TV som sin huvudsakliga k&#xE4;lla f&#xF6;r information om samh&#xE4;llets sociala och politiska utveckling. Mer &#xE4;n 80% av Ukrainas TV-bolag &#xE4;gs av 4 ukrainska oligarker. En studie fr&#xE5;n 2015 visar att 49% av tittarna inte kunde identifiera n&#xE5;gon ukrainsk Tv-kanal (varken statlig eller oligark-&#xE4;gd) som uppn&#xE5;r kriterierna f&#xF6;r att klassas som oberoende. Trots att intresset f&#xF6;r fria och oberoende informationsk&#xE4;llor &#xF6;kat kraftigt i landet sedan Euromaidan 2014 forts&#xE4;tter media att kontrolleras av oligarker. Under 2014-2016 togs ett ramverk fram f&#xF6;r etablering av ett &#x201D;public service&#x201D;-system, vilket nu s&#xE4;tts p&#xE5; plats av parlament och regering under h&#xE5;rda p&#xE5;tryckningar fr&#xE5;n civilsamh&#xE4;llet. National Public Broadcaster of Ukraine (NPBU) etablerades under f&#xF6;rsta halvan av 2017. NPBU st&#xE5;r inf&#xF6;r en sv&#xE5;r uppgift f&#xF6;r att kunna bli en effektiv och konkurrenskraftig organisation och utg&#xF6;ra ett alternativ till existerande oligark-media.

Etableringen av ukrainsk public service har utgjort ett av tre mediarelaterade kriterier inom EU-Ukraine Association Agenda. N&#xE4;r denna reform blev tekniskt m&#xF6;jlig att genomf&#xF6;ra under 2017, har EU-delegationen i Ukraina tagit fram ett fyra &#xE5;r l&#xE5;ngt kapacitetsst&#xF6;d med m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning att modernisera NPBU:s Kievbaserade delar. 
NPBU skall etableras utifr&#xE5;n tidigare statlig ukrainsk television samt 26 lokala och regionala TV och radiostationer. 

Revisionen avser att genomgripande kartl&#xE4;gga hur NPBU arbetar. Revisorernas rekommendationer kommer att vara utg&#xE5;ngspunkt f&#xF6;r vidare utveckling inom NPBU och p&#xE5;verka bed&#xF6;mningen av organisationens budgetbehov och en efterf&#xF6;ljande omdisponering av statligt finansierade medel. Revisionen skall &#xF6;verl&#xE4;mnas i form av en detaljerad rapport &#xF6;ver slutgiltiga unders&#xF6;kningsresultat samt en handlingsplan till tillsynsn&#xE4;mnden (Supervisory Board), styrelsen (Management Board) och andra parter engagerade i reformprocessen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ernst &amp; Young</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Public Broadcasting Company of Ukraine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="220" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communications</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="22030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Radio/television/print media</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">520988.6771610052</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">474446.9759734879</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-01">529729.729729</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-28">41541.5423916045</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">80724.2566510172</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">238684.2538893491</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">115531.7960047869</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">-2034.8890730001</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The new public broadcasting system was established on the basis of 31 national and regional formerly state-controlled TV and radio broadcasters, which were united in 2017 and became NPBU. The audit held at the entry stage of this important media reform assessed the governance, organisational structure, human resources and process management as inherited from the predecessor state broadcasting system. As a result, EY developed a three-year Roadmap of transformations &#x2013; the set of recommendations and a timetable of recommended organisational transformations (short-, mid- and long-term). In summer 2018 this Roadmap was operationalized by the NPBU Management Board and Supervisory Board, with the view to transform NPBU into an efficient and sustainable media organisation. This Roadmap is also being used now as guidance by the donors working with the public broadcasting reform in Ukraine (e.g. Internews Network, DWA, Council of Europe).
The first financial audit held by a credible international auditor EY became the foundation for further accounting reform of the National Public Broadcaster in line with international standards. Based on EY audit recommendations, NPBU managed to successfully align their accounting with IFRS already in 2018, which was confirmed as a result of 2018 independent audit.&#xA0;
Unplanned, but important result: Based on EY financial audit opinion, the stocks of the public joint stock company NPBU were issued by the state registrar in October 2018, completing a legal process of establishing the national public broadcaster.
The organizational audit had two deliverables:
1) detailed report on findings;
2) comprehensive roadmap of NPBU transformation for the use of Supervisory Board, Management Board and other parties engaged in the public broadcasting reform and NPBU operations.
Both the report and the Roadmap were duly and timely developed in a high-quality multi-stakeolder consultation process.&#xA0; The Steering Committee including EY team, NPBU senior management and the Embassy representatives was involved at the design stage, progress reporting, validation and finalization of the findings. This ensured strong ownership of the audit recommendations within NPBU at relevant levels, and their further rigorous implementation.&#xA0;
The first stage of implementing the audit recommendations already brough noticeable changes to the company:&#xA0;
- unnecessary layers of responsibility and unclear delegations of power were eliminated, new organizational structure of the company was approved by the Supervisory Board;
- a system of recruiting and adapting new employees was launched, staff evaluation system was put in place;
- new collective agreement was introduced;
- an internal audit service was established and started working;
- anti-corruption function was added (appointment of an anti-corruption commissioner, approval of the anti-corruption program);
- a number of policies and regulations were developed (compliance policy, accounting policy, transparency policy, code of ethics, information partnership policy, strategy for the development of broadcasting networks, etc.);
- legislative solutions for modernization of governance and internal control were developed.&#xA0;
The expected, and a number of unexpected results were achieved. Among some unexpected results in a broader context is replication of this project&apos;s approach to other large-scale institutional reforms (i.e. Pension Fund, Prosecutor&apos;s Office. The Embassy provided reference letters to EY for participating in these initiatives).&#xA0;
At the impact level it would be also sensible to take stock of the progress when the full 2018-2021 Roadmap of Transformation would be implemented.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10416" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
