<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13934A0101-UKR-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 UNFPA Ukraine: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination 2020-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 UNFPA Ukraine: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination 2020-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New/additional funds to mitigate the impact of COVID-19
UNFPA has applied to Sida for funding of 15 400 000 SEK to carry out the &quot;Equality springboard: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination&quot; Project in Ukraine during the period 2020-2023. 

The intervention aims at boosting the process of social norms change and withdrawal from gender stereotypes in education, at work and at home, as well as in the community life. This goal will be achieved by 1) enhancing capacities of the education system to integrate gender sensitive approach; 2) supporting men and boys&#x2019; engagement into advancing gender equality at the community level through applying equal distribution of duties in family life and participation in fathers&apos; programs; 3) engaging corporate sector to introduce family friendly gender sensitive approaches, including domestic and gender-based violence prevention practices.  

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 15 900 000 SEK, out of which the organization&#x2019;s own funding is approximately 494 000 SEK (54 000 USD).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Nya medel/medeltill&#xE4;gg f&#xF6;r att lindra konsekvenserna av covid-19
UNFPA har ans&#xF6;kt Sida om 15 400 000 SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &quot;Equality springboard: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination&quot; i Ukraina under perioden 2020-2023. 

Insatsen syftar till att fr&#xE4;mja f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringen av sociala normer, samt att eliminera genderstereotyper inom utbildningaq, i arbetslivet, i hemmet och i samh&#xE4;llslivet. M&#xE5;let kommer att uppn&#xE5;s genom 1) att &#xF6;ka kapaciteten inom utbildningssystemet att kunna integrera ett j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet; 2) att st&#xF6;dja m&#xE4;ns och pojkars engagemang i att bidra till j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet i samh&#xE4;llet genom en j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lld arbetsf&#xF6;rdelning i hemmet och deltagande i program f&#xF6;r pappor; 3) att engagera n&#xE4;ringslivet att inf&#xF6;ra arbetss&#xE4;tt som fr&#xE4;mjar j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, inklusive f&#xF6;rebyggande av k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld och v&#xE5;ld i hemmet. 

Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 15 900 000 SEK, av vilka organisationens egna medel &#xE4;r cirka 494 000 SEK (54 000 USD).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the project is to boost the process of social norms change and withdrawal from gender stereotypes in education, at work and at home and in the community life and create supportive environment and growing public demand for advancing equal rights and opportunities for women and men in Ukraine. 
The objectives of the Project are as follows: 
Objective 1. To enhance capacities of the education system to integrate gender sensitive and non-discriminative content and approach in the school curriculum, textbooks and education materials and teaching practices and to support educational practitioners to promote stereotype-free gender norms among young Ukrainian men and women;
Objective 2.  To support men and boys&#x2019; engagement into advancing gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment at the community level through applying equal distribution of duties in family life, including care of their children and participation in fathers programmes;
Objective 3. To engage corporate sector and provide it with guidelines and tools to introduce family friendly gender sensitive approaches in their corporate policies and programmes for staff and corporate social responsibility programmes, including domestic and gender-based violence prevention practices.
Key strategies: 
Empower change agents networks: educators to support young women and men to grow and develop free-from-stereotypes and benefit from the equal rights and opportunities;&#xA0;&#xA0; male community leaders to demonstrate benefits and opportunities of egalitarian gender roles, equal distribution of family duties, equality in childcare and responsible fatherhood; corporate sector champions to pilot and demonstrate economic benefits of &#x2018;family friendly&#x2019; gender sensitive corporate policies and programmes for employees.
Boost grow of public demand for changing social norms and overcoming gender stereotypes through effective targeted communication and advocacy.
Impact
The overarching long-term impact level objective is that women, men and girls, boys are able to realize their full potential and rights free from stereotypes and violence at school, at work, at home and at the community level. This is due to more equitable gender norms and comprehensive gender-responsive family policies that are championed by private sector and government.
The impact of this project will contribute to the achievement of the Sustainable Development Goals as well as national development plans such as: Sustainable Development Strategy for Ukraine by 2030 and the National Action Plan on the Strategy Implementation by 2020.
The project will contribute to the following longer-term outcomes:
Outcome 1. Adolescents and young men and women in Ukraine benefit form modernized education system free from discrimination and gender stereotypes and promoting equal opportunities in education and career choices.
Outcome 2. An increasingly supportive enabling environment created for boosting gender equality and gender-responsive family practices through public campaigns and engagement of local communities.
Outcome 3. The corporate sector has improved understanding of the value of gender-responsive family policies, the link to gender equality and business outcomes.
The project design assumes that these changes will continue beyond the project period as champion companies will make public, high level commitments to continue work to ensure workplaces are family friendly and companies will institutionalize these commitments through corporate policy change which will have a domino-effect on other companies. This will be complemented by work at the national level, whereby local authorities will commit to support for family friendly initiatives at the community level.
The intervention will work towards the following six outputs:
Output 1.1. Enhanced capacities of the Ministry of Education and Science of Ukraine (MoES) to integrate non-discriminative gender-sensitive approach into sectorial policies and action plans in line with international commitments on gender equality and human rights-based approach
Output 1.2. Network(s) of educators as change agents strengthened, capacitated and equipped with modern tools and methods to deliver free-from-discrimination and gender stereotypes education and promote equal choices and opportunities among young people
Output 2.1. Partner municipalities supported to develop and implement local crisis rooms for GBV survivors and men-engage programs and solutions to support fathers to exercise their roles at home and in childcare
Output 2.2. Public campaign to unveil gender stereotypes, promote change of social norms based on gender equality and gender-responsive family developed and implemented
Output 3.1 Corporate sector is sensitized on benefits of gender equality and zero tolerance to GBV
Output 3.2. Corporate sector is supported in introducing and sustaining gender sensitive practices and family-responsive policies to advance gender equality and achieve a better health/life balance for women and men at work.
Together, these outputs are indispensable elements of the project puzzle as they secure the impact from three different yet critical angles.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.4 - Erk&#xE4;nna och v&#xE4;rdes&#xE4;tta obetalt omsorgs- och hush&#xE5;llsarbete genom att tillhandah&#xE5;lla offentliga tj&#xE4;nster, infrastruktur och socialt skydd samt genom att fr&#xE4;mja delat ansvar inom hush&#xE5;llet och familjen, i enlighet med vad som &#xE4;r nationellt l&#xE4;mpligt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.4 - Recognize and value unpaid care and domestic work through the provision of public services, infrastructure and social protection policies and the promotion of shared responsibility within the household and the family as nationally appropriate.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">738351.9550039632</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1520267.5791952803</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">738351.9550039633</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1520267.57919528</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-01">2154161.699078</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">738351.9550039632</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">641257.3307372128</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">879010.2484580675</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/13934_AgreementAmendment1countersigned.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Amendment 1 with UNFPA Ukraine &quot;Equality Springboard: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination 2020-2023&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/13934_UNFPAUkraineAgreement-scannedversionsignedbySida&amp;UNFPA07092020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement &quot;UNFPA Ukraine: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination 2020-2023&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/13934_Decisiononcontribution_UNFPA_Sept2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision &quot;UNFPA Ukraine: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination 2020-2023&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/13934_DecisiononAmendmentofContribution(13934).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Amendment of Contribution with UNFPA Ukraine &quot;Equality Springboard: social norms change and gender stereotypes elimination 2020-2023&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the Embassy monitoring, UNFPA Ukraine has completed the activities planned for Year 1 of this intervention with impressive interim results, already outperforming by a number of indicators planned in the Logframe (see updated Logframe enclosed as Annex III). The cooperation partner has managed to achieve a lot in all the pillars of the project in the constrained circumstances already during Year 1, including at the policy level. It is notable that the government overview of the Biarritz Partnership for Gender Equality outputs after the first year of implementation included the interim results of the UNFPA Sweden-funded contribution, namely on STEM education for girls, IT reskilling of GBV survivors, opening of two Tato Hubs (fathers&apos; clubs) in Poltava and Zaporizhzhya and the renovation of  crisis rooms for GBV survivors in 9 cities of Ukraine, impacted by the pandemic. which demonstrates a strong alignment between project objectives and government priorities.
Project implementation dynamics has been quite high despite Covid-19-related limitations.

The most important changes the programme has led to so far:

1. Gender mainstreaming in education
- 65% of publishing houses and 1537 education experts working on the development, technical expertise or licensing of the textbooks and other educational content have been intensively trained on non-discriminatory educational content, including online learning during the pandemic.
- UNFPA Ukraine conducted a nation-wide public opinion
poll to study the gender dimension of the career choice among Ukrainians of the 14-60 age and identify factors which impact the choice of the profession. Most respondents supported the gender division of professions into &quot;female&quot; and &quot;male&quot;. These poll results are now being used as a baseline for project activities on eliminating gender stereotypes in career choice. 
- Around 4000 girls and female students were trained on the basics of IT and programming, career planning, copy-writing, STEM content development, self-presentation, gender equality and digital security and were motivated to take active steps
in choosing STEM as their future career. The teaching community increased their knowledge in methods and tools of gender sensitive STEM teaching. In frames of the all-Ukrainian contest for the best gender sensitive STEM lesson, more than 500 teachers submitted their lesson concepts for the experts review and 5 lessons were recommended by the Institute of Education Content Modernization as best practices.

2. Increased men engagement in fatherhood and household duties
-  At the policy level, the Verkhovna Rada of Ukraine adopted the bill #3695 on the provision of equal opportunities to a mother and a father for childcare. The new law provides the possibility for both the mother and father of a child to use the right for parental leave until the child reaches the age of three (the equal right for each of the parents). Before that, a father could take parental leave only if the mother of a child was back to work or was hospitalized for a long term. Also, the bill introduced a new type of leave for fathers, i.e. one-time 14-day paid leave after the birth of a child, and extra 17 days of paid annual leave in case of the childs or children&apos;s disability.
Despite COVID-19 disruptions, UNFPA also managed to secure adequate level of support from the pilot local councils to roll out fathers&apos; hubs in the regions and started a nation-wide public awareness campaign on equal distribution of household chores.

3. Gender mainstreaming in the corporate sector
UNFPA intensified the work on engaging business partners which share the values of gender equality and equal opportunities for all. Three more companies - Truman
Agency, Mondelez Ukraine and Syngenta - joined the initiative and plan to contribute to the achievement of the Sustainable Development Goals 5 and 8. The cooperation partner also conducted an information session for 20 representatives of the Swedish business in Ukraine and presented the potential strands for cooperation in gender mainstreaming and GBV prevention. As a result of the session, Sigma Software and
Electrolux expressed their interest in joining the Declaration for gender equality and prevention of domestic violence.

Covid-19 response:

The problem of domestic violence has exacerbated during the coronavirus crisis, as evidenced by the growing number of complaints from victims to the National Police. Under these circumstances and in frames of the Biarritz Partnership for Gender Equality agenda, the First Lady of Ukraine Olena Zelenska and the Deputy Prime Minister for European and Euro-Atlantic Integration of Ukraine Olga Stefanishyna encouraged local governments to open shelters for GBV survivors and improve interoperability of all services involved in GBV response and prevention. In frames of the Equality
Springboard project, UNFPA has addressed this problem by opening crisis rooms in 9 municipalities heavily impacted by the pandemic. Despite COVID-19 limitations and specifics of work with GBV survivors in this context, UNFPA has received adequate level of support from the local councils and makes sure the selected cities have enough capacity to operate them efficiently in the time of and after the pandemic.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13934" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
