<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11372A0101-UKR-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EU4PFM Ukraina 2019-2024</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU4PFM Ukraine 2019-2024</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslutet g&#xE4;ller det svenska bidraget till EU:s st&#xF6;dprogram f&#xF6;r Ukraina EU4PFM (EU Action Public Finance Management Support Programme for Ukraine). St&#xF6;dprogrammet har en total budget om 55 MEUR och best&#xE5;r av fyra olika komponenter som ska implementeras av Sida, Litauiska CPMA (Central Project Management Agency), V&#xE4;rldsbanken och IMF. Sida kommer att ansvara f&#xF6;r en del av aktiviteterna under komponent 1, de som r&#xF6;r utveckling av nationella institutioners kapacitet p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;det budgetering p&#xE5; medell&#xE5;ng sikt, programbudgetering, utgifts&#xF6;versyn, skattem&#xE4;ssig konsekvensbed&#xF6;mning, makroekonomiska prognoser, likviditetsf&#xF6;rvaltning och offentlig redovisning liksom modernisering av IT-programvaror f&#xF6;r budgetprocesser och offentlig redovisning. Sidas st&#xF6;d kommer att g&#xE5; till Finansministeriet, Ministeriet f&#xF6;r ekonomisk utveckling och handel samt skattemyndigheterna. Huvuddelen av aktiviteterna kommer att upphandlas genom ett upphandlad entrepren&#xF6;r.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This decision concerns the Swedish contribution to the EU Action Public Finance Management Support Programme for Ukraine (EU4PFM). The overall Action is 55 MEUR and has four different components to be implemented by Sida, CPMA of Lithuania, the World Bank and IMF. Sida will manage a part of Component 1 activities, in particular, those related to the strengthening of the capacities of national Ukrainian institutions regarding medium-term budgeting, program-based budgeting, spending reviews, fiscal impact assessment, macroeconomic forecasting, liquidity management and public accounting, as well as modernisation of IT software for budget process and public accounting. The beneficiaries of Sida support will be the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Economic Development and Trade of Ukraine, and Treasury. Most part of the activities will be implemented through a contracted contractor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the conclusion on performance for the period January-December 2020. The&#xA0; conclusion on performance for 2019 was covered by the Major Amendment to Contribution - Decision on Additional Funding UKR37/2019&#xA0;as of 12 December 2019.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Project information is provided below.
The beneficiaries of the project are the Ministry of Finance, Ministry of Economic Development and Trade, and Treasury. In particular, the project aims to strengthen the capacities of relevant national partners in mid-term budgeting, program-based budgeting, performing spending reviews, fiscal impact assessment, macroeconomic forecasting, liquidity management and public accounting.
The Expected Results were updated after the scoping mission commissioned by the Embassy in February-April 2019. The purpose of the mission was to define the scope for the 2 new components for Sweden on liquidity management and public accounting, as well as to update the scope for previously defined components. Detailed work tasks are listed in ToR for procurement, and expected results are listed in Results matrix that will be updated after the Inception Phase.
The intervention logic of the contribution can be summarized as follows:
Overall objective of EU4PFM program: Improve performance in core systems of public financial management (PFM).
Specific objectives of Component 1 implemented by Sweden: Provide assistance to the Government of Ukraine in the implementation of the PFM Strategy 2017-2020.
Expected results:
Component 1 &#x2013; Budget planning
1.1. Improved medium-term budget planning.
1.2. Improved programme-based budgeting.
1.3. Preparation and implementation of spending reviews.
1.4. Establishment of process for, and conduct of, fiscal impact assessments.
Component 2 &#x2013; Macroeconomic forecasting
2.1. Improved capacity for macroeconomic forecasting (MEDT).
2.2. Improved capacity for macroeconomic forecasting and impact analysis (MoF).
Component 3 &#x2013; Liquidity Management 
3.1. Improved capacity in cash and liquidity management.
3.2. Improved coordination of cash, liquidity and debt management.
Component 4 &#x2013; Public Sector Accounting 
4.1. Updated national public sector accounting standards (NPSAS).
4.2. Proposal for improvement to organisational arrangements of government accounting services.
4.3. Preparation of consolidated financial statements.
Other PFM thematic areas (upon request)
During the Inception Phase and/or during the course of implementation of the Project, additional PFM thematic areas may become a priority for the beneficiary institutions and be considered by the Project.
Such areas may include but not limited to: strategic planning; public investment management; revenue forecasting; sector-specific expertise in planning and budgeting in inter alia education, health, agriculture, energy, transportation etc.; information technology to support and automate PFM processes and systems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Misc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A to be procured</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="17.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.1 - Strengthen domestic resource mobilization, including through international support to developing countries, to improve domestic capacity for tax and other revenue collection.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.1 - St&#xE4;rka den inhemska resursmobiliseringen, inklusive genom internationellt st&#xF6;d till utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra den inhemska kapaciteten att ta upp skatter och andra int&#xE4;kter.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-01">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first year of implementation was concentrated on the procurement of an implementing partner, a consultancy. The Embassy launched a tender on 28 October 2019 with the closure date of 9&#xA0;December 2019 and intention to start project activities in February 2020. The budget ceiling for the tender was EUR 10,531,480.
The procurement of the implementing partner has followed the Swedish procurement legislation, in particular, Swedish Public Procurement Act (2016: 1145). Certain requirements derived from the contribution agreement between Sida and the EU, in particular, General Obligations, Conflict of Interests, Data protection, Communication and visibility, Accounts and archiving, Access and financial checks, Confidentiality and Restrictive measures were transferred to Sida&#x2019;s standard contract template of the consultancy contract.
The tender evaluation took place in December 2019 &#x2013; February 2020.&#xA0;However, on 4 March 2020 the Embassy had to cancel the procurement as during the standstill period the Embassy identified risks that it had not been possible to fully uphold equality between the tenderers in the procurement procedure.
To ensure project implementation, the Embassy decided to re-launch the tender. Due to Covid-19 outbreak, the tender was taken up to Sida HQ.
According to a tentative timeplan, the tender is to be announced during 1st quarter 2021 and project to start in 2nd quarter 2021.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11372" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
