<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5507004101-UKR-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core Support to Razumkov Centre</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">K&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till Razumkov Centre</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida will provide a grant for a pre-core support against a detailed   budget and an action plan. If the outputs of the pre-core support are delivered according to plan, Sida will provide core support. In this  intervention Sida both relies on the internal systems of the          organisation and helps the organisation to develop them further with  Sida&apos;s support.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sidas f&#xF6;rberedande st&#xF6;d ges i form av en g&#xE5;va mot en detaljerad       budget och en handlingsplan. Om prestationer av det f&#xF6;rberedande      st&#xF6;det levereras enligt plan, kommer Sida att ge organisationen       k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d. I denna insats Sida b&#xE5;de f&#xF6;rlitar sig p&#xE5; organisationens    interna system och hj&#xE4;lper organisationen att vidareutveckla  och     st&#xE4;rka dem med Sidas st&#xF6;d.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute to the building of a democratic, ruled by law, socially-oriented European state in Ukraine, development of civil society, improvement of the quality of life of its citizens, enhancement of the international image of the Ukrainian state and attainment of its national interests.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Razumkov Centre/Ukrainian Centre for Economic and Political Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">84443.8985444943</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">633391.1573055001</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">646910.1823401706</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">537836.7323087711</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">84443.8985444942</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">633391.1573055001</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">646910.1823401706</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">417226.6697832057</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-10292.0463960232</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">2295338.6968</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-08-28">84443.8985444943</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-02-28">370996.6617589178</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">262394.4955465823</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-28">237267.6260187679</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">296584.5325234599</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">113058.0237979429</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">315549.5821889791</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">101677.0875942266</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">-10292.0740127037</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The pre-core support started with the Razumkov Centre in 2013, and resulted in the elaboration of the system based audit recommendations, which the implementing partner had to follow in order to receive the core support funding. In 2014, the Swedish Embassy signed the Agreement with the Razumkov Centre on core-support.&#xA0; The funds were allocated to finance the three years Strategic Operations Plan, based on which respective annual plans were developed.&#xA0; During the cooperation with the Swedish Embassy, the Centre completed the development of internal standards determining both, research procedures and the quality of the analytical products based on best practices of leading foreign think tanks, as well as the internal procedures of Centre&apos;s operation, which were brought in accordance with the best international standards. In particular, the Centre introduced a mechanism for procurement of goods, work and services through tender procedures, created provisions for financial and human resources management, developed job descriptions, principles of anti-corruption policy, etc. The Centre also formalised the structure and responsibilities of Centre&apos;s governing bodies, which include the General Assembly, Centre Council, Director General, the Audit Committee and the Supervisory Board. The Centre was able to additionally hire relevant experts in foreign policy, gender policy, domestic policy. 10 workstations for sociological surveys at the Centre were re-equipped. The respective software was updated, thus the Center launched its new web-site, ensuring its continuous content management and promotion in media and social networks. The Center also strengthened its Facebook presence and the Youtube channel was launched with live streams of the Centre&apos;s events. The Center issues a regular newsletter in Ukrainian and English. Whenever it is deemed essential, the Center engages the interns. &#xA0; In order to expand the capacity of its Sociological Service, the Center established a modern call-centre, which is fully equipped with modern equipment and software, and the staff is trained to operate it.&#xA0; According to the annual 2016 Global Go to Think Tank Report (issued by the Think Tanks and Civil Societies Program of the University of Pennsylvania since 2006), Razumkov Centre was among 175 top think tanks worldwide (55th place, in 2015 &#x2013; 60th place out of 150) and among 150 top think tanks worldwide excluding USA (36th place, in 2015 &#x2013; 42nd place out of 137). The Razumkov Centre was ranked 5th among the 90 top think tanks in Central and Eastern Europe. The Razumkov Centre was also ranked among the top think tanks in 7 other nominations, such as best managed think tank and think tanks with the most efficient use of budget.&#xA0; In the period 2014-2017, 54 research projects were implemented, out of them 33 were already completed, 17 various studies conducted in cooperation with foreign think tanks, 69 public events held, 17 issues of the Razumkov Centre Library series were published, and 26 issues of the National Security and Defence journal were prepared and dessiminated. The Centre conducted 72 public opinion surveys and 2 exit polls. The Center&apos;s&#xA0;experts took active part in the elaboration of two drafts of coalition agreements for parliamentary coalitions, two drafts of Government Action Plans (for two Cabinets of Ministers), and other policy proposals for government bodies, sector ministries and administrations, Verkhovna Rada committees, divisions of the Presidential Administration, NSDC Secretariat &#x2013; among others, on the issues of country defence and strengthening its defence capabilities. The Center&apos;s experts participated in developing the New Energy Strategy of Ukraine til 2035. According to the state programme of the Cabinet of Ministers of Ukraine, this strategy was used as a basis for the development of a coordinated draft of Ukraine&apos;s energy strategy, which would be approved by the Government. The Centre has established and is maintaining partnerships with government think tanks and research institutions: National Institute for Strategic Studies, Institute of Political and Ethno-National Studies, Yaroslav Mudryi National Law Academy, National University &quot;Kyiv-Mohyla Academy&quot;, Institute of State and Law of the NAS of Ukraine; National Academy of Legal Sciences of Ukraine; National Academy of Public Administration under the President of Ukraine, Institute of Legislation of the Verkhovna Rada of Ukraine, Institute for Demography and Social Studies, etc.&#xA0; Some of Razumkov experts gave lectures for students at Royal Defence College in Norway, Swedish Defence University, National University &quot;Kyiv-Mohyla Academy&quot;, attendees of the National Academy of Public Administration under the President of Ukraine. Razumkov Centre experts participate in the work of consulting and advisory bodies of Verkhovna Rada committees and other government bodies (on a permanent basis). For instance, Razumkov Centre experts, as of 2017, are working at the Constitutional Committee (V. Musiiaka, Deputy Chairman), Council for National Unity under the President of Ukraine (Y. Yakymenko), expert group for defence sector reform at NSDC (O. Melnyk), expert group for energy strategy development at the Cabinet of Ministers (V. Omelchenko), Public Council at the Verkhovna Rada Committee for Foreign Affairs (M. Pashkov), public board of the Council at NBU (V. Yurchyshyn). However, despite all the successes described above, the Centre has failed to introduce a transparent and open procurement policy. The audit recommendations&#xA0;on improvement of&#xA0;internal policies, in particular for HR management and procurement, have been repeated by the auditors each year.&#xA0; The Center also failed to develop and introduce an independent Board of Directors. During 2015 and ongoing in 2016, the Embassy has been raising the concern regarding the chairmanship in the Board with the Management of the Razumkov Centre. In particular, the organization has been strongly recommended to withdraw the Head of the Board, who is the Ukrainian Politician, under investigation of corruption in some European countries. In Ukraine the person is also under investigation of the National Anti-Corruption Bureau. Unfortunately, the partner organization has not resolved the issue. The Embassy has notified the Razumkov Center that under the circumstances, financial support shall not be extended further, and all outstanding tranches were terminated. In December 2016, the Agreement with the organization came to the end, and was not extended or renewed by the Swedish Embassy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="55070041" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
