<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5507004901-UKR-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Women as Political Leaders</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Promoting Women as Political Leaders</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med piloprojektet &#xE4;r att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka kvinnors politiska deltagande i Ukraina. Detta skall g&#xF6;ras genom att, i samarbete med ukrainska organisationer, utveckla och genomf&#xF6;ra ett  innovativt medieprojekt samt driva en offentlig utbildningskampanj    som p&#xE5;verkar  allm&#xE4;nhetens uppfattning om kvinnor i politiken och     minimerar en negativ mediabild av kvinnor i ukrainska medier.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching goal of the project is contribute to strengthening    women&apos;s political participation in the Ukraine.   The objective for   the one-year project is to, in partnership with Ukrainian NGOs,       develop and pilot an innovative integrated media and public education campaign strategy that maximizes positive public perceptions of women in politics and minimizes negative gender biases in Ukrainian media.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NDI/National Democratic Institute for International Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">921206.1659399373</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">77899.3862884299</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">921206.1659399372</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">77899.3862884298</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-10-01">1003252.164834</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-28">921206.1659399373</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">77899.3862884299</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Over the entire project period, the following results can be seen. 

At the end of each of the two workshops for journalists and editors, participants were asked to provide feedback, discuss what they had learned about gender bias, and discuss how their coverage of gender issues would change in the future. Participants stressed the practical nature of the trainings and noted that they gained a better understanding of sexism and discrimination in the media and in everyday life. In regard to the more difficult skill of recognizing subtle gender bias in the media, more than 30 percent reported greater confidence. Moreover, the skills gained from the training &#x2013; such as integrating gender-responsive standards into reporting &#x2013; were being utilized. Fourteen of the trained journalists have become advocates for gender equality by regularly publishing articles and participating in online discussions on the topic. Of the 16 who participated in the advanced training, five have become regular contributors to the Povaha website. 

NDI also surveyed the participants several months after they completed training, and found that the majority of journalists who responded believed that the training they received from NDI had positively impacted their coverage of gender issues. Almost all said that they regularly visited the Povaha website and expressed an interest in further training in the future. 

The Povaha website published 35 original articles about women in public life, most of which were solicited from participants in the journalist training program. Povaha received approximately 200 daily visitors and 5,600 unique hits, and the majority of articles were read by 550 to 800 people. A video highlighting sexist remarks by Ukrainian politicians was viewed more than 450 times, a video explaining sexism was viewed more than 500 times, and a video about how journalists contributing to sexism was viewed more than 300 times. The most popular story &#x2013; the translation of the op-ed from the KyivPost, &#x201C;Stop beauty-shaming women,&#x201D; by Olga Rudenko &#x2013; attracted more than 11,000 readers. 

As the new draft law on local elections does not include any provisions on women&#x2019;s representation, the EOC recently wrote a letter to 13 local party leaders, requesting the inclusion of at least 30 percent women on the party lists. 
 
The information campaign on women&#x2019;s political leadership reached a broad audience. Based on monitoring and evaluation of the campaign by NDI&#x2019;s Ukrainian public relations partner, MeToo, it is estimated that the TV spots reached more than 4 million viewers; online campaign materials 35 million; and billboards 37 million. In addition, 81,911 visitors accessed the campaign by clicking on the banner that was placed on various websites. The actual number of clicks on the online video  was 4.5 times higher than expected; viewers accessed the video more than 62,000 times. The campaign reached 76 percent of the target audience (women ages 25 to 45) in Lviv oblast and 68 percent in Vinnytska oblast.

Gender equity advocates also continue to leverage successes in the public education campaign. In advocating with party leaders for gender quotas or similar provisions in a new local election law, the parliamentary Equal Opportunities Caucus recently referred to MoUs these leaders signed with VOS as part of this initiative. In the MoUs, they had pledged to support an adequate number of women candidates in 2015 local elections.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55070049" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
