<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11821A0101-UKR-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EIA i Ukraina - F&#xF6;rberedande st&#xF6;d till det nationella registret</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIA in Ukraine &#x2013; Preparatory support to the National Registry</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project objective is to develop a well-functioning Unified National Environmental Impact Assessment Registry fully consistent with the appropriate EU standards and tailored to the context in Ukraine.
The purpose of the Registry is to enable the transparent process of the conducting the EIA for a new project. It records and makes publicly available online the assessment of a potential project&#x2019;s effects for the environment and human health, and records decisions and measures aimed at preventing, avoiding, reducing, eliminating significant negative environmental impacts of the planned activity. The Registry aims to contain open documentation for business and the public at all stages of the EIA procedure, which reduces corruption factors in decision making.
A key result of the project is the provision of software for launching a fully functional web-based Registry to the Ministry of Ecology, as well as technical assistance and communication support to the first cases entered in to the Registry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektets syfte &#xE4;r att bist&#xE5; Ukrainas regering (Ministeriet f&#xF6;r ekologi och naturresurser) i implementeringen av lagen om milj&#xF6;konsekvensanalys. I ett f&#xF6;rsta steg kommer projektet, som implementeras av UNDP, att utveckla ett fungerande elektroniskt Unified National Environmental Impact Assessment Register (ett register &#xF6;ver alla inkomna ans&#xF6;kningar till myndigheter d&#xE4;r n&#xE5;gon sorts milj&#xF6;pr&#xF6;vning &#xE4;r n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndig) i enlighet med relevant EU-standard. Registret kommer att skr&#xE4;ddarsys f&#xF6;r den ukrainska kontexten. Detta projekt kommer att ligga till grund f&#xF6;r den fortsatta implementeringen av lagen som innefattar kapacitetsutveckling av de centrala och lokala myndigheterna, utbildningar f&#xF6;r intressenter i enlighet med deras roll i systemet etc.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project purpose is to assist the Government of Ukraine (Ministry of Ecology and Natural Resources) in the process of the Environmental Impact Assessment Law implementation. At the first stage, the project, implemented by the UNDP, will develop a well-functioning electronic Unified National Environmental Impact Assessment Registry  in accordance with the appropriate EU standards and tailored to the context in Ukraine. This project will also lay the groundwork for the further implementation of the Law that will include capacity building of the central and local authorities, trainings for stakeholders in accordance with their role in the system etc.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-01">117000.117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">117000.117000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/11821_11821UNDPEIAAgreementScanDec2017.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement UNDP &quot;Environmental Impact Assessment in Ukraine &#x2013; Preparatory support to the launch of the National Registry&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/11821_11821UNDPEIANCEN12018.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">No-Cost Extension Agreement Amendment No.1 UNDP &quot;Environmental Impact Assessment in Ukraine &#x2013; Preparatory support to the launch of the National Registry&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/11821_11821UNDPEIANCE22Oct2020signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">No-Cost Extension Agreement Amendment No.2 UNDP &quot;Environmental Impact Assessment in Ukraine &#x2013; Preparatory support to the launch of the National Registry&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ukraine/11821_11821DoCUNDPEIA.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution  UNDP &quot;Environmental Impact Assessment in Ukraine &#x2013; Preparatory support to the launch of the National Registry&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This intervention was planned as a quick response to the need of the Ukrainian Government to launch the electronic Environment Impact Assessment (EIA) Registry and, therefore, achieve comprehensive&#xA0;implementation of the EIA&#xA0;Law that transposes EIA&#xA0;Directive into the Ukrainian legislative system and helps Ukraine to implement Association Agreement with the EU. The results achieved by the project by the end of 2019 are as follows: 1. The Project has developed and launched a pilot version of the Automated Information System &#x201C;Unified Environmental Impact Assessment Registry&#x201D;, which hosted more than 4,000 cases and over 4,500 compared to the initial plan of 50 cases and 50 users. 2. Technical support to MENR in maintaining the Registry, as well as assistance in preparing initial cases of environmental impact assessment in the pilot version of the Registry has been provided. 3. Communication and outreach support to the launch of the pilot version of the Registry has been provided. Over 25,000 experts, environmental practioners, journalists and members of the public have been reached by the project&#xA0;information and outreach campaign through various channels. 4. Pilot version of the Environmental Impact Assessment Registry has been migrated to the cloud infrastructure ensuring sustainability of the project. 5. Terms of Reference for the development of a full-scale automated information system &#x201C;Unified Environmental Impact Assessment Registry&#x201D; has been developed by the project, reviewed and approved by the Ministry of Ecology and Natural Resources. Procurement and delivery of the final version of the system based on the demo-version has been finalized in 2019. This upgrade has been seamless for the users of the registry - all data and access has been maintained. The most important result here is the acceptance of the system by the intended users and beneficiaries. Online, accessible registry of information on all projects that can have serious impacts on environment provides unique opportunities for public private sector and civil society. It also serves an important function by ensuring transparency, accountability and integrity of the government review and approval process. The EIA&#xA0;Registry has quickly gained wide-spread use and reached the usage levels of neighbouring Poland during the first year of operation (1700 cases). Ukrainian environmental activists&#xA0;and NGOs have&#xA0;made EIA&#xA0;Registry one of the main tools of their work - they get access to information, process it and disseminate&#xA0;it further (NGO&#xA0;Environment People Law, Save Dnipro&#xA0;and others), make use of the public consultation procedures to submit comments and influence investment decisions. The open nature of the registry allows modern digital instruments to be built around it - chatbots&#xA0;(that was developed under the name SaveEcoBot&#xA0;by NGO&#xA0;SaveDnipro&#xA0;outside of the project)&#xA0;and the like. This provides for further digitalization of the environmental governance in Ukraine, greater transparency and serves as deterrent against corruption.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11821" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
