<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-GMB-2750BXTHRD</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gambia Threshold-Threshold Fund</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gambia Threshold Program: In November 2021, MCC and the Government of The Gambia signed a $25 million Threshold Program. The grant will support The Gambia&apos;s biggest constraint to economic growth: the unreliable and inadequate supply of electricity. The investment will focus on two projects: Power Sector Governance and Power Sector Operations. The threshold program aims to reduce poverty through economic growth in The Gambia by improving the governance and operations of the power sector. On the governance front, MCC will help The Gambia to develop a more effective, accountable, and transparent power sector via support to NAWEC, the National Assembly, civil society, and the media. Regarding operations, MCC will support NAWEC in improving its capability to operate a power system that is adequate to meet existing and growing demand consistent with The Gambia&apos;s stated Nationally Determined Contributions under the 2015 Paris Agreement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-11-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administration &amp; Finance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Data Team</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>202-521-3618</telephone>
   <email>opendata@mcc.gov</email>
   <website>data.mcc.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1099 14th Street NW, Suite 700, Washington, DC 20005-3550</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/tpaa-the-gambia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/where-we-work/program/gambia-threshold-program">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gambia Threshold Program</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://mcc.dgmarket.com/tender/48312789">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Procurement Notice 2022-1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GM" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GMB-2750BXDILD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GMB-2750BXTHRD-GOVRN PJT" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GMB-2750BXTHRD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GMB-2750BXTHRD-PGM ADMIN" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-GMB-2750BXTHRD-PWR" type="2"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex III: Conditions precedent to disbursements of grant funds other than mcc service provider disbursements: PART A. Conditions Precedent for Entire Disbursement Request (Applicable to All Projects)
1. Prior to the second Disbursement, the Accountable Entity must develop and adopt, in each case, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:
(a) a comprehensive social and gender integration plan (&quot;SGIP&quot;) in accordance with the MCC Gender and Social Inclusion Operational Requirements, and
(b) an M&amp;E Plan in accordance with Section 4.2, which M&amp;E Plan includes indicators reflecting sufficient project design that measure the Governance Project Objective and the Operations Project Objective, and such indicators have agreed-upon baselines and final targets.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex III: Conditions precedent to disbursements of grant funds other than mcc service provider disbursements: PART A. Conditions Precedent for Entire Disbursement Request (Applicable to All Projects)
2. Prior to the third Disbursement, the Accountable Entity must develop and adopt, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, a Program-wide ESMS commensurate with the scope, scale, risks and opportunities presented by the Program, which ESMS shall include, inter alia, a Stakeholder Engagement and Communications Plan for each of the Governance Project and the Operations Project.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex III: Conditions precedent to disbursements of grant funds other than mcc service provider disbursements: PART A. Conditions Precedent for Entire Disbursement Request (Applicable to All Projects)
3. Prior to each Disbursement of funds for payment under any technical assistance contract for a given Project or Activity, the Accountable Entity must submit evidence, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, that the Accountable Entity is implementing and in compliance in all material respects with the requirements of each of the ESMS, the Stakeholder Engagement and Communications Plan for that Project or Activity, and all of the environmental and social requirements identified in each of the studies conducted as part of such Project or Activity.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex III: Conditions precedent to disbursements of grant funds other than mcc service provider disbursements: PART B. Conditions Precedent to Disbursement of Funds for the Governance Project:
1. Prior to the Disbursement of any funds for grants under the Accountability Activity, the Accountable Entity must develop and adopt, in each case, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, framework documents for the grant facility, including a grants operating manual, selection criteria, and a grant agreement template in accordance with MCC guidance, including MCC&apos;s Program Grant Guidelines.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex III: Conditions precedent to disbursements of grant funds other than mcc service provider disbursements: PART B. Conditions Precedent to Disbursement of Funds for the Governance Project:
2. Prior to the first Disbursement of funds in support of activities requested in an Action Request under the Governance Project, MCC and the Government shall have agreed in an Implementation Letter on a written process for vetting and approving Action Requests, including metrics for &quot;performing&quot; project teams.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex III: Conditions precedent to disbursements of grant funds other than mcc service provider disbursements: PART C Conditions Precedent to Disbursement of Funds for the Operations Project:
Prior to the Disbursement of any funds for procurements related to or arising from the Phase II Plan, the Parties shall agree in an Implementation Letter on the conditions for funding the components of the Phase II Activity, as such components are described in the approved Phase II Plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex IV: Additional Conditions precedent to Entry into Force: The following additional conditions must be met before this Agreement enters into force:
1. With respect to the Governance Project, (i) the Government, through MOPE, has established the Governance Reform Team and the Accountability Reform Team, and each such team is fully staffed, and has a documented scope of work, which scope of work includes details on their responsibility for overseeing the membership and operations of the relevant project teams, and (ii) the United States through MCC has approved the team membership and scope of work, and is satisfied that the Government has used its best efforts to ensure that such teams are as gender diverse as reasonably possible.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Annex IV: Additional Conditions precedent to Entry into Force: The following additional conditions must be met before this Agreement enters into force:
2. With respect to the Operations Project, (i) the Government, through NAWEC, has established the Transformation Team and this team is fully staffed, and has a documented scope of work, which scope of work includes details on their responsibility for overseeing the membership and operations of the relevant project teams, and (ii) the United States through MCC has approved the team membership and scope of work, and is satisfied that the Government has used its best efforts to ensure that the Transformation Team is as genderdiverse as reasonably possible.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Each Disbursement other than for MCC Contracted Activities. Unless waived or deferred in writing by MCC, the following conditions must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before each Disbursement of the Grant other than for MCC Contracted Activities:
(a) Deliverables. The Government has delivered to MCC the following documents, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC:
(i) a completed Disbursement Request, together with the periodic reports required under Section 4.6, covering the related Disbursement Period; and
(ii) a certificate from the Accountable Entity, dated as of the date of such Disbursement Request, substantially in the form provided by MCC.
(iii) a certificate of the Procurement Agent, substantially in the form provided by MCC (the &quot;Procurement Agent Disbursement Certificate&quot;); and
(iv) a certificate of the Fiscal Agent, substantially in the form provided by MCC (the &quot;Fiscal Agent Disbursement Certificate&quot;).</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Each Disbursement other than for MCC Contracted Activities. Unless waived or deferred in writing by MCC, the following conditions must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before each Disbursement of the Grant other than for MCC Contracted Activities:
(b) Other Conditions Precedent. MCC has determined in its discretion that:
(i) any applicable conditions precedent in Annex III have been duly satisfied, deferred, or waived pursuant to the terms of this Agreement;
(ii) the Government&apos;s representations set forth in Section 3.1 are true and correct on and as of the date of such Disbursement Request as though made on and as of such date;
(iii) no material breach of any responsibility, covenant or obligation by the Government, the Accountable Entity or any other Government entity has occurred and is continuing under this Agreement or any related agreement or document;
(iv) the activities to be funded with such Disbursement do not violate any applicable law or regulation;
(v) the Implementation Plan Documents and Fiscal Accountability Plan are current and updated and are in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the components of the Implementation Plan related to such Disbursement;
(vi) there has been progress satisfactory to MCC on the M&amp;E Plan (including the targets set forth therein, any related baseline data collection requirements set forth therein or any applicable reporting requirements set forth therein for the relevant Disbursement Period) and the SGIP;
(vii) there has been no material negative finding in any financial audit report delivered in accordance with this Agreement and the Audit Plan for the prior two quarters (or such other period as the Audit Plan may require);
(viii) any Taxes paid with Grant funding through the date ninety days prior to the start of the applicable Disbursement Period have been reimbursed by the Government in full in accordance with Section 2.5; and
(ix) each of the Key Staff remains engaged or, if a position is vacant, the Government
(i) is actively engaged, to MCC&apos;s satisfaction, in recruiting to fill that position and
(ii), for such period as agreed between MCC and the Government, the responsibilities of the position are covered by a member of the Interim MCA Team</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Entry into Force. Each of the following conditions must be fulfilled, in each case to the satisfaction of MCC, before this Agreement enters into force:
(a) The Government has delivered to MCC a signed legal opinion, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, by Minister of Justice or other legal counsel of The Gambia acceptable to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Entry into Force. Each of the following conditions must be fulfilled, in each case to the satisfaction of MCC, before this Agreement enters into force:
(b) The Government has delivered to MCC complete, certified copies of all decrees, legislation, regulations, or other governmental documents relating to the Government&apos;s domestic requirements necessary for this Agreement to enter into force, which MCC may post on the MCC Website or otherwise make publicly available.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Entry into Force. Each of the following conditions must be fulfilled, in each case to the satisfaction of MCC, before this Agreement enters into force:
(c) The Government has delivered to MCC an incumbency certificate and specimen of the Government&apos;s Principal Representative.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Entry into Force. Each of the following conditions must be fulfilled, in each case to the satisfaction of MCC, before this Agreement enters into force:
(d) MCC has determined that, since the time of signing this Agreement, the Government has not engaged in a pattern of actions inconsistent with the eligibility criteria for MCC assistance.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to Entry into Force. Each of the following conditions must be fulfilled, in each case to the satisfaction of MCC, before this Agreement enters into force:
(e) The conditions set forth in Annex IV have been satisfied.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(a) Entry into Force. This Agreement has entered into force as provided in Article 8.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(b) Implementation Plan. The Accountable Entity has developed a complete Implementation Plan; provided, however, that the Accountable Entity is only required to develop the Audit Plan by the time of the initial Disbursement if so required by the AE Audit Guidelines.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(c) Fiscal and Procurement Documents. The Accountable Entity has developed the Fiscal Accountability Plan (or an interim version) and an interim Procurement Operations Manual and the plan has been approved by MCC and the Board.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(d) Permitted Account. To the extent that any portion of the Disbursement is to be held in a Permitted Account, a Bank has been engaged, the Local Account and any other required Permitted Account has been established, and the Accountable Entity has delivered to MCC a copy of the Bank Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(e) Procurement Agent. The Procurement Agent has been engaged and the Accountable Entity has delivered to MCC a copy of the related Procurement Agent Agreement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(f) Fiscal Agent. The Fiscal Agent has been engaged and the Accountable Entity has delivered to MCC a copy of the related Fiscal Agent Agreement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(g) Interim MCA Team. The Interim MCA Team has been approved by MCC and appointed and engaged by the Accountable Entity in accordance with Section 3.2(b) and Annex I, Part B hereof, and the Government is making progress, satisfactory to MCC, on recruiting for MCA-Gambia employees.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From The Gambia Threshold Program Agreement: Conditions Precedent to the Initial Disbursement of Grant Funding other than MCC Service Provider Disbursements. Unless waived or deferred by MCC in writing, the conditions set forth in this Section 5.2 and the conditions set forth in Section 5.3 must be met to MCC&apos;s satisfaction before the initial Disbursement of Grant funding other than for MCC Service Provider Disbursements:
(h) Accountable Entity Governing Documents. The Accountable Entity has delivered to MCC full copies of all Governing Documents of the Accountable Entity</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
