<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA3/WASH/NGO/14902</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency response project for the displaced people of Ma`rat al-Numan and its countryside</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to recent hostilities in Southern Idleb, tens of thousands of civilians have fled from in southern Idleb governorate. Displacement happening in winter months is further exacerbating the vulnerability of people in need. Many of those who fled are in urgent need of humanitarian support. In light of the high population density and the dependence of civilians on alternative sources such as water trucking, which are absolutely unsafe, new concerns arise from the spread of diseases due to the lack of water, especially among children. The most urgent need currently is the safe drinking water, in addition to personal hygiene items, and sanitation facilities (latrines). 

BALAD in partnership with Minber Al-Sham organization are planning to implement and provide emergency WAHS services in Idleb camps for the newly IDPs from Ma&#x2019;arrat An-Nu&#x2019;man and its rural through this proposed, 
Minber Al-Sham has access to targeted locations through its team on the ground, it also has good experience in implementing the proposed intervention given that it is implementing a similar activity in 18 camps in Idleb in Sarmada and Killi areas. it will undertake construction of latrines and latrines for people with special needs given its previous experience in those activities. Additionally, it will implement the distribution of garbage bins and activity of removal garbage and solid waste. 
project aims to ensure continuity of life-saving activities for newly IDPs in 21 camps Harem sub-district (Ain Bakkara, Tlool, Kameshliyeh, Khreybat, Rasha, Mazrat Hamdoush, Souk Alhal , Al wa&apos;an , Al Hanadi , Beteya Road , Souk Alhal (Salqeen), Sharqye, Qastal, Haj Jouma, Almasara , Aldeyaa 4, Alsawame , Alqaria Altenia, Almazar , Alqaws, and Kafar Houm Aljanobi) by supporting 15036 IDPs. 

Distribution of water trucking will be on daily basis by augmented trucked water to reach 2506 families for 5 months. Project will ensure water is safe by testing water samples in sources, trucks, and in household level. Project includes conducting hygiene promotion sessions to raising awareness about personal hygiene and distributing hygiene kit for each family. HP will be done by trained team who will be consisted of 2 hygiene promoters and 1 team leader, in beginning hygiene team will be trained on HP principles and presentation skills by a local capacity and training development agency. Throughout session team will distribute materials printouts and stickers in public spaces in targeted camps. Project will work on WASH facilities by construction of latrine in accordance with the standards of allocation WASH cluster and sphere taking into consideration gender sensitive by building separate blocks, safe accessible, lighthouse and its doors provided with income locks, also taking into consideration persons with disabilities by building latrine and show that suit their needs. Project will provide containers for solid waste, communal garbage bins and small garbage bins for each tent, also trucks will periodically collect garbage and transport it to designated places to be processed by sorting the contents so as not to damage the environment and surroundings.

At the 1st month, we will prepare and finalized all engineering studies, MOUs, and conducting procurement and contracting processes. And also we will contract with contractor for construction of WASH facilities, expansion of it within camps will be done simultaneous with commence and construction of septic tanks until end of 3rd month. During 1st month of project we will working on increasing number of water taps to cover all targeted camps and from beginning of the 2nd month until end of the project, safe water will be supplied daily to all camp populations. During 2rd amp 3th month we will distributing hygiene kit, installation of solid waste containers, provision of communal garbage bins. also will be forming Hygiene promotion teams and train them on Hygiene promotion materials and conduct awareness camp</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-20">589814.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-14902">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-20">589814.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304471701">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-03">245408.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304687296">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-04">245408.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304981590">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-15">81223.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
