<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA2/WASH/NGO/13723</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure safe access to water, sanitation and hygiene in camps.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Considering the high numbers of newly displaced people, there is a significant need for the provision of WASH services to the people who are living in Camps which they do not have these services.
The proposed action will fill the gap of needs to displaced people from south of Idleb and north of Hama and improve safe access to water of sufficient quality and quantity sanitation hygiene practices for 9804 (4585 Male and 5219 Female) 1616 HHs conflict-affected people in mentioned camps below in Dana and Maaret Tamsrin sub-districts of Idleb governorate as following:
-Idleb, Harim, Dana, Kafr Deryan, (Aljabal camp)
-Idleb, Idleb, Maaret Tamsrin, Ma&apos;arrat Tamasrin, (Alzearaa camp)
-Idleb, Harim, Dana, Dana, (Madajen alzerba)
-Idleb, Harim, Dana, Burj Elnumra, (AlJarf Camp)
-Idleb, Harim, Dana, Atma, (Sanabel Alkhair camp)
-Idleb, Harim, Dana, Qah, (Salah Aldeen camp)
-Idleb, Idleb, Maaret Tamsrin, Haranbush, (Marbona camp)
-Idleb, Harim, Dana, Deir Hassan - Darhashan, (Aljehad camp)
The proposed action will ensure safe and chlorinated water delivery to 9804 IDPs, and improving sanitation and Hygiene promotion services for 8 camps, reaching 9804 people who will also benefit from increased access to safe water. This will be achieved through implementation of essential support for water trucking services in addition to providing, installing, maintenance, cleaning a Prefabricated latrines with desludging a septic as well as hygiene kits distribution to enhance personal hygiene, BRD will ensure an integrated approach covering Water, Sanitation and Hygiene&apos;s (WASH) needs and protecting the health of targeted camps.
In addition to mainstreaming the protection principles in all project phases. BRD will provide equitable access for men/women and boys/girls to the same amount of water during the project period, latrines, HKs and promotion activities.
BRD will train some M/F from affected population in those camps as hygiene promoters to take the lead of raising the hygiene awareness of the beneficiaries in those camps.
All planned activities build from BRD experience under previous funds and other WASH projects. These include implementation of provision of operations cost for water trucking and mentioned services.
The action builds on over three years of successful operational experience in the targeted sub-districts by BRD and will expand proven WASH programming to meet the needs of 8 highly vulnerable camps in urgent need of WASH assistance.
Implementation Plan:Day to day management by BRD team and department, firstly, procurement will be announced through bids.
BRD will implement the project in 8 camps for 6 months, at beginning  will conduct detailed technical assessment to assess the most current situation because the situation is changing daily (new IDPs)
Field staff will train voluntaries to conduct hygiene sessions promotion activities under supervision of BRD staff, BRD will conduct Hygiene awareness raising campaign with distributing the brochures and invite members of camps management, Provide presentations, Drama and street theatre to explain the importance of hygiene.
BRD will construct 32 latrines&apos; caravans, each caravan has 5 latrines (4 normal and 1 for older and disabilities) with ramp and lights, doors, windows and 3washbasins..etc)
BRD will rehabilitate 60 latrines in those camps as needed and water trucking as well.
After conducting the hygiene promotion activities BRD will distribute 1616 Hygiene kits for IDPs in those camps (Razor, Sanitary pads, Shampoo...etc)
BRD will distribute 300 water tanks with 50cm base and 2 taps with installation, BRD will deliver the chlorinated water (70 ML chlorine will be added to each 1000 L) Regular testing will be conducting for water in tanks and trucks..
25 L per capita will be delivered on daily basis (25 L*9804=245100 L per day), BRD will conduct PDM survey to measure the satisfaction and Verification of selected beneficiaries who received mentioned services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">158001.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">184045.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13723">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">342047.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304228934">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-25">171023.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304489229">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-13">171023.7</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
