<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/P/INGO/13014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated Protection Services in Northwest Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aims to save lives enhance protection and increase resilience and access to services, through a partnership between the SAMS and Hope Revival Organizations, building on the long experience of both organizations in their proposed activities in the areas of implementation.
In order to reduce the impact of explosive hazards, the proposed intervention has been designed to respond to life-saving health and protection needs in an area experiencing high severity of need. Specifically, SAMS will support Afrin Hospital in Aleppo governorate, with services focusing on those most vulnerable &#x2013; specifically persons with disabilities, war related injuries and survivors of explosive hazards incidents. The following services will be provided in Afrin Hospital: physiotherapy consultations, treatment sessions, medical consumables/needs assistive devices (wheelchairs, walkers, etc.) individual mental health consultations, self-care and group sessions, in addition to outreach activities. Capacity-building support will also be offered to the staff at the facility.
Through this project also, SAMS in partnership with HRO aims to Increase the safe access of the GBV case management and Women and Girl&#x2019;s Safe Spaces (WGSS) of affected women and girls especially those with special needs in both Jisr Ash Shugur City (new established center) and Maarzaf/Ariha as continuation of the service provision there, and increased legal awareness among affected population on how to access and safeguard civil and HLP documentation, including provision of individual legal assistance in Maarzaf/Ariha. The aim of establishing the new WGSS center in Jisr Ash Shugur city is to ensure the availability and access to specialized services in the area and to strengthen HRO role as focal point of GBV referral pathway and emergency focal point in the area. The following services will be provided in Jisr Ash Shugur: GBV services, Life Skills, GBV Raising awareness sessions through outreach (as the entry point for GBV services, these activities will be the basis for the detection of GBV incidents and thus identify cases requiring specialized intervention through case management), provide empowerment training, and provide free space for women. As well as, the following services will be provided in Maarzaf: GBV services, life Skills, GBV raising awareness sessions through outreach (as the entry point for GBV services, these activities will be the basis for the detection of GBV incidents and thus identify cases requiring specialized intervention through case management), women free space, protection monitoring assessment, Establish or work with existing committees, awareness sessions on protection risks awareness raising on CSD and HLP. All these activities will be focused on leadership and empowerment of the community as the center will be supervised by the beneficiaries &#x2013; WGMB &#x2013; as they already were part of designing the project and needs assessment. Activities were designed based on beneficiaries needs. The project will ensure a community engagement throughout understanding the point of view of the stakeholders, and local actors, in both design and implementation phases. The role of the stakeholder will be to advocate for enabling beneficiaries to participate in the program activities. The center will not be in isolated area it will be accessible and located in a central of the community map. The center activities will be culturally appropriate/ context related and in accordance with the age of the beneficiaries. In our centers and activities, we will take into consideration the needs of persons with disability. With regard to access, while the situation in northwest Syria remains volatile. 
Please refer to attached file, Project summary_22052019, for more information. 

The percentage of the clusters are: Mine Action: 44.69% GBV: 38,13% and GP: 17,18%</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-27">223304.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-27">297738.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13014">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-27">521042.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304078257">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-03">312625.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304906906">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-03">206906.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
