<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA2/NFI/NGO/13719</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide seasonal and supplementary  NFI assistance for the most vulnerable and newly IDPs  in North of Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Takaful Al-Sham Charity Organization through this project will support 1925 newly and most vulnerable internally displaced HHs, 9625 individuals (2076 men &#x2013; 2294 women - 2612 boys and 2643 girls ) with heating Items and stoves in 11 camps of Sarmada and Dier Hassan camps (Al-Bashir, Abnaa alziar, Al-Ahmad, Aldarraj, Al-Safa, Horan, Salam, Al-Jabal, Taibah, Al-Nory, Baraaem Abi Al Fidda) in Dana Sub-district through restricted value voucher with value $197 for each household as these IDPs didn&#x2019;t receive winterization assistance.
Targeted camps were identified based on need assessment (attached), where priority was given to camps which include newly IDPs and Takaful has full access, where newly IDPs were provided with tents, gravelling, NFI kits and food assistance (RTEs and regular food rations), in addition to that targeted camps are located near the main markets in Sarmada, Deir Hassan and Dana where there are many fuel and stoves vendors. We coordinated with other NGOs such like Mercy-USA, BINAA, Ahl Horan and SRD to avoid duplication in targeting the camps.
The value of the voucher was determined to meet the required amount of fuel, 360 liter for each HHs for three months (4 liter per day * 90 days) in addition to the stove value, where each voucher will contain : 6 coupons with 27$ values for fuel in addition to 1 coupon with 35$ value for stove. Fuel and stoves prices is determined based on the market assessment which conducted in the targeted locations (attached).
To ensure local community support, KIs including local actors and IDPs representatives in each targeted location were interviewed to take their suggestions and will be informed about project&apos;s goals and activities at the beginning of project. 
1925 HHs will be targeted with various fuel types (Kerosene - Diesel &#x2013; Firewood and Olive pits) and stoves according to family need where the diversity of fuel types will give the opportunities for the HH to choose the type of fuel she\he prefer and the related stove (if needed), priority will be given to most vulnerable families, then beneficiaries&apos; data and vulnerability will be verified through visiting their location, vendors will be selected through a committee according to specific criteria focus on accessibility, trust in community,,etc. Distribution of vouchers will be conducted in three phases (three months) for the same beneficiaries so their needs will be filled in time. The vouchers redemption will take place within 15 days in each phase, where project team will follow up the redemption process. Disbursement to vendors will be within 15 days after the redemption, this quick process enables vendors managing their cash and restock for coming vouchers. After the end of distribution, we will conduct a PDM to ensure that the service arrived to the beneficiaries in a smooth and good way and to measure beneficiaries satisfactory. 
In case of sudden displacement during the winter season and during the implementation period, priority will be given to newly arrived IDPs that meet the vulnerability criteria, furthermore, if an urgent problem occurs and there is no possibility to distribute in one of targeted location, we will replace the beneficiaries and choose another beneficiary according to criteria in another targeted location of the project in coordination with SNFI Cluster.
We will ensure that the principle of Do No Harm is applied in all project&apos;s activities through several visits to the markets, distribution monitoring and exit surveys. In addition, we will deliver the vouchers to the most vulnerable beneficiaries who hasn&#x2019;t an access to market because of their vulnerability, and giving them the chance to choose kind of fuel they prefer and then delivering fuel items to their locations.
We will coordinate with NGOs who are working in same locations to avoid any overlap or duplication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-SNFI-156550-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-16">291706.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-16">201740.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13719">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-16">493446.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304214986">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-19">246723.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497081">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">246723.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
