<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/H-N/NGO/12696</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing the gap in healthcare service provision and support Emergency IYCF in North West Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project includes four components: 

1- Supporting Sharan PHC in Sharan sub-district (which is the only active PHC in the subdistrict) with staff salaries, medical, lab, and dental consumables in addition to the general running costs to guarantee the continuity of service provision for the targeted population of 15,000 people living in the area. The center is currently operated by Al Ameen, with an average of 3,000 patient visits each month. This facility covers primary healthcare consultations and includes a general clinic, pediatric clinic, gynecology clinic and dental clinic in addition to a 24 hours emergency room. These services are supported by simple lab to provide essential lab testing for test-guided treatments. BEmONC services are also included in the facility and operate 24 hours a day.

2- Mental Health services will be integrated in Sharan Center through trained MH gap GP and PSWs. This center will be the only provider for mental health consultations in Sharan sub-district and will participate in providing comprehensive treatment for the patients. The expected beneficiaries of MH clinic will be 100 sessions monthly. 

3- The project will address the identified gap in physiotherapy centers and services through providing minimum standards of GYM equipment to 18 PT facilities in 8 districts in North West Syria to allow them to enhance the quality of their PT service provision. Additionally, the project will allow for purchasing and distributing essential assistive devices for active PT centers in 5 districts to support PT treatment procedures and improve the quality of life of patients with disabilities. The selected assistive devices and GYM equipment conform to  the minimum standards set out by the Rehab Work Group in Gaziantep Health cluster. Distribution will be based on information from the 4Ws reporting which shows the number of monthly sessions and new patients through full coordination with Rehab work group. Distribution will take place in Idleb, Ariha, Dana , Alma&apos;ra , Jabel Saman, A&apos;zaz , Afrin and Albab subdistricts.

4- IYCF intervention will be undertaken through the IYCF corner and MBA (Mother Baby Area) in Sharan PHC, as well as additional MBAs located in 3 further PHCs in Raju, Sheikh El Hadid, and Al Bab. As well as this, 5 mobile teams will conduct a program of outreach activities including mother support groups, one to one counseling and mother to mother counseling. Raising awareness will include distribution of IEC materials and delivering messages regarding breastfeeding and infant supplementary feeding. The teams, MBAs and IYCF corner will be form part of Al-Ameen&#x2019;s Health and Nutrition system covering Al-bab, Sharan, Shiekh Elhadid, Rajo and Jandiris, where Al-Ameen already has a network of PHCs and CMAM program.
 
The project will have an incentive training for IYCF-E programme for the outreach team, the facilities&apos; staff including (nurses, midwives, gynecologists, and pediatricians), in addition to the training for BSFP distribution team, who they targeted around 6,000 children monthly, The pediatricians and gynecologists will be involved in delivering and supporting the raising awareness messages and activities especially regarding the exclusive breastfeeding on 0-6 months and the BMS criteria and conditions. and PSWs will be involved in the mothers support groups as a part of facilitating the sessions and referring to further consultation when required.
Baby kits will be delivered to mothers who participate in support groups the for the first time, and center deliveries will benefit from this kit, in order to support the mothers to receive the minimum standards of care regarding pre and post-delivery visits for gynecology and IYCF.

The project will be coordinated with health cluster partners,  rehab work group partners, nutrition cluster partners, local health authorities, and Afrin ad-hoc group.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-HEA-155995-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-07">557372.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-07">238126.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12696">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-07">795498.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304041627">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-13">318199.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
