<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA2/WASH/NGO/13731</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve situation by assistance to conflict-affected IDPs in WASH services in North west Idleb camps in Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AL Resala Foundation (RF), aim through the SCHF, to provide WASH services in 9 camps North west of Idleb in sub district of (Darkosh , Janudiyeh, Harim, Slaqin and Ma&apos;arrat An Nu&apos;man).
In the last week of April 2019, southern Idleb and northern Hama governorates saw a sharp escalation in hostilities, shelling, and airstrikes, preventing access to essential services and endangering the safety of those living in the area. Following these developments, 334,2941 people were forced to flee their homes between 1 May and 13 June 2019. Displacement waves continue on a daily basis. The project will target 1,916 families in the 9 camps, this project consists of 2 main components by continuity of providing water trucking, and provide WASH services package in the selected camps. The project will run for a six months&#x2019; period, first month for preparation (staff recruitment, tendering and contracting). The project will focus on new IDP families. The project will target the IDP&#x2019;s new arrived in the locations, (IDP&#x2019;s 11,500) (1,842 Men 2,765 Women 2, 877 Boys 4,025 Girls). in order to improve the safe, adequate and sustainable access for these service along with the improvement for the public health and environment to avoid any outbreaks caused by contamination of the drinking water and lack in the SWM which might cause an outbreak in leishmaniasis. 
The project taken into account intervention during winter and in case of flooding for the selected camps, bathroom/toilet units rise from the ground 20cm in addition to the tendency of the roof in a calculated manner to flow the rain water to manholes. concrete foundation builds for each storage water tanks for drinking and rise from the ground. Construction of septic tanks will be in the low ground of the camp to avoid mix the water from or flood or rain. It has been verified that the selected camps are not located in the valley of flood channel. The construction for the WASH infrastructure in the camps has been designed for future construction for influx of additional IDPs.
-	Construction activity for 25 Bathrooms / toilets units, construction 9 reinforced concrete septic tanks, Construction sewer network system and this will take two months, 
-	WASH services for the camps Providing daily water trucking 287 cubic meter, water treatment services. Solid waste management, and this service will run for 5 months. Dislodging of the sewage from septic tanks, Running and cleaning Bathroom and toilets units, the services run for 3 months.
-	WASH installation installing 32 Communal water storage tanks for drinking, 25 solar power for lighting units, 25 galvanized water tanks for washing Bathrooms and toilets units. Installation for this services will take 2 months.
-	Distribution of 1916 Hygiene kits in the second month of the project implementation, in addition to post distribution for the hygiene kits. Distribution 7764 Jerry cans for each family two Jerry cans per duration, during the project implementation will be two distribution of Jerry cans.
Focus group discussion (FGD) eight 
- Monitoring and Evaluation by RF staff
-	Consultant for training hygiene Promotion campaigns for one month consist of   men and women team 
Topics are  
-	Drinking Water Quality, Effective water management, Measurement amp Treatment water
-	Communication skills between trainees and IDPs. 
-	Hygiene Awareness and Environmental Sanitation, Importance effective hand washing in the critical times and Safe use of latrines and blocking the route of germs. 
-	Water amp sanitation Related Diseases. 
-	Monitoring tools explanation.

- The project starts in first of October 2019 running for six months&#x2019; period, with a clear exit strategy
This project aims to support the coordination with the WASH actors and local councils and camp managers through monthly and weekly meetings to review the WASH needs and to develop an integrated WASH response. However, monthly WASH cluster meetings will be attended by RF</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-WASH-155907-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-19">230269.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-19">230269.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13731">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-19">460538.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304221716">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-23">230269.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497083">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">230269.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
