<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/CCM/NGO/12859</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve IDPs Living Conditions in Displacement Sites and Reception Center in Idleb Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed interventions aim to improve IDPs access to services in IDPs site equally and adequately according to the Humanitarian Principles through two specific main outcomes: 
1.	Provision of Reception Center management for 12 months:
This Outcome proposes providing the protection for new IDPs in emergencies in reception centre of Maaret Elekhwan, which has been established and managed by Saed Charity and receives new IDPs coming from crisis areas from the governorates of Idleb, Aleppo, Damascus, Hama, Raqqa, Deir Al-Zour, and Lattakia where the RC is located in Idleb governorate, Idleb district, Maaret Tamsrin sub-district in Maaret Elekhwan community. 
This project will specifically continue to provide temporary shelter for the most vulnerable groups of IDPs in emergencies. In addition, it shall ensure the continuity of multi-sectorial assistance in NFI, WASH, drinking water, personal hygiene, and protection from winter consequences for one year including activities of rehabilitation and developing center&#x2019;s basic infrastructure. Also, the project will provide repairing incidental damages in addition to the maintenance of humanitarian infrastructure (latrines blocks, showers, laundry room, sanitation network, NFI, solar lightening poles, tanks of drinking and washing water, big tents) to keep the RC always ready for receiving the IDPs. 
 So, this project shall ensure the durability of safe and equal access of 10600 IDPs (2756 men, 2650 women,2650 boys, 2544 girls) for the temporary shelter and life-saving humanitarian assistance, especially women and children according to the minimum standards and guides of CCCM sector, and International Committee of the Red Cross. Learned lessons of the previous camp management experience shall be also taken into consideration.
As IDPs arrivals to RC decreased within the last few months due to agreement between dispute parties on de-escalation zones and stopping the forced displacements, and to ensure the quality of using money, the budget of RC activities shall be built as on the half of RC maximum capacity 1800 IDPs. 
2.	Restoring basic infrastructure in 10 camps damaged by floods in Badama sub-district:
This outcome aims to reduce the negative effects of floods and weather forces to 13552 IDPs (3810 men, 4158 women, 2880 boys, 2704 girls) who live in 10 camps in Badama sub-district, Jisr Al shoughour distict, Idleb governorate through a set of carefully linked and studied interventions by a team of engineers and surveyors using GIS and topographical maps that includes:
- Establishing rain and floods drainage network engineered design according to the nature of camps&#x2019; nature, quantity of rain and floods in the camp and rehabilitate 2 drainage networks in 2 camps damaged by floods.
- Rehabilitation of main roads and pathways in targeted camps to improve IDPs access especially women, children, people of special needs and elderlies to services and prevent gathering of floods water inside camps, thus tents drowning. 
- Ground leveling for tents above the ground level using gravels, and blocks to prevent floods water entering inside the tent.
- Cleaning and scarping river main stream that crosses targeted camps, SCA will fund cleaning the parts of this stream which is outside camps and necessary for this project success according to the sector guidelines in the current allocation.
- Improve the level of basic services in targeted camps according to Minimum Standards of Response, taking into consideration special needs of women and people with disabilities like lighting latrines at night, and equipping some latrines to be suitable for disabled persons.
SCA has the necessary technical and technological experience to implement such activities and has vast experience in CCCM sector, besides, wide experience and safe access to this project operation areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-CCCM-156121-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">438411.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">614353.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12859">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">1052765.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304065320">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-26">631659.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304795912">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-16">324313.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
