<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/12921</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the resilience of Syrian women and men farmers in Aleppo by distributing agriculture inputs to support olive production.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project design is based on the following: 
Increasing the food security and enhancing the livelihoods of IDPs and host communities (25% IDPs, 75 % host communities) in Aleppo Governorate (Afrin District) as following:
1. (1000 HHs) in (Jandairis- Kafr safra-Jalma- Sheikh Abel Rahman -Haj Eskandar-Upper Diwan-Bayada Jandairis-Tal Slur-Fasha-Upper Maskeh ). 
2.(300 HHs) Cash for work in same regions for olive harvest and pruning.
1000 HHs will receive vouchers for (olive pesticides, olive fertilizers, olive irrigation, olive squeezes, and costs of harvest and pruning). to enable them to care for and service 3000 dunum of olive trees as total.
ATAA MEAL department conducted need assessments (please refer to attached documents): which have a identified significantly high need in the region for the care and service of olive trees after the decline of production in these areas due to different factors,
This has led to reduced purchasing power and income generation for households, which resulted finally in the breakdown of food security. It is critical to support these households to begin to restore the production, as main sources of livelihoods, and enhancing their resilience by enabling them to have more food availability through personal production of the crop products (as well as income generation from selling surplus products).
Key interventions will include: 
1- Provision vouchers to buy agricultural inputs, accompanied by related extension services
2- Capacity building targeting women and men farmers and local community members.
3- Follow-up the project with the integrated management of olive tree service.
ATAA is planning to implement the project through providing (1 types of fertilizer vouchers, 2 types of insecticide vouchers, 3 irrigation vouchers,1 voucher extract oil), in addition to services of pruning and harvesting (cash for work) to:
1. 1300 HHs in 10 villages distributed as follows (3315 female and 3185 male) approximately (1105 men, 1170 women, 2145 girls, and 2080 boys) (the women and men farmers and their children).
Beneficiary HHs will receive 7 types of voucher and redeem their vouchers against agricultural inputs and extension services, at the local markets contracted by ATAA.
ATTA will hold awareness sessions with the traders and all beneficiaries to explain the voucher redeeming mechanisms make them aware of the list of authorized agricultural inputs.
Throughout the duration of the project a market monitoring system will be put in place in all targeted areas. to ensure that the project does not disrupt or affect the markets systems and balance. 
ATAA monitors will collect information for the market monitoring during spot check monitoring visits at the local shops involved in the project. Traders will be warned ahead of the projects start that spot checks can be conducted by ATAA so as to discourage any forms of corruption. 
ATAA will also establish a complaint mechanism (hotline), and a participatory monitoring system through working with local authorities, and beneficiary representatives. Depending upon the good relationship and reputation that ATAA has established through distribution of food aid in the regions, all these measures will mitigate the risks of fraud and assure that gender sensitivity is taken into consideration. Any complaint related to abuse by any humanitarian worker will result in strict measures being taken.
ATAA will identify, verify and profile target beneficiaries through community leaders, volunteer and local councils (where the long list will be prepared). Then the short list will be identified by the criteria of selecting beneficiaries, considering vulnerable people, including: IDPs *, hosting families, and female headed HHs .  **
The planned date for the distribution of agriculture inputs vouchers will be in June.
ATAA agronomist will conduct surveillance during production cycle and provide technical advice and periodic follow-up necessary for project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">249158.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">81691.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6306964840">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-27">392.2</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12921">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-19">330849.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304065330">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-26">264679.7</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497080">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">66169.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
