<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/12853</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Resilience through Humanitarian Assistance and Income Generating Livelihood in North-West Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">825 Tons of wheat crop will be purchased from local farmers whom harvested their crop in June or from local market to support their wheat production and their income, hence support their resilience. 
  From the purchased wheat crops, 125 tons of wheat will be cleaned, sterilizes and packed to be distributed to 1000 vulnerable farmers including families headed by women and/or disabled along with agricultural baskets contain: pesticides, herbicide, fertilizer, and rodenticide. The agricultural baskets will be distributed at 18 affected villages at Al Rouj Valley in Idleb district (8 rain fed villages at the South West and 10 irrigated villages at South East of the Al Rouj Valley) using the following criteria for 8 rain fed villages and the beneficiaries&apos; list of 10 villages of farmers benefited from the QRC irrigation project: 
-Households (HH) who relies on agriculture as a source of income and show interest in this project and its instruction, with access to 5 dunums.
-HH headed by females. up to 50% of the total beneficiaries
-HH having a person or more with special need.
-Large household with more than 5 individuals in the family.
-Vulnerable IDP&#x2019;s and local resident households whom were affected by this crisis. 
-HH must not receive any agriculture support from other NGOs for this year.
The farmers will start planting the seeds in November of 2019, and harvest the crop in May 2020 during this period technical engineers team will conduct capacity building training and give advice on improved production and good farming practice in cereal production such as (soil management, plant protection, fertilization with special focus on organic fertilizers that can be produced using local resources, weeding, control of wheat rust, use of crop residues, post-harvest handling, as well as storage and marketing practices) 5 times during the growing season at 18 different villages. The training helps farmers produce their maximum capacity of harvest by minimizing their losses, in addition to reinforcing a skill set which extends well beyond one agricultural season to ensure high wheat production and yield. Those farmers will be supported regarding their income, and strategic wheat crops will be available for people in the next year which will be reflected on resilience of local economy to have more sustainable assistance. 
	 The second quantity 700 tons of wheat seeds will be sent to mills to produce 560 tons of flour that will be baked to distribute 650,000 bread bundles to  4000 affected and vulnerable IDP families in 33 camps in rural Ma&apos;rat An Numan up to 6 months including families headed by women and/or disabled. Bread distribution criteria will be: Households with 5 or less individuals will receive one bread bundle (1 kg), and more than 5 will receive two bundles.&#x650;
	Kids paradise (KP) will be responsible for all procurement according to their standard policies.KP will be responsible for sterilizing and distributing 125 tons of wheat seeds that will be used for planting 500 hectare, purchasing and distributing agriculture inputs, and provide technical agriculture capacity building to 1000 vulnerable farmers including families headed by women and/or disabled, in 18 villages belongs at Ariha amp Idleb sub-district  at Al Rouj Valley.
	Implementing partner INSAN CHARITY (IC) will be responsible for implementing activities aimed to improve food security for IDP&apos;s in camps of Ma&apos;ret  An Numan and enhancing livelihood opportunities for vulnerable farmers in host 
communities in Al Rouj valley. IC will determine the quality of 825 tons of wheat crop that will be purchased (testing seed samples using Standard Operating Procedures before purchases) from farmers or local market for bread distribution and agricultural input. IC will be responsible for milling of 700 tons of wheat seeds, storing 560 ton of flour it  in their warehouse, contracting bakeries, and distribute 650,000 bread bundles to 4000 families at 33 camps .</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-FOOD-156184-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-13">339990.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-13">259509.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12853">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-13">599500.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304059686">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-24">239800.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304244257">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-04">179850.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
