<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA2/WASH/NGO/13785</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diligent work and rapid response to WASH needs of all IDPs.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Silk Road&apos;s WASH intervention through this project is focused on the immediate, scalable and sustained provision of WASH services to the affected population in four locations (Ram Hamdan,  Maaret Elnaasan, Zardana Mashehad and Termanin located in Idleb governorate ), where Silk Road aims to improve the overall condition of most affected people with a special focus on newly IDPs and the already existed IDPs in the targeted communities in emergencies through implementing of planned activities aimed at filling the gaps and reducing the needs between the displaced and the newly displaced as follows:
1-Support to water quality assurance and operation and maintenance of water supply systems (Targeting both Newly IDPs and host communities)
2- Distribution of essential WASH NFIs amp Hygiene promotion 
3- Conducting Hygiene promotion campaign (Targeting Newly IDPs)
4- Establishment of the cost recovery system and safety plans as well. To ensure the sustainability of operation of wells after handing over the project where we will prepare and review plans and provided required training to the local councils during the period of operation.
5- Provide water testing devices, which includes portable chlorine testers, sterile sampling containers and microbiological analysis for the water authority /local council. This considers as the acritical need for us/ operators and the local councils and will allow us the control the quality of the water pumped through the water network (Targeting both Newly IDPs and host communities).
6- Support and strengthen the waste management system, which helps in the sustainability of the project after hand over to the local councils (Targeting both Newly IDPs and host communities).
7- Installation of waste bins (Targeting both Newly IDPs and host communities).
8-Distribution of water tanks 1 cubic meter and water trucking for the newly IDPs.
By implementing these main WASH activities, that will be the best solution for the current situation and in this context that can allow newly IDPs and the already existed IDPs have access to safe water through restored water systems to reduce vulnerability to preventable illnesses and improve resilience and IDPs and other vulnerable groups (disabled, elderly) have access to life-saving assistance to reduce the risk of WASH-related morbidity and mortality. Within the current situation of the targeted people in the communities and the scope of the intervention, the treatment of the pumped water will be the most effective method to secure access to safe water in sufficient quantity and quality and can ensure equitable and unrestricted access to all members of the community also Silk Road 
The hygiene promotion campaigns will focus on awareness of water-borne diseases, basic guidance for personal hygiene, environmental cleanliness and the specific activities and inputs of the overall project and will aim to encourage communities to adopt safer hygiene practices while also providing the necessary hygiene items to reduce the risk of occurrence of health threats. Good hygiene in a community is achieved through the promotion of hygiene messages in complementarity with the provision of basic hygiene items to enable the communities to practice good hygiene.  
Furthermore, the proposed WASH interventions in this proposal will ensure that they do not create additional risks for the affected population (especially IDPs women and children and the newly IDPs) but will provide the best solutions to the suffering population in the targeted areas, also Silk Road will ensure that the health impact in this emergency WASH intervention will reduced disease risk and reduced transmission risk and it adhering to internationally recognized standards and best practices, ensuring that services are provided in line with the Do No Harm framework, Sphere standards, and humanitarian principles, and that services are of the highest quality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-WASH-156165-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">288735.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">288735.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400311548">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-20">25395.76</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13785">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">577471.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304217629">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-19">461977.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304573370">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-21">115494.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
