<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA3/NFI/NGO/14917</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rapid Response for southern Idleb displacement through distributing Multi-purpose cash voucher</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 4-months project at hand aims to provide emergency cash assistance to recently IDP HHs from Southern Idleb by the provision of MPGs. The project has been designed to contribute to covering the shelter and winterization needs through helping the newly IDPs coping with the displacement and cover their needs by distributing one-off cash grants (120 $/HH). The grant value was designed based on clusters recommendations and in accordance with the value agreed between the FSC and SNFI clusters. Moreover,  cash modality was selected to give more flexibility for the BNFs to cover their priority shelter and winterization needs and allow them to cope with the situation in a dignified way
Violet seeks to target 3450 newly IDP HHs in the areas that have received the highest IDP influx over the last few weeks and have been identified with the highest needs including &#x64D;Sarmada, Atma, Benesh, and Maaret Tamsin. The targeted areas are accessible for Violet through it&apos;s on the ground operation team
The BNFs will be selected in close coordination with the community representatives based on the selection criteria including displacement duration since the newly IDPs are the most vulnerable to the shocks and protection risks. The project will prioritize women-headed HHs as well as HHs with children, elderly, PWDs, pregnant, and lactating women. Furthermore, Violet will ensure close coordination with the humanitarian actors and cluster with regards to need assessment and response analysis to avoid the potential overlapping, save time, and resources
Due to the lack of the banking system in NW Syria, Violet is transferring cash through the Turkish post (PTT). Moreover, Violet has a FWA for money transfer and distribution to the BNFs. Although the FWA will end by the end of March, VIolet is in the process of announcing a new FWA tender for MTA services to ensure continues service and timely response. The FWA will be utilized under this project FWA is attached. The MTA has been identified through a competitive and transparent procurement process after conducting a market and vendor assessment in the local markets. The contracted MTA will be responsible for delivering the cash amount to the BNFs in their locations. The cash transfer agent is obliged to follow Violet&apos;s PSEA, protection, and safeguarding policies
Before the distribution, a rapid market assessment in terms of market functioning and the accessibility to the markets will be conducted to ensure all BNFs have good and equal access to the shelter amp markets. due to the emergency situation on the ground, the RNA will be conducted 24 to 48 hours prior to the BNFs&apos; registration, while the distribution will be conducted from 1 to 2 weeks after the registration process to ensure the proper distribution arrangments and conduct the 100% verification for the BNFs
Later on, the cash distribution will be conducted in two steps 1) the distribution of vouchers to BNFs by Violet team, while the second step is the 2) vouchers redemption with its cash value (120 $) from the money transfer agent who is accompanying the distribution teams to all distribution points, immediately after receiving the vouchers. As for the special cases, sick BNFs, and PWD, can delegate someone else through written delegation in the registration stage to receive their assistance on their behalf
the Vouchers will be printed in a way that prevents the fraud and Forgery through equipping them with light thermal stickers as per Violet SOPs. Additionally, Violet will communicate that cash assistance is free of charge through verbal communication with the BNFs as well as brochures distributions. The project will effectively contribute to market recovery through pumping financial liquidity in the market and may create new job opportunities
Violet has developed its own SOPs for cash transfer and will ensure it&apos;s respected. In addition, Violet will ensure MEAL policies are applied, and the accountability mechanism is clear for BNFs</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-SNFI-156403-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-20">489461.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6307233496">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">1012.65</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-14917">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-20">489461.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304468798">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-29">244730.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304631507">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-04">244730.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
