<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA2/P/NGO/13784</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection Response through Integrated Mobile Emergency Services and existing protection facilities.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to continue responding to the influx of new IDPs displaced to Idleb and in response to the Northwest Emergency Response Allocation Strategy Paper 2019. This will be done through a) supporting the existing standardized mobile teams providing GP, CP, MA, and GBV services b) the expansion of existing Shafak&#x2019;s static centers that are supported through UNFPA and Care, and c) improved coordination of the emergency response in Idleb governorate and western-northern Aleppo governorate. This project will be a continuation component to the existing emergency response modality developed by the Protection Cluster. This coordinated emergency response is led by focal points, among which Shafak Organization. 
In particular, Shafak, being the emergency focal point for Idleb district, in coordination with the other focal points in other areas, will leverage the combined technical expertise and geographic coverage to provide a harmonized and comprehensive approach to the provision of prevention and response services for new IDPs in northern Syria. 
The expected outcome will be to:
- Enhance the prevention and mitigation of protection risks, and respond to protection needs through provision of integrated emergency protection services, including GP, GBV, CP and MA.
- Shafak Organization&#x2019;s role in this emergency will be to continue the provision of these emergency services through its protection mobile teams. Activities will include prevention and response services, Identification of GBV and CP cases, internal (within Shafak) and external referral to specialized (GBV and CP) and non-specialized services, and provide direct support to high priority cases. 
- Existing Shafak&#x2019;s static facilities that are supported by UNFPA and Care International will be expanded under the project to follow an integrated protection model, specialized CP and GBV referral services will be delivered in a wider range by the team in the facility, while outreach teams will be able to identify cases and refer them to the proper specialized service needed. RE sessions will be also conducted in all locations of new IDPs by outreach teams after liaising with UNMAS avoid duplication.
 - Capacity Building: Protection refresher training will be provided internally for the staff of the mobile teams as well as the centers&#x2019; staff. External trainings will be provided to non-protection humanitarian actors to encourage referrals between the sectors.
 - Coordination will take place and will be enhanced with actors in Syria and in Turkey at district level, as well as higher level coordination with Shafak, and the other emergency focal points (IHSAN, SEMA, HRO, Global Communities), and the Protection Cluster. Shafak, IHSAN, SEMA, HRO, Global communities are currently the focal points for Idleb district, Azaz district, Jebel Saman district, Jisr Ash-Shugur district, and Harim districts respectively. Each organization will work within their respective districts and will provide coordination with other protection actors to ensure sufficient coverage of priority areas with high numbers of new arrivals. In addition, Shafak will coordinate within its respective district with non-protection actors to facilitate referrals, share information about protection services, and engage in joint activities such as distributions.
- Shafak will continue to implement protection monitoring assessment and child protection situation monitoring in coordination with CPMTF, and PMTF.

Shafak&#x2019;s project aims to provide protection services for approximately 27972 beneficiaries, which include, awareness raising activities, legal awareness, counselling and assistance, PFA and PSS, referrals, direct assistance and capacity building. The project will implement 5 mobile teams, tentatively targeting Idleb district, and will also expand 1 existing WGSS in Maart Tmisreen location supported by UNFPA and 1 existing Community Center in Idleb city supported by Care International.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">176647.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">122167.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13784">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">298814.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304221713">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-23">149407.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497082">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">149407.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
