<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/RA2/WASH/NGO/13751</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency WASH services to men and women in newly IDP camps in Idleb</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb governorate has become extremely crowded amidst the significant displacement because of military operations in Syria, and this situation led to a huge displacement of thousands of civilians to the north of Syria, which led to increasing of establishing an unserved newly camps
This has made it difficult for the newly IDPs to have drinkable water, and all IDPs cannot go to the toilets because there are no WASH containers in the targeted camps, and this leads to IDPs go far away from camp in open under trees, and for children and women it is the same situation or they go to the next nearby formal camps that have toilets, and this situation will lead to the spreading of diseases and epidemics
All IDPs left their homes without taking anything. So, all IDPs have not Hygiene items and need to raising hygiene awareness sessions to limit the spread of diseases
All targeted camps had limited humanitarian intervention in WASH activities, so it is very essential to intervene in the targeted camps in WASH activities
This project aims to reach the most vulnerable people who are newly displaced people (1463HHs), 9,784 BNFs(59%female-41%male/30%under18-70%above18/5% elderly) in Idleb governorate, Maaret Tamsrin and Dana sub-district.

Based on findings of RNA and RNA1 conducted by Ataa, this project will take place in 11 camps that have no access to clean and drinkable water and no water storage tanks by:
- distribute and install 79 water storage tanks 5000 L/capacity depending on the need for water tanks in each camp (See 11 Ataa Project camps file in the attached), in addition to establishing water gender-separated pools 1 for women and 1 for men (in each water pool will be 3 water taps) to avoid crowded and long waiting by beneficiaries. Storage tanks will be filled daily, the amount of water for each person/day will be from 35Lto 40L/Day in the first 2 months and 25L to 30L in the last 4 months. Ataa will set a water safety plan through testing water in 2 spots(1 in water trucks and 1 at water taps) to make sure the water is safe to drink.
- Construction of public toilets (Sanitation Containers) 84 gender-separated WASH containers with a septic tank (4 latrines one of them dedicated to PWDs and 1 bathroom), in addition to dislodging the solid pits regularly. Recruitment of volunteers from the most vulnerable in the targeted camps (male and female) to clean latrines&apos; blocks on a daily basis to help them improve their temporary income (Cash for work). As well as renting/hiring a waste truck to dislodge septic tanks for 4 times on a monthly basis.
- Activate SWM process by providing 129 garbage bins-capacity 100L (1 bin for 10 families) and renting 2 garbage trucks and employees to collect the garbage on a daily bases to move the garbage to the main landfills
- Improve hygienic behavior and practices by distributing1463 Hygiene kits in addition to conducting hygiene awareness sessions for 3500 persons. Moreover, 653 Hygiene kits for a contingency plan in case of any sudden displacement to the targeted camps
In all above-mentioned activities, Ataa will integrate protection precautions to ensure prevention of any gender-based violence.

The targeted camps are in separate locations which makes it very expensive to build a surrounding wall around each camp, the nature of the camps land is rocky, which makes it difficult to build sewage network for the targeted camps in addition to the distance between the camps and nearest sewage system (2 KM and above).

Ataa will procure an additional 653 Hygiene kits as an emergency for the IDPs yet to come to the targeted camps and will distribute it as soon as they come.
Ataa planned for each latrine to person ratio 1:28-32, therefore if there is new IDPs, the ratio can be 1:35-40.
At the beginning of the project, Ataa plan to distribute 40Lt for each person for two months and to be reduced later during cold months and hence, there will be enough water to distribute to the new IDPs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">207887.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">486593.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-13751">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-18">694481.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304221710">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-23">555585.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304795913">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-16">106697.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
