<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/P/NGO/12822</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing GBV services and protection monitoring in Ariha</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Space of Peace (SOP) through this project aims at mitigating protection risks and responding to the critical protection needs in Ariha district by providing life-saving and specialized Gender Based Violence (GBV) services in Women and Girls Safe Space (WGSS) and through outreach teams in Ariha. SOP has presence in Ariha through an existing WGSS, the exacerbated needs and the staggering protections risks in this district has been identified through assessments and Focus Group Discussions (FGD).
Through this project, SOP will work to achieve the following two main outcomes:
1) The safety, dignity and well-being of vulnerable women and girls is improved.
2) The resilience of the local community is enhanced through providing life saving emergency protection services and protection monitoring.
SOP will target 2457 women, 1950 girls, 500 boys and 803 men of host communities and IDPs through this project with specialized and none specialized protection services. The activities in the static facility will include response to life threatening forms of GBV through the provision of specialized GBV services. Those services will be provided along with a full package of other services mitigating GBV risks through like awareness raising sessions, providing group and individual PSS sessions, providing case management,  and referral services to survivors of GBV and empowering women and girls through life skills and vocational training. This awareness raising activities and group sessions will be used mainly to identify and refer cases of GBV to specialized services and to build the trust with the local communities.
This project will enhance SOPs role as emergency focal point as outreach teams will be deployed to provide emergency protection services to newly displaced IDPs and to vulnerable people in communities (Bazabur, Farkya, Kafr Haya, Kafr Shalaya, Kafraziba , Kafrlata, Moataf, Nahlaya, Nahleh, Orm Aljoz and Shinan) around Ariha. the outreach teams will provide Psychosocial First Aid (PFA), focused PSS session, awareness raising sessions, dissemination of key messages and risk education sessions. those teams will be a valuable resource to respond to newly displaced IDPs and new waves of displacement. The teams will be comprised ofn one team leader, 2 GBV counselors and 2 PSS workers. they will target women, girls, boys and men with preventive activities through awareness raising sessions on protection related issues, recreational activities and, risk education sessions. They will also provide response to GBV risks through case management and referral to other services. the teams will be from SOP trained teams who worked before in protection projects and have knowledge on the available services, PFA and referral pathways. two field teams (each is comprised of team leader, PSS worker and protection worker) will provide the emergency protection activities. 
SOP will conduct protection monitoring in collaboration with Protection Monitoring Task Force (PMTF), 2 field teams dedicated for this purpose will collect information on the protection risks and the access to service for the population in Ariha. This activity will increase SOP&apos;s understanding of the local communities and their different needs. Field monitors will be trained on conducting assessments and the information will be systematically collected and sent for analysis to feed into the PMTF dashboard and periodic reports. interviews and questionnaires will be conducted with key figures of the community in local councils, hospitals, schools and Imams to learn from them about the needs of people in those communities and about the obstacles they face. this will contribute to improving the situation of those communities by sharing the information with other actors and helping them identify the needs more effectively. This will enhance the participation of the affected populations in the overall response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-CPROT;GBV-156498-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">140635.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">139866.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12822">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">280502.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304076222">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-02">112200.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304489249">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-11">84150.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304602916">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-08">84150.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
