<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/H/NGO/12616</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustaining and enhancing access to primary healthcare and mental health services in Aleppo and Idlib through Afrin , Al Resala ,Bulbul,Atareb, and Armanaz PHC centers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AL Resala Foundation (RF), aim through the TFH, continue to provide health services in RF three PHCs is located in Aleppo (Alresala, Afrin and Bulbul). RF provide the service through HPF grants TUR-17/3559/SA 2017/H-N/NGO/5390 until April 2018. Through its health projects, RF has worked to provide primary health care services that are the cornerstones of health services in any health system. These services include early detection of diseases, diagnosis, treatment, rehabilitation and promotion of health behaviors as well as reproductive health services for women through the provision of services Prenatal care, periodic child screening, immunization, postnatal or abortion services, family planning services, women&apos;s. in this project the implementing partner a local registered NGO, YARDIM UZMANLARI YARDIMLA&#x15E;MA VE KALKINMA DERNE&#x11E;&#x130; (UDER) will continue provide health service in two PHCs in Idleb and Aleppo (Atareb, Armanaz). The 2 PHCs in Atareb and Armanaz has been supported by Medical Team International (MTI) Until March 2019

This project consists of 2 main components by Continuity of quality primary health care at health facilities, and Conduct capacity building training for mental health, physical rehabilitation.

	Primary health care services (PHCs) for IDPs and nearby resident populations of Afrin. Al Resala, Bulbul, Atareb, and Armanaz.
	provide Mental health needs psychosocial support &#x201C;PSS&#x201D; for IDPs and nearby resident the IDPs in Afrin, Al Resala ,Bulbul,Atareb by Conduct capacity building training for mental health, physical rehabilitation

More specifically the project components will include the following:
1. Continuation of primary health care services of 5 PHCs level 2 based on the essential package of services for 9 months RF and 6 months for UDER:
The five stationary pre-fabricated PHCs will continue to provide services in Afrin city, Al-Resala,, Bulbul, Atareb , and Armanaz for an estimated catchment population of 88,632 and 68,016 IDPs. The 5 PHCs will provide basic general, three centers reproductive and pediatric health care services and continue to be part of the functional referral system to secondary level health care. It will also continue providing public health awareness for preventive measures through outreach, health education and disease screenings by community health care workers (CHW). 

2. Continuation of Mental health care services of 4 PHCs on the essential package of services for RF 9 months and UDER 6 months. in Afrin, Al Resala, Bulbul, and Atareb for a total of catchment population of 87,999 and 67,675 IDPs. estimated number of people with Chronic illness or psychological condition 2,802 people. through mobile clinic the service will be provide in Bulbul
The centers will provide mental health and psychosocial interventions in the form of psychotropic medication, basic emotional support, By Improving the access to services and support seeking behavior of mental health patients by increasing community awareness about mental health issues and decreasing stigma, improve access to services through awareness-raising initiatives and anti-stigma campaigns.
Conduct MHPSS training to 90 health workers at 4 health facilities. Mental health orientation will provide to 200 community members, and Psychological First Aid training will be providing to 200 community members.
RF will translate Mental Health Brochures to Kurdish and Arabic language.
Close support from the Health and Nutrition clusters information management units will be provided to RF and UDER by regular monthly reports using EWARN, HeRAMS and 4Ws reports


This project aims to support the coordination with the health actors and local councils and camp managers through monthly and weekly meetings to review the health needs and to develop an integrated health response. However, monthly health cluster meetings will be attended by RF and UDER to share the project inputs with cluster members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-10">297901.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-10">127272.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12616">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-10">425174.13</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304043038">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-14">255104.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497070">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">170069.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
