<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA2/FS/NGO/14461</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Livelihoods of The Breeders and Vets in Benesh and Maaret Tamsrin Subdistricts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a response to the needs of breeders which have been identified while conducting the technical needs assessment in the project areas, and based on the results of the implemented projects by IYD during last two years and SCHF priorities for the second allocation, this proposed project will assist the targeted vulnerable categories through lessening their financial burdens, contributing to establishing stable monthly income, correcting the improper livestock practices, and dissemination the recent and best livestock knowledge to the specialists and breeders as a whole. To reach this end, this project will support 200 cows&#x2019; breeders- 50 females, 150  males who own no more than three cows. Accordingly, one of these cows will receive healthcare and reproductive follow-up treatment and artificial insemination with the semen of high specifications and quality to improve the productivity and reproductivity of the local cows&#x2019; breed with a parallel increase of the livestock numbers in the targeted areas. Moreover, each cow will be provided with 10 kg of pellet fodder daily for four months and 5 kg of green fodder as hydroponic barley for two months, supplied from pre-established hydroponic barley rooms by IYD in the previous projects. Also, the beneficiaries&#x2019; cows will be supported with premix fodder which embraces all needed vitamins, minerals, and production modifiers based on the requirement values suggested in the last version of NRC book &quot;National Reacher Council 2001&quot; which lead to good nutrition practices and completing of the elements&apos; values which is either not exist in pellet fodder or existing as inadequate value. 

Secondly, IYD will support the targeted breeders with technical training to improve the community&apos;s skills in breeding livestock. This training will highlight the improper practices in breeding animals and recommended solutions. It is mentionable that IYD, from its experience in implementing the livestock projects, has a list of the most common improper practices conducted by breeders. To ease the process of correcting these prevalent malpractices, IYD classified the fundamental problems of breeding animals and the recommended solutions and included them within special technical handbooks that will be distributed while conducting the training. The training program to the breeders will discuss many significant aspects, and the nutrition section will be at the forefront of issues to be considered since all problems in breeding animals are directly or indirectly linked to animal feeding.  Based on the pre-post tests&apos; results, IYD will assist the top 25  breeders, who excel in the training, with the needed equipment for producing the hydroponic barley. The hydroponic barley production capacity of each unit of equipment will be approximately 15-20 kg green fodder on a daily basis which will be sufficient to feed 3-4 cows.

Finally, develop the capacity of ten unexperienced vets who graduated during the conflict period and couldn&apos;t have a chance to improve their skills in the field. This will be done through intensively theoretically and practically trainings. In this way, the vets&#x2019; chances of entering the labour market will considerably increase. The theoretical training will last for two months, and it will be based on a technical book adopted by IYD from previous projects, and this book was sourced from three international veterinary books. The second part will be practical training for ten vets, where each trainee will be responsible for dealing with 20 selected cows under the supervision of IYD&apos;s technical team. It is worth to mention that practical training will continue until the end of the project and each trainee will receive a medicine bag include the needed medicines and equipment to start with their jobs after establishing the link between the cows&apos; breeders and the trainees. Also, IYD will ensure to distribute a technical certificate for each trainee which will assist them in any future job</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-23">299984.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-14461">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-23">299984.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304474630">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">119993.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304677221">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-24">89995.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304784984">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-05">29071.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
