<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-19/3559/SA1/P/NGO/12976</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and adolescent girls have access to quality specialized GBV services support, particularly vulnerable women and girls, at-risk and survivors of GBV, to address their specific needs.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main goal of this project is to increase access of Women amp girls (WampG) to life-saving specialized GBV services provided at Bahar&#x2019;s WGSSs through mobile and static entry points embodied in 1 GBV focal point (FP) residents at Bahar fixed clinics in each of Afrin and Ma&#x2019;batli, These FPs will communicate with WampG targeting the clinics, provide PSS ampPFA, refer survivors and at risk WampG to the case managers to be provided with specialized case management, and introduce the VTs services and link WampG who express their interest with the WGSSs to be registered. Given that in Afrin Bahar has 2 fixed clinics in different locations (each provides specific medical assistance), one includes the WGSSs in the same building and 1 hospital the FP will work in the fixed clinic that doesn&#x2019;t include the WGSS and will conduct regular visits to the hospital as well. In Ma&#x2019;batli, the FP will be also resident in the fixed clinic where the WGSS exists but in a separated block of the clinic&#x2019;s building. Bearing in mind that the clinics&#x2019; FPs won&#x2019;t provide specialized services, but will coordinate closely with the medical staff to strengthen mutual referrals, and refer WampG to the WGSSs, where the confidential environment is available, representing health referrals FPs Then the case manager will refer cases back to the clinics&#x2019; FPs who will directly link the cases with specific clinics based on instructions from the case managers and in line with the referral principles to be provided with the medical assistance needed.
In addition to a mobile team of 2 PSWs in each location, targeting the whole sub-district of Afrin and Ma&#x2019;batli accompanying Bahar&#x2019;s mobile clinics in Afrin and Ma&#x2019;batli and conducting non-focused PSS, reach out to WampG with disabilities and other specific vulnerabilities to inform them and their caregivers about GBV, health, empowerment, and transportation services available referring survivors to life-saving GBV service Securing in result a wide scope of coverage of GBV services&#x2019; entry points. Moreover, this project aims to increase the accessibility of vulnerable groups to the GBV multi-sectoral response services by (1) providing safe and equitable transportation for WampG, including those with disabilities and specific needs living in urban peripheries from and to the WGSSs, (2) enhancing the inclusiveness of WGSSs though adding ramps and blind people&#x2019;s walkways, (3) and more importantly by training Bahar&#x2019;s GBV staff on the best practices of inclusion of PWDs by another NGO specialized in this field who will follow this training with a 1-month supervision on Bahar&apos;s trainees to ensure practical implementation of the acquired knowledge. Bahar will also target adolescent girls by a GBV program (My safety-My wellbeing) in order to mitigate GBV risks against them since they are highly vulnerable to various types of GBV. Bahar will implement the specialized GBV response in an integrated manner with empowerment services provided under this project including VT and Educational courses, where the most vulnerable WampG including survivors and at risk of GBV, who express their need and interest, will be referred to the empowerment services, and in integration with CP for girls, thus ensuring practical empowerment pillar and adding a pull factor for the most vulnerable groups to access specialized GBV services. As well as, Bahar will support GBV survivors, when needed, with in-kind grants conditional to specific vulnerability criteria to ensure a comprehensive multi-sectoral GBV service and needs-based oriented response. These criteria are WampG survivors or at-risk of GBV And 1-divorced 2-Headed HHs 3-Widows 4-disabilities 5-income under 50000 SYP 6-unable to secure her basic needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR19-CPROT;GBV-156835-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">152903.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">152067.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-12976">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">304971.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304076143">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-02">182982.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
