<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011872-01-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">SPEED for life - Miglioramento delle catene dei valori di SPices and sEEDs per lo sviluppo rurale del Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto ha l&apos;obiettivo di favorire il sostentamento di 3500 agricoltori su piccola scala migliorando la produzione agricola e la commercializzazione di sementi e spezie di alto valore commerciale. Verranno realizzate attivit&#xE0; incentrate sul miglioramento della produzione di semi di variet&#xE0; locali che andranno a soddisfare la domanda dei mercati locali permettendo cos&#xEC; un incremento del reddito medio dei produttori. Altre attivit&#xE0; saranno rivolte al miglioramento della produzione, commercializzazione e trasformazione primaria di spezie con potenziale per l&apos;esportazione, come lo zenzero, la curcuma e il peperoncino. Le attivit&#xE0; proposte sono state costruite partendo dai bisogni delle popolazioni beneficiarie dei distretti di Kavre e Sindhupalchock in cui si riscontrano principalmente problemi legati alla produzione di semi di qualit&#xE0;, scarse conoscenze dei canali e modalit&#xE0; di commercializzazione e delle tecniche di produzione. Un importante intervento per migliorare la qualit&#xE0; nella produzione delle spezie e incrementare la competitivit&#xE0; sui mercati &#xE8; legato al corretto uso dei fitofarmaci sia di sintesi che naturali. La migrazione da parte di molti uomini verso Paesi esteri per la ricerca di lavoro ha lasciato un vuoto nella gestione familiare e aziendale; una particolare attenzione verr&#xE0; data al ruolo delle donne nella gestione imprenditoriale, garantendo la partecipazione piena ed effettiva e pari opportunit&#xE0; di leadership a tutti i livelli del processo decisionale nella vita politica, economica e pubblica. Il cambiamento politico post elezioni del 2017 ha provocato un indebolimento delle politiche locali, non preparate all&apos;autonomizzazione. Un processo di governance verr&#xE0; attivato per supportare gli enti locali e governativi nella costruzione di strategie agricole nel territorio e per rafforzare la partecipazione popolare alle politiche locali.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support the livelihood of 3,500 small-scale farmers by improving agricultural production and the sale of seeds and spices of high commercial value.Activities will be carried out on the improvement of the production of seeds of local varieties that will satisfy the demand of local markets, thus allowing an increase in the average income of the producers. Other activities are aimed at improving the production, marketing and primary transformation of spices with potential for export, such as ginger, turmeric and chili.The proposed activities were built starting from the needs of the beneficiaries of the districts of Kavre and Sindhupalchock, where problems related to the production of quality seeds, poor knowledge of the markets and production techniques are encountered. An important intervention to improve the quality of spice production and increase market competitiveness is linked to the correct use of both synthetic and natural plant protection products.The migration of many men to foreign countries for job search left a gap in family and business management; special attention will be given to the role of women in entrepreneurial management, ensuring full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.The political change post-election of 2017 has led to a weakening of local policies, not prepared for self-regulation. A governance process will be activated to support local and governmental bodies in the construction of agricultural strategies in the territory and to strengthen popular participation in local policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIA - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; INTERNAZIONALE IN ASIA ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011872/01/1" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2019000253" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="21" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural co-operatives</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="52" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31191" percentage="27" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, maintain the genetic diversity of seeds, cultivated plants and farmed and domesticated animals and their related wild species, including through soundly managed and diversified seed and plant banks at the national, regional and international levels, and promote access to and fair and equitable sharing of benefits arising from the utilization of genetic resources and associated traditional knowledge, as internationally agreed</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance the use of enabling technology, in particular information and communications technology, to promote the empowerment of women</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="12" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure sustainable consumption and production patterns</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="12.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support developing countries to strengthen their scientific and technological capacity to move towards more sustainable patterns of consumption and production</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">709459.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIA - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; INTERNAZIONALE IN ASIA ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">382214.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIA - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; INTERNAZIONALE IN ASIA ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-22">327244.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIA - ASSOCIAZIONE PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; INTERNAZIONALE IN ASIA ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
