<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Reserve Allocation 2016/CSS/UN/4429</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support insecurity-affected populations in Pakistan through provision of timely, lifesaving information through formal and informal communication channels</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM Humanitarian Communications Programme (Hcomms) has been operating in areas affected by natural disasters and complex crises in Pakistan since 2009. Initially launched to meet communications needs of more than 3 million people displaced during the Malakand Crisis, IOM Hcomms has more recently focused on displacements from Kurram, Khyber and North Waziristan, as well as returns to Orakzai, Khyber, South Waziristan and North Waziristan in the Federally Administered Tribal Areas (FATA). The programme has a proven track record of implementation in volatile and complex environments, adapting activities and approaches as needed to ensure maximum outreach to target populations. The use of diverse communication channels to disseminate information regarding available humanitarian assistance allows flexibility and breadth in coverage, enabling simultaneous responses to displacements and returns. Customized awareness sessions for women, and information campaigns targeting vulnerable groups such as securing civil documentation for underage girls and boys allays humanitarian concerns compounding the susceptibility of these groups to increased risks during crises. 
As per latest KP and FATA IDP figures, 192,971 families (64% of the total IDP caseload) have returned to areas of origin since 16th March 2015  (OCHA Weekly Return Snapshot, 13 October 2016). The government in coordination with the humanitarian community and security counterparts has been de-notifying return areas the present IDP caseload of 105,769 families (740,383 individuals including 347,980 women) is expected to return to areas of origin by October 2017. With the present programme cycle concluding in October 2016, it is critical to continue humanitarian communications activities during 2017 so as to support the humanitarian clusters and disaster management authorities to support informed, dignified and voluntary return for displaced populations of FATA. 
The program will implement a broad range of communication activities. These include the following:
1. Public Service Announcements (PSAs): Development and broadcast of radio campaigns highlighting the assistance, services and processes available for returning population. Insertions and duration will vary subject to the nature of PSA with an average broadcast duration of one week with at least 6 insertions a day. Each PSA is (on average) 50 to 55 seconds. Potential radio campaigns include:
 Food Distribution and Dates
 Return dates, schedule, compensation 
 Mine Risk Education
2. Print Materials: Development and publication of print ad campaigns (which include pictorials that are especially aimed for IDPs that are illiterate) to announce return dates, schedules, food distributions, processes, etc. other print materials include the production, printing and dissemination of leaflets/brochures/pamphlets and banners/posters related to Protection Cluster Key Messages and Mine Risk Education (MRE). 
3. Awareness-Raising Sessions: At least 1,200 awareness raising sessions will be conducted in host areas and areas of embarkation to enhance information outreach. These sessions (with separate sessions for women and men) for the returning populations will be based on the communications products (FAQs, etc.) put together in collaboration with the clusters and provide assistance or refer cases to relevant authority and/or cluster.
4. Operation of Humanitarian Call Center (HCC): The toll-free Humanitarian Call Center will continue to serve as a helpline support for affected populations. The Humanitarian Call Center has dedicated Pashto speaking staff to provide helpline support returning populations. Queries that can be addressed by the staff themselves are done so immediately &#x2013; other  requests are referred to the appropriate agency or cluster.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ammarah Mubarak</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Operations Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>051-2307841-57 (ext.</telephone>
   <email>amubarak@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="12" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coordination and Support Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-12-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-23">2747.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-23">166705.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-23">1831.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-4429">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-23">171285</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302494763">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-07">171285</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
