<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Allocation 2016/N/UN/3104</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of  life saving nutrition services  for Orakzai and Kurram  Agencies  of Federally Administered Tribal Areas, Pakistan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">-	The activities will be carried out for  target population of  Orakzai and Kurram Agency, through local government health departments in close collaboration with other relevant government authorities (FDMA) and UN Agencies including WFP, UNICEF and UNOCHA coordinated through provincial nutrition cluster of KP/FATA. WHO will assist the government and I/NGO partners by providing support to implement the community-based and facility based nutrition interventions, and will procure and arrange timely delivery of supplies (stabilization center and surveillance equipment, medicines, etc.). Supplies (F-75, F-100) for the inpatient care will be provided by UNICEF  for treatment of SAM with complication children.
-	The proposed strategy for nutrition interventions is designed to ensure the provision of lifesaving nutrition services for severely acute malnourished children (boys and girls) to prevent poor nutritional outcome through rigorous promotion of therapeutic feeding practices, proper hygiene/sanitation and improved maternal nutrition and nutrition education on locally available foods setting up of a robust reporting and information system and monitoring mechanism establishment of a strong surveillance system, and emphasize capacity development of health care providers working in the target health facilities to be implemented in partnership with FATA nutrition cell, WFP, UNICEF.
-	 The Nutrition Stabilization Centers (NSCs)  and Health amp Nutrition Surveillance System (HANSS) will be streamlined in Kurram Agency and for TDPs of Orakzai agency. The project interventions will be monitored through various means including WHO internal monitoring, Cluster joint monitoring and by, line government agencies.
-	The overall objective of the proposed project under Nutrition Cluster for KP and FATA is to ensure provision of life saving nutritional services for vulnerable children (boys and girls) at the facility and community level that meet national and internationally recommended minimum standard of care for a population affected by an emergency.
-	 (1) To ensure provision of lifesaving nutrition services for severely acute malnourished children (boys and girls) less than five years of age through facility based nutritional management approach.
-	(2) To contribute to the prevention of malnutrition in early childhood through promotion of improved infant and young child feeding, care giving and care seeking practices at the facility, community and family level (in nutrition stabilization centers and surveillance system at community and family level)
-	(3) To strengthen capacity for effective implementation of nutrition interventions through briefing sessions of DoH and partners ensure effective and timely implementation of nutrition interventions through enhanced coordination and information gathering monitoring of trends and status of malnutrition in the target population.
-	(4) To streamline and strengthen the nutrition sentinel site surveillance system to know about the trend of nutrition in the population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Mazhar khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National professional Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>92-334 9009339</telephone>
   <email>khanmaz@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="PK2">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khyber Pakhtunkhwa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.48100000 72.09020000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-22">45393.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-22">19876.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-3104">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-22">65270</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="330201265">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">65270</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
