<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Allocation 2016/E/NGO/2964</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Back to School Campaign at Kurram agency (FATA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The summary consists of the following points: the Problem and its background, needs identification and its Solutions. 

1) The ongoing complex emergency including displacement and return processes (2008-2016) have overburdened the already fragile education system in FATA. Most of the tribes living in 151 villages of recently De-notified areas of central Kurram agency are in desperate condition, as there is no body to support their children&#x2019;s education on their return to home. The inter cluster mission under Neil Buhne has revealed the pathetic story by compiling an assessment report for all humanitarian agencies and convinced donors to support the area. Even before displacement, neither there was any proper schooling structure nor learning and teaching materials available particularly in Zemusht tribes in central Kurram. Therefore, there is a sort of uncertainty in the lives of parents and students regarding education. 

2) Philanthrope had meetings at the Directorate of education in FATA Secretariat to discuss the proposed project interventions. Based on feedback Philanthrope has developed the proposal to accommodate their suggestions.. All the damaged schools have been kept on priority particularly in central Kurram. Out of 20 schools of Alisherzai, 17 are fully damaged and out of 36 schools of Masozai, 25 are totally damaged while there is no school at Zemusht even before displacement. 

3) In such a backdrop, Philanthrope proposes to revive learning opportunities in 30 schools including 58 TLCs (29 for girls and 29 for boys) and constructing 2 pre-fabricated  schools structures (one for girls and one for boys) in IDPs returned and recently de-notified areas of central Kurram, Alisherzai, Masozia and Zemusht) for a total of 3000 returned children (50% girls) in tented class rooms in government schools coupled with enrollment drives, dramas and debates, radio programs along with gender balanced trainings for 60 teachers (30 females and 30 males) and 30 TIJs (15 mother groups and 15 father groups) having an improved, accessible, safe and quality education program for them. Philanthrope is having all the expertise and technical personnel (males and females) who can be of great help to this project. Philanthrope will by providing 5 additional teachers in order to rationalize students teachers ratio. There will be refresher courses for learners (2 batches of 2 days Teachers training having half day for Mentoring session) on child friendly spaces (CFSs), education in emergencies (EiE) how to cope with emergencies, DRR, psycho-social, lifesaving skills, Peace amp tolerance, conflict resolution, health hygiene and nutrition class planning methodology and how to conduct a class in such a way as to ensure that there is a child-centered, child-friendly approach to learning the rights of the child basic psychology of the child following the traumatic events and one day for TIJs strengthening about their roles and responsibilities. Moreover, all girls and boys in the targeted schools will be provided with free books, bags, ECE/ Learning kits, Recreational Kits, School in Box (SIB) Kits etc. All supplies and inventories issued to schools would be recorded in stock register having signatures of head Master to it. For all these intervention, Philanthrope requires a total budget of about US $ 200,000/- in order to make learning a fun for all girls and boys students. We know we cannot change the entire complex emergency situation (2008-2016) with tiny funds and in few months&#x2019; time but this can be the very first step towards a high goal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philanthrope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philanthrope</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yousaf Shah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chairman</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03009036943</telephone>
   <email>philanthropepk@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-30">184699.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-30">15300.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-2964">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-30">200000.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philanthrope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301956802">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-12">100000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philanthrope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302329545">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-30">100000.04</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philanthrope</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
