<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Allocation 2016/N/UN/3070</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Targeted Supplementary Feeding Programme (TSFP) Food commodities to support life-saving Community-Based Management of Acute Malnutrition (CMAM) services for moderately acute malnourished (MAM) children age (6-59 months) and pregnant  lactating women (PLW) in Kurrum and Orakzai agencies of FATA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The IDPs returns plan of approximately 30,000 families from Kurrum and Orakzai agencies starting from 20th April-16, The FDMA requested Humanitarian actors to initiate the humanitarian activities in these returns areas to build confidence of IDPs and provide basic lifesaving interventions for an early return process. Rendering to OCHA returns updates (May-2016), the Kurum and Orakzai Agencies collectively signifies 75% of the total returning IDPs while total of 67% from Kurrum and 8% for Orakzai agency have returned so far. The upsurge in the number of internal displaced population (IDPs) returns to FATA and the unexpectedly severe damages in the areas of return will require basic life-saving assistance for the population for the next six months in the priority areas of shelter, health, nutrition, food, wash and education as per the Inter-cluster mission reports (April-2016). The overall objective of the proposed project is to ensure the provision of equitable, improved and lifesaving nutrition services for the moderately acute malnutrition children age 06-59 months and pregnant and lactating women as per national and international recommended standard of care for population during emergency context. The proposed project is in line with PHPF, Allocation Strategy 2016: Critical Life-Saving Intervention to Support Return Process in FATA based on Nutrition Cluster prioritized activities and Strategic objective 1 and 3 through community based management of acute malnutrition (CMAM) approach. Considering the accessibility constraints and cooperating partners (CPs/NGOs) NOC issues in the targeted location of Kurum and Orakzai agencies, WFP will opt for distribution of food/supplies under the proposed PHPF funding support through Project Implementation Unit (PIU) Health Directorate FATA involving the Lady Health Workers (LHW) of the concern agencies or other IDPs hosting agencies of KP/FATA in case field level accessibility is not possible based on NGOs partners NOC or security issues and WFP may start food distribution with DoH-FATA (LHWs) for early response to emergency in case delaying in implementation with NGOs (NOC or clearance). Under the proposed project, WFP will procure and distribute the specialized ready to use Targeted Supplementary Feeding Programme food commodities to support the intervention of life-saving Community-Based Management of Acute Malnutrition (CMAM) services by NGO partners for moderately acute malnourished children 6-59months and pregnant and lactating women. Children with moderate acute malnutrition will be assisted with AchaMum, ready to eat specialized nutritious food produced in Pakistan while PLW will be assessed through Wheat Soya Blend and Veg. Oil. For a timely response, WFP will fill the gaps and deliver the services at the earliest possible through reallocation of Nutrition food from other existing areas of KP/FATA and will replenish the allocations after disbursement of fund from PHPF. Moreover to directly benefiting the MAM children and PLW, the proposal will also indirectly benefit the lactating women and mothers of children 6-24 months of age through community and health facilities based education to improve Infant and Young child feeding practices (IYCF) adopting context specific BCC strategy. WFP already has established nutrition services in both Kurrum and Orakzai agencies and the lady health workers from both agencies are already trained on nutrition by WFP through the FATA Directorate of Projects in 2014-15. Moreover, WFP is already in partnership with 2 national NGOs (PEACE and CERD) is Kurrum and Orakzai, and additional health facilities/ nutrition sites can be included subject to access, staff availability and security situation within the de-notified areas. Under the proposed PHPF funding support, 2,333 moderately acute malnourished children (6-59m, Girls: 1,190, Boys: 1,143) and 5,507 PLW will directly and 9,840 women indirectly benefiting over the next six months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-11" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Amin Ahsan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Finance  Budget Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+92 51 8312232</telephone>
   <email>Amin.Ahsan@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KP  FATA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Ijaz.habib@wfp.org</telephone>
   <email>Dr. Ijaz Habib</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Tahir Nawaz</telephone>
   <email>Islamabad</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Angela Cespedes</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Nutrition</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03458560175</telephone>
   <email>angela.cespedes@wfp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-11">164534.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-11">10461.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-3070">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-11">174996.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301997474/5/6">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-21">174996.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
