<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Allocation 2016/P/NGO/3069</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection of returnee children (boys and girls) and women through community-based mechanisms in return areas of Orakzai Agency, FATA.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main purpose of the proposed project is to provide protective and social services to vulnerable children (boys amp girls) and women in recently ten de-notified villages of Orakzai Agency, FATA. Under this project, Sanjh Preet Organization will establish 10 Child Protection Centres (CPCs) in ten targeted de-notified villages of upper and lower Orakzai Agency. The project will primarily focus those children (boys and girls) who are at risk of violence, exploitation, neglect, abuse, discrimination and exploitation to provide them supportive and protective environment in the target communities. The proposed interventions will enhance the knowledge of target community on child protection and empowered them on monitoring, preventing, responding and reporting on the child protection issues. The project interventions are designed in line with child protection sub-Cluster objective of the Humanitarian Strategic Plan 2016. The project will target 6,575 individuals including 5,000 children (52% girls), 1,575 adults (1,300 women and 275 men) for the provision of protective services. Sanjh Preet Organization, will establish 10 Child Protection Centers in de-notified villages of tehsil central and upper for the provision of protective and social services to children (boys and girls) and women including psycho social support, social and recreational activities, delivery of child protection information and messages, life skills-based education, mine risk education and social services (identification and case referrals through monitoring, integration, community mobilization).
 The project will also form 20 community-based Child Protection Committees (10 male and 10 female) and 20 Adolescent Groups (10 boys and 10 girls) in each Child Protection Center within the targeted communities. These CP Centers will be managed by 20 trained Child Protection Facilitators (preferably 10 males and 10 females). The project will also hire 10 Child Protection Monitors along with two Psychosocial Counsellors. These project staff will be engaged in identifying, monitoring, reporting and referral of vulnerable cases to service providers. The trained psychosocial counsellors will identify children and women in need of psychosocial support through structured and appropriate psychosocial support services.  The project team will organize orientation sessions on various child protection issues like mine risk education, child labor, missing, separated and unaccompanied children, child marriages, children conflict with law, psychosocial issues and on life skills based education. Women and girls will be given special attention in protecting them from abuse, violence, early child/forced marriages and from violence and abuse. 
The CPM will also be responsible for monitoring the overall protection situation of girls, boys and women, identifying protection issues and finding out solution to those issues in consultation with the Child Protection Committees, identifying vulnerable children and ensuring their access to basic services. They will conduct a mapping exercise to identify the existing service providers, make linkages with them and establish a strong referral mechanism in the target area. The most vulnerable children and adults will also be referred for specialized services to psychiatrist in nearby towns. They will also hold awareness sessions on protection issues with parents, community and child protection committee members to further disseminate those messages to the wider community. &#x2018;
Furthermore, SPO, throughout the project implementation, will build strong coordination at all levels including communities, local authorities, Political Administration and international NGOs and FDMA in Orakzai Agency. SPO will also maintain regular coordination at representative and technical level with CP Sub Cluster, Protection Cluster including GBV sub-Cluster and OCHA in order to keep them updated on the project progress and related constraints and challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanjh Preet Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanjh Preet Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pervaiz Akhtar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03004431697</telephone>
   <email>pervaiz@sanjhpreet.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">113429.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">36570.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-3069">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">149999.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanjh Preet Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301956824">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-12">89999.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanjh Preet Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302482361">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-02">59999.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanjh Preet Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
