<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Allocation 2016/Shelter/NFI/NGO/3086</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter Assistance for Vulnerable Returnees (SAVE) at Kurrum</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recent return in May 2016 in Kurrm created a lot of shelter gaps which needs immediate attention to response. The most vulnerable women headed households, PWDs, elder, child headed households whose house are damaged  needs immediate shelter assistance in Alisherzai, Kurrum Agency and same was verified by UN field assessment mission as well as RP&#x2019;s and PRDP&#x2019;s own needs assessment. RP along with is partner are active in the area with valid NOC, established office in Kurrum and have established community based organizations including Youth Groups of boys and girls along with Islahi Jirga&#x2019;s (IJs) of elders including women in 200 villages. The ongoing interaction and request by vulnerable returnees whose house are damaged warranted RP and PRDP to initiate shelter assistance. The project aims to target the most vulnerable  Their houses are fully damaged, Women head households, child headed households, Older persons (gt60),   Persons with disabilities (PWDs). Inline with the shelter cluster technical approach 300 most vulnerable families will receive cash of PKR 60,000 to construct one room shelter in 3 different installments and a solar panel along with battery will be purchased and distributed.. A most secure, accessible, transparent and accountable cash transfer mechanism will be adopted with the support of Mobilink Microfinance Bank and Mobilink (Jazcash) (document of proposal is attached). Each selected and the most vulnerable family will receive ATM card at their respective village after the database and list is finalized by project team. The project team will also be present at each village during ATM card preparation by Third Party (Mobilink Microfinance Bank/JazCash). This will ensure 3rd party transfer directly to each beneficiary after verification and confirmation for transparency. The three stages of cash transfer are defined and shelter engineer along with village committee members will support each beneficiary in designing one room shelter. Shelter engineer along with VC and other teams will verify each stage of construction with a checklist and give recommendation for the release of next installment. The transfer request against each beneficiary will be processed by Finance after it is received from Shelter engineers with duly approved by Project Manager. Regular following and monitoring will be carried out and gender and age segregated data will be maintained for reporting and targeting. The project is in line with the humanitarian Strategic Plan 2016 and shelter cluster priorities and needs identification. The shelter design is also considering DRR and resilience measures and recommended by SAG of Shelter. The project will also ensure downwards accountability through complaint response mechanisms with proper monitoring and capturing learning. Value for money approach is adopted for the project to ensure efficiency, economy and effectiveness as the best cash focused approach is adopted where community will also use salvaged material of damaged shelter to the possible extent. Through technical assistance will also be provided to the shelter beneficiaries through shelter engineers. Do No Harm (DNH) approach will be adopted for conflict sensitive approach and strong engagement of local village committees with involvement men and women. Markets will also be flourished due to cash injection and new employment opportunities for labour will be created through this project which is an extra advantage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pak Rural Development Program</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief Pakistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief Pakistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daud</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03018554991</telephone>
   <email>jandaud@hotmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-08-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-24"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-06">249998.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-3086">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-06">249998.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief Pakistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302122911">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-13">199998.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief Pakistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1104367722">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-29">199998.41</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief Pakistan</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
