<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-16/DDA-3474/1st Allocation 2016/H/UN/3066</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROTECTING WOMEN AND GIRLS IN RETURN AREAS OF  KURRAM AGENCY</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In collaboration with FATA Health Directorate, the project will deliver critical lifesaving maternal and reproductive health information and services and strengthen the protective environment to an estimated 10,000 women of reproductive age 500 men and 500 boys and in  Kurram agency through the application of Minimum Initial Service Package (MISP) for Sexual and Reproductive Health in Crises for the period of nine months. MISP, a SPHERE standard, is a set of priority activities to be implemented in emergency situations with the goal of reducing maternal mortalities, morbidities and disabilities. In any affected population, about 3.5 % of the total returnee population re pregnant, another 3.5% are lactating women and 15% are adolescents. Around 15% of pregnancies may end up in complications while 5 to 15% will require a Caesarian section. The proposed project will adopt of cultural sensitive health care frame work . The Project aims to promote the right to self-determination of returnees when it comes to their reproductive health. Community ownership and leadership&#x201D; of response efforts will be strengthened as well as promoting enabling partnerships between and among affected populations, government agencies ), civil society organizations and other relevant stakeholders to ensure coordinated support in strengthening women and girls access to essential and quality RH services. The interventions will consist of four major components namely:
 Participatory SRH Needs Assessment- utilizing the PEER methodology , the perceptions of indigenous women and girls as well as key community stakeholders on access issues and barriers to service use will be assessed as bases addressing different needs for health information and care with the overall objective of creating opportunities to improve the system.
 Two-Pronged Service Delivery- this will be in static (facility-based) and mobile modalities. For Kurram where facilities are functional support for improving functionality (RH supplies, medical equipment, facility and deployment of additional female providers) will be done to reinforce local health system capacities for BEmONC, FP, HIV and STI prevention as administration of Post Exposure Prophylaxis (PeP). The service delivery while focused on sexual and reproductive health services will also cater general health concerns of affected populations.
 Capacity Building of Health Service Providers and Community Volunteers- short duration trainings on MISP, FP Counseling and coverage mapping and planning will be done for health staff and community focal points 
 Monitoring and Knowledge Management- indicators based data collection will be installed and documentation of emerging good practices will carried be out and shared to inform service delivery practices and government policies.

In addition, *Cash for Work for women and adolescents will be developed based on the findings of community appraisals to incentivize women&#x2019;s efforts to increase referrals and uptake of SRH and protection services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ms.Ana Maria Leal</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Specialist for Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+923008554812</telephone>
   <email>leal@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-14">81742.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-14">168321.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-3066">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-14">250064.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302002992/3/4">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-26">250064.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
