<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41116-PROJECT-01884</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41116" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delivering integrated waste solutions at  the national and local level</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to enhance the implementation of integrated waste management solutions at national and local level to reduce adverse public health and environmental impacts of waste, to increase resource recovery from waste to protect livelihoods, and to improve the resource efficiency of the waste management system. A holistic approach for waste management is promoted to support circular economy with strong links to sustainable consumption and production (SCP) patterns based on life cycle assessment (LCA). The project is closely linked with the 10 Year Framework of Programmes (10YFP). The project outputs will strengthen the capacity of national and city governments for sound waste management. The benefits of sound waste management are reduced impact of waste on public health and environment, resource recovery from waste and resource efficiency in waste management. The project is divided into three components based on the step-wise approach. The first component will raise the awareness, provide the tools such as guidelines for legislative framework and economics of waste, and build capacity through academic curriculum and training on waste management. The second component will capitalize on component 1 and assist to develop national and city level waste management strategies. These strategies will have associated action plans to implement the strategic decisions. To build the confidence of the stakeholders in implementation of the strategies and associated action plans, pilot demonstrations are also included in this component. The third component will help to scale up with studies at sub-regional level in cooperation with sub-regional bodies such as Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) and Inter-state Commission on Sustainable Development (ICSD). This will lead to consensus building of the governments at the sub-regional level on waste management strategy development. The sub-regional bodies will be pursued to issue a political note for member states to develop national and city level waste management strategies and action plans. The bilateral and multilateral agencies will be engaged for implementation of infrastructure for waste management as identified in the action plans at national and city level.This project is developed as a part of UNEP sub-programme on Chemicals and Waste in line with the UNEP Programme of Work (PoW) output 534.1 for Expected Accomplishment 5C - Countries, including Major Groups and stakeholders, increasingly use the scientific and technical knowledge and tools needed to implement sound waste management and the related Multilateral Environmental Agreements (MEAs). This project will be implemented in close cooperation with various UNEP offices including the Regional Offices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BASEL CONVENTION REGIONAL CENTRE FOR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BASEL CONVENTION REGIONAL CENTRE FOR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRO NACIONAL DE PRODUCCION MAS LIMPIA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COUNCIL FOR SCIENTIFIC AND INDUSTRIAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL ENVIRONMENT CENTRE FOUNDATION-GEC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROUP OF SPONSORS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INSTITUTE FOR GLOBAL ENVIRONMENTAL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM OF GERMANY TO THE UNITED NATIONS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM OF JAPAN TO THE UNITED NATIONS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM OF NORWAY TO THE UNITED NATIONS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM OF THE K OF THE NETHERLANDS TO THE UN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAINT LUCIA SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSIDAD DE CIENCIAS APLICADAS Y</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSITY OF DAR ES SALAAM - DEPARTMENT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-29" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shunichi Honda</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>Shunichi.Honda[at]unenvironment.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="GLO" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="DISASTERS CONFLICTS" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disasters Conflicts</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="HARMFUL SUBSTANCES" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harmful Substances</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-01">9939439</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">2543184.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure as from 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
