<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41116-PROJECT-01926</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41116" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secretariat Support to the Global Partnership on Waste Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The demand from developing countries for international cooperation on waste management has increased recently due to a rapid increase in waste generation and complex waste streams including hazardous waste. Based on previous support provided by UNEP on waste management leading to tangible outcomes for waste reduction, recycling and proper disposal, there have been discussions in, and decisions by the Governing Council (GC) and subsequently, the United Nations Environment Assembly (UNEA) (GC 27/12, GC 26/3, GC 25/8, UNEA.1/L.4 and UNEA.1/17) meant to scale up UNEP&amp;rsquo;s support for waste management.In response to this demand, UNEP has developed a comprehensive approach, focusing at supporting countries and stakeholders on waste management issues through the establishment of a key coordination mechanism: the Global Partnership on Waste Management (GPWM). This approach aims at major groups and stakeholders, ensuring they increasingly use the GPWM knowledge platform to implement sound waste management and the provisions of the related MEAs. This will help countries to improve waste management and attain co-benefits including improved environment and health, climate change, resource efficiency, employment and poverty alleviation.The outcome of this project is to increase international cooperation on waste management to support developing countries to improve their unsound management of wastes through the GPWM knowledge platform. This outcome will have long term impact on the environment and health and provide economic opportunity on waste management. This project will produce the three output as follows:1.Generated knowledge to inform international cooperation on waste management in developing countries;2.Secretariat services and guidance provided to the GPWM to increase international coordination in supporting waste management in developing countries; and3.Pilot solutions for emerging and complex waste streams for potential future inclusion in GPWM approach.The project will help to reduce the duplication and increase synergies among projects, design demand-based interventions, disseminate knowledge, and address emerging waste streams including hazardous waste. The project will be supported by international and national organizations including the Government of Japan for hazardous waste management focusing on mercury waste.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL ENVIRONMENT CENTRE FOUNDATION-GEC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GROUP OF SPONSORS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM OF JAPAN TO THE UNITED NATIONS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOI ENVIRONMENT NETWORK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="3">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fuaad Alkizim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>Fuaad.Alkizim[at]unenvironment.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shunichi Honda</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>Shunichi.Honda[at]unenvironment.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="GLO" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="CLIMATE CHANGE" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Change</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="HARMFUL SUBSTANCES" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harmful Substances</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-01">5246041</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-31">806695.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure as from 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
