<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="3" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-NL-KVK-41048542-20ko-8714</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Foundation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="NL">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing access to affordable  medium term to long-term financial services to farmers in greater Mbarara Districts.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra in partnership with SNV is implementing the value chain component of The Inclusive Dairy Enterprise (TIDE) -2 project in Southwestern Uganda. Through this joint effort  Kashongi Farmers savings and credit cooperative was identified to be supported to offer affordable and longer-term finance to dairy farmers among other members in different agricultural value chains. To this end  SNV in partnership with Agriterra commissioned a cooperative assessment of  Kashongi Farmers SACCO. The Cooperative assessment resulted  among others  in the following key recommendations: a) Creation of more specific agri-based product portfolio following member needs assessment. b) Offering loans with a longer-term and improved agricultural loan appraisal process. c) Improving exposure of board and management by benchmarking with other SACCOs in dairy value chain financing. d) Sharpening the strategic plan including a marketing and communications strategy. e) Investing in internal capitalization with a clear focus to reduce interest rates and improve member loyalty. f) Training board on financial management with a focus on cash flow projections and interpretation of the financial reports.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kashongi Farmers SACCO&apos;  Big Hairy Audacious Goal (BHAG)  is &apos;&apos;To be a sustainable SACCO of choice for agricultural finance in South Western Uganda &quot;     Specific goals by 2025:                                                                                                                  i)  Increase membership by 113% from 9 146 to 19 510                                                             ii) Increase share capital by 180% from 1.609 billion to 4.5 billion                                            iii) Increase savings by 380% from 2.248 billion to 10.8 billion                                                  iv) Grow the loan portfolio by 439% from 3.821 billion to 20.6 billion                                           v) Grow total assets by 355% from 5.495 billion to 25 billion                                                     vi) Increase the size of the loan portfolio by 88% from 40% to 75%                                           vii) Sustainably lower the loan interest rate by 50% from 3% to  1.5 % per month on reducing balance                                                                                                                          viii) Sustainably increase the maximum loan term by 50% from 2yrs to 3yrs.The above specific goals will be achieved by  among others  the following interventions;a) Sharpening strategic planb) Tailor-made financial products development/refinement c) Linkage to low-cost loan fund optionsd) Clients relations managemente) Youth councils developmentf) Women leadership development</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at solving difficulties in access to affordable tailor-made finance for investments in the agricultural value chains especially dairy enterprises for rural farmers including women and youth. The interventions will range from sharpening the strategic plan of the SACCO  training board  management  and staff to exposure to similar SACCOs actively funding dairy chains.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="KAFSACCO" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kashongi Farmers SACCO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SNVUG" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNV Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0031264455445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
   <website>https://agriterra.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willemsplein 42 6811 KD Arnhem  Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
