<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="3" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-NL-KVK-41048542-20FACT-8724</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Foundation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="NL">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TA Implementation-Indirect Investments for FACTS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main objectives of the technical assistance to be delivered:1. The objective off the TA is to structure and standardise the Value Chain Analysis process at FACTS to make it more efficient and to reduce risks when stepping in new agri sectors.2. Another objective is to prepare FACTS and its field-staff for this scaling-up at client level.3. The consultant will assist the bank in making the newly gained knowledge part of the product and market development process. A good implementation will make the process more efficiently and will reduce the risks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Technical Assistance Fund (TAF) was created by IFAD as a separate mechanism linked to the ABC Fund  which provides advisory services to agricultural organizations  SMEs and financial institutions. ABC fund is available for direct investments in Farmer organizations and SMEs  and indirect investments in financial intermediaries.
The TAF consortium is led by Stichting Agriterra with Rabobank Partnerships  Advance Consulting and AgriCord as partners. Rabobank Partnerships focusses on Technical Assistance (TA) for the indirect investment via financial intermediaries. The TA implementation plan for SUMAC is based on de Due Diligence (DD) and Environmental Social and Governance (ESG) assessment of the bank executed from 27-11 to 29-11 2019.
Financial Access is a long established financial sector advisory firm with a global 25 year track record of implementing change and capacity development for &#x2013; and with &#x2013; financial institutions in emerging markets. In November 2015  Financial Access incorporated a finance company called Financial Access Commerce amp; Trade Services (&#x201C;FACTS&#x201D;) with operations in Kenya  Uganda and a Head Office in the Netherlands.
Today  FACTS lends to SMEs in Kenya  Uganda and (soon) Tanzania. The ideas and concepts behind our business model go back to the successful Finance for Agriculture (&#x201C;F4A&#x201D;) programs that were run in Kenya and Uganda between 2013 and 2017 in cooperation with the Embassy of the Netherlands.
Under the ABC fund  a revolving credit facility of USD 2m to be lend to FACTS Advance B.V. was approved after a Due Diligence was carried out by a joint team of Bamboo Finance and Rabobank in May 2020. A summary of the outcome of the ESG assessment can be found in the annex.
During the loan period</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will be implemented between Jan and June 2021 covering the following key things:1. Structure and standardise the value chain analysis.2. Assist FACTS in Market development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FACTS BV" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FACTS Advance BV</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0031264455445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
   <website>https://agriterra.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willemsplein 42 6811 KD Arnhem  Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
