<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-NL-KVK-41048542-19kdc-8263</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boosting sustainable coffee farming and marketing through cooperatives</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Strengthen the income base of coffee smallholders and their cooperatives  by:  
Improved coffee productivity by effective extension systems promoting GAP Strong cooperative unions and primary cooperatives that are successful in accessing finance for business development Improved domestic and international marketing of coffee  2. Generating decent employment opportunities in on-farm and off-farm coffee-related activities by:
Improved coffee productivity by effective extension systems promoting GAP Strong cooperative unions and primary cooperatives that are successful in accessing finance for business development Improved domestic and international marketing of coffee</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coffee can offer substantial income to smallholders who have diversified their farming activities. This income contributes to the food and nutritional security of families and makes households resilient to the fast-changing environment. Coffee cultivation can also contribute to climate-smart agriculture especially when good agricultural and agroforestry practices are embraced  protecting the soils from over fertilisation. The shade-loving coffee allows for natural protection against erosion. The coffee sector in Kenya collapsed as a result of the privatisation of the sector  but it is still an important cash crop contributing to 4% of Kenya&apos;s total export value. 
However  due to low prices  coffee production is not being maximised. If a fair price is paid to farmers  for example  by local value addition or strong marketing practices  coffee can offer a substantial income to smallholder farmers. 
In order to achieve this  Unions can play a pivotal role in the process to boost coffee production and marketing.  
The coffee unions are active in the collection  procurement  washing  grading  milling  roasting and marketing of coffee on the county level. Both are looking for direct market linkages within their own country but also neighbouring counties or even export opportunities.
Both Unions are very active in improving their governance (on a Union as well as Primary Coop level)  financial management and extension services in order to increase productivity at the farmer level.
 SO  # 1: FOs and farmer-led enterprises improve technical and economic services to their members along the value chain:
Good Agricultural Practices are promoted through a sustainable extension structure  with a focus on reaching out to lead-farmers and their group in order to improve the soil structure and quality  resulting in higher productivity  less costly input supply and contributing to the de-acidulation of the soil. The focus will be on transformation towards (semi-) organic farming practices. 
SO # 2: FOs influence policies and business environments for the transformation of family farming and the development of sustainable  adaptive economic initiatives and farmer-led enterprises:
The Farmers Advocacy Consultation Tool (FACT) training and coaching will support both unions in conducting effective lobby trajectories at the county level and at the national level by the Unions to access public and/or private sector financial means to further invest in the coffee sector  but also creating an enabling environment for direct export linkages in order to support the Kenyan farmers adding value at the local level and getting a fair price for the coffee. 
SO # 3: Improved access of FOs to financial services:Through financial management training  and support in preparing solid business plans  with the support of Agripool experts  both unions will be supported to mobilize alternative means of financing such as working capital and investment funds to further expand the coffee business (besides mobilizing internal capitalization and lobby for public investment). 

At a Union level  Agriterra already built the capacity on governance and financial management  yet continued support is needed to assist the clients in mobilizing capital to structurally improve the organisation and position in the value-chain.  This approach shall be rolled out to the primary levels as well. &#x2013; 
  
Strategic Financial Management (Unions)  Financial Management Training (PCs). 
  Record keeping at farmer level and benchmarking
  Internal Capitalisation training
  
Support in business planning and lobby with financial institutions to get access to working capital and/ or investments MCCCU aims for KES 20M (&#x20AC;200K) as working capital to finance farm inputs to their members in 2019. KDCU aims to access KES 70M working capital for parchment advances and 7M for working capital for operations.
  
 

SO # 4: FOs are accountable organizations able to effectively perform their institutional functions:Good governance and leadership practices are understood and implemented by the leaders of the Unions and Primary cooperatives. This is key to successful and transparent decision making fair economic transactions and active participation and loyalty among the members. Improving the understanding of good governance and leadership is key at both union and primary cooperative level to ensure maximum functioning of the FO  allowing for economic transaction and expansion in the agricultural business.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The generic project plan can be found under the uploaded documents. Detailed action plans per union are prepared for 2019. For 2020-2021 and 2022  detailed action plans will be developed shortly  but actual updated versions will be prepared annually in close coordination with the unions. The advisory services that will be provided by Agriterra are already detailed per year and will further guide the action plans as well. 

        The   coffee unions have many Primary Cooperatives as members. This project will   focus on further professionalising about 50% of the Primary Cooperatives (30   PC) aiming to reach about 20% of the total number of individual farmer   families (22.000). To select the PCs  a light assessment (1 day) will be done   to know the current state of the cooperative and know what intervention would   be most needed to address the identified challenges in the five described   programme components.
    
   O1:   Improved capacity of FOs to deliver technical and economic services and   connect their members to markets 
    
   Both unions focus much on business development by 1. good extension   service provision to members focussing on increased and sustainable productivity   and 2. output marketing marketing support to enhance the position in the   value chain value addition by further processing and branding. This will   ultimately improve the business performance  increase the membership and   contribute to better income at farmer level. The   introduction of demand-driven services   and new value adding activities will lead to increased   productivity  quality and resilient production by members and an enhanced   position in the inclusive value chain which will eventually result in better   income levels   at farmer level. These demand-oriented services are sustained by income   generated through the PCs.
    (Follow up   on) Sustainable Services Workshop: capacity   of Extension team and lead farmers and the structure of service provision is   improved
   Soil testing as a business training will result   in affordable soil testing for small holders   resulting in better soil management and higher productivity among 4% of the   members in 2019  8% in 2020  16% in 2021 and gt,20% in 2022.
   ToT on soil management and fertility training for   extension officers and few outstanding lead farmers (Agripool experts):   better technical advise to farmers    leading to better productivity
   Value   creator tool: identify opportunities to add value at the level of farmer    cooperative and/or union in the coffee value chain.
   Branding for visibility in the national market
   Marketing training for staff resulting in improved   skills for professional handling of customers.   
   Facilitate linkages with the export market: At   least 2 successful international market linkages facilitated 
   Participation of KCDU and MCCCU in international   coffee fairs (at least 1 event per year for both organisations) 
   Strategic Financial Management (Unions)    Financial Management Training (PCs). 
   Record keeping at farmer level and benchmarking
   Internal Capitalisation training
   Cooperative governance training and roll out to PC: Improved   governance and leadership of KCDU and MCCCU.
   Governance and Leadership training (through ToT to local trainers) will strengthen the   ownership and absorption capacity of the partners
   Financial management training for PC (roll out   programme through ToT to local trainers) will improve financial management at   the PC level and create more awareness among the supervisory board to enlarge   accountability. 
    
   Marketing   support services:
    
   O2:   Improved access of FOs to financial services 
    
   Cooperative   development is crucial to have a successful   business run by cooperatives and be loyal and trustworthy business partners   for banks  buyers  suppliers. Good governance and financial management are   the main pillars of our approach. At a Union level  Agriterra already built the capacity on governance   and financial management  yet continued   support is needed to assist the clients in mobilizing capital to structurally   improve the organisation and position in the value-chain.  This approach shall be rolled out to   the primary levels as well. &#x2013; 
   Support   in business planning and lobby with financial institutions to get access to   working capital and/ or investments MCCCU aims   for KES 20M (&#x20AC;200K) as working capital to finance farm inputs to their   members in 2019. KDCU aims to access KES 70M working capital for parchment   advances and 7M for working capital for operations.
    
   O3:   Improved business environment for sustainable  adaptive economic initiatives   and smallholder competitiveness
    
   Majority   of the coffee producers are small holders.    In order to enhance competitiveness   and be adaptive  this project focussed specifically on the inclusiveness of youth and women. They are an   important workforce   and in need of decent employment either on- or off-farm. Constituting an important part of the labour force  it is   important to ensure their equal participation and access to services and   support  but also in representation. Youth participation and young leadership   will be addressed with the aim to have a fair representation of youth in the   board but also to support youth to be heard and seen as serious actors in the   value chain  that can bring a positive change and decent employment. Already   established youth councils will be further supported to identify and address   relevant areas of intervention such as introducing ICT innovative solutions    youth engaged as service providers and entrepreneurial young farmers as a   role model. 
    
   The   focus on women empowerment is implemented through all activities with the   objective to try and achieve participation of at least 30% women in all   activities. The aim is to have more female members and empowered women in   leadership positions.  
    
   Activities:
   -              Youth trajectory (Youth   Masterclass and coaching)
   -              Female leadership training    Masterclass and coaching
   -             Youth (at least 10%) and gender (at   least 30% women) quota set for all activities 
   -             Lobby activities specifically   addressing youth and women needs
    
   O4:   Strengthened institutional capacities and professionalism of FOs,
    
   All   activities that will be conducted and supported by Agriterra aim to further   strengthen the professionalism of the FO as well as its institutional   capacities. The direct target group of   advisory services are mostly board and   staff of the unions and the primary cooperatives. It includes Financial   Management  governance and lobby capacity building.
    
   The   Farmers Advocacy Consultation Tool training supports the unions in effectively influencing both their regional and national   business environment in general and the results on farm level in particular. KDCU and MCCCU   already received training on FACT including a follow-up through an intensive   FACT write-shop and will be supported to further   roll-out FACT to members unions and PCs   respectively. Through FACT trajectory the unions will be successful in   lobbying with the county government (for necessary investments) and be   critical sparring partners in creating an enabling environment for the   development of the sector. FACT will also support the organisation to   position itself stronger into the value   chain. 
    
   -            Farmers   Advocacy Consultation Tool 2 (FACT) Training and support in the effective lobby. Result: at least 2   successful lobby trajectories conducted at county/ local level for access to   inputs or finance   or policy changes.
    
   O5:   Enhanced knowledge and dissemination among peers for replication and   scaling-up.
    
   -            Specialized Advisory services and knowledge   exchange with experts facilitated by Agriterra&#x2019;s Agripool. Agriterra promotes   the use of local Agripoolers or peers as well. 
   -            Through the Agripool  Agriterra will facilitate   multiple knowledge exchanges. These exchanges will connect the clients with   Finance  Governance  Business  Agronomic  Youth  Women  and Lobby   experts from African and or Dutch partner organisations.
   -            The focus is on about 50% of the PC. It is   expected that by realising improved business performance due to the
   Various project   interventions  the other PC will also be triggered and gain interest in   changing certain practises. 
   -            Lead Farmers and will play a pivotal role in   further dissemination among peers and scaling up. This project invests in   uplifting their skills  knowledge and willingness to share and coach others. 
    
   Linkages
   At the   end of this project  it is expected   that the unions have: a. Gained access to capital and investment funds   through thorough financial management support.  b. Improved the quality and quantity of   coffee production by providing good advisory services to the member   cooperatives. c. Collected more coffee from their members hence enlarging   their market share and d. Improved access to direct coffee markets such as   the auction market (bulk coffee) and created some niche markets like the   local market and/or speciality coffee   markets.
    
   This   will result in horizontal integration in the value chain (cooperation among   various unions to access the auction market) and vertical integration by   establishing more direct market linkages  reducing dependency on the middle-men. This trajectory is already   gaining traction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="IFAD" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Fund for Agricultural Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Kipkelion" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kipkelion District Coop Union (KDCU)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="MCCCU" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meru Central Coffee Co-operative Union Ltd.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0031264455445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
   <website>https://agriterra.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willemsplein 42 6811 KD Arnhem  Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="5"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31165" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">1529</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk days</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk days</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">1529</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment DGIS</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-NL-1-PPR-28456" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment DGIS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">1529</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund DGIS</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-NL-1-PPR-28456" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund DGIS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">12328</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="19kdc-8263" ref="MCCCU" type="72">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meru Central Coffee Co-operative Union Ltd.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment of benificiary client</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">9148</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="19kdc-8263" ref="MCCCU" type="72">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meru Central Coffee Co-operative Union Ltd.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment of benificiary client</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">9148</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="19kdc-8263" ref="MCCCU" type="72">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meru Central Coffee Co-operative Union Ltd.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment of benificiary client</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-12-31">4574</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local cost</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="19kdc-8263" ref="MCCCU" type="72">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meru Central Coffee Co-operative Union Ltd.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment of benificiary client</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
