<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41048542-NL-KVK-41048542-19AgRw-8388</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Foundation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="NL">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth inclusion Coffee Rwanda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusion of youth in the coffee value chain.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Name project: CBI Specialty Coffee Programme Rwanda
CBI Project:114711 / RW2301
Name activity: Youth Inclusion
Period: October 2019 ndash; December 2020Agriterrarsquo;s proposal to battle the problem of the aging workforce in the coffee sector is to partner with the eight start-up SMErsquo;s as selected by CBI  in addition to two coffee cooperatives (Abakundakawa Rushashi and Twongerekawa Coko) in Gakenke District. These cooperatives complement the SMErsquo;s in such a way that they form ideal vehicles for jobs creation for youth in the coffee sector and have the ambition to increase their presence on the international specialty coffee market. We believe that cooperatives are a perfect channel to mobilize youth and to make their business activities sustainable. Please find below the customized composition of our proposal  which will contribute to making the Rwandan coffee sector cool and profitable for youth.Overview of activities
Youth workshop
Youth participation is the key to sustaining the cooperative in the future. The objectives of the workshop are to inform cooperatives about youth participation by setting up youth councils and supporting them to specify their aim  structure and place in the cooperative. Agriterrarsquo;s renown youth workshop approach stimulates interactive discussions between board members  management and young members on youth participation in the coffee sector  their interests and possible concerns and lists the benefits and challenges related to youth participation.
Youth mobilization events to the coffee sector
To make the coffee sector cool  there must be fun activities for youth to enjoy but again to earn income. We plan to organize football matches from village up to sector level in Gakenke district to attract more youth as active members of the coffee cooperatives. During those matches  sensitization on engaging in the coffee sector (production or other coffee related business activities) will be done and winners will be offered some prizes to motivate them.
Media campaign to mobilize youth in the coffee sector
A specific media campaign will be conducted to inform youth about the importance of joining the coffee sector and the earnings they can make out of the sector. Rwandarsquo;s National Agriculture Board will be engaged in the campaign  which should have impact across the country  from production to marketing.Organic compost production training
Agriterra will organize a training course for youth on composting. Many coffee fields are not in optimal production because the soil is not being stimulated to offer the best environment for prosperous coffee production. By training interested start-ups and the youth of the Gakenke communities on compost making  they are offered a new skill which can allow them to generate income. Farmers  either organized in cooperatives  or operating individually as coffee farmers will be tempted to pay for these new services of local youth  because it will immediately impact their production and hence their income.
Management of coffee fields by youth
During the youth workshop  Agriterra will sensitize the coffee producers to make pieces of land available for youth to work on; not only for them to learn more about coffee farming techniques  but also to earn an income. The eight selected start-ups can offer management services to old farmers of the cooperatives. Youth will help old farmers on the land and support them in their daily work on the field which will increase the coffee production. Not only this will create employment for youth and generate income but also will ensure the efficient production. Larger communities will benefit from the increased coffee revenues.
Training on organic farming
The international market is increasingly asking about the agricultural practices used to produce the coffee it enjoys so much. To meet this market demand  and to ensure that the green coffee is produced under sustainable economic  social and environmental conditions  Agriterra will train the cooperatives and the selected SMEs on organic farming. This training will include practical sessions to make different fertilizers which can restore the natural fertility of exhausted soils  good agricultural practices and organic insect prevention using ash resolution.
Business development workshop
To support cooperatives and the selected SMEs to identify challenges in their value chain and come up with interventions and solutions  Agriterra will organize tailor made business development workshops for entrepreneurs in the coffee sector. This will improve their position in the value chain. Among others  during this workshop cooperatives/SMEs are taught how to make a sound business plan and create value for this international commodity.
Business advisory services and project management
Agriterra will assign one Rwandan business advisor to this project for 80 days for the total duration of the project. He/she will be in charge of coaching selected start-up SMErsquo;s and two coffee cooperatives in different aspects such as agronomic practices  business development  marketing amp; branding and daily advisory services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overview of activitiesYouth workshop Youth participation is the key to sustaining the cooperative in the future. The objectives of the workshop are to inform cooperatives about youth participation by setting up youth councils and supporting them to specify their aim  structure and place in the cooperative. Agriterrarsquo;s renown youth workshop approach stimulates interactive discussions between board members  management and young members on youth participation in the coffee sector  their interests and possible concerns and lists the benefits and challenges related to youth participation.Youth mobilization events to the coffee sector To make the coffee sector cool  there must be fun activities for youth to enjoy but again to earn income. We plan to organize football matches from village up to sector level in Gakenke district to attract more youth as active members of the coffee cooperatives. During those matches  sensitization on engaging in the coffee sector (production or other coffee related business activities) will be done and winners will be offered some prizes to motivate them.Media campaign to mobilize youth in the coffee sector A specific media campaign will be conducted to inform youth about the importance of joining the coffee sector and the earnings they can make out of the sector. Rwandarsquo;s National Agriculture Board will be engaged in the campaign  which should have impact across the country  from production to marketing.Organic compost production training Agriterra will organize a training course for youth on composting. Many coffee fields are not in optimal production because the soil is not being stimulated to offer the best environment for prosperous coffee production. By training interested start-ups and the youth of the Gakenke communities on compost making  they are offered a new skill which can allow them to generate income. Farmers  either organized in cooperatives  or operating individually as coffee farmers will be tempted to pay for these new services of local youth  because it will immediately impact their production and hence their income.Management of coffee fields by youth During the youth workshop  Agriterra will sensitize the coffee producers to make pieces of land available for youth to work on; not only for them to learn more about coffee farming techniques  but also to earn an income. The eight selected start-ups can offer management services to old farmers of the cooperatives. Youth will help old farmers on the land and support them in their daily work on the field which will increase the coffee production. Not only this will create employment for youth and generate income but also will ensure the efficient production. Larger communities will benefit from the increased coffee revenues.Training on organic farming The international market is increasingly asking about the agricultural practices used to produce the coffee it enjoys so much. To meet this market demand  and to ensure that the green coffee is produced under sustainable economic  social and environmental conditions  Agriterra will train the cooperatives and the selected SMEs on organic farming. This training will include practical sessions to make different fertilizers which can restore the natural fertility of exhausted soils  good agricultural practices and organic insect prevention using ash resolution.Business development workshop To support cooperatives and the selected SMEs to identify challenges in their value chain and come up with interventions and solutions  Agriterra will organize tailor made business development workshops for entrepreneurs in the coffee sector. This will improve their position in the value chain. Among others  during this workshop cooperatives/SMEs are taught how to make a sound business plan and create value for this international commodity.Business advisory services and project management Agriterra will assign one Rwandan business advisor to this project for 80 days for the total duration of the project. He/she will be in charge of coaching selected start-up SMErsquo;s and two coffee cooperatives in different aspects such as agronomic practices  business development  marketing amp; branding and daily advisory services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="Abakundakawa" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAKUNDAKAWA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="Abakundakawa" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ABAKUNDAKAWA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="AgriRwanda" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Rwanda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Rwanda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41048542" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="TWOKAWACOKO" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TWONGEREKAWA COKO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="TWOKAWACOKO" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TWONGEREKAWA COKO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations</narrative>
   </department>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0031264455445</telephone>
   <email>agriterra@agriterra.org</email>
   <website>https://agriterra.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Willemsplein 42 6811 KD Arnhem  Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">51663</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">160</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise assignments</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise assignments</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">5401.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise assignments</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advise assignments</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">2921</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk days</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk days</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">9640.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk days</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desk days</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">2668</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events / Training / Exchange</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events / Training / Exchange</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">5643.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events / Training / Exchange</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events / Training / Exchange</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">2616.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">External consultancy</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">External consultancy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-08-31">1164</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Full payment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">19AgRw-8388-20ATRW-13053</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="19AgRw-8388-20ATRW-13053" ref="ATRW" type="72">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Rwanda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-06">230.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Full payment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">19AgRw-8388-20AgRw-12609</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="19AgRw-8388-20AgRw-12609" ref="ATRW" type="72">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriterra Rwanda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">-23594.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment DGIS</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-NL-1-PPR-28456" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming commitment DGIS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">-23594.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund DGIS</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-NL-1-PPR-28456" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directoraat Generaal Internationale Samenwerking</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming fund DGIS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal commitment various donors</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal commitment various donors</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">50000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal commitment various donors</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal commitment various donors</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">10000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal funds various donors</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal funds various donors</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">50000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal funds various donors</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming internal funds various donors</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">1743</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partner-network assignments (Agripool)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partner-network assignments (Agripool)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">3104.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partner-network assignments (Agripool)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Agriterra</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" ref="NL-KVK-41048542" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partner-network assignments (Agripool)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41048542-FCSB-2016-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
