<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12308A0101-TUR-15130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal Aid Practices  (UNDP) 2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">R&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lpspraxis (UNDP) 2019-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet med insatser &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka kvalit&#xE9; och tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp i Turkiet genom att utveckla samordnning, kvalit&#xE9; och systematik i praxis f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp. UNDP blir avtalspart till Sida och ansvarig f&#xF6;r projektledning och samordning. Federationen f&#xF6;r tuskiska advokatsamfund &#xE4;r huvudsaklig genomf&#xF6;rare. Insatwsen har utformats i konsultatin med Justitieministeriet och ministeriet kommer att vara delaktig under genomf&#xF6;randet. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande;  

Samordning: &#xD6;ka samordning och samarbete mellan enskilda organisationer, advokater och advokatsamfund i tillhandah&#xE5;llandet av r&#xE4;tthj&#xE4;lp,
Systematisk ansats: Sprida erfarenheterna fr&#xE5;n Ankaras advokatsamfund s.k. &quot;Poppy centers  (center f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga konsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld och tillhanda r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp till som blivit offer f&#xF6;r s&#xE5;dant v&#xE5;ld)genom 7 andra advokatsamfund i Turkiet 
- Kapacitetsutveckling: St&#xF6;dja fortsatt kapacitetsutveckling av advokater som levererar r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp via en webportal f&#xF6;r on-line utbildning 
- &#xD6;kad medvetenhet bland advokatsamfund i Turkiet kring operationalisering av ett system f&#xF6;r prestationsbaserad uppf&#xF6;ljning och system f&#xF6;r att anvisa r&#xE4;ttsfall till advokater</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the contribution is to enhance the quality and access to legal aid services in Turkey through the development of more coordinated, qualified and systematic approach into legal aid practices. UNDP will be the contract partner to Sida and ensure overall project management and coordination. The Union of Turkish Bar Association is the main implementing partner. The contribution has been designed in consultation with the Ministry of Justice and the Ministry will be involved throughuout implementation. The objectives can be summarised below: 

- Coordination: enhance coordination between NGO&#x2019;s, lawyers and bar associations in legal aid provision,
- Systematic Approach: instrumentalise Ankara Bar Association&#x2019;s Poppy Practices (violence prevention centers where legal aid is supplied to persons inflicted with GBV) in 7 Bar Associations in Turkey,  
- Capacity Development: further support capacity building of lawyers providing legal-aid via an online training portal,
- Awareness Raising among bar associations in Turkey for operationalization of performance management tools and automation system of CCP lawyers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The theory of change for the intervention is to further enhance the quality and access to legal aid services in Turkey through the development of more coordinated, qualified and systematic approach into legal aid practices. The approach is developed to enhabce coordination between bars and CSOs and supply information on legal aid to citizens and to seek opportunities to work on legal aid.&#xA0;It will establish violence prevention centers to supply legal aid services for&#xA0;vulnerable persons. It is foreseen that CSOs will direct vulnerble persons to these centers. Efforts to enhance the capacities of lawyers on vulnerable persons and well being of the lawyer&#xA0;will carry on with online training.&#xA0;Build awareness on the operationalization of performance management tools and mechanisms will help to establish&#xA0;a more standardised and sytematic legal aid practices to&#xA0;improve access to justice.
Outcomes:
- Coordination: enhance coordination between NGO&#x2019;s, lawyers and bar associations in legal aid provision,
- Systematic Approach: establish Ankara Bar Association&#x2019;s Poppy centers(violence prevention centers where legal aid is supplied to persons inflicted with GBV) in 7 Bar Associations in Turkey,
- Capacity Development: further support capacity building of lawyers providing legal-aid via an online training portal,
- Awareness Raising among bar associations in Turkey for operationalization of performance management tools and automation system of CCP lawyers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">488615.264340858</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">488615.2643408581</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-30">1427680.072758</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-28">488615.264340858</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-28">466368.967808882</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/12308_12308amendmenttothebudget.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12308 Legal Aid Project Amendment to the Budget</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/12308_12308signedagreementwithUNDP.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12308 Legal Aid Project Signed Agreement with UNDP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/12308_Beslutominsats(12308).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12308 Decision on Contribution for Legal Aid Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">It was foreseen that there is a long list of CSOs that are implementing activities to raise awareness among vulnerable groups on legal aid however some Bar Associations are not aware of this and do not have a dialogue to benefit from the services of the CSOs. Also CSOs should be made more aware of the services the bar associations supply and a partnership should be established to address the problems and bottlenecks of the system together also with public authorities, to develop common solutions and meet the needs of people in demand of legal aid. A meeting was held with CSO and bar association representatives where possible partnership points and actions to be taken was discussed. The suggestions of CSOs are expected to be incorporated to the dialogue and partnership with CSOs and the implementation of Violence Prevention Centers (VPC). The CSOs are made aware of such a project and if not already established possible partnership, referral to bar associations are expected. The meeting had an important impact on CSOs in terms of raising awareness and facilitating their engagement for networking with Bar Associations. This first outcome will be further assessed once the VPC are operational which constitutes the second outcome.
A Needs Assessment was conducted in the inception phase of the project. A guideline to establishment and operations of the VPC was drafted and approved by the pilot bar associations. Visits to 7 pilot Bar Associations were completed for infrastructure analysis and locations were determined for 5 Bar Associations. The bars have continued to show their support and willingnes to open the VPC by supplying the premises. The premises allocated for Antalya has transportation problems; therefore a new location is still being sought. Nevsehir Bar Assocation is waiting approval by the Municipality toi use the premises allocated by the municipality. The approvals in respectively from Chief Prosecutors Office and Municipality is on hold due to the COVID pandemic. It is expected that these approvals will be obtained and VPC will be operational once the pandemic is over. Overall the VPC were expected to be established by the end of this first phase however the COVID pandemic effected their opening.
Visibility will be major important in raising awareness of legal aid services. Project logo was designed and the website is ready to be launched. A communication guideline has been drafted. Comprehensive informative document to be uploaded on the website that includes legal and definite information regarding violence, actions to be taken, precautionary measures and channels of reporting violence was also made available. Gender Expert also prepared a &#x201C;Communication Elements In the Scope of Gender&#x201D; document as a guideline for a gender-sensitive communication approach for the project. The website is expected to serve as a medium in sharing information with stakeholders and keeping them up to date. Monitoring should be conducted as project websites suffer from not receiving enough attention as content matter is scarce.
Due to COVID, work on Outcome 3 has started earlier.Desktop work has been conducted where preparations for the training needs assessment for the online training program has started. Priority areas is expected to be presented in the coming days.
The project is important in assessing the different dynamics of every province in terms of coordination and institutional relationships. One of the most important points raised is how to establish a dialogue and coordination with relevant civil society organizations and public institutions in order to strengthen collaboration and local violence prevention mechanisms. MoJ, General Directorate of Criminal Affairs, Department of Victim Rights Unit have greatly contributed to the first phase of the project as they have been in the previous SILA project. They are seeking ways to work in coordination with the Ministry of Family, Labor and Social Services and the Ministry of Interior and the ILAP for access of disadvantaged groups to justice. They are looking forward for more coordination meetings between public administration and that the project will contribute to the promotion of both Violence Prevention Centers and Judicial Support Centers (ADM) and Judicial Interview Rooms (AGO) which will serve people seeking legal aid and justice.
Due to COVID pandemic further desktop work was created to benefit the results of the project. A GBV analysis for mapping the current situation in pilot provinces and understanding services or solutions provided to GBV victims was conducted. Data was collected from Bar Associations, NGOs and Municipalities. chief prosecutors&#x2019; offices, courthouses, S&#xD6;NIMs, police and gendarmerie directorates in pilot provinces about the number of gender-based violence applications, number of injunctions granted, number of victims transferred to shelters and gender-based violence case types. The analysis report is still under preparation due to pending statistical information from related institutions.
As an unexpected result; In the first&#xA0;hjalf of this phase,&#xA0;President of UTBA contacted the First Lady to share experiences between VPCs and S&#xD6;NIMs (Ministry of Family, Labour and Social Services). Intentions were stated that experienced attorneys working at VPCs will support S&#xD6;NIMs in providing consultancy and following cases through legal processes. Ministry of Justice representatives also held a meeting with the president of UTBA for future collaborations about violence against women. In line with these developments, a circular devoted to the prevention of gender-based violence was published by the Ministry of Justice. According to the circular, &quot;Domestic and Gender-based Violence Offices&quot; will be operational nationwide and specialized prosecutors will be designated for specific cases. A similar circular has also been issued by the Ministry of Interior, mentioning that vocational trainings will be conducted for law enforcement and related staff. Ministry of Interior also aims to expand its cooperation in the area of violence against women. This development maybe overshadowed by the new amendments on the Law of Attorneys where a tension between bar associatons and the government is high.
This current project is a continuation of a previous project Support to the Improvement of Legal Aid Practices PLANit:55020276. Certain outputs of the previous project was included in in the scope of 2 communication campaigns of the UNDP Communications Team, Phase I project has been included as success stories within the reporting period. The first campaign was &#x201C;Space4Life&#x201D;: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qj_73VpVCog and the second one was &#x201C;Happiness Is&#x201D;: https://bencemutluluk.undp.org.tr/nurettin-kilic-mardin/ .</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12308" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
