<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12479A0101-TUR-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till &quot;Vote and Beyond&quot; F&#xF6;nening</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to &quot;Vote and Beyond&quot; Association</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet med bidraget &#xE4;r att &#xF6;vervaka president- och parlamentsvalet den 24 juni 2018 f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerhetsst&#xE4;lla r&#xE4;ttvisa och fria val. Bidraget best&#xE5;r av f&#xF6;ljande tre delar: &#x201D;Samordning, utbildning och utplacering av frivilliga observat&#xF6;rer&#x201D;; &#x201D;&#xF6;ka medvetenhet om val- och medborgarr&#xE4;ttigheter&#x201D; och &#x201D;utveckling och underh&#xE5;ll av IT-verktyg f&#xF6;r online observation av valresultat via T3-program och mobilapplikationer&#x201D;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the contribution is to monitor the presidential and general elections on 24 June 2018  in order to secure fair and free elections. &quot;Coordination, training and deployment of volunteer observers&quot;; &quot;Awareness Raising on Electoral and Citizen Rights and Training&quot;; and &quot;Development and Maintenance of IT Tools for Electronic Observation of Election Results through T3 software and mobile application&quot; are the three components of the contribution.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oy Ve &#xD6;tesi Dernegi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oy Ve &#xD6;tesi Dernegi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">55664.8715824358</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">55664.8715824358</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-3180.4481857888</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-31">55664.871582</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">55664.8715824358</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">-3180.4217472689</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pre-Election Day? The online training materials prepared for the observers and voters in order to contribute to the Election Day has been watched approximately 350,000 times.? From the date of he registry, their website was visited 1,700,000 times.? In 4 weeks, Vote and Beyond performed over 200 face to face training sessions in all regions.? Vote and Beyond received over 50,000 voluntary applications within 24 days of the date the registry.? &#x201C;T3 Send Report&#x201D; mobile application, which was developed to facilitate the collection of data in 2017 improved with new features like &quot;Count Vote&quot;, &quot;Process Control&quot;, &quot;Election Information Bank&quot;, allowed voters and observers to access all the tools and information they could need throughout the day.
Election Day? On the day of June 24, approximately 40,000 of our volunteers, along with nearly 1,000 attorneys, were at the ballot boxes in 81 provinces as observers of a political party they preferred.? The mobile application &#x201C;T3 Send Report&#x201D; was downloaded by 138,000 people in 7 days and used by 122,000 people on the day of the election.
Cooperation with Turkey Bar Association and the Call CenterOn June 24th, starting at 06.30, approximately 2.000 calls was made throughout the day to the call center in which Vote and Beyond volunteer attorneys and Turkey Bar Association started working. The subject calls were given legal support, and most of the information about the cases which were transmitted during the calls was recorded. Within the scope of the June 24th elections, more than 20 judicial cases were reported in which Vote and Beyond volunteers were included as witness/subject/suspect. Vote and Beyond received complaints that over 50 of our volunteers at the ballot box were subjected to beatings, mistreatment, threat or defamation.
Online Survey Among Volunteers of Vote and Beyond:On the day of June 24, at 16.00 (when the counting process has not been started yet) 17.093 persons (92,18%) out of 18.543 answering the survey via &#x201C;T3 Send Record&#x201D; application stated that everything was fine in their ballot boxes; while 1389 persons (7,49%) stated that the representation of the parties was insufficient in the balloting committee, On 756 of them (4.08%) felt that they were oppressed but continued to serve their duties, and 427 (2.3%) were distracted from the ballot box due to pressure and uneasiness
Use of T3:
Turkey Record Confirmation (&#x201C;T3&#x201D;) is a software that enables the photographs by our volunteers as a result of entering into the system of numerical data on past ballot box results and the comparison with the Supreme Election Board data for these numerical data and helping the detection of differences between them.150,546 to the Presidential election and 133,898 to the parliamentary general election; a total of 284,444 photos from 81 provinces were uploaded to the T3 system via mobile application &quot;T3 Send Record&quot; by Vote and Beyond volunteers. The number of single records Vote and Beyond has received after all the repeating records are separated; 65.254 were for the presidential election and 63.178 for the parliamentary general election
Record Confirmation:
The ultimate aim of Vote and Beyond is to make record confirmation, that is comparing the numerical data on the records of the ballot box with the numerical data of the Supreme Election Board and reporting if there are any inconsistencies. Record confirmation of Vote and Beyond confirms the following findings:
The inconsistencies that have so far been confirmed as a result of confirmation within the T3 system as a total of 180,065 ballot boxes established within the country, 49,415 (27,4%) for the presidential election and 51,631 (28,7%) for the parliamentary general election are as follows:
? Inconsistency was found in the distribution of 7.402 votes used in the 194 ballot boxes for the Presidential election.This effect when proportioned to the number of total valid votes throughout Turkey is 0,015%.
? For the parliamentary general election, in 1,110 ballot boxes with 80,019 inconsistencies were detected. This effect when proportioned to the number of total valid votes throughout Turkey is 0,16%.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12479" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
