<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11312A0101-TUR-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till Centre for Economics and Foreign Policy Studies EDAM 2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Centre for Economics and Foreign Policy Studies EDAM 2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den planerade utvecklingsinsatsen syftar till att st&#xF6;tta oberoende informationsspridning i Turkiet f&#xF6;r att bidra till en mer pluralistisk s&#xE5;dan. P&#xE5; s&#xE5; vis ses insatsen vara ett st&#xF6;d till &#xF6;kad yttrandefrihet och ambassaden bed&#xF6;mer att insatsen p&#xE5; sikt kan bidra till &#xF6;kat ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande g&#xE4;llande yttrandefrihet p&#xE5; n&#xE4;tet och demokrati. Det planerade svenska st&#xF6;det till Centre for Economics and Foreign Policy Studies (EDAM) bereds som ett projektst&#xF6;d utifr&#xE5;n syftet att st&#xF6;tta organisationens k&#xE4;rnverksamhet s&#xE5; att den kan fortl&#xF6;pa under r&#xE5;dande omst&#xE4;ndigheter.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The planned contribution aims to support dissemination of independent information in Turkey to enable a pluralistic environment of available independent information. The contribution is therefore supporting freedom of expression and the Embassy assesses that it in time can contribute to increased accountability regarding freedom of expression on-line and democracy. The planned Swedish support to Centre for Economics and Foreign Policy Studies (EDAM) is made through a project-grant with the aim to support EDAM&#x2019;s core activities so that the think tank can continue to undertake its work under the current circumstances.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EDAM/Centre for Economics and Foreign Policy Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">58902.5389025389</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">58902.5389025389</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-5429.414439662</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-04">58902.538902</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">58902.5389025389</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">-5429.414439662</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project year was going to cover the completion of two streams of research studies, one on multilateralism, the other on internet freedoms. The third stream is a roundtable event called Bodrum Roundtable which is a forum to discuss global and Turkish foreign policy challenges with distinguished guests and experts.
Multilateralism and Global Governance: The Turkish View
The research project aimed to examine how various parts of the Turkish society view global challenges, gauge the awareness about the role of multilateral institutions and evaluate the proclivity for Turkey to support the work of these institutions as well as clarify the public linked barriers to such an engagement. A related objective was to assess the motivation for and the public support for unilateral as opposed to multilateral diplomacy. As part of this aim, the perception of specific global and regional multilateral institutions were examined.
The project focused on five different areas of global governance, Namely:
1. Global economy (IMF, World Bank, WTO, Black Sea Economic Cooperation);2. Security (NATO, SCO, OSCE, UN, NPT); 3. Climate change;4. Cyber space (i.e. censorship, surveillance), and 5. International institutions and international law (EU, UN, Council of Europe).
B. Surveillance and Freedom of Expression Online: Finding the Appropriate Balance in Democratic Countries
EDAM&#x2019;s research project seeked to produce a detailed, analytical and evidence-based report that comprises of a set of policy recommendations for Turkish policy makers. The report contributed to a better understanding of the legal and regulatory safeguards of democratic countries that limit their surveillance powers in the digital arena; discussed what priorities (i.e. national security) may interfere with and restrict freedom of expression online and whether these comply with the fundamental principles of legality, proportionality and necessity; explored existing national and international institutions that oversee and review those bodies involved in online surveillance operations and whether they are properly resourced (i.e. oversight/vision, personnel capacity, financial solvency).
C. The EDAM Bodrum Roundtable
The EDAM Bodrum Roundtable is an annual international conference for opinion leaders that is held in Bodrum, a resort area along the Aegean coast of Turkey. The Roundtable was first launched in 2005 with the idea of establishing an effective and continuing high-level network where issues of common concern to Turkey and its transatlantic partners can be discussed. The Roundtable brings European and US opinion makers from politics, civil society, academia, media and the business world together with their Turkish counterparts and facilitates an open and frank discussion on topics that are vital to shaping the future transatlantic agenda. The twelve meetings between 2005 and 2016 have contributed to this objective. In fact, according to the recently released global think tank rankings by the University of Pennsylvania, EDAM&#x2019;s Bodrum Roundtable has been ranked as the 9th best think tank event in the world.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11312" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
