<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12308A0102-TUR-15130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal Aid Practices  (UNDP) 2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">R&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lpspraxis (UNDP) 2019-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet med insatser &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka kvalit&#xE9; och tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp i Turkiet genom att utveckla samordnning, kvalit&#xE9; och systematik i praxis f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp. UNDP blir avtalspart till Sida och ansvarig f&#xF6;r projektledning och samordning. Federationen f&#xF6;r tuskiska advokatsamfund &#xE4;r huvudsaklig genomf&#xF6;rare. Insatwsen har utformats i konsultatin med Justitieministeriet och ministeriet kommer att vara delaktig under genomf&#xF6;randet. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade resultat &#xE4;r f&#xF6;ljande;  

Samordning: &#xD6;ka samordning och samarbete mellan enskilda organisationer, advokater och advokatsamfund i tillhandah&#xE5;llandet av r&#xE4;tthj&#xE4;lp,
Systematisk ansats: Sprida erfarenheterna fr&#xE5;n Ankaras advokatsamfund s.k. &quot;Poppy centers  (center f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga konsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld och tillhanda r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp till som blivit offer f&#xF6;r s&#xE5;dant v&#xE5;ld)genom 7 andra advokatsamfund i Turkiet 
- Kapacitetsutveckling: St&#xF6;dja fortsatt kapacitetsutveckling av advokater som levererar r&#xE4;ttshj&#xE4;lp via en webportal f&#xF6;r on-line utbildning 
- &#xD6;kad medvetenhet bland advokatsamfund i Turkiet kring operationalisering av ett system f&#xF6;r prestationsbaserad uppf&#xF6;ljning och system f&#xF6;r att anvisa r&#xE4;ttsfall till advokater</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the contribution is to enhance the quality and access to legal aid services in Turkey through the development of more coordinated, qualified and systematic approach into legal aid practices. UNDP will be the contract partner to Sida and ensure overall project management and coordination. The Union of Turkish Bar Association is the main implementing partner. The contribution has been designed in consultation with the Ministry of Justice and the Ministry will be involved throughuout implementation. The objectives can be summarised below: 

- Coordination: enhance coordination between NGO&#x2019;s, lawyers and bar associations in legal aid provision,
- Systematic Approach: instrumentalise Ankara Bar Association&#x2019;s Poppy Practices (violence prevention centers where legal aid is supplied to persons inflicted with GBV) in 7 Bar Associations in Turkey,  
- Capacity Development: further support capacity building of lawyers providing legal-aid via an online training portal,
- Awareness Raising among bar associations in Turkey for operationalization of performance management tools and automation system of CCP lawyers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The theory of change for the intervention is to further enhance the quality and access to legal aid services in Turkey through the development of more coordinated, qualified and systematic approach into legal aid practices. The approach is developed to enhabce coordination between bars and CSOs and supply information on legal aid to citizens and to seek opportunities to work on legal aid.&#xA0;It will establish violence prevention centers to supply legal aid services for&#xA0;vulnerable persons. It is foreseen that CSOs will direct vulnerble persons to these centers. Efforts to enhance the capacities of lawyers on vulnerable persons and well being of the lawyer&#xA0;will carry on with online training.&#xA0;Build awareness on the operationalization of performance management tools and mechanisms will help to establish&#xA0;a more standardised and sytematic legal aid practices to&#xA0;improve access to justice.
Outcomes:
- Coordination: enhance coordination between NGO&#x2019;s, lawyers and bar associations in legal aid provision,
- Systematic Approach: establish Ankara Bar Association&#x2019;s Poppy centers(violence prevention centers where legal aid is supplied to persons inflicted with GBV) in 7 Bar Associations in Turkey,
- Capacity Development: further support capacity building of lawyers providing legal-aid via an online training portal,
- Awareness Raising among bar associations in Turkey for operationalization of performance management tools and automation system of CCP lawyers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.1 - Avsev&#xE4;rt minska alla former av v&#xE5;ld och d&#xF6;dligt v&#xE5;ld &#xF6;verallt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.1 - Significantly reduce all forms of violence and related death rates everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/12308_12308amendmenttothebudget.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12308 Legal Aid Project Amendment to the Budget</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/12308_12308signedagreementwithUNDP.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12308 Legal Aid Project Signed Agreement with UNDP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/12308_Beslutominsats(12308).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12308 Decision on Contribution for Legal Aid Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The dialogue with project partner UNDP and the beneficiary UTBA and cooperating partner MoJ General Directorate of Criminal Affairs is still at a very good level. Deliberations are made in accordance with trust that has been established in 5 years of working together. Each discussion to the contribution is made openly and with a focus of obtaining results. Ownership of our partners is high. The pandemic had effect in the implementation. Although desktop work was done and trainings were completed online its affects on the bar elections and making the Victims of Violence Support Centers (VVSC) [The name of the centers was changed from the previous Violence Prevention Centers in due course] ready was major leading to postponements. While the partners adhere sturdily to the project documentation of outputs and activities Sida encourages them to diversify further outputs and activities and show adaptive management in order to achieve more in the result areas.

To this end in scope of the first outcome enhance coordination between NGOs, lawyers and bar associations in legal aid provision, although a meeting was held with a diverse number of CSOs, Sida has asked UNDP to further hold meetings with Sida partners that work on gender issues and VAW. Furthermore in order to further enhance coordination between CSOs and VVSC that will be set up in the Bars the parties have come to an understanding to hold more activities. Sida also asked for the collaboration between UN agencies like UN Women, UNHCR and UNICEF. This will be closely monitored.

VVSC has been established in Antalya, Balkesir, Denizli, Mardin, Rize, Samsun are all ready to start functioning. Only problem was with Nevsehir since a premises could not be found despite dialogue with bar, municipality and governate. UNDP has stated in a meeting that two rooms have been supplied to VVSC in the Governate with the efforts of UTBA, the rooms are being assessed. The parties have decide to hold an opening ceremony for the launch of VVSC however this was postponed several times due to the pandemic and as an effect the elections of the bars were postponed, which are now completed as of this day. There were changes to the head of Bars in Denizli and Nevsehir. Currently the focal points are the same but as the elections have been held recently these may be affected by the change. The UTBA elections are expected to take place at the first week of December and UTBA has asked for the launched of the event to be postponed to a date after the elections. It is expected that Nevsehir VVSC will also be ready until the launch event. Apart from the general opening launch UTBA is keen to hold opening ceremonies in each bar location. It was discussed with UNDP and UTBA that the campaigning materials should be ready for these events. UNDP has delivered a campaign plan and stated that they are working on the campaign material to be ready for the launch. It was suggested by Sida that UNDP makes use of their Gender Equality Advocates for the campaign and Goodwill Ambassador that are public figures. The trainings of TOT for the VVSC has been undertaken as per the previous reporting period. The important matter is to monitor the functioning of these VVSC. Due to the reasons explained above as the opening and functioning of VVSC were postponed it was thought that the period for the contribution will run out. Due to Covid as the budgetary amounts were not spent UNDP is considering an extension in the contribution which will also allow for a better monitoring of the functioning of the VVSC. Operationalisation of performance management tools foreseen as Outcome 4 will be utilised here in the VVSC. The performance will be based on the files that are addressed in the VVSC.

Capacity Development: further support capacity building of lawyers providing legal aid via an online training portal, is ongoing. The ToR for the tender to supply the services was shared with Sida. The tender process is coming to an end and implementation is expected to be picked up. A Needs Assessment for the portal was performed and 5 important issues H

- Foundations of human rights

- Notions of legal profession

- Practical internet applications for lawyers

- Effective advocacy in practice

- Basic accounting, financial literacy and office management for lawyers

 was identified.

The study tours is still in discussion due to the pandemic. The partners will decide whether to do the visits or utilise the money for other outcomes.

UNDP is also implementing a VAW project. With outcomes identified as: Recommendations report produced for strengthening VAW response mechanisms, Capacities of CSOs which provide tailored services to VAW survivors developed, Raising Awareness of Justice Actors in relation to Supported Bar Associations to Improve Current Violence Against Women Mechanisms and Legal Aid Service Provision and Coordination, Bar Associations Supported for Improved Legal Aid Service Delivery and Coordination. A briefing was given on the project to the PO and the gender focal point. As seen the VAW project is closely interlinked with ILAP and both is expected to feed into each other.  

An evaluation was performed by UNDP. A meeting was expected to be held to discuss the findings of the report however UNDP has not set up a meeting as the findings was rejected by UTBA and MoJ indicating that there are major mistakes. Sida will follow up on the final report.

Turkeys withdrawal from the Istanbul Convention has had effects on the project as the public authorities working on the subject of VAW in order to further make use of the local legislation has shown more interest to the project outcomes especially on VVSC. MoJ, General Directorate of Criminal Affairs, Department of Victim Rights Unit have been opening up both Judicial Support Centers (ADM) and Judicial Interview Rooms (AGO) which will serve people seeking legal aid and justice. To this end, UTBA representatives have met with Ministry of Family, Labour and Social Services and the Ministry of Interior and have supplied information on project goals. It has also been stated by the UTBA representatives that the Minister of Justice has expressed its intention to further expand the VVSC in other bars.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12308" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
