<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5502009302-TUR-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till kvinnors politiska deltagande i Turkiet</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to women&apos;s political participation Turkey</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the KA.DER Project &#x201C;Increasing the Number of Women with Gender Awareness Who Are Appointed or Elected in All Decision Making Processes Program&#x201D; supported by SIDA is to ensure equal representation of women and men in all fields of life and especially equal representation in all elected and appointed decision-making positions. The project aims at increasing the number of women in decision-making positions, with a focus on political parties. The idea is that such change would happen through influencing the practices of political parties, empowering women candidates, influencing legislation, making the public more gender aware - and strengthening KA.DER as an influential organization.&#xA0;&#xA0; 
The completion date of the project was 31st of March 2018. The project received nt is a cost extension to extend the implementation of the Project until December 31, 2018 with additional funds amounting to 1650000 SEK. 
The extension period covers the below results/activities:
1) Strengthening the organization&#x2019;s internal structures 
2) KA.DERs&#x2019; core activities: Political Schools, Campaign, Lobbying &amp; Advocacy
3) Strengthening Woman in Local Politics: Women Muhtars Project</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet syftar till att ge st&#xF6;d &#xE5;t kvinnor som deltar i den         turkiska politiken samt verka f&#xF6;r fler kvinnor inom beslutsfattande   mekanismer. KA.DERs arbete best&#xE5;r bl.a. i att anordna utbildningar i  politiskt deltagande med ett j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsperspektiv, d&#xE4;r kvinnor     fr&#xE5;n olika politiska partier deltar. KA.DER &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; del av ett       n&#xE4;tverk som lobbar mot diskriminerande lagstiftning i Turkiet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support women in their participation in politics  as well as lobbying for more women in decision-making mechanisms.     KA.DER organizes political schools with a gender equality perspective where women from different political parties participate. KA.DER is   also part of wider networks that lobby towards reforms of             discriminating laws and policies in Turkey.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dev. country based NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kader Kadin Adaylari Destekleme Dernegi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">47453.5252037536</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">46438.2570320193</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-01">61413.744395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">14236.0575611261</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">32202.1626944112</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This section will assess the full agreement period in two terms as per the results; 2013-2016 and 2017-2019.
2013-2016
It can be concluded that Kader only reached the expected outcomes to a small extent during this period. As the evaluation has mentioned the effectiveness and efficiency of the programme has been limited. This was mainly due to unfavourable contextual developments, gaps in Kader&#x2019;s strategic approaches and limited learning and revision of approaches and management and governance problems.&#xA0;
During this period Kader has not been able to achieve its results and it is assessed that there has been serious deviation from plan almost at every outcome. The reasons behind this has been discussed in the previous statements.
During this period Sida has seen that Kader has gone through severe internal conflicts and unrest (among the staff as well) and had failed to reach consensus at several occasions. This and many other issues have led KADER to lose its capacity to run itself effectively and therefore has fallen behind the activity schedule and almost no progress has been achieved in the project period between 2013-2016. It has also been seen that there was no organizational memory within the association as no systems had been established for that. All the above and more have resulted in the Sida funds being used in a very ineffective way.
Nevertheless, some of the activities have still taken place such as ToTs, internal meetings, campaigns, advocacy and lobbying activities and such. However, these have not made it possible to say that the results have been achieved. There have been also many activities that the project could not realise. Also, the recommendations of the evaluation made by Sida at the end of 2015 has helped Kader to focus on the improvements needed afterwards.
As per the main outcomes, increased participation of women in national and local politics for instance, it is seen that the outreach to the potential candidates has been very limited. Apart from the political schools there has been limited support to women candidates. Kader has realised well designed media campaigns ahead of the local and national elections. However no concrete results have been observed. Kader&apos;s work during this project period has been severely hampered by the internal and external conflict within the political arena. This has been the same for the legislation and policy work. The external environment made it impossible for any NGO to improve legislations and influence policy making. Yet, most of the focus of the women&#x2019;s movement has been on stopping negative developments. However, Kader has continued to work on raising awareness on the topic anyway.
At the organisational level, as mentioned before, Kader&apos;s board had faced many challenges during this period. Different fractures within Kader attempted to gain power and control over the administration several times and hampered the work to be carried out in order to change the board through extraordinary board meetings. This chaos led the organisation to not to be able strengthen its organisational structure and the target to become a more transparent and democratic organisation.
By the end of the initial agreement period the negativities and the downward trend have resulted in the rejection of a new term proposal for 2017-2018 period by Sida. Instead Sida has decided to make an amendment with additional funds to the current agreement for one more year. The aim was to enable Kader to implement all recommendations from the evaluation and raise funds from other donors as well as re-visit the organisations vision and mission. At that time the amended agreement was designed as a phase out support. It was decided that a new proposal by the end of the agreement could be considered if a significant improvement had been achieved.
2017-2019
The period April 2017- February 2019 has been an extension(2 cost extensions) provided after the refusal of a new term project. The reporting at that time therefore provides information on the activities realised in line with the cost extension periods&#x2019; activity plans. The reporting has been activity and output based rather than outcomes as before.
The first cost extension period(April 2017-March 2018) was mostly about strengthening the internal structure of the association as well as help them run their basic activities that are within the basic mandates of the association and therefore it was not expected to reach outcome level changes.
Kader has done some important work on their internal management systems which were lacking and somewhat inefficient in line with the recommendations of the evaluation that has been realised in 2015. The board has become more active and had an improved understanding of the project and its implementation. The strategy for 2018-2020 produced has been one of the most important outputs. These studies have also caused the NGO to have an increased solidarity between the members and the board and an increase in the efficiency has been also observed.
The new management has been also very active and willing to realise the activities designed for this period. Networking efforts are observed to be worthwhile. They have managed to reach the conservative and government supporting groups, increased cooperation with universities, INGOs, local governments. They have also run campaigns during the national election, which required an extensive amount of work. During this time, they have also continued their basic activities such as political schools which was important for the election period for the women to be empowered. In addition to these Kader increased their in-kind contributions as well as other sources of funding as suggested by Sida. This has been found to be a very important improvement. It is possible to say that Kader has managed to build itself up in a very steep and positive trend.
After the assessment made by Sida it has been decided that Kader has effectively utilized the funds provided through the cost extension. Upon this it has been decided to extend the support to Kader for another year (March 2018-February 2019) with the purpose of supporting the upcoming local and national elections, main Kader activities as well as Kader to draft a new project proposal for 2019-2021 for Sida.
The most important outcome o this period was the proposal for a new term which has been accepted by Sida for 2019-2021 period. Other than this the activities have been realised as agreed. During this period Kader continued to work on strengthening its internal structure. Some amendments to the bylaws have been realised, increased participation and involvement of the members and branches have been attained, the organisation increased their relations with young volunteer women.
Kader, under its core work areas, continued lobbying and advocating through increased publicity and promotion of Kader and its work in the media and the social media. It is observed by Sida that Kader has significantly increased its relations with international partners, other NGOs and the political parties. Kader also realised a national campaign for the March 2019 elections as aimed. Kader&#x2019;s political schools have been also organised in this period and a total of 125 women have been trained for the March 2019 local elections. Another important activity has been the women mukhtars training in 7 cities for the local election in 2019 and more than 500 women has been reached and trained through this activity.
Kader also has very well responded to Sida&#x2019;s suggestion of diversification of Kader&#x2019;s funders and received funds from different sources for some of their projects developed outside the Sida programme.
With respect to the activities realised, the reports show that Kader has managed to realise what has been expected and has achieved beyond within some of the particular areas it works on. However the quality of teh report still needs imrpvement. It is still possible to say that Kader is going through a period of amelioration and this is expected to continue in the new period as well.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55020093" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
