<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11748A0102-TUR-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ILO &apos;Fler och B&#xE4;ttre Jobb f&#xF6;r Kvinnor&apos; Andra Fasen</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO &apos;More and Better Jobs for Women&apos; Second Phase</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO has applied to Sida for funding of 30 million SEK to carry out the &quot;More and Better Jobs for Women: Women&#x2019;s Empowerment through Decent Work in Turkey&quot; during the period 2019-2022. 

The intervention aims at improving the employment chances of women in Turkey via two components with the following objectives:

Component I: &#x201C;More and Better Work Opportunities for Women Job-seekers in the pilot provinces&#x201D; which aims to ensure that the National Action Plan (NAP) and Local Action Plans (LAP) on Women&#x2019;s Employment effectively implemented and monitored;
Component II: &#x201C;Improving Working Conditions for Women in the piloted sectors&#x201D; which aims to that measures for decent working conditions for women (special focus given to gender pay gap, gender-based violence at workplace, work and life balance and women&#x2019;s leadership) adopted and implemented by Director-General of Labour, the constituents and by pilot enterprises.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 30 million SEK which is financed by Sida solely.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Internationella arbetsorganisationen, ILO, har ans&#xF6;kt om Sida-finansiering p&#xE5; 30 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r sitt projekt &#x201D;Fler och b&#xE4;ttre jobb f&#xF6;r kvinnor: en f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning av kvinnors situation i Turkiet&#x201D;, andra fasen, f&#xF6;r perioden 1 januari 2019 till 31 december 2022. 

Projektet best&#xE5;r av tv&#xE5; delar och syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kvinnors arbetsvillkor i Turkiet. Den f&#xF6;rsta delen; &#x201D;Fler och b&#xE4;ttre arbetstillf&#xE4;llen f&#xF6;r kvinnliga arbetss&#xF6;kande i utvalda pilotprovinser&#x201D;, syftar till att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att landsplanen (National Action Plan, NAP) och de lokala planerna (Local Action Plans, LAP) f&#xF6;r kvinnors arbetssituation implementeras och f&#xF6;ljs upp. 

Den andra delen; &#x201D;F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade arbetsvillkor f&#xF6;r kvinnor i utvalda pilotprovinser&#x201D;, syftar till att inf&#xF6;ra mekanismer f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade arbetsvillkor f&#xF6;r kvinnor. Detta innefattar att minska l&#xF6;negapet mellan m&#xE4;n och kvinnor, f&#xF6;rhindra v&#xE5;ld p&#xE5; arbetsplatsen, g&#xF6;ra det l&#xE4;ttare f&#xF6;r kvinnor att balansera arbete och andra &#xE5;taganden s&#xE5;som familj, samt att fr&#xE4;mja kvinnligt ledarskap.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the Project for Promoting Decent Work for Women in Turkey is to increase the number of women working under decent conditions in Turkey. The Project has two components with specific aims:
Component I: &#x201C;More and Better Work Opportunities for Women Job-seekers in the pilot provinces&#x201D; which aims to ensure that the National Action Plan (NAP) and Local Action Plans (LAP) on Women&#x2019;s Employment effectively implemented and monitored;
Component II: &#x201C;Improving Working Conditions for Women in the piloted sectors&#x201D; which aims to that measures for decent working conditions for women (special focus given to gender pay gap, gender-based violence at workplace, work and life balance and women&#x2019;s leadership) adopted and implemented by Director-General of Labour, the constituents and by pilot enterprises.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41144" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO/International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41144" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO/International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.4 - Erk&#xE4;nna och v&#xE4;rdes&#xE4;tta obetalt omsorgs- och hush&#xE5;llsarbete genom att tillhandah&#xE5;lla offentliga tj&#xE4;nster, infrastruktur och socialt skydd samt genom att fr&#xE4;mja delat ansvar inom hush&#xE5;llet och familjen, i enlighet med vad som &#xE4;r nationellt l&#xE4;mpligt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.4 - Recognize and value unpaid care and domestic work through the provision of public services, infrastructure and social protection policies and the promotion of shared responsibility within the household and the family as nationally appropriate.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">217162.339707048</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-26">230139.003958</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/11748_SIDA_ILOagreement_2ndphase.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO More and Better Jobs for Women Second Phase agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/turkey/11748_BeslutominsatsILOflerochbattrejobbforkvinnor.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On an overall level this was the first year of the implementation of the project and was an intense one. The activities were rather related to building up and strengthening relationships with the old and new partners as well as laying the foundations of the project. The activity year has focussed on setting up of teams and networks, establishing and formalising partnerships, formulation of activity plans, road maps for partners and a monitoring framework for the project, trainings, meetings, gender analysis for partners, communication, advocacy, etc.
The project has not produced any of the outcomes yet as this is still very early times of the implementation. However, both of the outcomes will be assessed in terms of what has been achieved.
Outcome 1
This outcome has three outputs, (i) Technical capacity of ISKUR enhanced on a) gender-responsive employment services, b) advocacy skills; c) results-based management approach; (ii) The results-based monitoring framework in place and operational for NAP and LAPs on Women&#x2019;s Employment through social dialogue practices; and finally (iii) The implementation of NAP and LAPs supported though piloting of gender-responsive ALMPs. The progress under this outcome is assessed to be rather at output level in the first year of the project.
In order to reach these outputs a Cooperation Protocol for project implementation has been signed between ILO and ISKUR that aims to ensure ownership and leadership of ISKUR for results achievement. The Protocol defines mutual duties and responsibilities to achieve results, as well as the detailed activity plan was signed between ILO and ISKUR on 17 September 2019. Additionally, ISKUR Project Monitoring Committee that was composed of representatives of ISKUR General Directorate and provincial managers and Gender Focal Points at the pilot provinces has been established in order to provide a smooth and concrete management of the project. Sida assesses that this is a rather crucial step to keep ISKUR accountable for their commitment hence, it has been observed by Sida that ISKUR has been highly committed in terms of the project implementation.
In order to improve the NAP/LAPs on Women&#x2019;s Employment (from the first phase of the project) efforts have been initiated to include &#x201C;SMART&#x201D; targets and indicators. Additionally, capacity and needs assessment exercises has been conducted on result-based management, targeting ISKUR and national and provincial technical teams to revise their action plans.
As an unintended positive effect Ordu has requested to become a pilot city for the project and has been accepted by ISKUR.
However, it is reported by ILO that output 1.2 and 1.3 on &#x201C;The result based monitoring framework in place and operational for the NAP and LAPs on Women&#x2019;s Employment through social dialogue practices&#x201D; and &#x201C;The implementation of the NAP and LAPs supported though piloting of gender sensitive Active Labour Market Programmes (ALMPs)&#x201D; are delayed.
Outcome 2
The progress under this outcome is also assessed to be rather at output level in the first year of the project.
An important activity was the capacity and need assessment studies, which have been initiated at 16 trade unions, 3 employer organizations, 3 worker confederations, and an employer confederation as well as a government institution. ILO Participatory Gender Audit methodology has been used to make the capacity and need assessment as well as identify the entry points for each institution. ILO PGA is the first time implemented in the tripartite structure in the world with participation of the workers and employers&#x2019; organisations and the public institutions and assessed to be worthwhile to mention here.
In order to improve gender equality at pilot enterprises Enterprise Development Teams have been established in 4 SMEs and one big enterprise, where women workers have been involved in the process. The Plans that were developed for each enterprise comprised of measures to improve the decent work conditions of women. This reporting period mostly concentrated on revising and implementing the model in different sectors and develop strategic partnerships and scales to accumulate the experiences and needs, which will set the baseline for advocacy and guidance for better legislation and regulations. This pilot implementation at private sector has received a significant attention and some other big enterprises also requested to implement the model such as Ege Business People Association, Marks and Spencer, Primark, INDITEX, H&amp;M, Varner Group, ENERJISA and several other stakeholders and companies contacted the project to develop partnerships.
On the legislative work ILO aims to contribute to revision of legislation for smoothing establishment of women cooperatives as it is intended in the 11th Development Plan.
The project also established strategic partnerships with TURSTAT for gender pay gap and cooperation with European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) for reconciling work life balance. Additionally, the project contributed to the improvement of knowledge and awareness of key actors on GPG, its reasons and consequences.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11748" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
