<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012397-01-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Palestine refugees in Syria through health and protection services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;intervento proposto rientra nell&#x2019;obiettivo strategico 2 dell&#x2019;Appello di Emergenza di UNRWA: Contribuire a un ambiente protettivo per i rifugiati palestinesi mantenendo l&apos;accesso ai servizi di base. L&#x2019;intervento mira a fornire assistenza umanitaria attraverso la fornitura di servizi sanitari primari, secondari e terziari in 25 dei centri sanitari di UNRWA, incluse due cliniche mobili, attraverso la copertura dei costi di ricoveri e la fornitura di sussidi ai pazienti in ospedali convenzionati, nonch&#xE9; ad estendere i servizi di sensibilizzazione e tutela della protezione attraverso varie attivit&#xE0;. L&#x2019;Iniziativa si articola attraverso 2 componenti: 1. Salute - Fornitura di Servizi sanitari ai rifugiati palestinesi; 2. Tutela della Protezione - Assistenza per la tutela della protezione e maggiore consapevolezza della tutela della propria protezione per i rifugiati palestinesi in Siria. Il Programma si rivolge a circa 35.380 rifugiati palestinesi per la componente sulla tutela della protezione e coprir&#xE0; 810.000 consulenze di assistenza sanitaria di base per la componente sulla salute.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project falls into the following UNRWA Emergency Appeal Strategic priority 2: contribute to a protective environment for Palestine refugees by maintaining access to basic services. This project aims to provide primary, secondary and tertiary health care services and undertake interventions to meet some of the most acute health and protection needs faced by the Palestine refugee community. UNRWA will be able to maintain the provision of primary health care services in its 25 health facilities, including two mobile clinics, through the coverage of 60 health staff for 11 months. The 60 health staff are frontline workers directly involved in service delivery. In addition, UNRWA will reimburse hospitalisation referral costs and subsidize patient treatment for secondary and tertiary care, for a total of about 410 cases. Additionally, 35,850 Palestine refugees and UNRWA staff will be provided with protection-related awareness and/or interventions, including: 4,000 Palestine refugees will be supported with legal assistance interventions; 840 Palestine refugees will participate in disability inclusion and awareness activities; 4,260 Palestine refugees will be provided with PSS support; 26,350 Palestine refugees will be provided with ERW awareness; 400 UNRWA staff and volunteers will be provided with protection training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41130" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41130" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41130" ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA - AGENZIA NAZIONI UNITE ASSISTENZA E RICOSTRUZ. A FAVORE RIFUGIATI PALESTINA VICINO ORIENTE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012397/01/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End poverty in all its forms everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implement nationally appropriate social protection systems and measures for all, including floors, and by 2030 achieve substantial coverage of the poor and the vulnerable</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-04">1000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA - AGENZIA NAZIONI UNITE ASSISTENZA E RICOSTRUZ. A FAVORE RIFUGIATI PALESTINA VICINO ORIENTE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-15">1000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA - AGENZIA NAZIONI UNITE ASSISTENZA E RICOSTRUZ. A FAVORE RIFUGIATI PALESTINA VICINO ORIENTE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
