<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-29105</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achmmach  Tin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although Morocco has considerable mineral resources, the mining sector in Morocco has been dominated by the Government of Morocco with primary focus on phosphate rock. Current Government policies and incentives aims to diversify and grow its mineral industry and attract foreign direct investment. A few international junior mining companies have started exploration programs in the country.  A successful exploration program by Kasbah would have notable demonstration effect and help establish mining as an attractive sector for private investors, supporting/promoting sustainable resource development and economic growth through infrastructure development and employment generation.

The Project is in an early exploration phase so its developmental impacts are limited in scope at this stage. However, the project is located in an under-developed part (IFC Frontier region) of the country and outside of key centers of commercial activity and will likely contribute significantly to the areas development should it transition into a full operating mine through generation of employment, improved infrastructure access, local economic development through purchased of local goods and services and payments to government in the form of royalties and taxes.

During the early exploration phase the key impacts to monitor will include: (i) finalization of drilling program, completion of the feasibility study and acquisition of mining license; (ii) number of local employees; and (iii) completion of Social and Environmental Impact Assessment (SEIA).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasbah Resources Limited (Kasbah, or the Company) objective is to build a successful Moroccan focused exploration and mining company.  The Companys prime exploration target is the hard rock Achmmach Tin prospect, located on the western edge of the El Hajeb province in Morocco, 110 km southeast of Rabat and 40km southwest of Meknes. Kasbah currently has an exclusive option to acquire 100% interest of the Achmmach Project from the Office National des Hydrocarbures et des Mines (ONHYM) upon the completion of a positive feasibility study by June 2011. ONHYM is Government of Moroccos (GoMs) regulatory body responsible for the exploration and promotion of national mineral and energy resources.

In December 2008, Kasbah announced a Joint Ore Reserve Committee Code (JORC) inferred resource of 6 million tonnes at 0.9% tin grade containing 52,000 tonnes of metal. It is Kasbahs intent to increase the JORC resources and progress Achmmach to the development phase.  As a result, Kasbah is seeking IFCs engagement as a strategic partner to help develop the Achmmach project in line with industry best practice in environmental and social sustainability.

IFCs investment will support: (i) underground drilling and exploration, (ii) feasibility studies and environmental and social impact assessments; and (iii) general exploration and working capital purposes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KASBAH RESOURCES LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-29105" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-05-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Wayne Bramwell
Managing Director
19 Hardy Street
South Perth
WA 6151 Australia

Tel: +61 8 9463 6651
Fax: +61 8 9463 6652

Website: www. kasbahresources.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MA-Morocco">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Achmmach Project is located on the Western edge of the El Hajeb province in Morocco, 110 km southeast of Rabat and 40km southwest of Meknes. The Achmmach tenement is covered by two exploration permits covering an area of approximately 32 km2. 

The El Hajeb province is an underdeveloped frontier region which is mainly sustained by agricultural and herding activities and has limited formal employment opportunities. The project is located in a sparsely populated area.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.0000000000 -6.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BG - All Other Metal (Including Tin, Tantalum, Tungsten, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $9.16 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-05-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-05-18">9160000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-05-18">9160000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KASBAH RESOURCES LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/29105/achmmach-tin">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
