<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acindar Industria Argentina de Aceros S.A.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Argentina: Acindar Industria de Aceros S.A.            Region    Latin America and Caribbean        Sector       Project No009220   Projected Board DateSeptember 30, 1998   Company NameAcindar S.A.    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	A significant portion of the Companys stock is owned by the Acevedo family who, through a combination of A and B shares, control approximately 25% of Acindar.  The balance of the Acindars shares are traded on the Buenos Aires Stock Exchange where it is one of the most actively traded stocks.      Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total project cost is estimated at US$275 million. IFC is considering a total new investment of US$50 million including an &quot;A&quot; Loan of US$25 million for its own account and a &quot;B&quot; Loan of US$25 million, for the account of participants.    Location of project and Description of site    	The proposed project consists of an expansion and modernization of the Company&apos;&apos;s steel-making shop and rolling mills, including: (a)enhancing the steel-making shop productivity at Villa Constitucion, Province of Santa Fe ; (b) setting up a new bar mill, at Villa Constitucion, Province of Santa Fe; (c) upgrading the wire drawing operations at both Villa Constitucion and La Tablada, Province of Buenos Aires; (d) opening three new distribution centers.      Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	Acindar is a world scale integrated steel producer using the DRI/EAF process and employing state of the art technology.  It is the largest producer of non-flat steel products in Argentina and is fully integrated downstream with a product range of over 200 product lines and a total annual production capacity of 1.25 million tons. The Company recently implemented Phase II of the comprehensive modernization program which allowed Acindar to increase production capacity, introduce new value-added products and enhance market presence.  The Company is continuing the modernization with Phase III of the program, designed to further improve its operational and commercial performance. IFC has been closely involved with Acindars strategy to secure its position as a competitive steel producer.     Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental review procedure because the specific impacts that may result can be avoided or mitigated by adhering to generally recognized environmental performance standards, guidelines, or design criteria.  Environmental issues associated with this project include: site location; land use and habitat modification at each of the three distribution centers; air emissions; water supply; liquid effluents and solid waste disposal;   local employment and socioeconomic impacts; fuel storage and handling; and general occupational health safety including employee exposure to heat, noise and dust.  Environmental evaluation of control equipment design and mitigation actions for the new plant and environmental audits of the existing facilities will be used to verify compliance with World Bank guidelines and policies.    	The  is  from the InfoShop.       Date SPI sent to InfoShop     August 26, 1998      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACINDAR INDUSTRIA ARGENTINA DE ACEROS S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9220" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-01-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-01-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Argentina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AR-Argentina">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-34.0000000000 -64.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Integrated Steel Works</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $50.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-01-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-01-12">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-01-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-01-12">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACINDAR INDUSTRIA ARGENTINA DE ACEROS S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9220/acindar-industria-argentina-de-aceros-s-a">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
