<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7182</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Neuquen Basin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Argentina-Neuquen Basin              Region    Latin America        Sector       Project No007182   Projected Board DateMarch 29, 1996   Company NamePetrolera Argentina San Jorge S.A. (San Jorge)   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	San Jorge, an independent Argentine exploration and production company. It is a member of the Bolland Group of companies, which has been involved in the manufacturing and distribution of petroleum equipment and materials and in providing oil company services in Argentina, since the 1930s.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	US$190 million, including US$80 million in past costs.  IFC proposes to acquire a 15% participating interest in the Project for up to US$25 million.    Location of project and Description of site    	Provinces of Neuquen, Mendoza and Rio Negro, all within the Neuquen Basin.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project (include IFC role/development impact)    	The Project, undertaken in the form of Unincorporated Joint Ventures between San Jorge, IFC and international oil companies, involves the appraisal and early development of the recent oil/gas discoveries in the Confluencia and Rio Negro Blocks (the Discoveries), the rehabilitation of the El Sauce oil field within the El Sauce Block, and the continued exploration of the El Sauce, Zapala, China Muerta, Estaci&#xF3;n Cervantes, Laguna Blanca, Rio Negro and Confluencia Blocks, located within the Neuquen Basin.  The development of the Discoveries will contribute to increasing Argentinas hydrocarbon reserves and maintaining hydrocarbon production at current levels.  IFCs participation will assist San Jorge move towards becoming a mature oil company.  Although the fourth largest oil producer in Argentina today, it still remains an emerging company by both Argentine and international standards.  The success of the project and the continued growth of San Jorge will have significant developmental impact by creating important secondary and tertiary employment opportunities, particularly through the various oil field services provided by local contractors in remote and economically underdeveloped regions with little or no other employment opportunities  Finally, in addition to its socio-economic impacts, the project will generate significant monetary benefits for both the provincial and federal governments in the form of taxes and royalties.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental review procedure.  Environmental issues associated with this Project include hydrocarbon contamination as a result of past activities and the Project&apos;&apos;s compliance with the Government of Argentina&apos;&apos;s Energy Secretariat&apos;&apos;s environmental requirements for the management of produced gas and water, reserve pit cleanups and environmental impact studies.  The Sponsors have completed environmental baseline studies of the existing contamination and environmental programs for the blocks which have been developed including reduction in gas flaring in compliance with the Government of Argentina Energy Secretariats requirements.  The Project is expected to comply fully with World Bank environmental and health and safety guidelines, as well as with the requirements of the Argentine government.    The  is  from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     February 28, 1996      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAPEX S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7182" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1996-10-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1996-10-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Argentina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AR-Argentina">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-34.0000000000 -64.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Oil and Gas Production (Includes Development)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $26.40 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1996-10-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1997-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1996-10-18">26400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1996-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1996-10-18">26400000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAPEX S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7182/neuquen-basin">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
