<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9486</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAPLAC, S.A.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Argentina - Faplac S.A.      RegionLatin America and Caribbean   Sector   Project No009486   Projected Board DateSeptember 25, 1999   Company NameFaplac S.A.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Faplac is 98.9% controlled by the Louis Dreyfus Group, a worldwide organization of diversified companies with headquarters in Paris and New York. The balance of Faplacs shares is traded on the Buenos Aires stock exchange.     Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total project cost is estimated at US$95.5 million. IFC is considering a US$10 million A Loan and a US$5 million convertible loan (C Loan), both for its own account.    Location of project and Description of site    	The proposed project consists of the construction of a particle board and finished panels plant in Z&#xE1;rate, an industrial zone located in the province of Buenos Aires. The Z&#xE1;rate plant will replace Faplacs existing particle board plant in Tigre, province of Buenos Aires.       Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	Faplac S.A. pioneered the production of particle board in South America in the 1960s and is currently one of Argentinas largest producers of particle board. The company&apos;&apos;s product line includes raw panels, plastic laminate, decorative paper coated panels and wood veneered panels. The companys 1998 total sales reached US$48.3 million, or 115,000 m&#xB3; of particle board, of which about 87% was sold in the domestic market and the remaining 13% was exported. Over the last few years, Faplac has averaged about 35% market share.    	The new plant will employ state of the art technology, providing significant cost-savings in the two most important raw materials: wood and resins. In addition, the project will allow Faplac to increase production capacity, improve quality, introduce new value-added products, and enhance market presence domestically and internationally.   By financing the construction of an modern particle board plant outside of the Greater Buenos Aires area, the project will attract investment to less industrialized parts of the country, and assist Argentina in maximizing its comparative advantage in the forestry products sector by contributing to its growth and development.     Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure. Key issues considered during appraisal include:  plantation management and sustainable harvesting; environmental issues associated with closure of the existing plant at Tigre; acquisition of the Z&#xE1;rate site; compliance with World Bank Group environmental requirements; fire protection and emergency response; occupational health, safety and social issues relating to change of processing location and any retrenchment.    The Company currently operates three plantations and no wood is obtained from natural forest. The plantations are long established and well managed with appropriate fire-breaks and control systems as well as Integrated Pest Management. The company is considering acquisition of other areas set aside for plantations. These would be managed in the same way as existing Faplac plantations and would not result in significant adverse impacts to natural habitats.    The Tigre site will close in September 1999. While a 1997 survey indicated elevated levels of phenols and hydrocarbons in soils and groundwaters in and around the site, this is not attributable to Faplac. Local planning and environmental authorities are aware of this issue and are content that Faplac has no liabilities with regard to the contaminated land.   The new production site at Z&#xE1;rate is within a designated industrial development area west of the city. The site was formerly farmland, no resettlement has been required and no economic displacement has occurred.    The Z&#xE1;rate site is being designed to comply with World Bank Group requirements and the wood products from the plant will be E1 certified. Closure of the Tigre plant will result in significant improvements in local air quality.   At Z&#xE1;rate, a comprehensive fire control system has been installed throughout the plant and fire control systems are adequate at other sites. The company provides appropriate training and provision of personal protective equipment to staff and there are adequate occupational health and safety controls.   A compensation program has been developed to address retrenchment, and severance payments will be paid in accordance with Argentinean requirements.     The  is  from the InfoShop.       Host country location of environmental documents    At the gate of the new plant whose address is:   Camino de la Costa Brava S/N   (2800) - Z&#xE1;rate   Provincia de Buenos Aires   Rep&#xFA;blica Argentina      Date SPI sent to InfoShop August 23, 1999   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAPLAC S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9486" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-12-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-03-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Argentina</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AR-Argentina">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-34.0000000000 -64.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FC - Wood Panels and Engineered Wood Products</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $15.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-12-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-12-09">15000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-12-09">15000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAPLAC S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9486/faplac-s-a">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
