<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12347A0101-BFA-15110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Functional Reviews</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Funktionell granskning av ministerier</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank has requested Swedish support through an Externally Financed Output (EFO) of 18,5 million SEK and 18 months of duration to carry out the project &quot; Functional Reviews of Education, Health, Finance, Public Service and Justice sectors&quot; . 

The intervention aims at identifying relevant elements for effective policy dialogue in the areas of deployment of state resources and support the public administration&#x2019;s capacity to lead performance driven reforms in the Education, Health, Finance, Public Service and Justice sectors by 1) Conducting functional reviews of the Education, Health, Finance, Public Service and Justice sectors ; 2) Developing a change management and communication strategy; and 3) Developing a body of knowledge adapted and relevant to Burkina Faso&#x2019;s specific socio-political context. The World Bank will implement the intervention together with the Government of Burkina Faso.

The total budget is 18,5 MSEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">V&#xE4;rldsbanken har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering av 18 500 000 kronor till Sida f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet  &quot; Functional Reviews of Education, Health, Finance, Public Service and Justice sectors&quot; i Burkina Faso under perioden 2019-2020.

Interventionen syftar till att identifiera relevanta delar f&#xF6;r en effektiv politisk dialog f&#xF6;r utnyttjande av statliga resurser, och att st&#xF6;dja den offentliga f&#xF6;rvaltningens f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga att leda prestationsbaserade reformer inom sektorerna f&#xF6;r utbildning, h&#xE4;lsa, offentliga finanser, offentlig sektor och justitie genom att 1) genomf&#xF6;ra en funktionell granskning av dessa ministerier: utbildning, h&#xE4;lsa, finans, offentlig sektor och r&#xE4;ttsliga sektorn; 2) Utveckla en f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringshanterings- och kommunikationsstrategi; och 3) Utveckla en kunskapsbank som &#xE4;r anpassad och relevant f&#xF6;r Burkina Fasos specifika sociopolitiska kontext. V&#xE4;rldsbanken kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen tillsammans med Burkina Fasos regering.

Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 18,5 miljoner kronor</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the contribution is to develop analytical work and knowledge products to identify relevant elements for effective policy dialogue in the areas of deployment of state resources and support the public administrations capacity to lead performance driven reforms.
The three following activities envisioned under this contribution will articulate&#xA0;a multi-disciplinary and multi-stakeholder approach for a more effectiveassistance to the Government in the areas of deployment of state resources andpublic administrations capacity:&#xA0;
1) Conduct functional reviews of the Education, Health, Finance, Public Administration and Justice sectors in order to promote effective allocation and management of resources in the targeted ministries.&#xA0;
2) Develop a change management and communication strategy through a change management program focused on strategic communication.&#xA0;
3) Since there is a variety of actors involved in the policy reform path and implementation of human resources deployment who do not necessarily share the same understanding of the aims and means of the approach to follow, a body of knowledge adapted and relevant to Burkina Fasos specific socio-political context will be shared, aiming at creating a common understanding amongst the actors/stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1956450.4700768832</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1956450.4700768832</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-1.9e-9</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-12">1956450.470076</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">1956450.4700768832</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The implementation of activities during 2021 made it possible to achieve the main result that were expected. Regarding the result &quot;Conduct functional reviews of the Education, Health, Finance, Public Administration and Justice sectors in order to promote effective allocation and management of resources in the targeted ministries&quot;, consultants have been contracted and preliminary functional review notes for 4 pilot ministries are being finalized. There remains the validation of the reports by the government.
In addition, the World Bank provided technical assistance focused on the identification of potential reform options, the production of high level cost and time implementation plans and the conducting of a high-level restitution workshop. 
Regarding the capacity building for development of a change management and communication strategy, the World Bank provided technical assistance to help build the capacity of government staff to produce a stakeholder engagement strategy paper and a strategic communication strategy.
On capacity building for pursuit of knowledge management activities, the World Bank supported to build the capacity of government staff to develop methods to create an adapted and multimedia knowledge platform, analyze potential bottlenecks to deployment of state resources and map public services. These functional reviews constitute an important analytical contribution for the Government in the development of its new strategy for the modernization of public administration. They maximize the alignment of public functions and resources allocated to government priorities and determine improvements and gains. The functional review process took place in several phases: A start-up phase with: (i) scoping (June 2020); (ii) development of collection and analysis tools; (iii) appointment of focal points; (iv) four sector workshops at the technical level (November-December 2020); and the High Level Inception Workshop (March 2021). A diagnostic phase for: (i) data collection and analysis; (ii) establishing the diagnosis; (iii) drafting and delivery of the interim report. The next steps are: (i) development of the action plan; (ii) approval by the Technical Committee; (iii) validation by the steering committee; and (iv) the reporting/ action plan workshop. With regard to the particular case of the Ministry of Justice, the report presented the general socio-political and institutional context of the reform in the sector, the diagnostic analysis and the conclusions and possible recommendations. The security, social and health context has an impact on the presence of the State in the regions most affected by insecurity. As of April 2020, over 2,500 schools were closed, depriving some 350,000 children of education and affecting over 11,200 teachers. Similarly, 135 of the 1,140 health centers are closed and 1,600,000 people no longer have access, or very limited access, to health services. The justice and human rights sector was affected with the closure of the court of Djibo in the province of Soum, thus limiting access to justice for approximately 350,000 citizens. One of the causes of the erosion of social cohesion and peace is the insufficiency of the administration of republican justice and the non-respect of human rights. According to the analysis carried out, the organization and functioning of the Ministry of Justice have structural and functional strengths and weaknesses in the implementation of management by objectives which constitute an obstacle to the success of the reforms in progress. On the governance, the review of the justice sector shows that despite significant achievements, challenges that are still topical, affecting the strengthening of the performance of the judicial system, access to justice and effectiveness of human rights, arise acutely. The revision of the constitution in 2015 introduced an unprecedented upheaval in the relationship between the executive and judicial powers on the one hand, and in the management of the careers of magistrates on the other. The diversity of specific statuses within the ministry is not without consequences on the working relationships between the judicial actors, on the performance and the quality of the services rendered. In terms of its missions and organization, the ministry of justice is marked by organizational instability with frequent mergers and splits (four times) between the justice sub-sector and the human rights sub-sector There are overlapping responsibilities with other structures. In terms of human resources, the Ministry of Justice suffers from the absence of a formalized human resources policy for its staff. The absence of an HR Development Plan (HRDP) is a real handicap within the ministry. Its workforce is mainly grouped into 5 major job groups, but the jail guard alone occupies 58% of the department&apos;s workforce. If the independence of the judiciary is consecrated, the financial autonomy of the justice sector is not yet acquired. The multiple logistical and material obstacles are sources of dysfunction of the justice services and more particularly of the penal chain at all levels of the procedure. Finally, the functional reviews led to the identification and formulation of 23 recommendations including 10 &quot;quick-wins&quot; that could produce rapid improvements for human resources management. In addition to these functionnal reviews, the World Bank provided to the government technical assistance.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12347" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1660000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
