<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-7300093402-BFA-14030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PNAEPA Sector Programme Drinking Water Supply and Sanitation Sector Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PNAEPA Sektorprogram</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Att: Sverige ing&#xE5;r avtal med Burkina Faso f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av dricksvatten- och sanitetsprogrammet under 2014 och 2015; 
Att: Ett SEK 20 miljoner tildelas fr&#xE5;n budgetkonto 155.001 Burkina Faso f&#xF6;r att finansiera programmet 2014-2015; 
Att: Charg&#xE9; d&apos;affaires Margareta Kristianson p&#xE5; uppdrag fr&#xE5;n Sida undertecknar avtalet med Ekonomi-och finansministeriet, Burkina Faso, i enlighet med det bifogade utkastet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The renewed Swedish Sector Budget Support to the Burkina Faso Drinking Water and Sanitation Programme aims at helping the Government of Burkina Faso pursue its efforts to reach the MDGs goals regarding access to drinking water and sanitation for both rural and urban population of the country. The Swedish contribution will be used for the implementation of the following activities: 
- Improving access to drinking water in rural areas: construction and rehabilitation of water infrastructure using an approach that guarantees the sustainability and equity of water supply system in a process of integrated management of water resources;
- Improving access to sanitation in Rural areas : implement actions to address the infrastructure gap and remove barriers to sanitation development using an approach that encourages people to invest in sanitation infrastructure building, operation and maintenance;
- Coordinating and supporting the governance of the sector through : human resources development, technical and logistical capacity building of central and decentralized water administration, the communes, as well as and the civil society (NGOs, associations). 
It is expected that by the end of 2015, the access rate to drinking water will reach 67% in rural areas and 89% in urban areas against 63,5% and 86% in 2013. Regarding sanitation, the access rate shall move from 6% up to 12% in the rural areas and from 30% to 40% in the urban areas. In addition to that, water governance shall improve at communal levels thanks to a more decentralised approach to the programme implementation.

However, some weaknesses are still noticed regarding regarding the financial management of the programme, the quality of the infrastructure and the ownership of the programme by basic stakeholders, namely the communes and the water users associations. 

Sida has in consultation with the other donors required the Government to develop and implement an action plan to improve the programme financial management as well as the ownership of the infrastructure by the beneficiaries. In addition to that an external evaluation of the quality of the infrastructure shall be established. In order to make sure that this will happen, the disbursement of the Swedish contribution is planned to be disbursed in single tranche of twenty (20) Million SEK as soon as the agreement is signed, upon request forom the Government as stipulated in the agreement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mottagarlandets regering</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">31626.856931517</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">47026.4001536439</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">31626.856931517</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">47026.4001536439</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-07-01">72693.066007</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-03-28">276.4994144116</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-10-28">31350.3436479073</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-07-28">47026.3262863981</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: PN-AEPA is implemented within the framework of sectoral budget support. 
 In the rural areas, the intervention consists of three components :

- A component called &#x201C;a united intervention framework&#x201D; that the aim is to obtain an efficient and effective management of water and sanitation in rural areas, to create a favourable environment for the construction and maintenance of the water and sanitation infrastructure and provide a sustainable water and sanitation service. 
- A component to build infrastructure for drinking water including the construction of modern water points, simplified drinking water supply networks, autonomous water posts, replacement of manual water pumps and reparation of some of the existing water infrastructure. 
- A component to build infrastructure for sanitation through the construction and rehabilitation of public and household latrines and sewage systems. 

The sector benefits a result based budgeting. Due to inefficient procurement by projects, there has been a decrease in the rate of budgetary absorption over the past 3 years.The level of performance during the year 2015 is quite satisfactory. The rate of implementation of sectoral measures and actions is 75%,  09 measurements are fully implemented on 12 measures. The overall financial implementation rate of measures and actions is 76.7% or 681 102 857 SEK spent on 887 487 142 SEK62 provided.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="73000934" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
