<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5120005101-BFA-15151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso 2015 and 2016 elections</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Burkina Faso 2015 and 2016 elections</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developed in conjunction with national and international partners and resourced by the basket fund donors, the electoral process will support four components as mentioned above with a clear description of the outcomes of the intervention. These outcomes are aligned with the impact defined in the 2011-2015 UNDAF  extended to 2016: human rights are better known and respected, for the benefit of democratic governance and the rule of law. Intended outcome as stated in the Project document  are:(1)  National Institutions (CENI, MATDS, the Constitutional Council, the State Council and the Higher Council for Communication) organized and supervised professionally and in a responsible way free, credible, tranparent and non-violent  elections; (2) Institutions contributing to the strengthening of democracy and the promotion of peace (political parties, civil society and the media) have played their roles adequately for the polls are conducted citizen, inclusive and without violence; (3) the turnout in the different elections are significant population of voting age with a good participation of women ; and (4) National institutions responsible for the conduct of the electoral process have acquired skills and are to be professionalized empowerment after the period covered by the electoral cycle. The logical framework provides 13 planned outputs. These outputs are relevant and follow a logical chain in relation to the intended outcomes mentioned above and contribute to the overall impact. 1-	The Project management unit (PMU) is operational2-	The steering committee and the and the technical committee are functional3-	The capacity strengthening of the CENI and the other institutions  of the national electoral management body is effective, and the skills transfer at the end of the electoral process is ensured4-	Populations are informed on the basic principles of democracy, the elections for national reconciliation issues, the procedures of voting, rights and duties in electoral matters, etc.5-	The respect of Human rights is guaranteed and its effective monitoring is guaranteed6-	Public and private media ensure an impartial coverage of the three stages of the electoral process7-	Gender aspects are integrated and the equal participation of women and men is promoted 8-	A domestic electoral observation through the CSOs enables an effective coverage and contributes to the transparency of electoral operations 9-	The strengthening of dialogue among all the stakeholders involved in the electoral process prevents conflicts and consolidates the peace10-	CENI and  competent courts are endowed and capable to better manage electoral disputes 11-	Information on the electoral process is disseminated and citizens and the Donors are well informed and contribute to the smooth running of the process 12-	CENI is equipped to effectively manage the electoral disputes13-	The institutional and professional capacities CENI and other electoral management body are reinforced.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;det till UNDP (PAE-BF 2015-2016) bidrar till strategim&#xE5;let, att fr&#xE4;mja demokratisk samh&#xE4;llsstyrning, och st&#xF6;det kommer att ges genom en fond tillsammans med andra givare. Enligt Burkina Fasos regeringen uppg&#xE5;r den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra valen 2015 och 2016 till ca 766 MSEK. UNDP:s korgfond &#xE4;r budgeterad till ca 84 MSEK (10 MUSD).  M&#xE5;len med insatsen &#xE4;r att bidra till genomf&#xF6;randet av fria, r&#xE4;ttvisa och inkluderande val (president-, riksdags- och lokala) som &#xF6;verensst&#xE4;mmer med internationell vedertagen standard samt att bygga l&#xE5;ngsiktig institutionell kapacitet bland landets fr&#xE4;msta akt&#xF6;rer som ansvarar f&#xF6;r valens genomf&#xF6;rande. Det tekninska och finansiella st&#xF6;det som kommer ges utg&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d till hela valprocessen som inneh&#xE5;ller valf&#xF6;rberedelser, val och uppf&#xF6;ljning av valet och dess resultat. St&#xF6;det har f&#xF6;ljande komponenter; 1: att st&#xF6;dja den nationella valkommissionen och andra institutioner som m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av valen, 2: st&#xF6;d till civilt l&#xE4;rande, kommunikation, kvinnligt deltagande samt att mobilisera valdeltagande 3: preventiva &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder, konflikthantering och fredsbevarande insatser, 4: st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla l&#xE5;ngsiktigt st&#xF6;d till den nationella valkommissionen. St&#xF6;det ges till UNDP som i sin tur kanaliserar st&#xF6;det vidare till sina samarbetspartners. En stearing committee &#xE4;r ansvarig f&#xF6;r den strategiska styrningen av projektet. Kommitten leds av UNDP tillsammans med CENI (nationella valkommissionen). Givarna tillsammans med de civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer som finns med i implementeringen av projektet kommer att bjudas in till kommitten som observat&#xF6;rer.Genom att Sverige tillsammans med andra givare samfinansierar PAE-BF bidrar Sverige med att st&#xE4;rka den organisatoriska, tekniska och finansiella kapaciteten hos de centrala akt&#xF6;rerna som &#xE4;r involverade i valprocessen, inklusive valkommissionen (CENI), regeringen, statliga instititioner, politiska partier,  civila samh&#xE4;llsorganisationer, kvinnoorganissationer, massmedia, och andra relevanta akt&#xF6;rer.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP has applied to Sida for funding of 35 million SEK to carry out the &quot;&quot;Elections Support Project in Burkina Faso (2015-2016) - PAE-BF&quot;&quot; in Burkinq Faso during the period 2015-2016. 

The intervention aims at contributing to the organization of transparent and credible elections in conformity with international standards and regional instruments governing the electoral process, including gender equity.by 1) Support the CENI and other institutions for the organization and holding of elections; 2) Support for Civic education, women&apos;s participation and mobilization of voters; 3) Prevention, conflict management and education for peace; and 4) Sustainability of the achievements and long-term capacity building of CENI. UNDP will implement the intervention together with CENI and other national institutions involved in the electoral process. 
The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 84,6 million SEK (10 000 000 USD), out of which UNDP&#x2019;s own funding is approximately 6,77 million SEK (800 millon USD) and the remaining 77,83 million SEK (9,2 million USD) is contributed by Suisse, Canada and Japan. Approximately a financial gap of 41,5 million SEK (4.9 million USD) is remaining.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elections</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">4152183.455328438</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.0781277391</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">4152183.455328438</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.078127739</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">4745352.520375</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">4152183.455328438</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">584351.0781277391</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project activities generated the following products:1. Dialogue among the actors of the electoral process is strengthened with a view to creating the optimal conditions for preventing electoral violence and consolidating peace;2. The capacity of the management structure of the electoral process is reinforced by training sessions for staff to enable them to perform their tasks to the satisfaction of the general public, but also by supporting the acquisition of equipment and materials essential to his mission ;3. The capacities of other public institutions involved in the electoral process, political parties, civil society organizations, the media are strengthened and the population is informed and sensitized on issues related to the electoral process (issues, voting methods, places of voting, right to vote, etc.) as well as non-violent means of expressing concerns about the process;4. Citizen participation is encouraged, including through support for initiatives for women, youth and persons with disabilities;5. Elections are carried out: logistical arrangements (assessment of needs and elaboration of specifications, calls for tenders, order and deployment of electoral materials and equipment) are concluded; election materials are available on time; security is provided by the Government to enable all voters to exercise their right to vote in peace. However, of the four expected results, two have been achieved: &quot;national institutions have organized and supervised credible elections&quot; and &quot;the institutions in charge of the conduct of the electoral process have acquired skills and have become professionalized&quot;. One result was partially achieved &quot;the participation of women leaders in the electoral process&quot; and a moderately achieved result &quot;The national institutions in charge of the conduct of the electoral process have acquired skills and have become professionalized: the CENI only, but not all the institutions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="51200051" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
