<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10954A0101-BFA-15152</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to National Assembly Burkina Faso 2018-2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to National Assembly Burkina Faso 2018-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By the end of the intervention the parliament vision is that &quot;In 2020, the ultimate goal of this initiative is to make the National Assembly of Burkina Faso a strong institution contributing to strengthening good governance, democracy and social cohesion of the country.&quot; Specifically strengthened, the parliamentary controles the governemental action and improve women representation in the parliament.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Burkina Faso&#x2019;s parlament har ans&#xF6;kt om 36 MSEK fr&#xE5;n Sida f&#xF6;r att finansiera programmet &#x201D;PROCAB&#x201D; under perioden 2018 &#x2013; 2020, p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;.
Huvudsyftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att utveckla det burkinska parlamentet till en stark institution som bidrar till att f&#xF6;rdjupa demokratin, fr&#xE4;mja god samh&#xE4;llsstyrning och social sammanh&#xE5;llning. Programmet best&#xE5;r av tre delar:
1)	St&#xE4;rkt parlamentariskt ledarskap och ansvarighet f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av parlamentets handlingsplan och vision.
2)	F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrat genomf&#xF6;rande av parlamentets olika uppdrag och dess samverkan med civilsamh&#xE4;lle och medborgare.
3)	St&#xE4;rkt politisk vilka och ansvarighet inom parlamentet vad g&#xE4;ller genderfr&#xE5;gor och fr&#xE4;mjandet av kvinnors roll i politiken.
De huvudsakliga aktiviteterna omfattar kapacitetsutveckling f&#xF6;r parlamentsledam&#xF6;ter inom omr&#xE5;dena administration och IT,  tidsplanering och prioritering, beslutsprocesser, balansera arbetsliv och familj, utbildning i j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsfr&#xE5;gor med mera. Andra aktiviteter omfattar utformandet av en plan f&#xF6;r personalfr&#xE5;gor, formulerande och genomf&#xF6;rande av manualer f&#xF6;r parlamentariska procedurer, administration, finanser och r&#xE4;kenskaper, intern revision, utformandet av en l&#xE5;ngsiktig kommunikationsplan, uppr&#xE4;ttande av ett bibliotek. 
Ytterligare aktiviteter g&#xE4;ller utformandet av en guide f&#xF6;r analys och f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring av lagar, utformandet av nya lagar och formandet av individuella utvecklingsplaner f&#xF6;r ledam&#xF6;ter och administrativ personal. 
En organisationsanalys av oppositionspartierna och dess gemensamma strukturer ska genomf&#xF6;ras i syfte att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra dess funktion. Synergier mellan olika granskningsfunktioner ska analyseras och utvecklas (den statliga revisionen, den statliga kontroll- och antikorruptionsinstansen ASCE-LC m fl) och en enhet f&#xF6;r budgetanalys och -kontroll byggas upp. Vidare ska en j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsenhet inr&#xE4;ttas och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetslagen revideras. De direkta m&#xE5;lgrupperna f&#xF6;r insatserna &#xE4;r de folkvalda och parlamentets administrativa personal. Indirekt v&#xE4;ntas landet som helhet gynnas av insatserna.

Ansvaret f&#xF6;r att Genomf&#xF6;ra PROCAB vilar pa den kanadensiska organisationen Palamentariskt Center. Parlamentscentret i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med ANBF &#xE4;r fullt ansvarigt f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av PROCAB och f&#xF6;rvaltningen av de ekonomiska bidragen. Parlamentscentret har ett avtal med en lokal organisation, Yons Associates, som representerar dem i Burkina Faso. Fonder kommer att &#xF6;verf&#xF6;ras fr&#xE5;n Parlamentcentret till Yons Associates. Yons Associates har ett avtal med Burkina Fasos parlamentet men inga pengar kommer att &#xF6;verf&#xF6;ras till parlamentet.

Total budget uppg&#xE5;r till 148 MSEK och det svenska bidraget &#xE4;r 36 MSEK. Parlamentet bidrar sj&#xE4;lv med 78 MSEK och &#xF6;vrig finansiering kommer fr&#xE5;n EU och Schweiz.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Burkina Faso National Assembly has applied to Sida for funding of 36 millions SEK to carry out their &quot;PROCAB&quot; program in the national territory during the period 2018-2020. 
The intervention will be implemented during the years 2018 to 2020. The ultimate goal of this initiative is to make the National Assembly of Burkina Faso a strong institution contributing to strengthening good governance, democracy and social cohesion of the country. The program has the following three components:
1-Strengthening the leadership and accountability of the various Assembly actors in implementing the strategic plan and its driving vision;
2-Improved Assembly performance in the conduct of its various missions and in its work with CSOs and citizens;
3-Strengthening the political will and the accountability of the Assembly in the area of gender equality and the advancement of women in political life.
The main activities are capacity strengthening of the MPs in computer knowledge and management, implementing MP training plans on diverse themes like time management and priorities, decision making, balancing family life-work life, gender, etc. Other activities concern the formulation of a human resources developement plan, the formualtion and implementation of a manual of procedures, including administration, finance and accounting, the design and implementation of an internal audit charter and methodological guide, the developement and implementation of a multi-year communication plan, and the creation of a library.
A guide for the analysis and amendment of legislation will be formulated. Information and training workshops for MPs will be organised along with the formulation and implementation of individual coaching plans for the MPs and administrative staff.  An organizational audit for the opposition party will be done. Synergies will be sought between the audit institutions (State Audit Office, Supreme State Control and Anti-Corruption Authority-ASCE-LC) and a unit for budget analysis and control, which is to be set up. A gender unit will also be set up.

The direct beneficiaries will be MPs and the administrative staff. The indirect beneficiaries will be the entire population.

The implementation of the PROCAB will be managed by the canadian Parliamentary Centre. The Parliamentary Centre in close collaboration with the ANBF is fully responsible for the implementation of the PROCAB and the management of PTFs&apos; financial contributions. The Parliamentary Center will have a contract with a local organisation, Yons Associates, in charge to represent them. Funds will be transfered from the Parliamentary Center to Yons Associates. Yons Associates will have a contract with the Parliament but nos funds will be transfered to the Parliament.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 147,604,000 SEK , out of which Sweden funding is 36 millions SEK, the Organisation&#x2019;s own funding is approximately 79,950,600 SEK and the remaining is contributed by EU and Swiss during 2018-2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Parliamentary Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legislatures and political parties</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1380834.0237503452</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1692065.271417845</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">868649.358828192</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1380834.023750345</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1692065.271417845</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">868649.3588281919</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-08">4142502.071251</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">1380834.0237503452</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">1692065.271417845</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">868649.358828192</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/burkina-faso/agreement-su--de---centre-parlementaire.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/burkina-faso/annexe-i-de-l-agreement---paf-du-procab.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/burkina-faso/10954_2017_015supporttoassemblynationalBF.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision of Sweden Embassy to support National Assembly of Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/burkina-faso/decision-on-contribution_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regarding the control of the governmental action&#xA0; A hearing mission was carried out and another by the general committee as part of the oversight of government action. The hearing mission&#xA0; on the employability of young people for the benefit of the Committee on Youth, Education, Employment and Culture and the mission of hearing on the implementation of the national policy on access to water and sanitation and the achievement of sustainable development objectives for the benefit of the environment committee. The parliament by carrying out these missions with the assistance of PROCAB experts who reinforce and assist deputies in orders prerogatives to control government actions. These hearing missions allow deputies to assess the consequences for society of measures taken by the government in the areas of employability of young people and access of populations to water and sanitation. In addition, they allow parliamentarians to ensure that sufficient resources are allocated to deliver government programs and to meet national and international commitments.In addition, a second audit mission and an independent strategic analysis of the performance of the water and sanitation sector from 2016 to 2019 was carried out by a consultant. A feedback workshop was held to discuss the findings of the study, which was attended by nine deputies and eight staff members. This analysis allowed parliamentarians to have, among other things, key questions and points of attention for discussions with stakeholders in the sector. The said mission held talks with government actors in charge of water and sanitation, finance and health. Civil society actors working in the field as well as the managers of standpipes and users of manual pump boreholes in the villages are been involved in the interviews. It enabled the deputies who are members of the environment committee to better contribute to the debates on&#xA0; water and sanitation issues and to formulate to the government effective and sustainable solutions in order to meet the challenges and constraints in the water supply sector.&#xA0;- Contribution of the parliament to the transparent and efficient management of public affairs. Regarding this objective, the deputies benefited from capacity building sessions but also the parliamentary administration benefited from an audit tool for better administration of its management and audit system and human resources management. Indeed, a Human Resources Development Plan has been drawn up to rectify the weakness in the strategic management of human resources and the strong mismatches between the existing profiles and the requirements of the positions concerned at the administrative level. Thus, documents which offer the possibility of optimizing the management of human resources have been designed and made available to the parliamentary administration. These are (i) the forward management plan for jobs, staffing and skills, (ii) the staff career plan, (iii) the initial and continuing training plan for staff and (iv) a staff motivation plan. The national assembly has tools for better administrative and accounting management.The parliament has benefited from the advice of experts recruited by the program to advise on the budget analysis but also on the proposal of new taxes that do not have a negative impact on the population. The parliament has benefited from support for the development of numerous guides for parliamentary work. It is for example a guide for the monitoring of public policies, a guide for the conduct of a parliamentary hearing. PROCAB has supported the development of modern management tools to strengthen the performance of the parliamentary administration.&#xA0;The organization chart of the parliament has been reviewed and a new administrative organization adopted. One of the main innovations compared to that&#xA0; is the transformation of the Strategy, Coordination and Monitoring and Evaluation Unit in the Foresight, Monitoring and Evaluation and Projects and Programs Department. The reinforcement of the governmental action on public and privates policies As part of the performance of community assessments of government action, workshops were organized in five provinces to assess the achievements of the State in the infrastructure, water and sanitation, education sectors. The meetings recorded a total of ten deputies and five hundred and eleven other actors (323 men and 188 women) in the development of the provinces concerned. Religious leaders, young people and women, local elected officials, heads of technical structures&#xA0; decentralized and civil society organizations take part on the process and are beenconcerned by the theme. The deputies with the local populations identified the priority needs of the localities which are not covered in the implementation of public policies and identify with them the factors which do not promote effective implementation. Recommendations have been formulated for the attention of the government, decentralized structures, local authorities and the National Assembly. The deputies asked the government questions on the management of COVID but also on its impact on the economy, particularly on youth employment. The reinforcement of the opposition leader&apos;s capacities. The leader of the opposition as an institution benefited after the equipment including a car and computers and an institutional audit. The institution has also benefited from the revitalization of its website and support for the development of a communication strategy.&#xA0;Three&#xA0; training sessions were organized for the benefit of forty-eight political leaders of the Opposition and nineteen communications officers of the political parties that are members of the CFOP.  - Taking gender into account A gender promotion strategy within the National Assembly has been developed. It identified major actions that the National Assembly could take to reduce existing inequalities between men and women within the institution. Two women have also been appointed by the national assembly to represent Burkina Faso in sub-regional parliaments such as ECOWAS and the African Union. Several capacity building actions were carried out. A training session on the gender approach was organized for the benefit of the deputies. It aimed to sensitize and encourage ministerial departments to make equity between men and women a reality in Burkina Faso through gender sensitive budgeting. Also, a training workshop on gender-sensitive public budgeting was organized for the benefit of deputies. A documentary film on female leadership in Burkina Faso was produced as well as a revised law on the gender quota with a view to increasing the participation of women in decision-making bodies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10954" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1660000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
