<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12696A0101-BFA-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Common Gender Fund 2019-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Gemensamma j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsfonden 2019-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Diakonia, en av Sidas ramorganisationer, har till Sida inkommit med en ans&#xF6;kan om att Sida,  tillsammans med fem givare, bidrar till insatsen &quot; Common Gender Fund and its Strategic Plan 2019-2023&quot; i Burkina Faso 2019-2023. Insatsen syftar till att bidra att st&#xE4;rka kvinnors och flickors sociala, ekonomiska, politiska r&#xE4;ttigheter genom diverse &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r att p&#xE5; s&#xE5; s&#xE4;tt minska oj&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet mellan k&#xF6;nen p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;. Sida har tidigare bidragit med st&#xF6;d till Common Gender Fund under perioden 2012-2014 och 2016-2018. 

Diakonia kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra st&#xF6;det tillsammans med lokala icke-statliga organisationer och myndigheter. Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 89 miljoner kronor, varav Sida bidrar med 15 miljoner kronor.  &#xD6;vriga givare (Danmark, Schweiz, UNFPA, UNICEF) kommer att bidra med cirka 27 miljoner kronor. Cirka 73 procent av budgeten kommer att vidaref&#xF6;rmedlas till tredje part.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia, one of Sida&apos;s framework organizations, has submitted an application to Sida to jointly finance the intervention &quot;the Common Gender Fund and its Strategic Plan 2019-2023&#x201D; together with four other donors during the period 2019-2023. The intervention aims to contribute to the implementation of relevant and effective actions to strengthen women&apos;s and girls&apos; social, economic, political rights through actions to promote the abandonment of GBV, promotion of economic and political empowerment, strengthening gender mainstreaming, involvement of women and youth in the management of security issues, in order to to reduce gender inequalities at the national level. Sida has previously contributed to the Common Gender Fund in 2012-2014 and 2016-2018. 

Diakonia will implement the intervention together with local CSOs and Government authorities. The total budget is 89 Million SEK out of which Sida will contribute with 15 million SEK. Other donors (Denmark, Switzerland, UNFPA, UNICEF) will contribute with   approximately 27 million SEK. Approximately 73 % of the intervention budget will be forwarded from Diakonia to third parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention FCG 2019-2023 (Gender Common Fund and its Strategic Plan 2019-2023) is to contribute to the implementation of relevant and effective actions to reduce gender inequalities at the national level by CSOs, and Government authorities in order to prevent and combat gender-based violence, to promote economic empowerment, to enable greater participation of women in politics and decision-making, and women&apos;s and young peoples&apos; involvement in security issues.
The FCG 2019-2023&#xA0; is based on five strategic axes: Axis 1: Strengthening actions to promote the abandonment of gender based violence (GBV) Axis 2: Economic and political empowerment of women and young people Axis 3: Strengthening gender mainstreaming in the development and monitoring of public policies, projects and programs by institutions and CSOs Axis 4: Involvement of women and youth in the management of security issues  Axis 5: Coordination, monitoring, evaluation, capitalization of achievements and promotion of innovative approaches
The five main expected results are:
- Actions to prevent, reduce and end GBV are strengthened;
- The economic and political empowerment of women and youth are strengthened;
- Gender mainstreaming in the development and monitoring of public policies, projects and programs by institutions and CSOs is strengthened;
- Better involvement of women and youth in the management of security issues is ensured;
- Coordination, monitoring, evaluation, capitalization of achievements and promotion of innovative approaches is ensured.
At the end, women poverty is reduced.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.4 - Erk&#xE4;nna och v&#xE4;rdes&#xE4;tta obetalt omsorgs- och hush&#xE5;llsarbete genom att tillhandah&#xE5;lla offentliga tj&#xE4;nster, infrastruktur och socialt skydd samt genom att fr&#xE4;mja delat ansvar inom hush&#xE5;llet och familjen, i enlighet med vad som &#xE4;r nationellt l&#xE4;mpligt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.4 - Recognize and value unpaid care and domestic work through the provision of public services, infrastructure and social protection policies and the promotion of shared responsibility within the household and the family as nationally appropriate.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.69853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1085811.6985352403</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-25">1586311.191954</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">1085811.69853524</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/burkina-faso/12696_AgreementGenderCommonFund12696_Diakonia.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Gender Common Fund 12696</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/burkina-faso/12696_DecisionBF_019_201912696GenderCommonFund.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision Gender Common Fund 12696</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities carried out by 12 implementing partners made possible to achieve the 2020 following results based on&#xA0;the 5 axis of the 2019-2023 Strategic Plan:
Axis 1: Strengthening actions to promote the abandonment of gender based violence (GBV)
The results of this axis were achieved thanks to the activities carried out by 5&#xA0;implementing partners:
- Association for the Promotion and Development of Gulmu (APDG) for the implementation of the &quot;Project to promote women&apos;s rights and reduce gender-based violence in the Eastern region&quot;
- Catholic Organization for Development and Solidarity (OCADES) Banfora for the implementation of the &quot;Project to strengthen actions to reduce GBV in the rural commune of Soubakani&#xE9;dougou&quot;
- Catholic Organization for Development and Solidarity (OCADES) Nouna for the implementation of the &quot;Project to strengthen the role and status of women and young people within local communities in the provinces of Kossi and Banwa&quot; 
- Permanent Secretariat of the National Council for the Fight against the Practice of Excision (SP-CNLPE) for the implementation of the &quot;Project to strengthen actions to promote the elimination of the practice of excision in eight (08) regions of Burkina Faso&quot; 
- National Federation of Wend Yam Groups (FNGWY) for the implementation of the project &#x201C;STOP Gender-Based Violence in Internally Displaced Persons Sites&#x201D;
Theses results have been achieved:
466 people (79 women) have a better understanding of GBV&#xA0;Gender-based violence (physical, sexual, psychological, economic violence) and are committed to being intermediaries to reduce GBV as much as possible.14 651 people including 8 997 women (61.4%) changed the behavior regarding&#xA0;FGM (Female Genital Mutilation) and 132 heads of families benefiting from family dialogues signed commitments for the abandonment of FGM.&#xA0;
2 funds (mutual legal assistance fund and emergency care fund) have been set up to support victims of GBV.&#xA0;
Emergency kits for repairing the after-effects of excision for 200 girls/women were handed over to health centers.&#xA0;17 cases of female circumcision in 15 provinces were denounced, 7 cases tried, 2 preventive denunciations, 3 cases where investigations were unsuccessful and 3 cases under investigation
75 people (32 men and 43 women) from the Technical Services, namely Social Action, Police, Gendarmerie and Justice, were trained on GBV among internally displaced persons,&#xA0;commit to denounce all forms of gender-based violence.&#xA0;
45 customary chiefs come together to reduce the length of chores inflicted on step-sons and review the value of the dowry
Practices that value women in rural areas are promoted: The actions of the husbands of the 12 model couples to unload their wives (bringing water from the fountain, carrying wood from the fields) led to the beginnings of change in the villages.
50% of GBV in households selected for the family dialogue approach and 25% in the project intervention area are reduced: 10 monitoring committees, 10 community watch committees and 10 Souambouli school clubs have been set up. Several leaders and authorities (mayors, prefects, heads of establishments, decentralized technical services, civil society organizations, press, etc.) are involved in the fight against GBV in their respective localities
130 community actors and 800 students are involved in raising awareness about the VEFF law (violence against women and girls) and GBV.
Axis 2: Economic and political empowerment of women and young people
The results of the axis 2 were achieved thanks to the activities carried out by 2&#xA0;implementing partners:
- African Union of Development NGOs (UAOD) for the implementation of the project &quot;Support for strengthening the citizenship of women and young people&quot;
- Burkina Business Incubator (BBI) for START UP Incubation Project.
Theses results have been achieved:
 The technical skills of the eighteen (18) Startups were strengthened in leadership, financial and commercial management, fund raising.
1400 women were made aware of the challenges of voting.&#xA0; A toll-free number for denunciations of cases of gender-based violence in connection with the elections has been opened. 76 cases of violence (psychological, physical, sexual) were recorded on the toll-free number. 40 men and 1,760 women animated the citizens&apos; chamber which made it possible to monitor and supervise the elections from a gender perspective and reduce gender-based violence. A network of 300 observers were deployed in the field for the 2020 elections. A study on the level of involvement of women and women&apos;s civil society organizations in strengthening the electoral process in Burkina Faso from 2009 to 2020 was conducted.&#xA0;
Axis 3: Strengthening gender mainstreaming in the development and monitoring of public policies, projects and programs by institutions and CSOs
Activities carried out by 3&#xA0;implementing partners allowed to achieve the results of this axis:&#xA0;
- Center for Information, Training and Studies on the Budget (CIFOEB) for the implementation of the &quot;Gender Champions Project&quot; 
- Higher Authority for State Control and the Fight against Corruption (ASCE-LC) for the implementation of &quot;Gender activities of the Enlarged Action Plan (PAE) for institutional and organizational strengthening of the ASCE-LC&quot; 
- Permanent Secretariat of the National Council for the Promotion of Gender (SP-CONAPGenre) for the implementation of the &quot;Support Project for the Institutionalization of Gender in Public Policies, Development Projects and Programs&quot; 
Results achieved:
25 gender champions have been identified (17 women). A gender index is available for all local actors (CSOs, local authorities and decentralized technical services)
Gender interventions are better coordinated because statistics are available through the National Gender Booklet, the statistical yearbook and the woman and gender dashboard, and the National Gender Strategy and its Operational Action Plan are available.&#xA0;
Axis 4: Involvement of women and youth in the management of security issues
The results of the axis 4 were achieved trought activities carried out by 2&#xA0;implementing partners:
- Center for Democratic Governance (CGD) for the implementation of the &quot;Project to strengthen the participation of women and girls in the promotion of peace, security and their resilience in the face of Covid-19&quot; 
- Association Burkina Camp de l&apos;Espoir (ABCE) for the implementation of the &quot;Project to strengthen the resilience of women and young people in the face of the rise of terrorism and violent extremism in the Province of Kossi&quot;
Results achieved:
A synergy of actions, an inter generational&#xA0;dialogue of women on issues of security and the advancement of women is possible because mixed women&apos;s clubs (180 women and young girls) are awareness-raising relays for the promotion of peace and security.&#xA0;
Endogenous dialogue and peace promotion mechanisms to prevent and manage terrorism and violent extremism exist: municipal security consultation frameworks (219 men and 33 women), home visits (4 200 people&#xA0;2715 women affected), an open day for the security and defense services is organised (29 men and 23 women).&#xA0;
5 Regions each have a gender citizen platform
Axis 5: Coordination, monitoring, evaluation, capitalization of achievements and promotion of innovative approaches
This axis is implemented by Diakonia the Manager of the Fund and concern actions for coordinating.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12696" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1660000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
