<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11838A0102-BFA-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Democratic Governance (CGD) 2019-2024</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Centre for Democratic Governance (CGD) 2019-2024</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sida avser st&#xF6;dja le Centre pour la Gouvernance D&#xE9;mocratique med 15 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r projektet &quot;st&#xE4;rka r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer, fr&#xE4;mja medvetenhet och demokratisk styrning i Burkina Faso&quot; under perioden 2019-2023.

Insatsen syftar till att bidra till ett fredligt samh&#xE4;lle med stabila institutioner. F&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; detta m&#xE5;l st&#xF6;ds tre huvudsakliga omr&#xE5;den: 

1: att st&#xE4;rka konstitutionen, r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer samt politisk och socioekonomisk styrning; 
2: att fr&#xE4;mja social sammanh&#xE5;llning och god styrning inom s&#xE4;kerhetssektorn; 
3: att fr&#xE4;mja institutionell utveckling av CGD.

Interventionens totala budget &#xE4;r cirka 17 700 000 kronor, varav Sidas bidrag &#xE4;r 15 miljoner kronor fr&#xE5;n 2019 till 2023 och ytterligare 300 000 kronor f&#xF6;r halvtids- och slututv&#xE4;rderingar 2021 och 2024. Danmark kommer att bidra ca 2, 4 miljoner kronor fr&#xE5;n 2019 till 2020.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida will support le Centre pour la Gouvernance D&#xE9;mocratique with 15 million SEK to carry out the project &quot;strengthening the rule of law, promoting civic awareness and democratic governance in Burkina Faso&quot; during the period 2019-2023 and additional 300 000 SEK for a mid-term and final evaluation respectively in 2021 and 2024. 

The intervention will support the construction of a peaceful society with stable institutions. To reach this objective, the cooperation partner has identified three areas: 
1: Strengthening the constitution, the rule of law and political as well as socio-economic governance;
2: Promoting civil society,  social cohesion and good governance in the security sector;
3: Building the institutional development of CGD.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is approximately 17 700 000 SEK, out of which Sida&#xB4;s contribution is 15 million kronor from 2019 to 2023 and additional 300 000 SEK for a mid-term and final evaluations in 2021 and 2024.  Denmark will contribute approximately 2,4 million SEK from 2019 to 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the intervention is to contribute to the construction of a peaceful society with stable public institutions in 2023.
To reach this global objective, the cooperation partner has identified the following three&#xA0;main axes of intervention :
Axis 1: Strengthening constitutionalism, the rule of law and political and socioeconomic governance;Axis 2: Promoting civic awareness, social cohesion and good governance in the security sector;Axis 3: Institutional support and organizational strengthening of the CGD.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CGD/Centre pour la Gouvernance Democratique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">10858.1169853524</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">21716.2339707048</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">10858.1169853524</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">21716.2339707048</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">31726.223839</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/burkina-faso/agreement-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/burkina-faso/11838_1183801_BF_011_2019_dEcisionCGD(1).pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/burkina-faso/bf_011_2019_decision-cgd.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The results presented below are drawn from the narrative reports for 2019 (final version) and 2020 (draft version), as well from information provided during the steering committee meeting of February 2020.&#xA0; A central part of CGD&apos;s activities is the organization of democratic dialogues&#xA0;which consist of inviting various actors to debate on the most important issues in the area of ??good governance. These debates aim to make relevant recommendations to improve the democratic governance of society. This is an activity that usually gathers between 150 and 400 people. Due to the Covid-19 pandemic, the government took steps to limit the spread of the virus which included on gatherings of more than fifty people. This made it impossible for the CGD to organize democratic dialogues as planned during 2020. Instead, they were organized in an alternative way through live TV broadcasts with the opportunity for viewers to call in to contribute or ask questions to the panellists. During 2020, five democratic dialogues were organized. The first democratic dialogue focused on the effects of covid-19 on the electoral process in Burkina Faso.The dialogue aroused great interest, attracted widespread attention and had the desired effects, as the president of Burkina Faso a few days later invited the majority and the opposition to a political dialogue on the issue.&#xA0; During 2020, CGD carried out several activities in the mining sector. These essentially focused on the citizen monitoring of the management of the mining development fund. Also, activities on the environmental and social impact of mining activities were carried out. These activities brought together local elected officials, women&apos;s and youth associations and other civil society organizations.&#xA0;In regards to the mining development fund, it can be noted that the advocacy conducted in 2019 with the mine chamber and the actions of the CGD in the field contributed to increasing the level of revenue collection for the fund. In fact, in the two intervention municipalities&#xA0;of Hound&#xE9; and Yalgo, a&#xA0; significant increase in revenues from the mining fund for the benefit of the mining commune of Hound&#xE9;&#xA0;has been noted, despite the fact that the mining company was initially reluctant to pay the fund.&#xA0; Another focus for&#xA0;CGD is strengthening the capacity of the national parliament. The recommendations of studies, advocacy meetings and technical support in terms of public policy and monitoring of these policies have contributed to the growth in capacity of Parliament in 2019 and 2020. In addition to its legislative production capacity, which has improved, there has been progress in parliament&apos;s&#xA0;efforts&#xA0;to monitor the implementation of policies and recommendations from parliamentary missions. This was made evident in the creation of a specific committee, CEPSUR (Commission d&#x2019;&#xE9;valuation des politiques et de suivi des recommandations). However the&#xA0;activities of the committee have been limited to following up on the recommendations of the parliamentary inquiry committees, and not as much the evaluation of public policies.  CGD has undertaken workshops for the capacity strengthening of locally elected officials and civil society organisations on&#xA0;the subject of&#xA0;civic participation&#xA0;in three different municipalities. These workshops have facilitated the implementation of a framework for civic&#xA0;participation&#xA0;on basic social services&#xA0;and resource management between elected officials&#xA0;and CSOs&#xA0;. With these frameworks for participation, CGD is promoting an improvement in local governance through the culture of management rigor and accountability. This approach bore fruit at&#xA0;the end of 2019, when the first participation&#xA0;framework meetings were held. This exercise allows for increased opportunities for population of these communities to participate in the efficient and effective management of public services.&#xA0; Another core CGD activity is the organisation of&#xA0;university students in cells to strengthen their knowledge of democratic values. During 2020, the focus was partly on the upcoming election. Each student had to register to be able to vote in the election and presented their voting card on the common platform. Each enrolled student then had to in turn mobilize five other students or youth from their neighborhood to do the same. This strategy made it possible to register thousands of students and has really contributed to the high proportion of young people enrolled in the electoral roll.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="11838" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
