<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-14063A0101-BFA-15131</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to human rights defenders national forum</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to human rights defenders national forum</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den Nationella kommissionen f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter i Burkina Faso har ans&#xF6;kt om finansiering fr&#xE5;n Sida om 90 000 kronor f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra ett nationellt forum i Ouagadougou under tv&#xE5; dagar  i januari under &#xE5;r 2020.
Insatsen syftar till att st&#xF6;dja den Nationella kommissionen f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter och st&#xE4;rka samarbetet med de andra akt&#xF6;rer som v&#xE4;rnar de m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheterna i Burkina Faso f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra deras kapacitet och deras programresultat.
Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 425 000 SEK, varav UNDP-finansierar cirka 347 500 SEK, eller 80 procent.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National Commission for Human Rights in Burkina Faso has applied to Sida for funding of 90 000 SEK to carry out a two-day national forum in Ouagadougou in January  2020. 
The intervention aims at supporting the National Commission for Human Rights to strenghten is collaboration with the other actors defending the human rights in Burkina Faso for improving their capacity and their programs results. 
The intervention&apos;s total budget is 425 000 SEK, out of which the UNDP funding is approximately 347 500 SEK, or 80 percent.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this contribution was to support the CNDH to hold a workshop with the human right defenders. The activity financed was specific and not really related to a theory of change nor to a frame of results based management. According to the agreement the partner provided lately in 2021 the narrative and the financial reports and the certification of financial report. The reports are relevant and the information complete to atteste the right use of the ressources provided by the embassy. Following the financial report statement, the partner had refund about 6 400 SEK to the embassy. The contribution should be then completed and closed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12004" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CNDH/Commission Nationale des Droits Humains</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12004" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other public entities in recipient country</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15131" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice, law and order policy, planning and administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.a - Strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels, in particular in developing countries, to prevent violence and combat terrorism and crime.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.a - St&#xE4;rka ber&#xF6;rda nationella institutioner, bland annat genom internationellt samarbete, i syfte att bygga upp kapacitet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, i synnerhet i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE5;ld och bek&#xE4;mpa terrorism och brottslighet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">9772.3052868172</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">8716.2448288218</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-676.2435258477</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">9772.305286</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">8716.2448288218</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">-676.2348393542</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This workshop involved 150 human right defenders from 45 provinces of the country. The overall objective of this meeting was to strengthen the partnership between the CNDH and other actors in the defense of human rights with a view to strengthening human right protection. In a specific way the workshop aims to:.&#xA0;Create a national framework for consultation between actors for the protection and defense of human rights;.&#xA0;Define the missions of HRDs in a context of security crisis;.&#xA0;Identify the major risks that HRDs face in the exercise of their missions. .&#xA0;Set up an alert mechanism (CNDH-other human rights actors) within the framework of the protection of HRDs;.&#xA0;Identify and set up at least two focal points of the CNDH in each province of Burkina Faso;. Make recommendations with a view to strengthening the protection of HRDs and creating an environment conducive to the implementation of strong and concerted actions between HRDs in the fight against violent extremism and terrorism. During the workshop, about 6 technical communications themes&#xA0;(1.&#xA0;The protection of human rights in a context of security crisis. 2.&#xA0;Human rights defenders in the united nations system.&#xA0;3. Legal framework for the protection and situation of human rights defenders.&#xA0;4.&#xA0;Role and missions of human rights defenders in the context of the security crisis.&#xA0;5.&#xA0;Risks and threats to human rights defenders in the context of the security crisis.&#xA0;6.&#xA0;What strategy for the protection of human rights defenders in a context of security crisis.)&#xA0;were made and group work carried out.The conclusions of this work led to the following recommendations: To the government : . Take all measures in accordance with the obligations arising from universal regional and national human rights texts to put an end to attacks against populations and the SDF . Ensure that operations to secure the territory comply with human rights and initiate investigations into allegations of human rights violations . Implement its obligation to ensure the protection of HRDs by taking all measures to investigate violations and infringements of their rights . Open investigations into acts carried out against defenders in the exercise of their activities to promote the protection and defense of human rights. To CNDH . Institutionalize this forum which provides a framework for consultation with stakeholders. . Accelerate the process of setting up the HRD protection mechanism.&#xA0; &#xA0; . Provide all necessary assistance to HRDs who are victims of violations of one or more of their rights. . Set up a monitoring committee for the implementation of the recommendations of the forum To the donors . Continue their support for the CNDH and human rights defenders organizations. . Provide technical and financial support for the operationalization of the HRD protection mechanism, . Provide support for the functioning of the periodic consultation framework between the commission and HRDs The outputs of the activity have been achieved but for the expected outcomes and results the implementation of all these recommandations will be an assets and a important condition to achieve the results.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="14063" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1660000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Burkina Faso 2018-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
