<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-KHF-MonitoringEvaluation</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" secondary-reporter="0" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4. Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and evaluating implementation of the project is conducted throughout the life cycle of the project to review the progress of the planned activities and ensure goals and objectives are achieved as planned and reassess and adjust if needed.Through various meetings and communication via email and phone, and later during the quarantine period through online communication tools (Skype /zoom/teams) with the Monitoring and Evaluation specialist in the project management unit, an evaluation plan in line with the project proposal and action plan to be used as way to track the progress of the project was designed. This plan contains different elements such as relevant outputs
indicators, indicators grids with columns designed to show any disaggregation required and mean of verification, source of information used to collect the indicator, person responsible for data collection, when the indicator should be collected, how often the indicator should be collected, baseline and target distributed over three years (2020,2021,2022). Monitoring tools annexed</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="JOD" value-date="2020-10-31">0</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
