<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-KHF-VI. Partnerships-Y2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" secondary-reporter="0" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VI. Partnerships</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VI. Partnerships:
The project is implemented by a consortium led by the King Hussein foundation and its two sister organizations the Institute for Family Health (IFH) and the Information and Research Center (IRCKHF) in collaboration with I Am Human Society for Rights of Persons with Disability.   The consortium also collaborates with like-minded civil society organizations mainly Jordanian National Commission for Women (JNCW), Human Society for Rights of Persons with Disability, National Woman&#x2019;s Health Care Center (NWHCC), the National Council for Family Affairs (NCFA) and the Higher Population Council (HPC). Partnership with the public sector is also ensured through development of capacity of the Ministry of Health staff in GBC protocol, code of conduct and referral pathways. 

Agreements have been made with two main stakeholders;  the National Council for Family Affairs  (NCFA) and the Higher Population Council (HPC) to conduct pre-assessment for the 4 Centers Sweileh, Karak, Zarqa and Ajloun to measure the current level of adhering with &#x201C;The Standards National Procedures manual for the prevention and response to gender-based, family violence and violence against children&#x201D; that was developed by NCFA in 2017 and &#x201C;The National Standards for Youth-Friendly Sexual and Reproductive Health Services&#x201D; that was developed by HPC.
The Knowledge Attitude and Practices study on marriage contracts component is implemented in partnership with the Jordanian National Commission for Women (JNCW), with whom a Memorandum of Understanding has been signed. Project consultants include Dr. Sara Ababneh and Dr. Hayel Daoud, with whom consultancy contracts have been signed. IRCKHF met with project partners and consultants to discuss the project objectives, expected outcomes, specifically the marriage contracts component and what this research will focus on.
The KAP study was assigned to a third party with strong quantitative research skills and experience to conduct the study nationally with a sample size increase from 1200 surveys to 2500. The procurement process was undertaken as per the King Hussein procurement Policy and supervised by the PMU Head of Logistics and Procurement Unit. An agreement was signed with We Field to measure the Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practices on women&#x2019;s legal rights to add stipulation on marriage contract among males and females across Jordan, to formulate baseline data on Gender-Based Violence to generate an understanding of the current situation in Jordan, and consequently formulate the most effective and efficient programs, activities, or lobbying on the subject. WeField will be responsible to identify the target population knowledge, attitudes, and practices (KAP) related to stipulation on marriage contracts, and Gender-Based Violence, measure differences in Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practices towards the subject of the study between different segments (Gender, Areas, Age, Socio-Economic Classes &#x2026;etc., capture past and current experiences in the subject and ways of dealing with the same, and the impact caused, understand people&#x2019;s expected changes of behavior in the future and adaptation levels to stipulations on marriage contract, identify the important social and cultural norms and the associated behavioral determinants related to subject of the study, and support identifying programs and activities that may contribute positively to face GBV and its implication on society and women&#x2019;s right with regards to marriage contracts.

WeField / Headway was established to capitalize on over 2 decades of market research experience by professionals who are passionate about market research to support the success of businesses by translating data into valuable and actionable insights

Our partners from the I Am Human Society and the Institute for Family Health contributed to producing the policy paper on ending violence against women and girls with disabilities in Jordan and the access to justice in its final form. This paper was presented through a discussion session with representatives of the National Council for Family Affairs, the Jordanian National Commission for Women, and the Higher Council for the Rights of Persons with Disabilities to collectively develop the recommendations of the policy paper, which achieves the purpose of producing this paper and gives it importance if it is given to policymakers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AT-99</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
