<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-KHF-V. Sustainability-Y2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" secondary-reporter="0" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V. Sustainability</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V. Sustainability

Consortium Partners &amp; networking: The proposed project is implemented by a consortium led the King Hussein Foundation (KHF), a national multiciliary development organization that was able to sustain its programs for over three decades through internal and external sources of funding with a track record of initiating programs and continue supporting high impact programs. The expertise of the consortium&#x2019;s partners including KHF&#x2019;s renowned healthcare and policy and research institutes and the strategic partner on people with disability will ensure institutional sustainability and build on the existing human resources and models to continue provision of high-quality services and access to information during and after the completion of the project. Networking and coordinating with other existing programs of the consortium partners and other like-minded organizations will also contribute to the long-term sustainability and form strong synergies and a holistic approach to strengthening the protective environment for women in Jordan whereby beneficiaries of the project can have access to the services provided by the partners after the completion of the project. 

Marriage Contract Template: The template for a marriage contract with all of the optional conditions accepted in Islam, will be made accessible online on at least two websites, that of the Jordanian National Commission for Women, and HAQQI, the open-access information site of the King Hussein Foundation. The partners anticipate that the religious clergy and scholars, who were engaged in the discussions and design on the template during the second and third year of the project, will share the template with all the couples to be married and be able to explain in details supported by evidence -based findings what the conditions mean and how they can be used to prevent marriage conflicts and protect women&#x2019;s rights. The milestone would be that this template will be made officially accessible on a national scale and KHF will continue to work towards achieving this goal during and after the completion of the project. In the long-term, the more couples use the template for their Muslim marriage contracts, the more it will become a common practice and hopefully one day a social norm. KHF and its partners will host dissemination events, roundtables, and meetings with local stakeholders, including policymakers and practitioners, working in women&#x2019;s rights, gender equality, prevention of gender-based violence and early marriage who will be able to use the contract template as a tool to eliminate GBV in all their projects. 

Capacity Building: By setting a capacity-building objective including enhancement of CBOs and public sector capacity on GBV project design, GBV protocol, standard operating procedures (SOPs), code of conduct and referral systems, a long-term sustainability in responding to a mass rooted GBV in the community will be ensured. By building the capacity of service providers especially CBOs, who are the primary contact and front line of the civil society, high quality services will be ensured and sustained after the project is completed.  The Media training and the cooperation with the media is also another sustainable factor.  Additionally, setting up a proper system for collecting evidence will yield long term benefits and will serve as a resource for other groups who would like to litigate GBV complaints.  

Advocacy and awareness: The national media campaign will be sustained by the dissemination of tailored awareness-raising messages in local communities, including online sessions on issues related to social, psychological and religious aspects linked to domestic violence and protection services. The Jordanian National Commission for Women&#x2019;s national network, Neshmiat, who will be part of the project&#x2019;s national campaigns, will also continue to inform and share information and messages with their local communities to ensure sustainability. Advocacy efforts will be also sustained by a dedicated campaign, displaying awareness raising messages addressing all age groups. Overall, KHF in collaboration with the its partners, will promote all its activities, findings and services through its partners&#x2019; media and social media channels, including radio and TV interviews.

Scalability and replicability: By the end of the proposed program, the evidence-based impact (Social return on Investment reports) will allow the partner organizations to measure and value the results achieved by the project and the contributions that made the activities possible and successful as well as the change affected from the activities told from the perspective of the beneficiaries and stakeholders. This report will inform the King Hussein Foundation and partners on the most evidence based successful activities that can be scaled up and replicated in different parts of the Kingdom. 


During the policy paper launch event, part of the event was devoted to holding working groups with the aim of reviewing these recommendations and identifying the parties responsible for their implementation during the advocacy campaign. As marriage contract conditions, the authority will be granted to the advocacy committee whenever it deems it appropriate to design an independent interactive website for inquiries about marriage contracts conditions. Another option is to host it on the National Committee for Women&#x2019;s Affairs or the National Council for Family Affairs websites in addition to the Haqqi website.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AT-99</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
