<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-KHF-3.Advocacy and Media campaign and partnership network-3.3-Y2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" secondary-reporter="0" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3. Advocacy and Media campaign and partnership network: 
3.3. developing partnerships increase outreach and generate support for sustainability and long-term impact. All relevant partners in this project will partner with like-minded organization who are implementing projects that are in line with the objectives of this proposed project to enhance outreach, sustainability and long-term impact.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. developing partnerships increase outreach and generate support for sustainability and long-term impact. All relevant partners in this project will partner with like-minded organization who are implementing projects that are in line with the objectives of this proposed project to enhance outreach, sustainability and long-term impact. 

The Project developed partnership wish different national organizations for sustainability and long-term impact like: The Jordanian National Commission for Women (JNCW), National Council For Family Affairs NCFA, the National Woman&#x2019;s Health Care Center (NWHC), Higher Population Council (HPC), Supreme Judge Department (SJD), General IFTAA&#x2019; Department GID, Royal Institute for Interfaith Studies (RIIFS), National Center for Human Rights NCHR, Higher Council for the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (HCD). 

Additionally, partnerships were established with GBV service providers from the civil society sector and the public sector in the South region including Ministries of Health, Social Development, Education, Justice, Interior, Labour, in addition to the Police Directorate, Family Protection and Juvenile Department Media Commission, Aqaba Special Economic Zone Authority (ASEZA)- and Municipalities of Tafileh, Karak Maan and Aqaba. List of community based organizations attached. Work is in progress to engage youth representatives in the awarness and advocacy efforts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AT-99</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
