<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-law22.1999-XI-IATI-KHF-3. Advocacy and Media campaign and partnership network-3.2-Y2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" secondary-reporter="0" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3. Advocacy and Media campaign and partnership network: 
3.2 Mobilize the public, change perceptions, and build support to influence decision-makers and stakeholders around legal women&#x2019;s rights regarding marriage and Gender based Violence through the design and implementation of mass media</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2 Mobilize the public, change perceptions, and build support to influence decision-makers and stakeholders around legal women&#x2019;s rights regarding marriage and Gender based Violence through the design and implementation of mass media:

3.2.1 Awareness and advocacy utilizing media and social media to influence decision-makers and the public.

Marriage Contracts awareness campaign:
Design of the communication and advocacy plans. (Annex 3: Communication Plan)
Through a tender and in close cooperation with the King Hussein Foundation and PMU, a specialized company was selected to design and implement the awareness campaign to disseminate the findings of the knowledge, attitudes, and practices of Jordanian society when it comes to Muslim marriage contracts and their stipulations. As a separate component, but also part of this media campaign, the cartoonist Emad Hajjaj was selected to develop a series of caricatures regarding the research findings. IRCKHF team developed the material of social media posts.
Two brainstorming sessions were held at the Information and Research Center and attended by representatives of the Embassy of the Netherlands in Amman, project partners, the cartoonist Emad Hajjaj, and the company that was selected to design the awareness campaign materials, such as social media posts, videos, etc. These sessions were a prelude to launching the awareness campaign, as in this session, there was a presentation of the results of the quantitative research on the conditions of marriage contracts and the perceptions of the institution responsible for designing the awareness campaign material on the mechanism for implementing this campaign.
After extensive contacts with the team at the Information and Research Center, the company designed a logo for the campaign and suggested designs for social media posts. This content and designs are currently being reviewed before their launch on social media platforms.

The cartoonist designed five drawings that include the character of Abu Mahjoob to convey messages through the character and reflect the most important research findings on the use of conditions in marriage contracts. Currently, these drawings are under review in terms of content and design

Advisory committee for advocacy efforts: Through meeting with Dr. Hayel, he added his recommendations on the suggested panel names to supervise the Marriage Contract Conditions Awareness Campaign. His honor, the Chief Judge, was approached for the placement of an expert from the Chief Judge Department within the committee. After contacting the suggested names, confirmations were obtained from: 
o	Mahmoud Abu Rumman, Shari&apos;a Judge, Chief Judge Department
o	Representative from the Iftaa&apos; Department.
o	Dr. Hayel Daoud, the Sharia consultant (Shari&#x2019;a Professor at the University of Jordan)
o	Representative from the Royal Institute For Inter Faith Studies
o	Mr. Kamal Mashriqi &#x2013; Human rights expert
o	Representative from the Jordanian National Commission for Women
o	Representative from the National Council for Family Affairs.
o	Youth representative 
The list of candidates for the advocacy committee will be finalized in year 3, with feedback from the Embassy of the Netherlands in Amman. The first meeting is expected to take place in January 2022.

3.2.2	Creation of crowd map to generate data in order to mobilize local communities, through which the public can read more stories and case summaries about the documented cases in order to grow an engaged online and offline community that can be mobilized to demand justice, equality, and increased protections for disabled women. 

Work is in progress to establish a crowd map to generate data to mobilize local communities including two major components ; 1) a search engine / file open to the public whereby the browsers can access a monthly updated information and news relevant to people with disabilities including the most prominent local, regional and international news and topics related to legislations, national policies and best practices through successful models, success stories and lessons learnt  locally, regionally and internationally and 2) a data bank that provides browsers with access to studies, researches, and strategies that tackles issues relevant to people with disabilities updated monthly through an online accessible calendar on the crowd map. This activity will be conducted in the 3rd year of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-law22.1999" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King Hussein Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AT-99</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
