<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011292-02-4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to the Social and Economic Development of Rakhine State through the Safeguard, Management and Valorisation of the Mrauk-U site.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Breve illustrazione dell&apos;iniziativa con particolare riferimento ai seguenti elementi essenziali contenuti nel documento di progetto: origini e contesto dell&apos;iniziativaIl Rakhine &#xE8; recentemente balzato agli onori della cronaca internazionale in relazione alla crisi della popolazione Rohingya. In realt&#xE0;, sia le autorit&#xE0; locali che la comunit&#xE0; internazionale sono da tempo impegnate nell&#x2019;area con iniziative volte a mitigare sia situazioni di conflitto, sia eventi naturali straordinari (inondazioni). Da alcuni mesi l&#x2019;attenzione ha iniziato a concentrarsi sulle tematiche del sottosviluppo e della povert&#xE0;, che sono alla base dei conflitti etnici e dell&#x2019;instabilit&#xE0; dell&#x2019;area. Al fine di individuare e lavorare su tali tematiche, il Governo birmano (insediatosi nell&#x2019;aprile del 20162) ha nominato una Commissione Consultiva sul Rakhine (Kofi Annan Commission - KAC) guidata dall&#x2019;ex Segretario Generale delle Nazioni Unite Kofi Annan.3 La KAC individua infatti nella povert&#xE0; e nel sottosviluppo del Rakhine uno degli elementi che alimentano i conflitti in corso, suggerendo la realizzazione di interventi di sviluppo economico come misura di mitigazione. Il patrimonio culturale assume una posizione di rilievo nelle raccomandazioni della KAC, con particolare riferimento alla valorizzazione del sito monumentale di Mrauk-U. Il Governo del Myanmar ha ufficialmente assicurato il suo impegno nel dare seguito alle raccomandazioni contenute sia nell&apos;Interim Report (marzo 2017) che in quello finale, pubblicato il 24 agosto u.s.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rakhine State has been mainly targeted by Donors with emergency response or humanitarian funds, due to the conflicts in the area and to natural disasters often occurring.&lt;br&gt;Since its establishment in April 2016, the new Government has tried to address the main causes of the social tensions and instability in the area: poverty and under-development. The importance of sustainable socio-economic development of Rakhine State as a mean for stability has also been raised by the Advisory Commission on Rakhine (KAC), appointed by the Government to investigate on the causes underlying the under-development of Rakhine State. KAC has issued a preliminary report in March 2017 (immediately endorsed by the Government), while the Final Report followed on 24 August 2017.&lt;br&gt;One of the recommendations issued by KAC involves the valorization of Mrauk-U site in the perspective of social inclusion and economic development.&lt;br&gt;In line with this, the Project intends to contribute to the local economy development by a capacity development of the Entities and the Civil Society Organizations (CSO) of the area strengthening the management and the sustainable use of the Mrauk-U site.&lt;br&gt;To do so, the Project will:&lt;br&gt;a) sustain local authorities of the Department of Archaeology (DOA) of the Ministry of Religious Affairs and Culture in managing and protecting the monuments and temples of Mrauk-U, through capacity building and capacity development actions. Specific activities will include cultural and environmental mapping, documentation, conservation and/or restoration of monuments and mapping of the ancient hydrological channels network as a significant part of Mrauk-U cultural landscape;&lt;br&gt;b) promote actions to leverage the community economic and social development through a participatory approach. Specific activities are envisaged for the public opinion and the youth for understanding the need to preserve this site&#x2019;s fragile environment and to sensitize the community towards its promotion;&lt;br&gt;c) support local entrepreneurs in developing their skills and enhancing their businesses valorizing the local intangible heritage (traditional arts and crafts) and/or promoting tourism related activities. Training and business support should increase employment and income thus fostering economic development.&lt;br&gt;These actions, will be carried out engaging the Civil Society Organizations and training their staff, assuring that the protection of cultural intangible assets goes together with sustainable development.&lt;br&gt;Specific initiatives for children and the overall community will strengthen the community awareness and understanding of the local heritage values.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011292/02/4" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2017000349" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="41040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Site preservation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, devise and implement policies to promote sustainable tourism that creates jobs and promotes local culture and products</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-27">1000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-01">580000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-20">420000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-28">-263768</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-07">-512000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011292-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
