<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011870-01-4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">S.A.F.E. C.R.O.P.S. : Sesamo, Arachide, Fagiolo: Economie Comunitarie Resilienti e Organizzazione della Produzione Sostenibile in Dry Zone, Myanmar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">La proposta, nel suo obiettivo specifico, mira a migliorare le economie delle famiglie contadine e delle micro e piccole imprese che fanno parte delle filiere del sesamo, arachide e fagiolo (mungo verde), principali coltivazioni e fonti di entrata nelle zone di intervento. Le componenti del progetto agiscono sulle principali restrizioni che, a livello di filiera, ne limitano uno sviluppo integrato, sostenibile ed inclusivo, in particolare migliorando: - Gli aspetti produttivi (componente/Risultato 1), aumentando le disponibilit&#xE0; locali di variet&#xE0; adattate di sementi (climate smart), favorendo l&apos;applicazione di tecniche di coltivazione certificate (Good Agricultural Practices, GAP), sostenibili ed efficienti, facilitando l&apos;accesso al credito agevolato per i fabbisogni produttivi individuali - L&apos;accesso al mercato (componente/R2), privilegiando la vendita congiunta attraverso l&apos;unica Associazione contadina in Dry Zone presente a livello regionale, facilitando la produzione a contratto e l&apos;accesso al credito agevolato per i fabbisogni associativi e delle micro e piccole imprese di filiera Gli aspetti di governance (componente/R3), rafforzando l&apos;organizzazione associativa, le inter-relazioni e le capacit&#xE0; dei servizi di estensionismo pubblico, promuovendo la pianificazione partecipativa multi-attore dei servizi e di politiche sinergiche di filiera.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The specific objective of the proposal is to improve the economies of the small farms and of the micro and small enterprises that are part of the sesame, groundnut and green gram value chains, the main crops and sources of income in the areas of intervention.  The components of the project act on the main restrictions which, at the level of the value chain, limit its integrated, sustainable and inclusive development, in particular by improving: - Production aspects (component/Result 1), increasing local availability of adapted varieties of seeds (climate smart), promoting the application of certified cultivation techniques (Good Agricultural Practices, GAP), sustainable and efficient, facilitating access to credit for individual production needs. - Access to the market (component/R2), favoring joint selling through the only Farmers&apos; Association present at regional level in the Dry Zone, facilitating contract farming and access to facilitated credit for the needs of associations and micro and small businesses in the value chain. - Governance aspects (component/R3), strengthening the associative organization, inter-relationships and capacities of public extension services, promoting multiactor participatory planning of services and synergistic value chain policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CESVI FONDAZIONE ONLUS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011870/01/4" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2019000251" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, reduce at least by half the proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End poverty in all its forms everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development, provide access to justice for all and build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions at all levels</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-12">1723398.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CESVI FONDAZIONE ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">577258.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CESVI FONDAZIONE ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-13">591057.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CESVI FONDAZIONE ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-12">554830.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CESVI FONDAZIONE ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
