<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="99" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17523" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ISLAMIC-AF-15-17523</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assisting Orphans Education in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) The project is proposing to support a total of 658 Orphans including to provide support to the present Orphans in Khoog Koor School of Jalalabad, Nangrahar province. The project is also aiming to pilot a community based component to support orphans in Bamyan province. In particular, they will be helped through improved livelihoods, hygiene proportion and water and sanitation including awareness raising on child rights. 

2) There are poor conditions for education, health and sanitation facilities for orphans and their families and lack of livelihood means for the families. The project will therefore support education, health and sanitation conditions as well as the economic situations of the orphan&#x2019;s families to ensure sustainability. This will be an extension of the previous project, extend support to orphans out of the orphanage and ensure means of livelihood for families. 

3) The project will continue support to Khog Koor orphanage from the previous IR USA funded project. In Bamyan, the project will focus on community based support to orphan education through improved conditions of orphan&#x2019;s families with sustainable livelihoods, water and Sanitation, hygiene promotion and skills enhancement. The vocational training skills facilitate their families to have means of livelihood that will provide sustainable economic support. This will complement, extend and sustain the 1-to-1 orphans support to their families as well. An assessment will be conducted to select vocations based on demands in the community, considering cultural and social issues and on the market. The survey will be conducted in coordination with Department of Labor and Social Affairs and support of community council.

4) Key Deliverables:
&#x2022; Provide quality education to 658 Orphans 
&#x2022; Provide school uniforms, bags and other required stationary and learning materials for 658 students. 
&#x2022; Provide health and sanitation awareness sessions to 658 beneficiaries and provision of hygiene kits
&#x2022; Provide skill development trainings to 200 women
&#x2022; Piloting formation of groups of 10-15 beneficiaries as business group</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To provide quality education to orphans in Nangarhar and Bamyan provinces through improved sustainable livelihoods and skill enhancement. This project is envisaging a shift from orphanage based approach to community based approach through improved family livelihoods, skill enhancement, hygiene promotion and child rights awareness raising.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-95-4453134" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ISLAMIC-AF-15-17523" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.irusa.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (Individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="658"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
