<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28691</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SB Thai NPL</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is well-aligned with IFCs Debt and Asset Recovery Program (DARP), a crisis response initiative that aims to create a programmatic and strategic response to the increasing DA in financial systems and thereby have a systemic impact on cleaning up the financial systems where build up of DA will occur.  Board Approval for utilizing US$600mn of economic capital under DARP globally has been obtained. The East Asia Region (CEA) has been identified as a target for the initial implementation of DARP. The proposed investment will further mobilize investments by Standard Bank in partnership with IFC.  In CEA, IFC plans to work with a group of select servicing companies and investors (Fanny Yang Tai, ACAP, Standard Bank) and provide financing currently not available due to traditional investors either exiting the market or facing liquidity constraints.   The project would consist of a series of Senior Loan, Equity and Quasi Equity investments by IFC in pools of distressed assets located in emerging markets in the East Asia Region. It is anticipated that this exposure would be diversified across 3 to 5 transactions that would occur over a one year period. This exposure would be counted as part of the exposure approved to be taken under the Distressed Asset Recovery Program approved by the Board. The pools of distressed assets to be acquired and resolved under this Facility would be identified jointly by IFC and Standard Bank and would be required to meet certain objective criteria and their resolution would have to be carried out on the basis of   servicing arrangements and standards that are acceptable to IFC. The details of these arrangements would be spelt out in a Memorandum of Understanding with Standard Bank that would serve as framework for this partnership. The commercial terms and its compliance with the agreed criteria of each transaction would be evaluated on a case to case basis.  All transactions under this Facility would be consistent with the overall approach established for the DARP program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Well-structured distressed asset transactions improve the stability of the banking system by:   - encouraging transparency in balance sheets as the true value of distressed assets is determined by the market value paid by the buyers of NPLs;  - Active recovery efforts of NPL servicers, who have different incentives from the typical workout departments of commercial banks, help contribute to the economy by redeploying assets pledged as collateral by defaulting borrowers which can lie idle once the loan is in default.  The ability of NPL investors and servicers to make settlements with the borrowers also helps many borrowers to de-leverage their balance sheets to sustainable debt levels thereby aiding/reviving companies, and  - Improvement of credit culture in emerging markets by creating disincentives for willful default</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standard Bank PLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28691" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nick Hamilton Managing Director, Standard Merchant Bank (Asia) Ltd 80 Raffles Place 41-01 UOB Plaza One Singapore 309420 +65 6232 8929 Nick.hamilton@standardbank.com.sg</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TH-Thailand">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project would finance NPL pools across the Asian Region, predominantly in East Asia.  The key counterpart is Standard Bank Plc, headquartered in London, and a subsidiary of Standard Bank Group. The Singapore branch of Standard Bank will work jointly with IFC in investing in NPL pools in Asia.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.5000000000 101.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5221" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AJ - Commercial Banking - Distressed Assets</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $75.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-12-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-12-15">75000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-12-15">75000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standard Bank PLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28691/sb-thai-npl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
