<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-506048</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GEF Asian Conservation Corporation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the ACC is to provide a financial return for investors while also generating a conservation return in terms of increased preservation of ecologically-significant marine habitats. The ACC has currently achieved a committed capitalization of $12.25 million towards its targeted level of $16.0 million.  It is managed by Next Century Partners, a Manila-based fund management company.     The purpose of this project is to conserve significant coastal and marine biodiversity through a unique partnership between a private equity investment holding company (ACC) and two local nongovernmental organizations.  IFC will channel a total of $4.5 million in GEF grant funds for the two local NGOs to carry out conservation activities in the six biodiversity rich areas mentioned above. The conservation activities in the Tranche 1 site of El Nido will be implemented by the El Nido Foundation (ENF).  The conservation activities in the five Tranche 2 sites in the Visayan Sea will be implemented by the World Wildlife Fund-Philippines (WWF-P).   ENF and WWF-P will involve and foster ownership among multiple stakeholders, including governmental agencies, local communities, private sector operators, and other local NGOs. The conservation activities will include: conservation management, marine enforcement, information-education-communication, sustainable livelihoods, biodiversity research and monitoring, and development of institutional and financial sustainability mechanisms.  The ACC portfolio companies  Ten Knots Corporation and Stellar Fisheries  will allocate some of their revenues to sustain these conservation activities after the GEF funds are fully utilized.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNKNOWN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-506048" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ms. Leigh Talmage-P&#xE9;rez				   President, Asian Conservation Company 		   #10-14, Ayala Tower One				   Ayala Avenue, Makati City  1226   Philippines   Phone: (63-2) 813-4678; (63-2) 848-6742   Fax: (63-2) 848-6741   Email: Leigh@asianconserve.com   www.asianconserve. com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PH-Philippines">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will be implemented in two tranches.  The first tranche will be implemented in El Nido, Palawan, which is a coastal area containing 19 communities and a marine protected area of significant biological importance.  The second tranche will be implemented in five sites within the Visayan Sea, including Sangay Reserve (Negros Occidental), Asid Gulf (Masbate), North Guimaras Strait (Negros), Estancia and Concepcion (Northern Iloilo), and Bantayan Island (Cebu).  All of these areas in the Visayan Sea contain significant marine biodiversity and fishing communities that will participate in this project.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0000000000 122.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">C - Finance Companies</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/506048/gef-asian-conservation-corporation">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
