<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26201</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Hospital 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHIs expansion and upgraded facilities will improve the overall level of healthcare being offered in metro Manila.  Increased private sector participation in the Philippines health sector is expected to improve service quality, efficiency and free up the Governments limited resources for public health care programs.    Specifically, the project will help:  - Expand AHIs capacity to better serve the local population:   AHI will continue to grow in patient volume with the expected population growth of 7% per annum in the South of Metro Manila.  With the emphasis on the working age group outpatient services are expected to increase at a pace greater than 10% and inpatient service to increase at about 4% per year.  - Increasing standards for delivery of health services in the Philippines:   As one of the leading hospitals in the country, AHI is constantly introducing new practices and procedures which the rest of the market is frequently compelled to follow.  Based on discussions with the DOH and others, Asian Hospital has already had an evident and positive impact on both public and private hospitals by causing them to improve facilities and services to keep up with AHI.  - Assimilate and disseminate best practices in delivery of health services from a leading global healthcare provider:    This project is a South-South investment and includes significant South-South knowledge transfer from a leading international healthcare provider, Bumrungrad Hospital (BH) of Thailand.   - Attractive employment alternative/stem brain drain:    There is a large out-migration of health professionals from the Philippines.  This expansion project will help to retain talent in-country by providing opportunities to work in a world-class health care environment.  Currently AHI has over 1,000 registered doctors and 900 employed staff.  This will increase with the expansion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Hospital, Inc., (AHI or the company) an existing IFC client, was founded in December 1994 with the strategy of developing the first major private hospital with tertiary care facilities in the southern Luzon corridor of metropolitan Manila.  Due to strong demand, the Hospital has reached or is quickly reaching its effective capacity in several service areas.  To address this it is planning to enhance its operations and expand its outpatient and inpatient facilities.  As well, it plans to normalize its debt structure through the refinancing of the majority of its existing debt.  The project cost is estimated at PHP3,056 million.    IFC has been invited by Asian Hospital to be the lead lender and arranger for the project and provide a peso denominated A Loan of up to PHP1,260 million.  Bumrungrad International Ltd. will participate in the equity financing for the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIAN HOSPITAL, INC.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26201" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-02-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-02-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main Sponsor Contact: Theo Seiler  Chief Financial Officer Asian Hospital, Inc. Phone:  +63-2771 9000 ext. 8402  E-mail:     tseiler@asianhospital.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PH-Philippines">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Hospital is located in the southern Luzon corridor of metropolitan Manila.  The hospital is located in an urban area with sufficient access provided to it by near by highways and roads.  Its location in the southern portion of Luzon is of particular importance since most other major hospitals are located to the north.  Since Bumrungrads involvement, the hospital has undergone various initiatives to prepare for its expansion.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0000000000 122.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Hospitals and Clinics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $29.39 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-02-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-02-08">29390000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-02-08">29390000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASIAN HOSPITAL, INC.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26201/asian-hospital-2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
