<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26987</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mindoro Resources Ltd</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFC released the original SPI in September 24, 2008. The project was not submitted to the IFC Board as exploration activities ceased due to the global financial crisis. In April 2010, the company restarted exploration and IFC undertook its second review. This SPI updates the version previously disclosed (please see attached) and should be read in conjunction with it.  Mindoro Resources Ltd (Mindoro, or the Company) objective is to build a successful exploration and mining company in the Philippines with focus on nickel, copper and gold.  Mindoros primary asset is the 75% interest in the Agata nickel laterite deposit in the Agusan del Norte Region, Northern Mindanao Island. The Agata nickel prospect has the potential to become a sizeable nickel mine with resources possibly in excess of 100 million tons at comparatively attractive nickel grades. Agata has a NI 43-101 compliant measured and indicated resource of 36.5 million wet metric tonnes at 1.11% nickel (dry), containing 657 million pounds of nickel and 24 million pounds of cobalt. Mindoro also owns interests in gold, copper, and copper-gold prospects in the Surigao District, Batangas District on Luzon Island, and on Pan de Azucar Island.  IFC equity investment will support Mindoros resource drilling, feasibility and other studies, and exploration activities for its nickel, copper and gold prospects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is in exploration phase so its development impacts are limited in scope at this stage. However, the project is located in an underdeveloped part and frontier region of the country. It is outside of key centers of commercial activity and will likely contribute significantly to the areas development should it transition into a full operating mine and refining operation. Expected impacts would include generation of employment, local economic development through purchases of goods and services, improved access to infrastructure, and payments to central and local governments in the form of taxes and royalties.  Mindoro has also entered into a novel partnership arrangement with local artisanal miners to help them secure small scale mining permits and meet environmental and social compliance requirements. Mindoro has also entered into a Benefits Sharing Arrangement with local indigenous people committing the Company to providing employment opportunities, skills training, scholarship funds and a share of any mining revenues.  During the exploration phase the key impacts to monitor will include: (i) finalization of drilling program and resource confirmation; (ii) number of local employees; (iii) completion of feasibility studies confirming mine planning and applicable onsite processing techniques; and (iv) completion of required Social and Environmental assessments for each stage of development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mindoro Resources Ltd</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26987" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jon Dugdale Director, President and CEO, Mindoro Resources Ltd Email: jon@mindoro.com Tel: (780) 413-8187 Toll Free: 1-877-413-8187 (North America only) Fax: (780) 426-2716  J A (Tony) Climie, P. Geol Director of Exploration, COO  Mindoro Resources Ltd. President, CEO - MRL Gold Phils. Inc Email : tony@mindoro.com Tel: (780) 413-8187 Toll Free: 1-877-413-8187 (North America only) Fax: (780) 426-2716  Penny Gould VP Investor Relations  Mindoro Resources Ltd. Email: penny@mindoro.com Tel: (780) 413-8187 Toll Free: 1-877-413-8187 (North America only) Fax: (780) 426-2716  Websites&#xA0;: www.mindoro.com www.mrlgold.com.ph</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="PH-Philippines">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Companys principal exploration tenement, Agata, is located in Agusan del Norte, 40 km south of Surigao City in the north western portion of Mindanao Island.  The tenement is largely undeveloped and sparsely populated ridge running adjacent to Mindanao Bay on the West and bounded by Lake Mainit. The area was logged prior to the 1970s, with very limited tree cover over low level ferns and similar vegetation. Mindoros secondary exploration target, Batangas, on the Southern coast of Luzon Island is being explored under a joint venture agreement with an international major Gold Fields Ltd.  Mindoro has approximately 30 employees, primarily based in Surigao. The Company also has an office in Manila.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.0000000000 122.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BD - Nickel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $9.53 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-07-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-07-14">9530000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-07-14">9530000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mindoro Resources Ltd</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26987/mindoro-resources-ltd">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
