<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41210820-FGG-ToC1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41210820" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Clothes Campaign</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FGG CCC ToC 1: Improved Corporate Conduct</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Clothes Campaign (CCC) aims to improve working conditions in the global garment industry, and to this aim engages in lobby, advocacy, campaigning and awareness raising targeting all stakeholders involved throughout the ready-made-garment supply chains. In its five-year global strategic framework the CCC network has committed to joint actions on the key issues of wages, occupational health and safety and stable employment relationships. Freedom of association and gender are at the core of these issues. Freedom of association is fundamental to bargain collectively and to advance occupational health and safety, increase wages, ensure full employment relationships and end discrimination. A thorough understanding of how gender shapes the experiences of women garment workers and perpetuates patterns of exploitation, needs to be at the basis of bottom-up worker organising, participation and bargaining. In this program, CCC will work with partners in key garment producing countries to support their lobby and advocacy work to increase the national minimum wage levels and implement minimum wage legislation. In the context of national wage struggles CCC will pressure brands and retailers to increase wages throughout the entire supply chains to a living wage level. CCC will lobby MSIs to put in place mechanisms to require from companies to provide time-bound progress on the implementation from living wages in their supply chains. CCC will work with partners in key garment producing countries to pressure governments to enforce better national and international regulations on Occupational Health and Safety and access to remedy, of workers&#x2019; safety. The CCC will strengthen the network with National and Global Unions, NGOs to pressure companies to realize effective OHS programs involving unions and workers. Capacity building of unions and federations in Bangladesh focus on identifying gender based abuses and violences at work, family and society; at Bangladesh factory level trade unions and their federations in organising, representation, negotiation and lobby work. Unions and labour NGOs from Bangladesh, Pakistan, Sri Lanka and India will have the opportunity to learn key lessons from the implementation of the Bangladesh Accord at a Asia level meeting CCC will engage in lobby and advocacy to ensure the use of precarious work arrangements in the global supply chain (short-term or fixed-duration contracts, part-time, casual and seasonal work, apprenticeships, &apos;sumangali&apos; schemes etc.) is regulated. As a result of this work, Southern organisations will be provided with knowledge and capacity building on precarious work arrangements, protection when defending rights in concrete cases of abuse of contracts, and increased space to engage in lobby and advocacy at supply chain, national and global level. In 2016 the CCC together with Global Unions, National Federations and labour NGOs will form National and Global coalitions and improve strategies to campaign and pressure governments to take punitive actions to end attacks on trade union organisers and violation of freedom of association rights. CCC will begin to support trainings to strengthen the capacity of unions and federations in organising, transforming into truely independent, democratic unions, include, empower, mobilize and represent the women workers, migrant workers, and workers employed on non-standard contracts. Governments, EU, ILO and other bodies will be pressured to focus on garment supply chain and freedom of association violations. Mutual capacity on freedom of association campaigning will be developed. CCC will focus on developing an international lobby advocacy strategy on Freedom of Association along with Bangladesh Unions and Global Unions and labour rights organisations. Jointly with partners CCC will target international and regional economic forums and lobby at relevant events (OECD, EU Flagship on the Garment industry, Dutch government/EU presidency, International Labour Conference 2016) to support wage increases, and improved OHS prevention laws and enforcement mechanisms; to establish permanent mechanisms to access full and fair compensation and remedy; to achieve a meaningful interpretation of &apos;due diligence&apos; and discredit the commercial social auditing system; to highlight the CCC agenda on stable, full and long-term employment; and to support a call to ban sandblasting globally. CCC will work with governments when key partners are directly calling for governmental support or engaging in negotiations and actions that require support from third countries (eg European governments in countries where a national CCC is established), and in cases of attacks on labour activists, union organisers and leaders in the context of the EU guidelines for protection of HRDs. In 2016 the CCC will work with the Dutch ministry, specifically DDE, around the Living Wage conference that the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and their German counterparts organize in Islamabad. Enforceable brand agreements are negotiated with companies (brands and retailers) that have a responsibility for working conditions and workers&apos; rights in their supply chains. The agreements deal with a &apos;root-cause&apos; issue that is relevant for the local context. CCC will work with partners in key garment producing countries to empower them to negotiate directly with brands and retailers to sign Enforceable Brand Agreements including wage clauses, and will push brands and retailers producing in Asian and Eastern European garment producing countries to take interim steps (such as interim wage payments) to increase wages towards living wage benchmarks, including the Asia Floor Wage. To ensure implementation of the Bangladesh Accord, with a strong focus on the establishment of the OHS Committees in the Accord listed factories, CCC will strategically collaborate with GUFs, Bangladesh Unions and partners to work within and outside the Accord Steering Committee meetings. In Indonesia CCC will support the implementation of the FoA Protocol. CCC will develop and run campaigns to push companies to improve the observance of human and labour rights in their supply chains, and hold companies accountable for the implementation of prior commitments to improve safety and wages. Lobby and public pressure will continue on existing cases of fire &amp; building safety: to ensure victims receive full compensation and remedy. CCC provides support to Human Rights Defenders in the garment industry through its urgent appeals work, with a focus on gender based violence cases, freedom of association violations, wage and severance payment and cases of building safety to sustain and broaden impact of past years. CCC will support partners to submit cases of rights violations with non-judicial grievance mechanisms (NJGM), in particular the Bangladesh Fire and Building Safety Accord, as well as multistakeholder initiatives in the garment industry, the OECD, ILO and regional and global human rights mechanisms. Cases are brought to the attention to CCC through its urgent appeals system, and through engaging in NJGM effective remedy for garment workers and their organisations is sought as well as strengthening and improving the accessibility and effectiveness of the NJGMs used. CCC will support garment labour partners to work with international organisations, including OECD Watch, global unions and Human Rights organisations to submit cases to the ILO freedom of association commitee, National Contact Points (OECD) and UN bodies. CCC works on implementing a new network structure, which partly consists of establishing and developing Asian and European regional coalitions, regional coordinating bodies, working international groups and more. Our network development also focuses on improving and maintaining a communication and information sharing system within the network. We make sure that CCC and its partners have the increased skills, knowledge and network contacts to have gender issues fully integrated and executed in all activities, lobby and public outreach. Concretely, we will further develop a gender policy to be used throughout our network (which will also include a gender focus and gender specific language in our communication). We will continue our capacity building via courses, regional meetings, national exchanges between women worker leaders, exchanges between factory women workers and women worker leaders and more. Our focus on highlighting gender based violence in concrete labour rights violations cases, as well as supporting women leadership at workplace and national trade union/NGO level, contribute to gender inclusivity and equality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210098" role="1" type="22"></participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210820" role="2" type="22"></participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210820" role="4" type="22"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="75" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1213349</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41210820"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG-ToC1" ref="NL-KVK-41210820"></receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="3"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">1140920</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41210820" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG-ToC1" ref="NL-KVK-41210820" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">1410003</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41210820"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">1433447</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-41210820"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41210820-FGG-ToC2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome C: Alternatives Developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A range of alternative, participatory initiatives and models related to corporate conduct have been developed, piloted and promoted by FGG and civil society actors, from best practices through to enforceable multi-stakeholder agreements.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://fairgreenglobal.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
   </document-link>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># alternative, participatory initiatives and models related to corporate conduct meeting core criteria including sustainability, participation (m/f), transparency and equity (m/f), that have been developed, piloted and/or promoted.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.C" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCC consulted partners and witness signatories of the Accord and developed a proposal for inclusion of safeguard provisions on Freedom of Association in Accord II and shared with Global Union Federations to take it forward in negotiations. The Accord is an legally binding EBA with brands and companies while FoA is an issue that should be addressed by multiple actors including the government, factory owners and buyers and companies. Ideally the FoA issues should be addressed at the national level through national policy and practise change. But in Bangladesh context national mechanisms failed to address the concerns raised on FoA. Our aim is to change that in the long run while also proposing a way to resolve the FoA issues in the Accord covered factories. CCC consulted partners and witness signatories of the Accord and developed a proposal for inclusion of safeguard provisions on Freedom of Association in Accord II and shared with Global Union Federations to take it forward in negotiations. The Accord is an legally binding EBA with brands and companies while FoA is an issue that should be addressed by multiple actors including the government, factory owners and buyers and companies. Ideally the FoA issues should be addressed at the national level through national policy and practise change. But in Bangladesh context national mechanisms failed to address the concerns raised on FoA. Our aim is to change that in the long run while also proposing a way to resolve the FoA issues in the Accord covered factories. CCC consulted partners and witness signatories of the Accord and developed a proposal for inclusion of safeguard provisions on Freedom of Association in Accord II and shared with Global Union Federations to take it forward in negotiations. The Accord is an legally binding EBA with brands and companies while FoA is an issue that should be addressed by multiple actors including the government, factory owners and buyers and companies. Ideally the FoA issues should be addressed at the national level through national policy and practise change. But in Bangladesh context national mechanisms failed to address the concerns raised on FoA. Our aim is to change that in the long run while also proposing a way to resolve the FoA issues in the Accord covered factories.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One proposal will be developed on the protection and promotion of trade union rights in Bangladesh related to the Accord follow up post 2018 (1)NB Proposals will find support within ILO (ILO Group of Experts), governments, Global Union Federations, amongst others.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. CCC will provide an overview of, and critique of, the various national, European and international Due Diligence supply chain regulatory/legislative initiatives. This is done in a working group with participants from 6 LLMIC countries. This includes the Covenant (NL), Buendnis (DE), UK anti-slavery act, French law on duty of care, EU action plans, and UN and OECD forums. Together with partner organisations, CCC will show how these initiatives should be strengthened with binding regulations to have real and structural effect. (1) 2. CCC will publish a position paper highlighting the failure of social auditing, and develop and highlight working alternatives in that paper and follow-up statements. (1) 3. CCC supports Pakistan partners as they formulate, negotiate and sign an Accord on Fire and Building Safety in Pakistan, by facilitating exchange on lessons learned between Bangladeshi and Pakistan CSOs, to use the experiences from the Bangladesh accord to strengthen the proposed Pakistan accord. (1) 4. CCC publishes a position paper on Myanmar dispute settlement (1), and on Myanmar wage violations (which proposes a strategy for brands on how they can avoid these wage violations).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Accord process in Pakistan is still an ongoing process. Bangladesh Accord staff visited Pakistan in September 2019 and explained in detail the Bangladesh Accord and the changes it made to the industry in preventing factory incidents. CCC supported Pakistan unions and NGOs to organise a consultation to discuss and reach a consensus on Pakistan Accord (1). This meeting was held in April 2019 in Karachi attended by around 20 organisations from Pakistan working in the garment and textiles sectors. At the end of the consultation meeting, Pakistan labour groups jointly signed a declaration calling to sign and implement an Accord in Pakistan. After this meeting a draft for the Pakistan Accord was worked out and the Pakistan Accord group invited Global Unions to start a process for the Accord in Pakistan and shared their input for the agreement. [1] The CCC network has worked intensively on developing an alternative for the current failing programmes to improve worker wages. An international campaign to create an Enforceable Wage Agreement to be signed and implemented by brands in their global supply chains was prepared by a) consulting unions within the CCC network on the structure of a future wage agreement and the role of grass roots unions in it leading to the announcement of their support for this campaign to the global union federations before launching a public campaign; b) the mobilisation of a large global coalition with a common understanding of the need for a worker led enforceable wage agreement (EWA). The campaign launch is foreseen for May 2020. From then convincing the first brands to adopt the agreement will start until the first will sign on. The campaign will generate additional knowledge on industry realities, mobilising civil society actors and building more favourable ground for future efforts. [1] After long-term campaigning and lobbying by the CCC network, with the confirmation of the Bangladesh Government&apos;s agreement in the fall in 2019, all stakeholders signed up to the trial of an Employment Injury Scheme in a number of factories. An Employment Injury Scheme would allow for pensions for workers injured on the job or the families of workers killed in the workplace. The trial is due to start in 2020. [1] Throughout the year, the CCC network examined closely the various national, European and international Due Diligence supply chain regulatory/legislative initiatives [including the Covenant (NL), Buendnis (DE), UK anti-slavery act, French law on duty of care, Dutch Child Labour Due Diligence Law, EU action plans, and UN and OECD forums]. Together with partner organisations, CCC substantiated how these initiatives should be strengthened with binding regulations to have real and structural effect. As a member of the MVO Platform, CCC actively contributed to activities of the working group that is working on a new mandatory due diligence law in the Netherlands. In September, the report &#x201C;Fig Leaf for Fashion. How social auditing protects brands and fails workers&#x201D; was launched and shared with key MSIs and brands in the garment sector. The report demonstrates the failure of commercial, voluntary social auditing practices and puts forward the case for binding regulation. [1]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Bangladesh Transition Accord 2018 is in place, a three-year renewal of the groundbreaking first Accord. CCC is on the Steering Committee and is one of the Witness Signatories (1). The Transition Accord coverage is extended to freedom of association. Around 50 brands signed the transition Accord in 2017. CCC supported a group of 20 Indian NGO&apos;s in developing the parameters of an Enforcable Brand Agreement against bonded labour. This in cooperation with the German &quot;Textilb&#xFC;ndniss&quot; and others. (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">- a Model Code of Conduct for brands is developed on how they should enforce dealing with non-standard contracts, subcontracting, agency employment and short term contracts. Currently under initial develpment by partners in South Asia, planned network-wide discussion and adoption across the CCC network in Q1 2018. &#x2013; Finalized a model EBA (Enforceable Brand Agreement) on living wage, and decide upon the target brand list. The goal is to get one or more of the main brands to support a concrete, enforceable, measurable agreement to reach a living wage in an acceptable time-frame. &#x2013; development of a second Indonesia protocol on wages, starting with sportswear sector &#x2013; linked to World Championships campaign. (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome A: Enabling Environment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both the rights and the legal and political spaces needed to claim and defend those rights are protected for people, communities and civil society actors, enabling them to address misconduct and grievances successfully, and promote improved corporate conduct and related governmental regulation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://fairgreenglobal.org">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-05-12"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.A.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms put in place or improved by governments that guarantee access for civil society to democratic decision making processes related to corporate conduct, including the right to resist developments.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.A.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-05-12" value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Parliament adopted with overwhelming majority in April 2017 a motion demanding mandatory due diligence in the textile sector and mandatory transparency in the supply chain, now goes back to EC. CCCs in national countries lobbied their respective MEPs, CCC IO also lobbied in Brussels. (1) Within one of the thematic working groups of the Dutch Agreement on Sustainable Garments and Textile, of which the India Committee of the Netherlands (Dutch CCC coalition member) is a signatory, a plan to tackle forced labour has been developed in October 2017 with local NGOs in South India based on (implementation of) local legislation on Worker&#x2019;s Grievance Redressal Committees and workers Internal Complaints Committee on a small scale (20 spinning mills) which will be extended to 50 mills. Also a Tamil Nadu-wide helpline is established for reporting problems of workers which will be linked to the participating Covenant members. ICN as part of Dutch CCC will monitor and follow up(1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within the Dutch Covenant on Sustainable Garments and Textiles (signed by Dutch garments companies and the Dutch government) it has been agreed that companies will develop an action plan based on their own due diligence, taking into account existing research and new information to ban forced labour in their South Indian supply chain. Participating companies will within three years only buy from South Indian companies where forced labour does not exists, either through improvements at existing suppliers or by changing suppliers. This above-mentioned plan will be developed in 2017. A survey among the signatories of the Covenant showed that forced labour is high on their priority list. A few companies have indicated already that they will participate in developing the action plan. SKC/CCC will use the research data for the &apos;Fabrics of Slavery&apos; paper to further identify forced labour in supply chains of Dutch brands and motivate them to participate in this working group. SKC/CCC gave input to parliamentary questions posed on 28 December 2016 based on Fabrics of Slavery, in which the need of working with civil society has been stretched. The Dutch ambassador on Business and Development Cooperation also raised the concerns on the space for civil society when visiting India.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both the Indian government as well as the government of the Netherlands (possibly in co-operation with other countries at the European level ) will implement binding agreements to tackle forced labour and related labour rights violations in the South Indian garment and textile industry in consultation with civil society, while also increasing space for them to resist insufficient progress</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The extension of the Bangladesh ccord (in which CCC is participating) explicitly includes strengthening of Freedom of Association, which should be taken up by the Bangladeshi government if it wants to &#x2018;take over responsibility&#x2019; as it has stated. This should lead to tangible changes in Bangladesh government approach to FoA (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.A.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># effective legal and other grievance mechanisms adopted or improved by governments and corporations via which CSOs and communities can resolve grievances with governments and companies, and claim their environmental, human and worker rights.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.A.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCC gave extensive feedback after consultation with partner network to current complaints procedures. FWF took this up and decided to do a thorough review of related areas of work, including verification and brand assessments, to be finished in 2017. The CCC through its participation in the CoE is engaged in these policy discussions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO convened the stakeholders in the Ali Enterprises fire case; the case was also presented by CCC at a European Parliament hearing, leading to finally resolving the case in late 2017/early 2018. This compensation scheme, together with Rana Plaza Arrangement and the Tazreen case compensation, is now seen as the model on which national employment injury schemes should be based, by ILO and others. (1) SKC, in its role of Committee of Experts (CoE) member, actively participated in the discussion to improve the Fair Wear Foundation&apos;s complaint mechanism. CCC consulted partner organizations who were working on cases of labour rights violations in factories supplying Fair Wear Foundation member brands, to be able to provide feedback to FWF based on the experiences of these organizations. Main suggestions made by CCC were inserted into the new policy document and decided upon by the FWF board (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Fair Wear Foundation (a Multi Stakeholder Initiative that works with member brands) improves their auditing and remedy process through dialogue and critique from CCC on concrete cases.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">With inputs from LLMIC member organisations CCC participated in a taskforce on social auditing resulting in Fair Wear Foundation adopting a holistic approach to remediation by using different tools such as country studies, social audits, complaints handling, worker education programs in a more coherent and effective way. Further suggestions made by this taskforce include increased transparency and access of worker to information and the need for worker involvement in remediation processes. [1] CCC took part in the workshop co-organised by Fair Wear Foundation during the OECD Forum on Due Diligence in the Garment and Footwear Sector to explore possibilities for cooperation between different MSI&#x2019;s on grievances. Based on its own experience and experiences from other grievances mechanism primarily in LLMIC countries such as Bangladesh, Indonesia, Myanmar, etc, CCC developed some preconditions in order to make such a collaboration credible and effective. This process is on-going through its &#x2018;regular&#x2019; channels (in Committee of Experts and board meetings). [1] The broad movement for more supply chain transparency, in which CCC is one of the most prominent actors that campaigned and lobbied brands, has now led to the Open Apparel Registry (whose Board CCC is a member of). This is an open source tool which maps garment facilities worldwide and assigns a unique ID number to each of them. This makes it much easier to identify factories, which will simplify the search for the responsible parties in cases of worker rights violations. Very soon after its launch, it had already over 9,000 factories listed, with good prospects of getting many more. The map and search functions can be used to search for factories. You can also see the origin of the data, such as a specific supplier list. [1] A long term CCC-partner has published a new research tool that helps workers, unions, and labour and human rights organizations to link apparel brands that source from Central America and Mexico to the companies that own them. This should help determine what leverage points to use to motivate these companies to remediate worker rights violations in their wholly-owned and supplier factories. [1]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2016 FWF is revising its complaints procedure after pressure and lobby CCC based on experiences obtained through Urgent Appeals mechanism on complainants satisfaction and effectiveness to address grievances (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A &apos;bridging solution&apos; is formed with the Bangladesh Government and ILO taking active steps to process any recent and future compensation cases until the permanent solution of National Employment Injury Insurance (EII) Scheme and National Laws are in place (1), and also the process of setting up the Employment Injury Insurance (EII) Scheme is expedited as result of lobby and pressure. (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome F: Practice Changed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved corporate policies and government regulations have been put into practice and enforced.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://fairgreenglobal.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
   </document-link>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.F.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># concrete steps taken by companies to actively identify, prevent and mitigate adverse social, gender and environmental impacts of their activities and those in their value chains.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.F.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(7) In 2016 we have worked on 21 Urgent Appeal cases in 11 different countries resulting in 7 (partial) success ranging from signing of agreements on fair compensation, to reinstatement, to the embassies intervening on severe violations and to companies taking action. Furthermore we have been actively involved in several solidarity campaigns asking for international attention concerning human rights violations in Asia. Completed the payments for a occupational health and safety case and agreement is reached for two other safety cases (3). CCC got involved in a case and took it forward with the Bangladesh Accord to resolve it. The factory was in violation of the terms of the Accord and the case was resolved through the Accord complaint procedure. Currently the Bangladesh unions are capable of using the Accord complaint mechanism and are now approaching the Accord directly, so there hasn&apos;t been a need for the CCC to get involved in Accord related cases. (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resolved UA cases (6), KIK &amp; Tazreen &amp; RanaPlaza (3) protocol pays out to workers&apos; families, resolved dispute resolution Accord cases (11)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Urgent Appeals system is the mechanism through which CCC gives support to workers whose rights are violated in specific and concrete cases. Cases can be resolved &apos;behind the scenes&apos; by negotiating with brands or governments, or sometimes by public pressure and campaigning. The countries and locations in cases X1, X2 are anonymised to protect the workers. After much public pressure by CCC and CCC partners, Nike relented and let independent auditors like the WRC into their factories. (1) UA case Geox factory Serbia: agreement signed (1) UA case Faremo Philippines: agreement reached (1) UA case X1: CCC pushing brands to put pressure on factory management and parent company to meet the demands of the union resulted in an agreement stipulating the reinstatement of three trade union activists including back wages, withdrawal of legal cases and good industrial relations. However management did not implement the agreement in full spirit and one former trade union leader is not reinstated. CCC and the union are following upon with the brands calling upon them to intervene. (1) UA case X2: After more than a year putting pressure by CCC and allies on brands, management and parent company, an agreement was reached between factory management and union stipulating the reinstatement of two union leaders and workers, and the improvement of industrial relations. The union is formally registered. The implementation of the agreement needs to be closely monitored for a few outstanding issues (1) UA case Sri Lanka: Workers voted to have the trade union recognised as legitimate bargaining partner in a workers&#x2019; referendum in two factories following on a period of intimidation of workers for their union membership and other union busting measures. The union is now recognized as a legitimate representative in the conflict on behalf of the workers. Actions included CCC, League, IndustriALL and other international partners addressing international buyers of the company. (1) [NB. Accord has a functioning dispute resolution, which functions without CCC direct involvement; hence the Results mentioned in the targets for 2016-2017 in this area are not counted here.]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. The signatories in the Bangladesh Accord (including over 200 brands) expand it to include Freedom of Association violations in their complaints mechanism. (1) 2. H&amp;M will take a concrete, measurable step in the direction of a living wage, after pressure by CCC/SKC (together with other European CCCs, WeMove.eu and CCC&apos;s Living Wage workgroup which includes strong representation by LLMIC CSOs) in the the &quot;Turn Around H&amp;M&quot; campaign. (1) 3. More brands join the Transition Accord in Bangladesh, with special focus on drawing in the home textile sector and Fair Wear Foundation (FWF) brands, after lobby and campaigning by CCC and LLMIC partners. (1) The goal is that all FWF member brands sign the 2018 Bangladesh Accord. CCC/SKC lobbies through the Committee of Experts and FWF board, and through public campaigning in collaboration with other CCCs on targeted FWF member brands. All Dutch Covenant member brands sign the 2018 Bangladesh Accord (1) as a result of lobby activities at the Covenant. 4. IKEA signs the 2018 Bangladesh Accord (1) after pressure via CCC&#x2019;s social media campaigns and CCC collaboration with FNV. 5. The ILO and other actors establish a bridging solution for remedy for families affected by recent factory incidents in Bangladesh as a result of lobby, meetings and eventually public campaigning by CCC in cooperation with Bangladeshi CSOs. (1) 6. In approximately (12) Urgent Appeal cases, brands take concrete steps to mitigate violations and thereby resolve the UA case. Steps can be to pay back wages, to re-hire unjustly sacked workers, or other remedies. Focus on which cases are taken up is partly determined by the type of violations and which ones the LLMIC CSOs find most pressing and strategic; in dialogue with the LLMIC CSOs the dominant themes are factory closures, Freedom of Association, wages, gender and migrants. An estimated 3 of those 12 will get lobby and campaigning support from SKC in the Netherlands</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The case of PT Kahoindah Citragarment in Bekasi, Indonesia, has been resolved with the agreement on the payment of full severance to the workers by the company. The total amount will be 4.5 million USD, which is likely the largest amount workers have ever won in a single case of illegally denied severance and an important precedent in Indonesia. CCC member Workers Rights Consortium (WRC) conducted an investigation in response to complaints from workers received by WRC after the factory announced its intention to close. Violations of US university labour standards and buyer codes were identified, and WRC lobbied brands (Fanatics, Gap, and Under Armour) to pressure the supplier. As a result, the supplier agreed to honour its obligations, and WRC &#x2013; with input from workers - worked with the supplier to develop a plan for the efficient distribution of funds to the former employees. After a WRC-led worker outreach effort, more than 99% of the eligible workers visited a designated meeting place near the location of the closed factory to sign documents confirming their acceptance of the planned payments. WRC was also a signatory in the agreement. [1] The Fair Labor Association accepted the CCC complaint against Uniqlo and S.Oliver and their lack of compensation and severance payments to workers after the closure of the Jaba Garmindo factory in Indonesia. FLA will start an investigation into Uniqlo and S.Oliver for violating FLA&#x2019;s code of conduct [1]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2013; an estimated 15 Urgent Appeal cases will be taken up, of which an estimated 10 lead to successful remedy of grievances. (10) NOTE: some of these steps might be taken by governments, but often after brands intervene as result of CCC campaigning. So some results could fall under 1.F.a. &#x2013; increase pressure on brands to sign Transparency Pledge; monitor the results of those brands that have signed on. Goals: at least 5 brands will publish their supplier data in an open, transparent way. (5)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.F.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># concrete steps taken by governments to actively identify, prevent and mitigate adverse social, gender and environmental impacts of corporate activities and those in corporations&apos; value chains.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.F.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCC, partners and Global Union Federations relaunched the compensation campaign on an occupational health and safety case in end 2015 and intensified the efforts in 2016. CCC approached the Dutch and German governments and the International Labour Organization (ILO) in 2016. On requests of the German Federal Ministry of Economic Cooperation and Development, the ILO enabled talks with the German retailer KiK, IndustriALL Global Union and the Clean Clothes Campaign since May 2016 to arrive at the compensation arrangement, in accordance with the ILO&#x2019;s Employment Injury Benefits Convention 121. On the eve of fourth anniversary of fire in September 2016, KiK Textilien signed an agreement to pay 5.15 million USD to fund the compensation for injured workers and families of the deceased workers. Pakistan government agreed to the process for compensation of Ali enterprises and ILO is taking a lead and convening role for Ali Arrangement.CCC, partners and Global Union Federations relaunched the compensation campaign on an occupational health and safety case in end 2015 and intensified the efforts in 2016. CCC approached the Dutch and German governments and the International Labour Organization (ILO) in 2016. On requests of the German Federal Ministry of Economic Cooperation and Development, the ILO enabled talks with the German retailer KiK, IndustriALL Global Union and the Clean Clothes Campaign since May 2016 to arrive at the compensation arrangement, in accordance with the ILO&#x2019;s Employment Injury Benefits Convention 121. On the eve of fourth anniversary of fire in September 2016, KiK Textilien signed an agreement to pay 5.15 million USD to fund the compensation for injured workers and families of the deceased workers. Pakistan government agreed to the process for compensation of Ali enterprises and ILO is taking a lead and convening role for Ali Arrangement.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">* Pakistan government implement the ILO compensation scheme for Ali Enterprises survivors (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Urgent Appeals system is the mechanism through which CCC gives support to workers whose rights are violated in specific and concrete cases. Cases can be resolved &apos;behind the scenes&apos; by negotiating with brands or governments, or sometimes by public pressure and campaigning. UA case Haeson factory Bangladesh: after pressure, the Bangladesh government has acted to resolve workers problems. (1) UA case: a Thai labor activist acquited after pressure (1) UA case: another Thai labor activist will be released earlier from prison, after years of campaigning (1) UA case: Bangladesh crackdown on trade unions and labor activists: produced briefing paper, lobbied Sustainability Compact, lobbied EU, embassy actions. Bangladesh government dropped charges. SKC together with FNV and CNV protested outside Embassy in the Hague to demand the release of the detained union leaders and resolve the crisis. On 23 February 2017, first important steps were taken including the release of the labour leaders and activists. (1) (see also 2.D)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results expected for 2018</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. The Bangladeshi government will establish a permanent Employment Injury Insurance (EII) scheme in Bangladesh, after much pressure from CCC, allies and Bangladeshi partners, and support from brands for such a scheme. (1) This is a result of political lobby at the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs to advocate for a national Employment Injury Insurance scheme in Bangladesh.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome B: Capacities Strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased capacity of civil society actors to research, network and advocate in relation to the conduct of corporations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://fairgreenglobal.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
   </document-link>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># CSOs in LLMICs that lobby and advocate for responsible corporate conduct based on increased skills, knowledge or network contacts.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.B" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian partner organisations and trade unions participated in the Lessons Learned Meeting (LLM) in Southeast Asia in March 2016 and shared their experience, knowledge in campaigning, lobbying and legal action for access to compensation to the major factory tragedies and other safety incidents. Also LLM helped to develop the knowledge and specificity of compensation schemes and identified the areas of further action, improvements and lessons for future cases. 23 CSOs in Asia and Eastern Europe and CCC IO organised together Urgent Appeal participatory workshops, thus increasing their capacities and working on further improving their joint strategising and lobbying. 6 CSOs in a South East Asian country increased their ability to communicate and strategise online safetly, without the threat of external unwanted surveillance or interference. Four federations in another South East Asian country are better equipped now to bargain at factory level, as well as to identify and tackle occupational health and safety issues.Asian partner organisations and trade unions participated in the Lessons Learned Meeting (LLM) in Southeast Asia in March 2016 and shared their experience, knowledge in campaigning, lobbying and legal action for access to compensation to the major factory tragedies and other safety incidents. Also LLM helped to develop the knowledge and specificity of compensation schemes and identified the areas of further action, improvements and lessons for future cases. 23 CSOs in Asia and Eastern Europe and CCC IO organised together Urgent Appeal participatory workshops, thus increasing their capacities and working on further improving their joint strategising and lobbying. 6 CSOs in a South East Asian country increased their ability to communicate and strategise online safetly, without the threat of external unwanted surveillance or interference. Four federations in another South East Asian country are better equipped now to bargain at factory level, as well as to identify and tackle occupational health and safety issues.Asian partner organisations and trade unions participated in the Lessons Learned Meeting (LLM) in Southeast Asia in March 2016 and shared their experience, knowledge in campaigning, lobbying and legal action for access to compensation to the major factory tragedies and other safety incidents. Also LLM helped to develop the knowledge and specificity of compensation schemes and identified the areas of further action, improvements and lessons for future cases. 23 CSOs in Asia and Eastern Europe and CCC IO organised together Urgent Appeal participatory workshops, thus increasing their capacities and working on further improving their joint strategising and lobbying. 6 CSOs in a South East Asian country increased their ability to communicate and strategise online safetly, without the threat of external unwanted surveillance or interference. Four federations in another South East Asian country are better equipped now to bargain at factory level, as well as to identify and tackle occupational health and safety issues.Asian partner organisations and trade unions participated in the Lessons Learned Meeting (LLM) in Southeast Asia in March 2016 and shared their experience, knowledge in campaigning, lobbying and legal action for access to compensation to the major factory tragedies and other safety incidents. Also LLM helped to develop the knowledge and specificity of compensation schemes and identified the areas of further action, improvements and lessons for future cases. 23 CSOs in Asia and Eastern Europe and CCC IO organised together Urgent Appeal participatory workshops, thus increasing their capacities and working on further improving their joint strategising and lobbying. 6 CSOs in a South East Asian country increased their ability to communicate and strategise online safetly, without the threat of external unwanted surveillance or interference. Four federations in another South East Asian country are better equipped now to bargain at factory level, as well as to identify and tackle occupational health and safety issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. During the OECD Forum on Due Diligence in the Garment Sector, CCC will host sessions with (3-5) CSO partners from LLMICs. The lobby and advocacy of these partners is strengthened by reaching new audiences and improved networking. The partners are chosen on their expertise, and voice their priorities in this international setting where policy-makers, brands and civil society meet. 2. CCC will host sessions together with (2-4) CSO partners from LLMICs at the OECD Forum on Responsible Business Conduct. The lobby and advocacy of these partners is strengthened by reaching new audiences and improved networking. The partners are chosen on their expertise, and voice their priorities in this international setting where policy-makers, brands and civil society meet. 3. CSOs in Georgia, Moldova and Ukraine (4) strengthen their lobby and advocacy by participating in the CCC European Production Focused Subgroup. There will be several regional meetings, and thematic work on wages and gender. With organisational, financial and strategic support of CCC these CSOs can learn from one another and from partners in neighboring countries within the region with a better developed civil society, and use their improved capacity (alliance building, strategic knowledge on wages and wage negotiations) to build stronger alliances in their own countries, through which they will actively advocate for living wages. 4. Several CSOs in CCC&#x2019;s network in the South Asia and South East Asia regions strengthen their campaigning on wages, fair contracts and safe workplaces by participating in CCC regional network meetings, trainings, thematic workgroups (40 CSOs). CCC provides organisational, strategic and logistical support. 5. CCC will strengthen links between CSOs in the South Asia/South East Asia region and the East Asia region. This region consists of non-LLMIC countries, in which factory ownership and brand ownership is increasingly concentrated. The LLMIC CSOs therefore need improved contacts with East Asia CSOs so their lobby and advocacy can be heard and amplified in these consumer and brand-ownership countries. They will use the Tokyo 2020 Olympic campaign planning as vehicle to improve advocacy on wages and fair contracts. This concerns 20 CSOs from LLMIC countries (Indonesia, Thailand, Myanmar, Vietnam, Philippines). 6. Approximately (6) CSOs in the Meso American region including Honduras, Nicaragua, Haiti will implement more effective campaigns as a result of improved network contacts with CCC and CCC&apos;s North American partners (most brands producing in Meso America have ownership in the USA). CCC supports this capacity development with a possible regional meeting and improved access to internal knowledge. 7. Due to increased organisational capacity, one country-wide union and several factory level unions in Bangladesh will be able to better organize their campaigning. CCC offers support in organising methods and practices. (1) 8. CCC (after having been concretely asked to do this by LLMIC CSOs) provides campaign and media training to organisations in the network, specifically to campaign on precarious work and short term contracts. The CSOs&apos; aim is to maximize the multi-media impact of workers&#x2019; struggles including through social networks. Special emphasis will be put on where unwanted gender bias can be introduced, for instance when &#x201C;worker&#x201D; is translated as a gendered term. The participating CSOs will directly apply their increased capacity in their social media campaigning (40 CSOs). 9. NGOs and labour unions in India will increase their understanding of developments in regard to MSIs related to the garment sector in European countries such as the Dutch Agreement on Sustainable Garments and Textiles and on possibilities for filing complaints with these initiatives and on brand mobilising in order to get access to remedy. This is achieved by regular communication and exchange between the India Committee of the Netherlands and Indian unions and NGOs. The NGOs and labour unions will apply their improved knowledge and understanding in advocacy for remedy and possibly in filing complaints. 10. When CSOs are under urgent repression their resilience is strengthened (and thus their lobby and advocacy continues) by the availability of CCC&apos;s Urgent Appeal Emergency Fund; on average it supports (3) CSOs when urgent help is required (legal, travel, other unexpected repression-avoidance).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="66">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Bangladesh, more than 30 factories had filed criminal charges against workers who peacefully protested their poverty wages in the start of the year. After intense campaigning towards brands sourcing from these factories, information gathering and cross-checking, brand identification, and direct worker support by CCC and its partners (3 Bangladeshi organizations and organizations in the US &amp; Europe), five charges were dropped by the end of 2019. [3] 2 CSOs in Moldova and Ukraine strengthened their lobby and advocacy capacities by participating in the CCC European Production Focused Subgroup. There were two meetings which included thematic work on wages and gender. With organisational, financial and strategic support from CCC, they learned from each other and from partners in neighbouring countries and used their improved capacity (alliance building, strategic knowledge on wages and wage negotiations) to build stronger alliances in their own countries, through which they will actively advocate for living wages. [2] In June 2019, in Chiangmai (Thailand), 28 organisations (unions and NGOs) participated in the South East Asia regional CCC network meeting and discussed the current trends in the RMG sector and gave their input to prepare the new Global Strategic Frame Work of CCC. In this meeting they also discussed Enforcable Wage Agreement, the research findings from 4 countries (Myanmar, Indonesia, Cambodia and Philippines) on low wages, FOA problems, Union registration, and gender related issues. They used this research to do a brand analysis focusing on wages, safety and employment relations, and they started to develop Tokyo 2020 Olympic campaign plan. They also discussed the lessons learned on CCC campaign in the region to build power to strategize and to lobby brands. CCC provided financial and strategic support to the South East Asia Regional Coalition for this meeting to take place. [28] 25 CSOs in South Asia participated in the regional CCC network meeting in September to discuss and develop strategies on living wage and Safety programmes, and developed a plan to pressure their governments and employers to improve working conditions. They discussed the current trends in the RMG and sportswear sector and gave input for the preparation of a new Global Strategic Framework for CCC. CCC South Asia used this meeting furthermore to improve its regional coordination for further follow up of the implementation of the plan and better communication between members and partners in the region. CCC provided financial and strategic support to the South East Asia Regional Coalition for this meeting to take place. [25] In September 2019, in Kathmandu (Nepal) around 21 trade unions from production countries (from South Asia, Eastern Europe and South East Asia) gathered and discussed Living Wage, the Enforceable Wage Agreement (EWA) in a meeting organized by the CCC network learning from the Lesotho Agreements to Combat Gender-based Violence and from the Harassment in Lesotho&#x2019;s Garment Industry, they discussed a negotiation strategy for EWA and they developed campaign strategies. As a result of this meeting unions jointly sent a letter to the Global Unions in favour of a global industrial enforceable and binding collective bargaining agreement for payment of living wages to garment production workers. [14] CCC South East Asia Coalition and East Asia Coalition have established collaboration on concrete cases which started with the Jaba Garmindo workers struggle in Indonesia, which is supported by unions and NGOs in the East Asia region. Now both regions are working together to develop the Tokyo 2020 Olympic campaign. CCC has provided coordination and financial support. [2] Nike is retreating its production from South Korean factories in Indonesia and the workers are affected by this. Indonesian Union and CSOs worked together with Korean CSOs on severance payment for the workers. This is also strengthening the collaboration between the two regions. [5] CCC offered financial and strategic support to a union federation in Bangladesh to increase the capacity and skills on communication to their members and outside. This has resulted in better organising and messaging on issues that are on the ground, such as negotiations and bargaining with factory owners. [1] In 2019 CCC Netherlands member Arisa (former India Committee of the Netherlands) presented the functioning of the Dutch Agreement on Sustainable Garments and Textiles (AGT) to 6 Indian NGOs and labour unions in National Capital Region, Bangalore and Tamil Nadu. Arisa supported one NGO (1) in raising an issue with the AGT and followed-up a previous complaints about Bangalore. The processes are pending. Arisa is in contact with brands about the issues/ complaints. Furthermore, Arisa supported one trade union (1) to get directly in touch with AGT member brands who are sourcing from a particular factory in Bangalore (where the labour union identified violations). [2] In April 2019 CCC supported Pakistan unions and NGOs to organise a consultation to discuss and reach a consensus on the Pakistan Accord. Bangladesh Accord staff visited four CCC member organisations in Pakistan in September 2019 and explained the Bangladesh Accord and the changes it made to the industry in preventing factory incidents. CCC together with Pakistan unions and NGOs, ILRF and WRC, published a Pakistan Safety report, &#x201C;PAKISTAN S GARMENT WORKERS NEED A SAFETY ACCORD&#x201D;. Through all these efforts, Pakistan Unions and NGOs capacities have been strengthened and they have reached out to other stakeholders in the industry including employers, the labour ministry and labour department in Sindh Province. [4] During the OECD Forum on Due Diligence in the Garment Sector, CCC hosted sessions with four CSO partners from LLMICs. The lobby and advocacy of these partners was strengthened by reaching new audiences and improved networking. The partners voiced their priorities in this international setting where national and transnational policy-makers, brands and civil society meet. [4] CCC hosted sessions together with three CSO partners from LLMICs at the OECD Forum on Responsible Business Conduct. The lobby and advocacy of these partners was strengthened by reaching new audiences and improved networking. The partners voiced their priorities in this international setting where national and transnational policy-makers, brands and civil society meet. [3]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacities of 30 partner CSOs will be strengthened through knowledge sharing, reflections on periodic lessons and building coalition.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="29">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">NOTE: some organizations took part in multiple initiatives. Discarding this double count, the overall count is 29. Urgent Appeal training in Bangalore, 19 participants from (7) organizations that have more knowledge on how to bring cases to the CCC UA system.The training has provided parters with the knowledge and skills to get more involved in Urgent Appeal work. This has increased their access to the UAC Network and, implicitly, to the key people and organisations who have the leverage needed to negotiate with the brands so that their corporate conduct improves. The trainings have also diversified the ways in which the partners lobby and advocate (moving beyond to local courts and Labor commission and tapping into the international arena), which can be practically seen in their case work Implemented organisational change process for a partner organisation in Bangladesh (1), making the organization functional and strong again. Almost 500 women increased their capacity to work on improving the labour rights of their communities and knowledge to participate in grievance handling, particularly via enforceable agreements. At the beginning of 2017, CCC in collaboration with (2) Pakistani partners, worked together with survivors of the Ali Enterprise fire on establishing the National Oversight Committee for Ali enterprises compensation and proposal for the calculation of claims. (3) Developed the capacity for (16) organizations in digital security through training during South Asia meeting. They can now communicate with far less risk of government interference and repression. Developed the capacity of (4) organisations (plus 2 that already took the English-language one mentioned above, but now with interpreter into Sinhalese for wider reach in their rank-and-file) in Sri Lanka on Digital security and communication through a National training. They can now communicate with far less risk of government interference and repression. NOTE: THE FOLLOWING WERE PARTLY FUNDED BY PARTNERSHIP WITH MAMA CASH, THE WOMEN POWER FASHION PROGRAMME * Supported Training of union leaders in Bangladesh for (3) federations: - training on Occupational Health &amp; Safety. Outcomes: participants better equipped while forming OHS committees. They are monitor factories, giving advice on improving situation, connecting OHS committees to local unions. (600 ppts - 240 female) - training on collective bargaining - (280 ppts - 135 female) - better campaiging for wage increase (ppts say they can now better write press release, rallies, skillsharing) - (1200 ppts) * Similar OHS training in Sri Lanka with (1) partner, 300 women workers are more aware about safety issues, the organization feels better equipped to deal with them. * Safety booklet developed with (1) partner in Pakistan, distributed to 600 workers. Contains safety tips, but also union contacts and organizing toolkit which has been used by recipients to start organizing in new factories. * Sexual harassment (genderbased violence in the workplace) manual developed with (1) Indian union, distributed to 1000 workers, with direct training to 300 women workers, who are now tackling gender violence when they encounter it. * Labour rights-focused newsletter for EPZ workers in Sri Lanka, strengthening (1) partner&apos;s capacity to organize these hard-to-reach workers. 2000 workers reached per month, the salary increase for 2017 was not provided by some factories; the newsletter led to awareness and protests by workers to get their rightful increase. (1) * Unnamed union India: 75 women workers gained skills and knowledge on how to extend and strengthen the union, increase membership, reach new factories (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2013; An Urgent Appeals Global Strategising and capacity building meeting will be held January 2018. It will have experience exchange between CSOs, joint strategy building on 3 main topics (Gender-based workplace discrimination, Freedom of Association, Factory Closures) which should directly lead to more focused campaigning in UA cases. (strengthened capacities of 40 participating CSOs) &#x2013; The UAC Manual and training materials will be updated and partly re-written; to account for new legal, societal and political challenges. A training of the manual and its practical uses will be provided in Q3. Changes include a more global focus, where there are countries that are simultaneously consumers and producers (e.g. Eastern Europe and Black Sea regions), and direct Region-to-Region campaigning where CSOs in e.g. Cambodia can campaign with CCC partners in factory-owning and brand-basing countries like Japan and Korea. (15 participating CSOs) Follow up trainings with these new materials by Country Focal Points in two countries (15 participating CSOs) &#x2013; The Urgent Appeal team will be responsible for explicitly addressing gender sensitive translations and interpretation, and be providing that expertise to the partner network. (3 Regional Coordinating bodies will dissipate to other partners) &#x2013; &#x201C;Organised by women&#x201D; project, focused on women organisers and Freedom of Association in several producing countries. This includes storytelling and experience exchange. Aim is to directly encourage and empower women organisers to network, and to reach more influental positions in their unions (10 CSOs) &#x2013; strengthening Europe South/East integration into the network, by inclusion into Regional Meetings and various thematic work (Living Wage, Gender). This includes CSO&#x2019;s in Georgia, Moldova, Ukraine (4) &#x2013; Regional development (network meetings, security training) and capacity building for the South Asia and South East Asia regions (40 CSOs) &#x2013; Strengthening links between CSO&#x2019;s in the South Asia/South East Asia regions with the East Asia region (which consists of non-LLMIC countries, but where factory ownership and brand ownership is increasingly concentrated. Therefore campaign strength against brands and factory owners in East Asia is vital for lobby &amp; advocacy for the LLMIC CSOs) (20). &#x2013; communication guidelines, resource toolkits and training to enhance the campaigning skills of the network partners. Integrate their social media presences into the global CCC website and social media presences to enhance reach and representation. (30) &#x2013; baseline study on preventive Occupation Health and Safety (OHS) in South Asian countries. lobby and campaign for OHS laws and preventive mechanisms developed {in one South Asian country}. (1) NOTE: MANY OF THE CSO&#x2019;s overlap here, the total estimate of CSOs in LLMICs reached is therefore not the sum of all participants in the activities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome D: Agendas Set</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private and public sector decision makers have prioritised improvement measures due to support from influential civil society actors, critical media attention, increased public awareness and effective scrutiny of corporate conduct.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://fairgreenglobal.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
   </document-link>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># proposals for improvement of corporate conduct discussed by private and public sector decision makers and/or in academia, public agenda, media and social movements.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.D" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) In May-June 2016, the International Labour Conference for the first time focused on &#x201C;decent work in global supply chains&#x201D;. The CCC contribution is the active participation in the ILC, the research and position paper done in advance, the lobbying done before and during the conference. CCC was present with a delegation of critical trade unions, to influence the debates both inside the workers groups as well as in plenary sessions (where we had received a speaking slot as International NGO) A position paper was shared and publicly referred to, and several points were taken up in the outcome papers. (0) The European Commission announced 2 years ago a flagship initiative on responsible management of the garment supply chain. CCC participated actively in the consultations and contributed with a proposal to mandate an ombudsperson and the CCC Transparency position paper. In April 2016, CCC expressed its frustration on this process that failed to reach any concrete outputs. MEPs decided to adopt an INI report on the flagship initiative on garment sector and CCC was provided inputs and comments on the drafts. Result not counted due to disappointing outcome. (1) Together with the MVO platform SKC/CCC presented our view on the Duty of Care research towards parliamentarians who raised it towards the government during official parliament hearings. SKC/CCC together with the MVO platform pushed for a MVO toezichthouder outside of the SER (Dutch Social and Economic Committee) to monitor the implementation of the convenants and to function as a independent body to be addressed by all stakeholders. (1) In May-June 2016, the International Labour Conference for the first time focused on &#x201C;decent work in global supply chains&#x201D;. The CCC contribution is the active participation in the ILC, the research and position paper done in advance, the lobbying done before and during the conference. CCC was present with a delegation of critical trade unions, to influence the debates both inside the workers groups as well as in plenary sessions (where we had received a speaking slot as International NGO) A position paper was shared and publicly referred to, and several points were taken up in the outcome papers. (0) The European Commission announced 2 years ago a flagship initiative on responsible management of the garment supply chain. CCC participated actively in the consultations and contributed with a proposal to mandate an ombudsperson and the CCC Transparency position paper. In April 2016, CCC expressed its frustration on this process that failed to reach any concrete outputs. MEPs decided to adopt an INI report on the flagship initiative on garment sector and CCC was provided inputs and comments on the drafts. Result not counted due to disappointing outcome. (1) Together with the MVO platform SKC/CCC presented our view on the Duty of Care research towards parliamentarians who raised it towards the government during official parliament hearings. SKC/CCC together with the MVO platform pushed for a MVO toezichthouder outside of the SER (Dutch Social and Economic Committee) to monitor the implementation of the convenants and to function as a independent body to be addressed by all stakeholders. (1) In May-June 2016, the International Labour Conference for the first time focused on &#x201C;decent work in global supply chains&#x201D;. The CCC contribution is the active participation in the ILC, the research and position paper done in advance, the lobbying done before and during the conference. CCC was present with a delegation of critical trade unions, to influence the debates both inside the workers groups as well as in plenary sessions (where we had received a speaking slot as International NGO) A position paper was shared and publicly referred to, and several points were taken up in the outcome papers. (0) The European Commission announced 2 years ago a flagship initiative on responsible management of the garment supply chain. CCC participated actively in the consultations and contributed with a proposal to mandate an ombudsperson and the CCC Transparency position paper. In April 2016, CCC expressed its frustration on this process that failed to reach any concrete outputs. MEPs decided to adopt an INI report on the flagship initiative on garment sector and CCC was provided inputs and comments on the drafts. Result not counted due to disappointing outcome. (1) Together with the MVO platform SKC/CCC presented our view on the Duty of Care research towards parliamentarians who raised it towards the government during official parliament hearings. SKC/CCC together with the MVO platform pushed for a MVO toezichthouder outside of the SER (Dutch Social and Economic Committee) to monitor the implementation of the convenants and to function as a independent body to be addressed by all stakeholders.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. (Dutch) political parties publicly endorse plans in relation to mandatory due diligence (1) as a result of CCC and partners from [LLMICs] sharing briefings, publishing a position paper and disseminating an info-graphic on the matter. 2. The European Parliament will discuss mandatory due diligence on EU level, as a result of CCC starting a European Citizen Initiative. (1) 3. Media pay attention to CCC&#x2019;s critique of the legitimacy of the Sustainable Apparel Coalition, as a result of CCC publishing reports, op-eds and otherwise conveying the message that the SAC&#x2019;s efforts at self-regulation are failing and that stronger, binding mechanisms are needed (1) 4. The Open Apparel Registry steering group will consider setting common data standards for the supply chain transparency data that brands are publishing, as a result of their collaboration with CCC. (1) 5. One or more brands will publicly support and sign the proposed Pakistan Accord on Fire and Building Safety, as result of lobby by CCC, allies such as trade unions and Pakistani CSOs. This creates a precedent for others to sign. (1) 6. The India Committee of the Netherland&apos;s research and publication of the research on working and living conditions of (migrant) workers in the garment and textile industry in Tamil Nadu results in an increased understanding of the topic among brands and retailers, business and multi-stakeholder initiatives and improved policies and actions taken by them such as include improved guidelines for migrant housing in their Codes of Conduct and/or taking housing of migrant workers into account while monitoring the situation. The research is done in collaboration with Indian partners. (1) 7. Public opinion in a number of key European and East Asian countries is influenced by successful campaigns in concrete Urgent Appeal cases. To achieve this, CCC enhances and strengthens the campaigning part of the Urgent Appeal manual, to make it more gender-specific and inclusive, and include more and different campaign strategies and better identify and map the pressure points of targeted brands. Another part of this is to continue the Urgent Appeal solidarity fund, to make sure campaigning presence in key strategic markets and countries in Europe and East Asia is enhanced. (1) 8. Digital security will be higher on the agenda of social movements as a vital and necessary precaution to combat their shrinking space, concretely as a result of a training by CCC in at least one region (lower estimate 5 CSOs), if funding can be found priority on extra national trainings in Cambodia and Bangladesh (for now count 1, as we don&apos;t know the number of CSOs that will participate). 9. Brands and retailers will implement guidelines for factory-provided housing. The India Committee of the Netherlands monitors the implementation through critical dialogue and engagement with partners in Bangalore and with brands and multi-stakeholder initiatives. (1) 10. The Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs fully supports/advocates its continuation in the Bangladesh Accord/the Transition Monitor Committee&#x2019;s agreement (1) as a result of political lobby by SKC (sharing write-ups and briefings amongst others). 11. One Dutch brand publishes a price make up (1) through developing and sharing a format for becoming transparent on how prices of a product are calculated. It shares this with other brands to increase transparency in relation to living wages. The format is partly based upon follow up research by CCC (done in 2018) on wages and working conditions of garment workers in South India (1). 12. The OECD National Contact Point decides on a legal case that CCC together with ECCHR filed in 2018 against auditing firm RINA to hold them accountable for failures in their auditing. A positive decision will expand legal options for remedy. (1) 13. The OECD decides positively on an ongoing complaint that CCC filed against Adidas on their failure of due diligence. (1) 14. The Dutch public gets an increased understanding of the importance of greater transparency in the garment industry, by SKC building a mobile sweatshop in a big city in the Netherlands, calling upon brands to sign the Transparency Pledge. (1) 15. Policy-makers engaged in the negotiations around the UN Binding Treaty on Business and Human Rights will bring in considerations around labour rights, as a result of CCC&#x2019;s work in the Advisory Committee of this treaty. (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCC organised and funded a trip to Denmark and The Netherlands of two Jaba Garmindo workers from Indonesia who made Uniqlo clothes for years, which was an unprecedented success in terms of outreach. We reached more than 2 million people, and Jaba Garmindo workers&#x2019; social media posts on the need for Uniqlo to pay the back wages and severance payments they were owed were shared more than 11.000 times. [1] The Turn Around, H&amp;M! Campaign calling upon H&amp;M to make good on its 2013 promise to pay workers in its supply chain a living wage ended up with over 180,000 signatures under the living wage petition, thousands of social media messages, media coverage (1) in a number of countries, and a mobilized base of consumers (1) who demand living wages for the workers who make their clothes. In May, CCC representatives handed over the #TurnAroundHM petition to the CEO Karl Johan Persson and Head of Sustainability Anna Gedda (1). During the subsequent shareholder meeting (AGM) the CEO reverted back to denying that H&amp;M had ever made the commitment at the center of the campaign, i.e. that 850,000 workers would be paid a living wage. [3] The CCC network report &#x2018;Tailored wages 2019: The state of pay in the global garment industry&#x2019; was launched. It reveals that none of the top 20 clothing companies can show that workers making their clothing in Asia, Africa, Central America or Eastern Europe are paid enough to escape the poverty trap. The research that underlies the Tailored wages 2019 report was additionally used by the University of Sheffield (1)for their study &apos;Corporate commitments to living wages in the garment industry&apos;, which was covered by some major media outlets (1) such as the Guardian and Reuters. [2] CCC together with the Pakistan Union and NGO partners, ILRF and WRC published Pakistan Safety report, &#x201C;PAKISTAN&#x2019;S GARMENT WORKERS NEED A SAFETY ACCORD&#x201D;, which included the call for a Pakistan Safety Agreement in line with the Bangladesh Accord by trade unions and labour groups in Pakistan. It was presented to employers, the labour ministry and labour department in Sindh Province, who responded positively (3), well covered in Pakistan media (1) and shared it with brands sourcing from Pakistan (e.g. H&amp;M, Next, Adidas, New Look, C&amp;A, Target, Zeeman) (1) to start discussing about Pakistan as their next focus. The report was also shared with the Dutch Agreement on Sustainable Garments and Textiles (AGT) (1) who in turn shared the information with their member brands via the internal newsletter. [5] The report &#x201C;Fig Leaf for Fashion. How social auditing protects brands and fails workers&#x201D; was launched, written by CCC, with input from partner experiences in LLMICs, with considerable pick-up from the media in various countries (e.g. Just-Style, Etsy, EcoTextile News, ASI). The report was promoted at the UN Forum on Business and Human Rights in Geneva [1] CCC Turkey published a report on the risks of potassium, a chemical substance used for bleaching denim. This report is the result of a study which researches potassium permanganate&#x2019;s (PP) harmful effects on denim bleaching workers. Being the first study conducted on the subject, it aims to lay foundation for future legal regulatory implementation, and was picked up by various Turkish media outlets [1] In 2018 C&amp;A promised to implement hostel guidelines in their supply chains in response to a complaint raised with C&amp;A followed from the report &quot;Labour without Liberty&quot; published in January of that year. Dutch CCC member Arisa followed up communication with C&amp;A to monitor the implementation of its promise by emails, calls and a meeting during the OECD conference on garment and footwear in Paris, Febr 2019. In a call in 2019, C&amp;A promised to Cividep, Garment Labour Union (GLU) and Arisa to share the guidelines in order to provide feedback on the guidelines. This did not happen. In October 2019, Arisa met again workers in India that were interviewed for the &quot;Labour without Liberty&quot; research. According to these workers no improvements in hostel conditions were realised. These findings were shared with C&amp;A and another AGT signatory brands. Arisa continues follow up with C&amp;A. C&amp;A again promised to share the almost finalised hostel guidelines soon. Even though no concrete result has been reached in 2019, Arisa is building a file in order to be able to submit a formal complaint with AGT&apos;s complaint mechanism if concrete outcomes will not follow soon. [1] A CCC press release on a new business-led safety initiative launched in August in Vietnam and India by the sustainable trade initiative IDH drew attention to the need for companies to move away from business-driven initiatives and to start putting worker representatives to the centre of their safety projects. The news was picked up by several trade-oriented media and debunked earlier reports that an initiative similar to the Bangladesh Accord was expanding into these countries. [1] The Dutch Ministry and Dutch Embassy to Bangladesh were regularly updated by CCC with input from Bangladeshi CCC members on developments related to the Bangladesh Accord and its successor the RSC through briefings, meetings and calls. CCC shared its concerns related to the process and also shares the need for a credible and effective continuation. [1] CCC generated increased understanding of the importance of greater transparency in the garment industry amongst Dutch public by huge media coverage on eight Dutch brands, such as HEMA and Marlies Dekkers, signing the Transparency Pledge and the launch of a new report that announced that now 39 brands have signed the transparency Pledge (up from 17 in 2017). Transparent supply chains enable access to remedy for workers as it makes clear who wields the most power in a supply chain. [1]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">- participation in the OECD advisory group, and the OECD forum on due diligence in the the garment and footwear sector. The following topics will be put on the agendas of these bodies: Transparency in (sub)contracting and sourcing of material Remedy mechanisms Freedom of Association rights and how to guarantee them &#x2013; Work with European lobby organisations to support the Transparency Pledge as policy goal across EU. &#x2013; Transparency Pledge accepted as a requirement for Fair Wear Foundation membership.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="14">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency Pledge: a public campaign together with a coalition (CCC, HRW, ICAR, ILRF, WRC, Maquila Solidarity Network, IndustriAll, ITUC, UNI Global Union), targeting 70+ brands to publish their supply chain. 70.000 signatures gathered. Several brands started making the data available due to the campaign. As a result Hugo Boss started to publish its production sites and Primark would start publishing its production sites in February 2018. (1) SKC published a position paper on Transparency including recommendations for brands and Dutch and European government underlining its importance. The paper was distributed to brands via the Covenant as well as to Dutch MPs and Dutch MEPs (1) A petition signed by nearly 11,000 people calling upon a living wage for garment workers in India was handed over to the Minister of Foreign Trade and Development Cooperation by SKC and the India Committee of the Netherlands. The minister promised to encourage the brands within the Dutch Agreement on Sustainable Garments and Textile (Covenant) to develop a roadmap to achieve a living wage. (1) Dutch Parliament questions have been raised in relation to the Bangladesh crackdown, transparency in supply chains, the first annual report of the Dutch Agreement, the Transition Accord 2018, different reports including SKC&apos;s publication on European Sweatshops, ICN&apos;s publication Fabric of Slavery and SOMO&apos;s report The Myanmar Dilemma. (1) CCC participated in the OECD round-table Due Diligence in Garment Sector and gave input on the debates (1) CCC presented a session and participated in other sessions at the UN Forum on Business and Human Rights raising the violations of human rights and labour rights in the supply chain (1) CCC joined the Worker-Driven Social Responsibility Network (WSR), participated in global meeting in NY where strategies for improving corporate conduct were discussed between a wide range of experts. (1) CCC Participated in ILC conference in Geneva, discussing Bangladeshi worker rights, FoA in Bangladesh and other countries (1) CCC published a report, did research and campaigned on poverty wages and mandatory overtime in South East Europe &amp; Turkey, which also set benchmarks for Living Wage in the various countries in the region. SKC released publication in Dutch. As a result, Mart Visser published its production countries on its website, not yet its suppliers list.(1) SKC made comparison between factory list of the Dutch Agreement on Sustainable Garments and Textile and the Bangladesh Accord on Building and Fire Safety revealing that not all Covenant signatory brands signed the Transition Accord 2018 even though it is recommended to the signatory companies. Following the comparison an intensive discussion between SKC and Covenant took place in regard to the importance of the Accord, and a request to all Covenant members to sign the Accord(1) Dutch and European Parliament Members stepped in SKCs pop-up sweatshop (street action) to sit behind a sewing machine to experience the daily life of women garment workers and called upon mandatory due diligence and transparency. This street action was well received by the passers-by and attracted a lot of media attention. (1) CCC in regular contact with Embassies (including the Dutch Embassy) and the EU about the political crackdown in Cambodia to seek opportunities to raise concerns bilateral or multilateral. The EU announced that it would watch Cambodia closely until the elections in 2018. CCC and allies also had meetings with ASEAN Parliamentarians for Human Rights about the situation. (1) As a result of CCCs reach out to international brands sourcing from Cambodia, the Ethical Trading Initiative sent a letter to the Minister of Labour and the Minister of Commerce to share concerns about the escalating repression in Cambodia. (1) CCC and SOMO jointly formulated recommendations to Fair Wear Foundation to improve the Myanmar policy based on the findings of the research report by SOMO revealing high risks on low wages, forced overtime, child labour and labour infringements at a number of factories. CCC shared feedback from Myanmar partners with FWF. Follow up discussion will take place within the Committee of Expert in 2018. (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">* A special discussion during the ILC on supply chains responsibility including wage protection, freedom of association and freedom of migration on ILC agenda (1); Transparency and disclosure of (garment) supply chain data on EU agenda (1), Proposal to Dutch ministry and parliament following the conclusions of the &#x201C;Duty of Care for Dutch companies&#x201D; research by University of Utrecht (1).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome E: Policies Changed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">These include improved government and corporate policies on corporate accountability, including transparency and safeguards policies, conflict resolution mechanisms, and policies promoting social justice, decent work and sustainability.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="TEXT/PLAIN" url="https://fairgreenglobal.org/">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
    </description>
    <category code="B01"></category>
   </document-link>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.E.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms, policies and regulations improved or introduced by national, regional and international government bodies to ensure companies promote more sustainable practices and are held accountable for respecting human rights and the environment and providing adequate remedy to victims of adverse impacts.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.E.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-05-12" value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(0)French legislative result achieved in 2017, so it will be part of next years&apos; reporting. (1) The German CCC actively lobbied and joined the German Textile Alliance, and works on several implementation projects (including in Tamil Nadu). They also managed to get stronger transparency requirements and the publication of due diligence reports included as mandatory conditions for brands to join the bundnis. CCC contribution was to get the policies on transparency accepted at the german budnis, which is a partnership of the german government, german companies and german TUs and CSO. As a membership condition of the bundnis companies HAVE to publish due diligence reports, which then will get reviewed, so that also is a policy change at the level of the company. Our contribution at IO was to provide inputs, documents, pressure on brands, to the german ccc who negotiated.(0)French legislative result achieved in 2017, so it will be part of next years&apos; reporting. (1) The German CCC actively lobbied and joined the German Textile Alliance, and works on several implementation projects (including in Tamil Nadu). They also managed to get stronger transparency requirements and the publication of due diligence reports included as mandatory conditions for brands to join the bundnis. CCC contribution was to get the policies on transparency accepted at the german budnis, which is a partnership of the german government, german companies and german TUs and CSO. As a membership condition of the bundnis companies HAVE to publish due diligence reports, which then will get reviewed, so that also is a policy change at the level of the company. Our contribution at IO was to provide inputs, documents, pressure on brands, to the german ccc who negotiated.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">French &quot;Duty of vigilence law&quot; was supported, and defended against following corporate backlash by sending public support letter and lobby, and CCC assessed impact for our purposes. French CCC played pivotal role in the eventual adoption of the law, supported by CCC IO (1) No progress on Czech due diligence UNGP law, so target not met there.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">French Legislative proposal parent company duty to care(1),Textile Alliance&#x2013; Germany (1),UNGP implementation through NAP &#x2013; Czech Republic, IMVO toezichthouder (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Labour Organization&#x2019;s annual Conference made history in 2019 by adopting the Convention and accompanying Recommendation to combat violence and harassment in the world of work. A number of CCC members, including the Asia Floor Wage Alliance, International Labor Rights Forum and more campaigned and lobbied over many years into making this happen. Two CCC member organisations have presented a roadmap for fast fashion brands on promoting women&apos;s leadership and implementing the historic convention. [1] As member of the MVO platform, CCC actively contributed to the realisation of the Dutch Child Labour Due Diligence law by providing input to Members of the Senate of the Dutch Parliament. [1]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2013; follow up on EU Flagship &amp; European Parliament resolutions to increase transparency in supply chain; In 2018 the EP will hopefully adopt a resolution to make EU import data public. - In order to make a case for stronger commitments towards paying a living wage by Dutch brands which signed the Dutch agreement on Sustainable garments and textile, a legal complaint will be filed at either the NCP or the complaint mechanism of the agreement on not paying a living wage in 10 factories in India. the mechanism that is aimed for is &quot;a stronger sustainable garment and textiles Agreement&quot;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.E.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># policies improved or introduced by companies on transparency and safeguards, conflict resolution mechanisms, and policies promoting social justice, decent work and sustainability.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.E.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">More companies sign FoA protocol Indonesia (2),companies that will release supplier lists/increase transparency supply chains (8), companies that adopt meaningful living wage policies (2)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No results yet</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. One (Dutch) target brand publicly supports the development of the Pakistan Safety Agreement and signs on when ready as a result of SKC&apos;s lobby and advocacy work on brands in regard to this topic. (1) 2. One (Dutch) target brand publicly supports the development of a living wage Enforceable Brand Agreement (EBA) and signs on when ready (1). SKC achieves this through joining the international CCC campaign (in which a variety of LLMIC partners are represented) in targeting brands, joining an international public launch of the living wage EBA and through writing a position paper on the matter. 3. CCC&apos;s work in the Transparency Pledge coalition includes contributing to an update of the report, putting pressure on brands and others to sign the Pledge. Several more brands, online retailers and MSIs start publishing their supply chain data according to (or exceeding) the Transparency Pledge (1) We expect (3) more Dutch brands to sign the Pledge, and both the Fair Wear Foundation and the Dutch Covenant (both of which are MSIs that have many brands in their membership) will adopt the policy to make Pledge adherence a condition for membership in future years (2) 4. One or more brands and MSIs (of which brands are a part) sign the Indonesia Freedom of Association Protocol as a result of CCC lobby(1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CCC network&#x2019;s lobby work with Fair Wear Foundation and with AGT to make the Transparency Pledge a condition for its member brands resulted in a strengthened transparency policy including amongst others a factory list supplying FWF member brands publicly available through a search function on the website [1]. At the AGT stakeholder day, eight Dutch brands [8] signed the Transparency Pledge, promising to disclose their supply chains along the transparency pledge standard, all members of the Dutch Agreement for Sustainable Textile and Garments. [8] Through its engagement in the Committee of Experts, CCC lobbied the Fair Wear Foundation (1) to make signing the Bangladesh Accord a condition for its member brands. Even though signing the Bangladesh Accord is part of Fair Wear&#x2019;s enhanced monitoring policy for Bangladesh that member brands need to follow, it is not mandatory. However, FWF member brands sourcing from Bangladesh who repeatedly do not comply to this requirement are sanctioned and will go to the &#x201C;needs improvement&#x201D; category that will lead to termination in case of no betterment. Almost all AGT (1) member brands signed the Bangladesh Accord as a result of strengthened yearly assessment of brands by the Covenant in regard to this topic. Neither of the MSI&#x2019;s made it mandatory to their brands. [2]</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &quot;Period 2016-2017&quot;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &quot;Period 2016&quot; and &quot;Period 2017&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three more brands signed up to the Indonesia FoA protocol and adapted their internal policies accordingly: Hagl&#xF6;fs, Kjus and SuitSupply (Dutch). (3)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2013; inclusion of boiler safety into the Bangladesh Accord since boiler explosions are a frequent cause of fatal incidents and are not currently covered under inspection regimes (1) &#x2013; use the reference document on critique of social auditing (finalized Q4 2017) to move brands from &#x2018;audit &amp; ignore&#x2019; to &#x2018;inspect and remedy&#x2019;. (1) &#x2013; improvement in the Indonesia FoA Protocol and more brands, FWF, and other MSIs sign on to the improved second Indonesia FoA Protocol (1)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
