<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">SCUOLA APERTA: ALLEANZE EDUCATIVE PER L&#x2019;INCLUSIONE</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto si inserisce nell&#x2019;attuale Programma Nazionale d&#x2019;Educazione Inclusiva del Regno del Marocco che 
prevede l&#x2019;inclusione delle bambine e dei bambini con disabilit&#xE0; (BcD) all&#x2019;interno delle scuole ordinarie attraverso 
l&#x2019;applicazione delle Linee Guida Operative sull&#x2019;Inclusione scolastica, destinate ai docenti, ai funzionari 
ministeriali e alle associazioni. L&#x2019;obiettivo dell&#x2019;iniziativa &#xE8; promuovere e attivare l&#x2019;inclusione attraverso la 
formazione del personale docente e di quello ausiliario, sensibilizzare la popolazione attraverso le attivit&#xE0; sul 
territorio. I volontari dello Sviluppo Inclusivo su base Comunitaria (SIBC), che operano capillarmente in tutte le 
regioni del progetto, permetteranno di raggiungere le famiglie dei BcD. Le Organizzazioni della Societ&#xE0; Civile 
(OSC) che si occupano di disabilit&#xE0; e che rivestono un importante ruolo di riferimento, saranno il collegamento 
tra le famiglie e le istituzioni. L&#x2019;intervento si concentra sugli inserimenti dei Bambini/e con disabilit&#xE0; nelle scuole 
ordinarie e sul potenziamento della qualit&#xE0; dell&#x2019;insegnamento e miglioramento dell&#x2019;accoglienza nelle classi
risorsa. I docenti riceveranno un ciclo di formazioni sulle metodologie pedagogiche adeguate al Nuovo 
Programma Nazionale di Educazione Inclusiva grazie alle quali saranno in grado di formulare un Progetto 
Pedagogico Individuale, che permetta l&#x2019;inclusione del BcD all&#x2019;interno della classe ed il raggiungimento degli 
obiettivi didattici. Il progetto si propone altres&#xEC; di formare il personale ausiliario che opera all&#x2019;interno delle 
scuole e che non ha conoscenze sulle corrette modalit&#xE0; di supporto ai Bambini/e con disabilit&#xE0; sia per i bisogni 
personali che per le attivit&#xE0; didattiche, impostando cos&#xEC; un lavoro in sinergia tra le diverse figure che operano 
nelle scuole. Indispensabile sar&#xE0; l&#x2019;adeguamento degli spazi dedicati alle attivit&#xE0; dei BcD, la &#x201C;classe Risorsa&#x201D; in 
particolare, che consentir&#xE0; attivit&#xE0; personalizzate. Le classi ordinarie dovranno essere adattate in modo da 
consentire l&#x2019;agevole l&#x2019;inserimento del BcD. La classe Risorsa &#xE8; la nuova opportunit&#xE0; introdotta dall&#x2019;attuale 
legislazione che prevede all&#x2019;interno di ogni scuola uno spazio dedicato alla gestione dei BcD: quest&#x2019; aula, 
attrezzata adeguatamente, consente all&#x2019;insegnante formato di lavorare con BcD applicando metodologie 
appropriate per favorire l&#x2019;apprendimento secondo le loro sensibilit&#xE0;. OVCI si occupa di disabilit&#xE0; in Marocco da 
decenni: in collaborazione con il partner Casa Lahnina nel 2007 &#xE8; stato aperto il primo Centro Socio-Educativo 
(CSE) di tutto il Marocco, rivolto a soggetti con grave disabilit&#xE0; ed &#xE8; stata realizzata una Classe Speciale pilota 
(CLIS) per bambini con disabilit&#xE0; medio-lieve. Il progetto operer&#xE0; sul territorio affinch&#xE9; si possa eliminare lo 
stigma ancora presente verso i Bambini/e con disabilit&#xE0; e questi possano essere inclusi nella vita sociale del 
paese: l&#x2019;accettazione della disabilit&#xE0; in famiglia &#xE8; il primo passo verso l&#x2019;inclusione. Attraverso il lavoro con le OSC 
e con i volontari SIBC si raggiungeranno le famiglie per sostenerle nella fase di accettazione della disabilit&#xE0;, di 
conoscenza delle istituzioni e dei servizi a loro dedicati, nonch&#xE9; nella fase dell&#x2019;inserimento e dell&#x2019;inclusione
scolastica. I volontari SIBC sono residenti nel territorio in cui operano e conoscono le dinamiche sociali, famigliari e le complessit&#xE0; della relazione con le istituzioni locali. I volontari sono formati sulle metodologie della 
SIBC e, affiancati dal personale tecnico (fisioterapisti, logopedisti, ecc.), stimolano le famiglie a corretti e positivi 
atteggiamenti verso i figli/e con disabilit&#xE0;, aiutandole ad uscire dai pregiudizi. L&#x2019;operato delle OSC sar&#xE0; sinergico 
con i volontari, le istituzioni locali e le scuole che si occupano di BcD. Le attivit&#xE0; di sensibilizzazione saranno
rivolte a tutti i componenti della societ&#xE0; al fine di evidenziare come la scolarizzazione sia un passo fondamentale 
verso l&#x2019;inclusione sociale</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is part of the current National Inclusive Education Program of the Kingdom of Morocco which 
provides for the inclusion of girls and boys with disabilities in mainstream schools through the application of the 
Operational Guidelines on School Inclusion, intended for teachers, ministerial officials and associations.
The aim of the initiative is to promote and activate the inclusion through the training of teachers and auxiliary 
staff, and to raise awareness among the population with local activities. The volunteers of the Community Based 
Inclusive Development (CBID), who operate extensively in all the regions of the project, will reach the families of 
children with disabilities. Civil Society Organizations (CSOs) that deal with disabilities and play an important role 
of reference, will be involved as a social glue between families and institutions. The intervention focuses on the 
inclusion for children with disabilities in ordinary schools and on the enhancement of the quality of teaching and 
on the improvement of &#x201C;resources class&#x201D;. The teaching staff will receive a cycle of training on pedagogical 
methodologies, appropriate to the New National Program of Inclusive Education, thanks to which they will be 
able to formulate an Individual Pedagogical Project, which allows the inclusion of the child with disabilities in the 
classroom and the achievement of the identified didactic goals. The project also aims to train auxiliary staff who 
work within schools and do not have knowledge on the correct methods of supporting children with disabilities, 
both for personal needs and for educational activities, thus setting up a job in synergy between the different 
figures who work in schools. It will be essential to adapt the spaces dedicated to the activities of children with 
disabilities, the &quot;Resource class&quot; in particular, which will allow personalized activities according their sensibility. 
The ordinary classes must be adapted to allow the easy inclusion of children with disabilities. The Resource class 
is the new opportunity introduced by the current legislation which provides within each school a space 
dedicated to the management of children with disabilities. This classroom, adequately equipped, allows the 
trained teacher to work individually or in small groups with children with disabilities, applying appropriate 
methodologies to facilitate the learning. OVCI has a specific expertise mainly deals with disabilities and has 
acquired the ten-year experience in this area: in 2007, together with the partner Casa Lahnina, the first SocioEducational Center (SEC) was opened in the whole Morocco, aimed at people with severe disabilities and a 
Special Pilot Class (SPC) was created for children with medium-mild disabilities. The project will operate in the 
area so that the stigma towards children with disabilities can be deleted and they can be included in the social 
life of the Country. Through the work with the CSOs on the territory and with the CBID volunteers, we will reach 
families to support them in the phase of acceptance, knowledge of the institutions and services dedicated to 
them, as well as in the delicate phase of inclusion and school inclusion. CBID volunteers live in the area in which 
they operate and know the social and familiar dynamics and the complexities of the relationship with local 
institutions. Volunteers will be trained on CBID methodologies. Supported by technical staff (physiotherapists, 
speech therapists, etc.), they will work within families too. The Civil Society Organizations will be the 
fundamental local support for all this inclusion process. Their work will be synergistic with the volunteers and 
institutions present in the area (and schools) that deal with children with disabilities. Activities for raising the 
awareness will be aimed at all members of society in order to highlight how schooling is a fundamental step 
towards social inclusion</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OVCI - ORGANISMO DI VOLONTARIATO PER LA COOPERAZIONE INTERNAZIONALE ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/05/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="11120" percentage="10" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education facilities and training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="99820" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promotion of development awareness (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Teacher training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure that all learners acquire the knowledge and skills needed to promote sustainable development, including, among others, through education for sustainable development and sustainable lifestyles, human rights, gender equality, promotion of a culture of peace and non-violence, global citizenship and appreciation of cultural diversity and of culture&#x2019;s contribution to sustainable development</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-28">1037795.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OVCI - ORGANISMO DI VOLONTARIATO PER LA COOPERAZIONE INTERNAZIONALE ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-12">622677.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OVCI - ORGANISMO DI VOLONTARIATO PER LA COOPERAZIONE INTERNAZIONALE ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
