<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA-18/NIG_ERF/RA1/WASH/UN/8652</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lifesaving humanitarian WASH response for new arrivals in Pulka, Borno State North East Nigeria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project interventions will overall benefit about 15,800 IDPs, host communities and returnees in Pulka with improved coverage levels for water supply, sanitation and hygiene. Focusing on new arrivals, 9,000 people in 3 camps (Damara Arrival Centre, Wege Arrival Centre and Wege Extension) will access safe water through water trucking for three months, and improved sanitation through 50 new shared combined latrines and shower blocks. All 15,800 people will be reached through hygiene messages while 9,000 people will be reached by newly drilled boreholes. Currently four partners are collaborating to support delivery of basic WASH service for IDPs and host community in Pulka: IOM, OXFAM, UNICEF and the Borno State Rural Water and Sanitation Agency (RUWASA)).  Water supply services are being run for 15 hours per day but the yield of source boreholes is getting less, indicating ground water is drying up as these water resources are overstretching their capacity. Over the course of the last two months, returnees and IDPs are arriving daily. As the current water structures are at their maximum capacity water source need to be found outside of the safety perimeter of Pulka town. The ground around Pulka is very hard and rocky and groundwater is found is fissures and fractures within depths of 60 metres.  Combined geophysical methods (Electromagnetic and Resistivity surveys) are thus needed to identify potential for groundwater development. UNICEF will review existing data from recent surveys conducted by RUWASA for OXFAM RUWASA will provide equipment and personnel for additional geophysical studies as well as the drilling (up to 4 solarized and 2 hand pump boreholes) that will increase the water supply coverage for all while focusing on the new arrivals. Through the geophysical study an area outside the current secured zone will be identified for the drilling.  

In the context of stretched borehole capacities within the Pulka town, the nearest water source for water trucking is at Gwoza, 21 km outside of Pulka, meaning outside of the safety barrier laid out around Pulka. Therefore, the water trucking needs to be done through military convoy as the road is extremely hazardous with security issues such as IEDs, mines and other risks. This daily water trucking will provide water daily for 7,000 individuals. Bacteriological water quality will be monitored for each water sources used in targeted areas to ensure water provided to the people is safe.  Similarly, Free Residual Chlorine will be monitored on regular basis at water point and household level. 

IOM is planning the construction of 1,500 additional shelters in Pulka on top of the reception centre upgrade. UNICEF will simultaneously provide gender segregated sanitation facilities comprising 150 latrines (drop holes) and 100 showers in 50 combined blocks of 3 latrines/2 showers. Concurrently UNICEF will monitor the filling up of existing and newly constructed latrines and will desludge latrines when deemed necessary, waste will be &#x2018;dumped&#x2019; in created waste pits, identified in close coordination with IOM.  There are plans to develop, using existing resources, a managed sludge dumping site through the Borno State Environmental Protection agency (BOSEPA). Hygiene promotion is included in all WASH interventions UNICEF is implementing. Hygiene promotion sessions will take place in the different camps and latrine cleaning kits will be distributed to latrine maintenance volunteers, who will receive training from RUWASA supported supervisors and community mobilizers on maintenance and cleaning of the latrines. 

UNICEF will mainstream gender throughout all activities and interventions with social mobilizers involved in the implementation of the project. UNICEF is committed to contribute toward preventing and responding to gender-based violence (GBV) in emergencies through these types of projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>zjurji@unicef.org</telephone>
   <email>Zaid Jurji</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geoffrey Ijumba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief of Field Office</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348036590388</telephone>
   <email>gijumba@unicef.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kabuka Mwatama Banda</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2347064184030</telephone>
   <email>kbanda@unicef.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olayinka Afolabi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+2348036590421</telephone>
   <email>oafolabi@unicef.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG008">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Borno</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.88898010 13.15334698</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-22">424645.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NGA75-8652">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-22">424645.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303248782">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">424645.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-NGA75-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
