<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10081</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Antonio International Terminal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)    Project NameChile - San Antonio International Terminal (San Antonio)    RegionLatin America and the Caribbean        Sector   Project No010081   Projected Board DateMay 8, 2000   Company NameSan Antonio Terminal Internacional S.A. (STI)   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	San Antonio Terminal Internacional S.A.&apos;&apos;s (STI) shareholders consist of: Sudamericana Agencias A&#xE9;reas y Mar&#xED;timas S.A. (SAAM), a Chilean stevedoring and transport service company owned by Compa&#xF1;ia Sud Americana de Vapores, a shipping company; and Stevedoring Services of America, a US-based international port operator.          Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	The estimated project cost is US$178 million, including concession fees, civil works, equipment, contingencies, value added tax, working capital and financing fees.  IFC proposed investment would include an A loan of up to US$35 million, a B loan of up to US$65 million and an equity investment of up to US$3.7 million.         Location of Project and Description of Site    	The project site is located in the city and province of San Antonio, in the Region V of Chile, about 100 km west of Santiago, which makes it the closest port to the capital city.  The area under the concession is the Molo Sur Terminal within the Port of San Antonio and comprises about 30 hectares, of which 18 hectares will be developed as a container yard.  The area also includes an existing 565-meter quay that will be extended to 725 meters.  The average water depth at the quay side is in excess of 10 meters.  In addition to good road access, the terminal is served directly by rail and a rail yard exists within the port.          Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	STI has been established exclusively to operate, maintain and expand the Molo Sur Terminal under a 20-year concession by Empresa Portuaria San Antonio (EMPORT), the port authority of San Antonio.  The purpose of the project is to expand the terminal&apos;&apos;s capacity from 300,000 teu to 600,000 teu per year and to improve the overall efficiency and quality of the terminals services.  IFC would be arranging long-term financing for the project including mobilizing debt from international sources.  San Antonio is one of the first three ports to be privatized in Chile.  Accordingly, IFCs support of the project is expected to have an important demonstration impact on the port sector.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure because specific impacts may result which can be avoided or mitigated by adhering to generally recognized performance standards, guidelines, or design criteria.  The potential environmental, safety and health and social issues associated with the project are: construction and maintenance dredging and dredge spoil disposal; effluent treatment; stormwater management; oil/hazardous materials storage and handling; handling and storage of dangerous cargoes; solid and hazardous waste disposal; emergency planning and response; employee health, safety, and training programs; and EHS organization and management.   IFC concludes that the proposed project will meet the applicable World Bank/IFC environmental and social policies and the environmental, health and safety guidelines upon successful implementation of the measures described above.   IFC will evaluate the project&apos;&apos;s compliance with the applicable environmental and social requirements during the lifetime of the project by reviewing the annual monitoring reports (AMRs) prepared by the project and conducting periodic site supervision visits.        The  is  from the InfoShop.   Host country location of environmental documentsOffices of EMPORT in San Antonio    Date SPI sent to InfoShop April 6, 2000   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Antonio Terminal Internacional S.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10081" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-11-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-12-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chile</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CL-Chile">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-30.0000000000 -71.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BB - Port and Harbor Operations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $38.70 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-11-15">35000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-11-15">3700000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-11-15">35000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Antonio Terminal Internacional S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-11-15">3700000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">San Antonio Terminal Internacional S.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10081/san-antonio-international-terminal">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
