<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-20217</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.Diego Portales</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University operates two campuses, in Santiago and Temuco.  It has approximately 9,300 students, 1000 professors, and offers 31 undergraduate degrees and 25 graduate programs (masters degree, post-graduate degree, executive programs and diplomas) within 8 faculties.  In addition, it conducts research in multiple areas funded, in part, by top international granting agencies (e.g. Ford Foundation, Fulbright Commission, UNESCO, etc.)  The university interacts with over 80 foreign universities through agreements and has received more than 200 foreign students.

The project consists of the construction and refurbishment of campus buildings.  UDP will follow new building regulations being proposed by the Municipality to help preserve the districts heritage and traditional architecture.  UDPs aim is to create a fully integrated urban campus that will link and standardize its faculty buildings. The project includes the construction of three new university buildings and the refurbishment/expansion of six existing sites.  It will cover approximately 50,000 sq.m. (including new construction and refurbishment).  Implementation is planned to begin in April 2003 and last approximately 20 months.

According to the same objectives, UDP is actively participating in a public-private partnership called BUS  (Barrio Universitario de Santiago, Santiagos University District) that intends to refurbish public space, squares, pedestrian walks, in order to improve the living standards in this area. The main partners (UDP, the Municipality and several educational institutions as universities, schools and technical institutes located in the area) have signed an agreement that defines the priorities and establishes an image of what the district should be in the next years. 

One of the universitys defining characteristics is its pluralism and commitment to the exchange of ideas from all parts of society.  The project will help foster links with the neighborhood (through a common auditorium, library, and cafeteria open to the public).  Also, the bond issuance itself is an important signal to the market of UDPs progressiveness and outwardness.  Both the project and the bond will solidify UDPs brand and better position vis-a-vis competition.  Also, the additional space will allow UDP to increase its student enrollment proportionately with the Ministry of Educations projections for the increase in demand for higher education over the next decade.

IFC will be assisting a successful private university to innovatively raise capital for its diversification and expansion through a local bond issue.  It will build the universitys investor base.  This structuring is the first for a higher education project undertaken by IFC and the first of its kind in Latin America region.  Also, it is expected to be among the first future cash flow securitizations in Chile.  It can provide a demonstration model for replication elsewhere.  IFCs credit enhancement will be essential for the bond to reach the AA- rating needed to attract institutional investors and, in turn, will allow local institutional investors to diversify their investment holdings into an as of yet untapped sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universidad Diego Portales</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-20217" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-02-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chris McCahan, Investment Officer
International Finance Corporation
Email&#xA0;: cmccahan@ifc.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chile</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CL-Chile">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The campus is located in the southwest district of downtown Santiago. It is in an area called the University District, co-located with other universities and colleges, retail outlets, residential housing, services, and public spaces.  The University is bordered by three major thoroughfares: Republica Street, Alameda Street, and the Panamericana Highway, making it highly accessible to students and professors.  Two subway stations cover the area, as well as public transportation buses.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-30.0000000000 -71.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Colleges, Universities, and Professional Schools</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2003-02-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2003-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-02-26">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2003-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-02-26">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universidad Diego Portales</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/20217/u-diego-portales">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
