<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Per una vita indipendente: organizzazione di un percorso di formazione  professionale per l&apos;inclusione lavorativa delle persone con disabilit&#xE0; in  Tun</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;istruzione di qualit&#xE0;, equa ed inclusiva &#xE8; strumento imprescindibile di inclusione sociale delle fasce vulnerabili
della popolazione, come descritto nel Documento Triennale di Programmazione e di Indirizzo (2019-2021)
dell&#x2019;AICS. L&#x2019;iniziativa proposta, di durata triennale, intende contribuire ad assicurare un&#x2019;istruzione di qualit&#xE0;, 
equa e inclusiva, per le persone con disabilit&#xE0; in Tunisia (Obiettivo Generale/Impatto a lungo termine, in linea 
con l&#x2019;OSS 4 / Target 4.5). L&#x2019;obiettivo Specifico (in linea con l&#x2019;OSS 4.4 / Target 4.4.) intende migliorare le 
competenze tecniche e professionali dei giovani e adulti con disabilit&#xE0; nei Governatorati di Le Kef, Kasserine e 
Medenine in modo da facilitare il loro inserimento nell&#x2019;impiego e nell&#x2019;imprenditoria. L&#x2019;idea del presente 
progetto nasce proprio dal confronto costante avvenuto tra gli esperti AIFO ed i rappresentanti dei diversi 
ministeri tunisini, in particolar il Ministero degli Affari Sociali/Comitato Generale per la Promozione Sociale 
(MAS/CGPS, partner locale del progetto) oltre che della societ&#xE0; civile. Il personale AIFO &#xE8; stato invitato a 
partecipare, come consulente tecnico, alle riunioni tra i funzionari ministeriali preposti ed i loro partner locali. 
Grazie alla partecipazione a questi incontri &#xE8; stato possibile avere un quadro generale della situazione, sia a livello di priorit&#xE0; per il Governo che a livello di necessit&#xE0;/bisogni, garantendo in tal modo la sostenibilit&#xE0; futura 
del progetto. Oltre all&#x2019;approccio ed al punto di vista pi&#xF9; istituzionale, la presente proposta sar&#xE0; arricchita 
dall&#x2019;esperienza di COPE e ARCO/PIN (Partner italiani) che garantiranno il sostegno tecnico e operativo 
necessari. 
I bisogni identificati durante l&#x2019;assessment riportano ad una medesima causa: il limitato accesso delle PcD alle 
opportunit&#xE0; formative esistenti, determinato a sua volta dalla scarsa accessibilit&#xE0; di queste ultime. Nonostante 
imprenditori e OSC abbiano evidenziato la conoscenza delle norme che incentivano la contrattazione di PcD, 
questi ritengono che la formazione delle PcD &#xE8; insufficiente a permetterne l&#x2019;inclusione nel mondo del lavoro. 
I beneficiari diretti dell&#x2019;azione, saranno: i formatori e utenti dei corsi tecnici professionali esistenti nel Paese; i 
Rappresentanti del Ministero del Lavoro; i giovani e adulti con disabilit&#xE0; che parteciperanno a corsi di 
formazione professionale; i Rappresentanti dell&#x2019;imprenditoria locale; Rappresentanti delle Organizzazioni della 
Societ&#xE0; Civile (OSC) e delle Organizzazioni delle persone con Disabilit&#xE0; locali (OPD); i fruitori delle campagne di 
informazione previste. I beneficiari indiretti saranno i familiari delle persone con disabilit&#xE0; che hanno 
partecipato ai percorsi tecnici e professionali, i datori di lavoro che potranno contare su mano d&#x2019;opera 
qualificata. In futuro, ne beneficeranno tutte le persone con disabilit&#xE0; e la societ&#xE0; tunisina nel suo complesso 
che potr&#xE0; finalmente fare tesoro delle capacit&#xE0; di una fetta importante della sua popolazione il cui potenziale 
attualmente non pu&#xF2; esprimersi a causa di barriere nel sistema formativo. Presupposto indispensabile per il 
raggiungimento dell&#x2019;obiettivo specifico, contribuendo al impatto a lungo termine, &#xE8; garantire l&#x2019;offerta di 
un&#x2019;educazione professionale di qualit&#xE0;, creando curricula adeguati e pensati per essere accessibili a tutti e 
riconosciuti istituzionalmente. A tal fine si prevede di raggiungere i seguenti risultati attesi (2): le agenzie 
tunisine per la Promozione Industriale e per la Formazione Professionale, riconoscono i curricula formativi 
accessibili ed inclusivi adatti alle esigenze delle persone con disabilit&#xE0; (Risultato in linea con l&#x2019;OSS 4 / Target 
4.5); I giovani e gli adulti con disabilit&#xE0; hanno ricevuto una formazione tecnica, che include uno stage 
professionalizzante, riconosciuta dall&#x2019;Agenzia Tunisina per la Formazione Professionale (Risultato in linea con 
l&#x2019;OSS 4 / Target 4.4).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quality, equitable and inclusive education is an indispensable tool for the social inclusion of vulnerable 
population groups, as described in the Triennial Programming and Steering Document (2019-2021) of the 
Italian Development Cooperation. The proposed three-year initiative aims to contribute to ensuring quality, 
equitable and inclusive education for persons with disabilities in Tunisia (General Objective/Long Term Impact, 
in line with OSS 4 / Target 4.5). The Specific Objective (in line with OSS 4.4 / Target 4.4.) aims to improve the 
technical and vocational skills of young people and adults with disabilities in the Governorates of Le Kef, 
Kasserine and Medenine in order to facilitate their inclusion in employment and entrepreneurship. The idea of 
this project stemmed from the constant dialogue between AIFO experts and representatives of the different 
Tunisian ministries, especially the Ministry of Social Affairs/Committee General for Social Promotion 
(MAS/CGPS, local partner of the project) as well as the civil society. AIFO local staff were invited to participate 
as technical advisors in meetings between the relevant ministerial officials and their local partners. By 
participating in these meetings, it was possible to get a general picture of the situation, both at the level of 
priorities for the Government and at the level of needs/requirements, thus ensuring the future sustainability 
of the project. In addition to the more institutional approach and point of view, this proposal will be enriched 
by the experience of COPE and ARCO/PIN (Italian Partners) who will guarantee the necessary technical and 
operational support. The needs collected during the assessment point to the same cause: the limited access of people with 
disabilities (PwDs) to existing training opportunities, determined by the limited accessibility of these 
opportunities. Despite the fact that entrepreneurs and OSCs have pointed out that their knowledge of norms 
encouraging the inclusion of PwDs, they believe that the training of PwDs is insufficient to permit their inclusion 
in the Tunisian economic system. 
The direct beneficiaries of the action will be: the trainers and users of the vocational technical courses existing 
in the country; Representatives of the Ministry of Labour; young people and adults with disabilities who will 
participate in vocational training courses; Representatives of local entrepreneurs; Representatives of Civil 
Society Organisations (CSOs) and local Organisations of Persons with Disabilities (OPDs); people that will access 
the planned information campaigns. Indirect beneficiaries will be family members of persons with disabilities 
who participated in the technical and vocational courses, employers who will be able to count on qualified 
labour. In the future, all persons with disabilities and the Tunisian society as a whole will benefit, as they will 
be able to make use of the skills of a large part of their population whose potential cannot be expressed due 
to cultural barriers. A prerequisite for the achievement of the specific objective, contributing to the long-term 
impact, is to ensure the provision of quality vocational education, creating appropriate curricula designed to 
be accessible to all and institutionally recognised. To this end, the following expected results are expected (2): 
Tunisian agencies for Industrial Promotion, and for Vocational Training recognize accessible and inclusive 
training curricula suited to the needs of people with disabilities (Result in line with OSS 4 / Target 4.5); Young 
persons and adults with disabilities have received technical training, including a professional internship, 
recognised by the Tunisian Agency for Vocational Training (Result in line with OSS 4 / Target 4.4).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA AMICI DI RAOUL FOLLEREAU ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/01/3" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-24">1757413</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA AMICI DI RAOUL FOLLEREAU ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">1054448</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA AMICI DI RAOUL FOLLEREAU ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
