<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-41382</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPM Debt Facility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i) Stakeholder effects: The Facility will improve access to finance for secondary cities in South Africa with limited access to commercial debt. The Facility supports implementation of a portfolio of municipal infrastructure projects, and by leveraging the municipalities balance sheets, these municipalities can accelerate much needed infrastructure investments. Furthermore, the Facility will support projects that address climate change, with potential implications on access to urban infrastructure services.

(ii) Integration: The Project would mobilize capital for municipal finance, with the potential to engage new investors to the underserved secondary cities. Furthermore, IFC&apos;s engagement will create a demonstration effect, which is expected to mobilize greater commercial financing in future fund-raising efforts by these municipalities. 

(iii) Resilience - By enabling secondary municipalities to establish a borrowing track record, the Project contributes to reducing dependence on government transfers for municipal infrastructure projects. The Facility will also provide technical assistance to build capacities of secondary municipalities, including in financial planning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is an investment in INCA Portfolio Manager&apos;s (IPM) Infrastructure Debt Facility (the Facility), a debt facility that is being set up to on-lend to creditworthy secondary municipalities (munis) in South Africa (SA). The Facility aims to enable access to commercial finance for creditworthy secondary cities in SA, where more than 80% of municipal financing is directed towards only 8 large metropolitan municipalities (out of over 200 municipalities in SA). In addition, the Facility is expected to be supported by a capacity building fund separately funded by the Switzerland State Secretariat for Economic Affairs (SECO), which will support these munis in prioritizing investment needs and in preparing bankable proposals for commercial financing. This would enable access to commercial financing for the munis to help them establish a borrowing track record and ultimately to reduce dependence on transfers from the national government..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INCA PORTFOLIO MANAGERS (PTY) LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-41382" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INCA Portfolio Managers Pty. Ltd.  Attie van Zyl  Chief Executive Officer  +2783 701 2443  attie.vanzyl@inca.co.za  Unit F14, Pinewood Office Park Square, 33 Riley Road, Woodmead Ext 3, Sandton, P.O. Box 1847, Gallo Manor, 2052  www.incaportfoliomanagers.co.za</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="ZA-South Africa">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-29.0000000000 24.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/41382/ipm-debt-facility">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/41382/ipm-debt-facility">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
