<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-31083</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abengoa CSP SA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	Increasing South Africa&apos;&apos;s renewable energy output and helping the country meet its renewable energy targets, including by diversifying its renewable energy mix.  South Africa is facing electricity supply and demand imbalances that risk power cuts and the increased generation capacity from the Project will help to address this.  2.	Associated displacement of thermal power, resulting in avoidance of carbon emissions and local air pollutants (Sox and NOx) associated with South Africa&apos;&apos;s predominant coal-fired power.  3.	Demonstration effect, as one of the first private sector renewable energy projects in South Africa and the first CSP projects in sub-Saharan Africa, proving the viability of financing a large CSP project on a limited recourse basis, demonstrating the suitability of solar power to South Africa given its excellent solar resources, and supporting the successful role out of the first projects under South Africa&apos;&apos;s new renewable energy independent power producer program.  4.	Job creation/community development: the local communities will benefit through (i) significant sourcing of labor from local communities during the construction period, and overall job creation during the construction and operation periods; (ii) community development programs undertaken as a result of direct ownership in the power plant companies by Community Trusts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project consists of the construction and operation of two greenfield concentrating solar power (CSP) projects near the towns of Upington and Pofadder, in South Africas Northern Cape Province, by Abengoa Solar, through its affiliates Abengoa Solar South Africa (Pty) Ltd (ASSA) and Son Revieren (Pty) Ltd, in partnership with the Industrial Development Corporation (IDC). Abengoa Solars parent company, Abengoa S.A. (Abengoa) is a leading developer of renewable energy projects. CSP is a term used to describe a variety of technologies by which solar energy is concentrated onto a receiver to heat steam for use in industrial or electricity generation applications.  !Ka Xu will use a parabolic trough CSP design and !Khi will use a power tower CSP design.  The power plants will sell electricity to the state owned utility, Eskom, under twenty year power purchase agreements.    !Ka Xu is a 100 MW parabolic trough CSP plant, with approximately 2.5 hours of molten salt storage, located 40 km from the town of Pofadder with an estimated total cost of ZAR 7.5 billion (approximately US$860 million). The solar plant will be located on the land of farm Scuit Klip 92 and will feed power into the Eskom Paulputs substation located approximately 1 km from the site. It will be structured as a special purpose vehicle and the project company is !Ka Xu CSP South Africa (Pty) Ltd.  !Khi is a 50 MW steam receiver power tower CSP plant, with approximately 2.0 hours of steam storage, located 15 km from the town of Upington with a total provisional estimated cost of ZAR 3.9 billion (approximately US$445 million). The solar plant will be located on the land of farm Mc Taggarts Camp 453 and will feed power into the Eskom 132kV transmission line located approximately 5 km from the site. It will be structured as a special purpose vehicle and the project company is !Khi CSP South Africa (Pty) Ltd.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaxu Solar One (RF) Proprietary Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-31083" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Louis van Heerden General Manager Abengoa Solar South Africa (Pty) Ltd Lord Offices Estate Block 10 276 West Avenue Centurion Telephone: +27126430033&#xA0; Fax: +27126631881 Email:  mailto:Louis.VanHeerden@solar.abengoa.com  Website:  http://www.abengoa.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="ZA-South Africa">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both plants will be located in the Northern Cape province of South Africa which is characterized by flat, desert type landscapes with high solar irradiation, making it suitable for CSP generation. Both plants will be located close enough to the Orange River to access water required for steam generation and mirror cleaning.   !Ka Xu will be  located on a 300ha parcel of land on the Scuit Klip 92 farm, which is 40 km from the town of Pofadder on the R64  and R358 roads in the Khai Ma municipality.  The site coordinates are Latitude 28.9S and Longitude 19.6E.   !Khi will be located on a 300ha of the Mc Taggarts Camp 453 farm, which is 15 km from the town of Upington on the N14 highway in the Kai Garaib municipality.  The site coordinates are Latitude 28.5S and Longitude 21.0E.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-29.0000000000 24.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V-BF - Solar - Renewable Energy Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $160.54 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-11-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-04">160540000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-04">160540000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaxu Solar One (RF) Proprietary Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/31083/abengoa-csp-sa">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
