<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-37402</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nelson Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In supporting Net1, IFC will promote a company that focuses on financial inclusion in Sub-Saharan Africa and has developed proven solutions and products that are specifically designed for the underbanked. This project aims to enhance financial access in South Africa and other emerging markets. In particular by: (i) Providing last mile access: the Company distributes social grants to more than 10 million beneficiaries on behalf of the SASSA and operates more than 10,000 cash-out points via a fleet of truck-based ATMs and a network of retail points of sale that can operate in remote areas without internet connectivity (ii) Financial Inclusion: The Company has been working with social grant recipients for almost 20 years and has developed a strong understanding of this customer segment. In July 2015, Net1 introduced a new transaction account platform, the EasyPay Everywhere or &quot;EPE&quot; platform, which is directed at the low-income segment of the population. The service and transaction fees associated with the EPE account are among the lowest in the South African market.  (iii) Affordable financial services: Net1&apos;&apos;s transaction account offering is complemented with micro-loans and life insurance products. Through the usage of technology and shared delivery infrastructure, the Company is able to reduce its cost base and offer very competitive financial services to its customer segment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NET1 UEPS Technologies Inc. (Net1 or the Company) is a South Africa-based provider of payment solutions and transaction processing services across a range of industries and in various geographies. Net1s core offering is financial inclusion to the unbanked. On behalf of South Africa Social Security Agency (SASSA), the Company registered 21 million people in South Africa, opened bank accounts for 10 million and serves those through its payment processing systems based on chip-enabled smart card technology, which includes biometric verification, a multi-functional electronic wallet, and both online and offline processing capabilities. The Companys technology enables the affordable delivery of financial services, especially in under-developed and/or rural locations. The Company plans to deepen its financial inclusion offering within South Africa and expand regionally, especially into countries where there is limited banking infrastructure and availability of financial services for the poorest segment of the population.   The Company is raising funds to finance its South African and international expansion which includes: (i) expanding the Companys reach in South Africa by rolling out new financial services centers and ATMs in low-income areas; (ii) entering into partnerships that will allow the Company to replicate its business model outside South Africa; (iii) developing and rolling-out mobile centric solutions as alternative delivery channels for financial services; and (iv) strategic acquisitions of payment companies in other emerging markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NET 1 UEPS TECHNOLOGIES INC.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-37402" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Net1 UEPS Technologies, Inc.  Herman Kotz&#xE9; Chief Financial Officer e-mail:  mailto:hermank@net1.com  Phone: +27 11 343 2000 Fax: +27 11 442 5908</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="ZA-South Africa">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Company is headquartered in Johannesburg, South Africa. Net1 offers various card based and mobile centric financial services that are available throughout the entire country. For the distribution of social grants, the Company operates around 10,000 pay-points in rural and urban areas.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-29.0000000000 24.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="522320" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O-MC - Retail Payment Points</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-11">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-11">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NET 1 UEPS TECHNOLOGIES INC.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/37402">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/37402">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
