<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28163</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cleaner Production Lending Facility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CPLF will focus resources and awareness on financially viable improvements in environmental performance across a range of sectors in IFC client countries. CP projects supported through the Facility are expected to be economically attractive as resource savings outweigh implementation costs. Key expected development impacts includes: i) having a positive climate change mitigation impact, including a reduction of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions; ii) enhancing the sustainable competitiveness of IFCs private sector clients; iii) supporting technology transfer; and iv) having a demonstration effect. Specific expected environmental benefits and climate change impacts (as relevant for the CP project) will be monitored.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Cleaner Production Lending Facility (CPLF, the Facility) is a proposed three year, US$125 million loan facility to finance Cleaner Production (CP) investments globally among IFC portfolio clients in good standing.  The Facility will build upon and scale up the Cleaner Production Lending Pilot (CPLP), a US$20 million facility approved by IFCs Board in 2007 to promote CP investments among IFC portfolio clients. The scale up is made necessary by the successful utilization of all funding made available under the pilot and strong demand from IFCs clients for continued support in identifying and financing CP projects. 

Like the pilot, CPLF will support investments in energy efficiency, use of renewable energy, recycling, water saving and use of clean tech solutions for IFC clients across a range of sectors and regions. Client demand for the integrated CP loan and advisory services offering developed under CPLP is due to the cost-saving and typical short payback characteristics of CP projects and the opportunity they give clients to improve their competitiveness and green their image. The CPLF will finance these high impact CP projects through a streamlined CP loan process established under the pilot.  A complementary advisory services project will support CP audits for clients (co-funded using donor funds) who require technical support to identify CP projects. 
 
CP is the improvement of operational processes to make more efficient use of inputs such as raw materials, energy and water along a companys value chain. Effective CP interventions: i) reduce resource consumption at the source and hence waste and environmental impact, thus reducing or eliminating the need for costly end-of-pipe solutions; and ii) improve operating efficiencies and reduce operating costs. Many CP projects also reduce CO2 emissions, thus helping to mitigate climate change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL FINANCE CORPORATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28163" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As CPLF is a global facility, individual borrowers and recipients of CP Loans under the Facility will only be identified after Board approval  is given.  Therefore, client-specific contact details are currently unavailable.  

Nina Zegger, Principal Investment Officer
Email: NZegger@IFC.org

John Richard Graham, Senior Environmental Specialist
Email: JGraham@IFC.org

Ceyda Dagdelen, Investment Analyst
Email: CDagdelen@IFC.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a global facility available to existing IFC clients. Separate SPIs will be made available with details on the client and project site as CP Loans for individual projects supported by the Facility are processed.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">XX - Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $125.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28163/cleaner-production-lending-facility">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
