<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26380</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCB Microfinance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of its commitment at the Clinton Global Initiative, SCB aims to provide $200 million in 2007 in loans and greater support to its existing MFI customers.  It is estimated that SCBs entire $500 million microfinance facility will benefit 4 million people who are currently excluded from participation in the financial sector.  Currently, SCB has been extending credit to MFIs in Bangladesh, India, South Africa, Botswana, Zambia, Ghana, Kenya and Uganda.  In the next stage, SCB will reach out to MFIs in Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Afghanistan, the Philippines, Indonesia, Vietnam, Cambodia, Nigeria and China.    The proposed transaction is a core element in SCBs risk management approach and in meeting its goal of reaching the 4 million unbanked customers in Africa and Asia.  By assisting SCB to distribute the credit risk exposure of a percentage of its MFI portfolio, the transaction will enable SCB to leverage the coverage and delivery capacity of its unique network in the emerging markets of Asia and Africa.  The transaction structure will open a new avenue for SCB and possibly others in a similar position, to sell down the micro finance risk in the international capital markets.  What this ultimately means is that this transaction is a precursor to opening up international capital markets for MFI customers in emerging markets.  If this and similar initiatives are successful it could mean a quantum increase in the available resources for the MFI sector in many markets.  Moreover, as this transaction improves SCBs efficiency in allocating its capital, it will encourage SCB to continue investing in this business.  As the transaction has a geographically diversified asset portfolio, it affords the opportunity to a wide range of potential international investors to support the MFI sector that otherwise do not have any practical or efficient means to do so.  If the transaction can be successfully closed, it should have a significant demonstrational effect and can be replicated and used on a wider basis.  This all should lead to greater willingness of commercial banks and other financial institutions to expand their microfinance activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is a capital markets transaction which consists of the issuance of credit-linked notes (CLN) by a special purpose vehicle (SPV), to be established by Standard Chartered Bank (SCB), to a group of institutional investors including the International Finance Corporation (IFC).    CLN represent the credit risk of 26 micro finance institutions (MFI) that are currently in the portfolio of SCBs subsidiaries and branches.  By issuing the CLN, SCB would be transferring a part of its MFI exposure to such institutional investors thereby creating headroom to allow for more financing to MFI.  The portfolio currently is diversified over 9 countries in Asia and Africa with 58% of the loans originated in Africa and 42% in Asia. However, the exact mix may well change at the closing date and the replenishment period of the transaction.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STANDARD CHARTERED BANK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26380" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-05-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-05-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alexander MacKay Standard Chartered Bank Plc. Asset Securitisation Group London, England  Phone:  +44 207 457 5426 Fax:  +44 207 280 7064  E-mail:    Alexander.Mackay@uk.standardchartered.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCB is headquartered in London with global business hubs based in Singapore, Hong Kong and Dubai.  SCBs subsidiaries, affiliates and branches are spread over 56 countries with a focus on Asia and Africa.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5222" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HA - Microfinance and Small Business - Non Commercial Banking</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $45.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-05-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-05-14">45000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-05-14">45000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STANDARD CHARTERED BANK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26380/scb-microfinance">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
