<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-40458</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TriLinc Global Impact Fund, LLC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to have a development impact in the following areas. (i) Increasing access to finance for growth-stage, middle market companies in Emerging Markets.  Access to term financing from financiers locally is typically scarce for middle market companies in Emerging Market countries.  Trilinc will be able to provide not only trade finance but final loan maturities of up to 5 years in agricultural and other value chains, providing the liquidity and growth capital that allows these companies to make the contributions to employment and economic expansion that developing economies rely on dynamic, middle market companies for.  Its estimated that the Project may help support about 10,000 jobs, of which more than 20% are estimated will be female.  (ii) The Project will help broaden channels for intermediating capital from investors in the U.S. to middle-market companies in Emerging Markets that are typically too small to access capital markets or cross-border finance.  The channels through which  U.S. individual and smaller institutional investors can invest in private credit that supports companies in Emerging Markets are still nascent.  This is even more the case with respect to the channels available to them to invest in Emerging Markets with an impact mandate.  Trilinc is helping develop the awareness of and a track record for the asset class among individual and smaller institutional  investors in the U.S. that would support growth of channels through which they can invest in private credit that supports middle market companies Emerging Markets.  Further, Trilinc is increasing the chances of developing this channel through the transparency and investor reach that an SEC-registered fund affords and is doing so with an impact mission.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project consists of a loan to a subsidiary of TriLinc Global Impact Fund, LLC, (the Fund) which is managed by TriLinc Advisors, LLC (together with its affiliates TriLinc) to provide term loans and trade finance to middle-market companies operating in Emerging Markets around the world. The project will provide capital that TGIF will on-lend to build its loan portfolio to middle-market companies that are active in various sectors, including&#xA0;&#xA0; agriculture, food and beverage; manufacturing; financial and non-financial services and infrastructure (the Project).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TRILINC GLOBAL IMPACT FUND CAYMAN, LTD.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-40458" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="6"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TriLinc Global, LLC  Tim Morgan  Director of Business Development  +1-310-997-0580  tmorgan@trilincglobal.com  Manhattan Beach, CA 90266  www.TriLincGlobal.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TriLinc and the Fund are based in the United States and the Cayman Islands. The Project will finance private sector, medium-sized companies based in or whose main operations are located in borrowing countries that are members of the IFC.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="525" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">P-GD - Small Business Fund</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $85.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/40458">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetail/SII/40458">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
