<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25874</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voxiva Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Better intelligence, targeted action: Voxivas solutions will allow governments to identify more quickly and better understand the patterns and location of disease outbreaks. With greater knowledge governments will be able to allocate resources more quickly (medical staff, drugs and medical equipment) to affected areas, better containing the spread of the disease and managing its treatment.   Efficient deployment of resources:     Healthcare and related costs rank, in most countries, as the 2nd or 3rd largest (public) budgetary expense.  Paradoxically, the most resource constrained countries squander more healthcare dollars because of lack of information systems that track usage, establish accountability and focus efforts.  Voxivas inventory management tools will enable governments to manage drug inventories and their location encouraging better use and preventing wastage.  Better value for the money:     Voxivas solutions cost only a fraction of the products offered by other software companies.  The high cost of deploying other technologies has left thousands of cities and towns in the developing world without an adequate citizen alert system, made implementation of integrated health systems impossible for both developed and developing countries etc. Voxivas systems, reachable by and able to reach every cell phone in a country, are of enormous value to the public and to governments in emergency situations.   No upfront costs for deployment:     Voxivas new push towards a recurring revenue model, will allow governments to deploy such economic systems without paying upfront, but paying for usage (pay-as-you-go).  This smoothes the budgetary needs and removes a significant adoption barrier.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voxiva is a leading provider of data capturing solutions for highly distributed data entry systems.  It makes use of commonly available devices like cell phones, touch-tone phones (including pay phones), as well as PCs to enter data from a large number of data collectors.  Such systems are ideal for capturing data in the field, where communication infrastructure is rudimentary and access to PCs is insignificant or non existent.  Voxivas systems are primarily used in the public health and safety markets. Voxivas users submit health, crime or inventory data with accuracy and at a fraction of the cost of the alternative  paper based systems - and make this data available immediately to related decision makers.  Such systems are now live in remote areas of countries such as Peru, Argentina, Rwanda, Kenya, Indonesia, India and Nigeria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voxiva, Inc.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25874" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-05-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-05-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justin Sims CEO 1990 K Street NW, Suite 400,  Washington, DC 20006 jsims@voxiva.net</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voxiva is headquartered in Washington D.C.  Its development offices are in Peru, Argentina and India and its systems are deployed in Rwanda, Kenya, Peru, Argentina, Columbia, Nigeria, India and Indonesia.  Over 80% of staff is based in developing countries, where the company generates over 90% of its revenues.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Other Services (Including IT Enabled Services)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $5.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-05-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-05-08">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-05-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-05-08">5000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voxiva, Inc.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25874/voxiva-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
