<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25134</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cleaner Production Lending Pilot</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CPLP will focus on financially viable projects which improve the conversion efficiency of raw material and energy inputs.  The sub-projects under the CPLP are expected to be economically attractive as resource savings outweigh the capital and operating costs of implementation.  Environmental performance is also expected to improve in most of the sub-projects.   At the enterprise level, CP projects may help maintain access to export markets, enhance reputation through green branding, and better manage scarce local resources to allow future expansion of activities.  Successful projects and companies are hoped to create a demonstration effect.  The individual project level results will be tracked in terms of cleaner production objectives as defined in each of the sub-loans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed Cleaner Production Lending Pilot (CPLP) will provide loans with an aggregate amount of up to $20 million over the next three years to promote Cleaner Production (CP) investments among IFCs portfolio clients globally.  These investments would take the form of small loans made on commercial terms to existing clients for the purpose of financing CP investments (CP Loans).      CP is the continuous improvement of industrial processes, services and products to enhance the conversion efficiency of manufacturing inputs (such as energy, water, raw materials) to saleable outputs.  This process reduces resource consumption and hence reduces waste streams and environmental impact at source.  Well-designed CP interventions are highly profitable.  CP initiatives can reduce or eliminate the need for costly end-of-pipe environmental protection projects, and in contrast to end-of-pipe interventions, CP reduces rather than increases manufacturing cost by reducing input costs and the costs of pollution mitigation.      Despite these obvious attractions, many CP improvement opportunities are not implemented by industry.  Previous work by IFC and others suggests that impediments to CP implementation include a combination of lack of awareness of financial benefits available from CP, lack of technical ability to identify CP opportunities and develop these into bankable projects and perception of risk and lack of access to finance.  IFCs Environmental and Social Department is already discussing the provision of donor support for CP with the following donors:   - Austria, - Bavaria, - Denmark, - Italy,  - Japan, and -  Norway.  By teaming up donor assistance with access to IFC finance, it is hoped that upfront barriers to CP will be overcome and adoption of CP will be accelerated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL FINANCE CORPORATION</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25134" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-07-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since this is a global facility, individual borrowers under this facility will be identified only after Board approval. Therefore, the clients  contact details are currently not available.  Corinne Jane Figueredo, Senior Investment Officer E-mail:    cfigueredo@ifc.org     John Richard Graham,  Senior Environmental Specialist E-mail:    jgraham@ifc.org     Tanja Ward, Co-Head (Electronics, Machinery and Appliances Sector Team) E-mail:    tward1@ifc.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a global facility available to existing IFC clients. See the SPIs for the individual CP Loans for further details on each borrower as they become available.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">XX - Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25134/cleaner-production-lending-pilot">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
