<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11251</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baku Tiblisi-Ceyhan Pipeline</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACG Development Phase 1 Project Description The Azeri Chirag deepwater Gunashli (ACG) fields operated by BP Exploration (Caspian Sea) Limited contain an estimated 5.4 billion bbls of recoverable crude oil reserves.  They will be developed in four separate phases, the first of which, the Early Oil project, was financed by IFC and EBRD in 1998 and is producing approximately 140,000 barrels of oil a day.  The second stage, called Phase 1, is currently being considered for separate financing by IFC and EBRD although the financing of the Phase 1 project will be conducted in parallel with the BTC project.  Phase 2 was sanctioned in September of 2002, while Phase 3 is in the project development stage.  Following the completion of all of the phases in 2009, the ACG field peak production of crude is expected to be over one million barrels of oil per day based on proved plus probable reserve estimates.    BTC Project Description: The Baku-Tbilisi-Ceyhan (   http://www.ifc.org/btc   ), or BTC, pipeline will transport up to one million barrels of oil per day (bpd) of crude oil primarily from the ACG field.  The 1,760 km pipeline, which starts at the Sangachal Terminal near Baku in Azerbaijan, passes through Georgia and ends at a new marine terminal at Ceyhan on the Mediterranean coast in Turkey, is due to become operational in early 2005.    ACG production is currently shipped primarily through the Western Route Export Pipeline, (WREP) completed as part of the Early Oil project, ending in Supsa, Georgia; however, the current capacity of this route is approximately 150,000 bpd.  In addition, the Northern Route pipeline to Novorossiysk, Russia has a capacity of 115,000 bpd. The BTC pipeline became a necessity because of current constraints on capacity that would limit the ability to bring ACG crude to market.  Early conceptual development of the project took into account the need for a dedicated export route for the ACG field that would not require the shipment of Caspian oil through the Bosphorus Straits thereby significantly reducing environmental risk.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BAKU-TBILISI-CEYHAN PIPELINE CO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11251" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-01-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2004-03-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">See attachment 3                   BTC pipeline project web site available at:    http://www.ifc.org/btc    Commments or inquieries about the project can be sent to    NGOrelations@ifc.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACG Phase 1 Project:   The ACG Field Complex is located in the Caspian Sea east of the Sangachal terminal in Azerbaijan.  The ACG contract area established under the PSA covers the Azeri, Chirag and deepwater portion of the Gunashli fields.  The fields, which together are approximately 50 km long and cover an area of approximately 440 sq km, are approximately 85 km southeast of the Apsheron Peninsula along the Apsheron-Pribalkhan trend, at water depths of 100 m to 400 m.  BTC Project:   The 1,760 km long BTC pipeline originates at Sangachal where crude from the ACG fields is received.  From here, the pipeline is routed west, closely following the existing WREP.  At the Georgian border with Azerbaijan, the route traverses west and south until it meets the Turkish border.  In Turkey, the route runs south to Erzurum, then west to Erzincan and Sivas before turning south to the Ceyhan terminal.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Oil and Gas Production (Includes Development)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $125.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2004-01-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2004-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-01-30">125000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2004-01-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2004-01-30">125000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BAKU-TBILISI-CEYHAN PIPELINE CO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11251/baku-tiblisiceyhan-pipeline">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
