<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26705</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECOM Agroindustrial Corp. Ltd.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFC is considering providing ECOM Agroindustrial Corp. Ltd. (ECOM or the company) a corporate loan of up to $55 million (the Facility). The Facility will be used principally to finance permanent working capital (inventory and advances to suppliers) for the Company coffee operations in Asia (Indonesia, Vietnam and Papua New Guinea), its cocoa operations in Indonesia and Papua New Guinea, and its coffee operations in Africa (Kenya, Tanzania and Uganda), with a small portion of the facility to be used for capital expenditures (dry coffee mills facilities and warehouses in Uganda, Kenya, Papua New Guinea and Vietnam).   ECOM is a leading supply chain manager and integrated supplier of both raw and semi-processed agricultural commodities. Incorporated in Switzerland, ECOM and its subsidiaries are commodity operators covering 30 countries in the United States, Central and South America, Europe, Asia and Africa. ECOMs principal activities consist of trading coffee, cotton and cocoa and to a lesser extent grain and other agricultural products, and raising pork. ECOM was founded in 1849 in Barcelona, Spain by the Esteve family which is still the majority owner (92%).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is expected to provide continued direct benefits to rural populations and a demonstration impact on sustainability. ECOM&apos;&apos;s operations provide substantial benefits to rural areas of many developing countries given the company&apos;&apos;s ability to   - enhance the efficiency and transparency of agribusiness logistics and  - provide knowledge transfer in the primary processing of products which set high standards needed to meet the requirements of international buyers, thereby providing best practices for local companies to emulate.  External benefits.   Sustainability and traceability of supply are key components of ECOMs business strategy. ECOMs operations provide direct benefits to small and medium sized farmers in developing countries that depend on commodity exports.  These benefits include:   - financing of capital and infrastructure improvements to achieve efficiencies and lower production costs;  - technical assistance to improve agricultural yields and quality;  - crop financing and inventory management;  - providing knowledge transfer in primary processing to set high standards as needed to meet the requirements of international buyers;  - implementation of environmental and social standards and Best Management Practices to achieve international certification for value-added products;  - helping mainstream commodity brands to promote sourcing from sustainable coffee producers.  Sustainability.   As part of this investment, ECOM will be required to develop a corporate level Environment and Social Management System and start its implementation under an action plan agreed to by IFC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECOM Agroindustrial Corp. Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26705" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-06-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-09-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andrew Falconer 79 Robinson Road, #17-04/05/06 CPF Building,  SINGAPORE 068897 Tel: +65-63189918, Fax: +65-63189916</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Facility will be used principally to finance Company coffee operations in Asia (Indonesia, Vietnam and Papua New Guinea), the cocoa operations in Indonesia and Papua New Guinea, and the coffee operations in Africa (Kenya, Tanzania and Uganda).  ECOMs subsidiary company for coffee in Indonesia is PT IndoCafco and led the industry in traceable, certified coffee, now maintaining established programs as the rest of the industry in Indonesia is just beginning. PT IndoCafco currently has traceable certified coffee programs in Aceh, Toba, Lampung, and Bali.  ECOMs subsidiary company for cocoa in Indonesia is PT Tanah Mas Celebes Indah. The company sources cocoa from Makassar, South Sulawesi, and Palu, Central Sulawesi.  Monpi Coffee Exports Ltd. (Papua New Guinea) is located in Goroka.   Atlantic Commodities Vietnam Ltd. (Vietnam), milling facility is located in Bao Loc, in the Lam Dong province.  ECOMs subsidiary company in Uganda is Kawacom Uganda Ltd. Kawacom has organic and Utz Kapeh certified coffee projects in     - Bushenyi, South Western Uganda,    - Nebbi District, Paidha, North Western Uganda, and    - Kapchorwa, Eastern Uganda.    Mawenzi Coffee Exporters (Tanzania) has a head office in Dar es Salaam, and a support office in Moshi in northern Tanzania.  Sangana Commodities (Kenya) Ltd. is based in Nairobi.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Coffee, Cocoa, Tea</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $55.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-06-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-06-25">55000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-06-25">55000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECOM Agroindustrial Corp. Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26705/ecom-agroindustrial-corp-ltd">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
