<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28749</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Warehouse Finance Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Program is expected to have a very high development impact in four critical areas:   (i)	The Program will increase access to finance for banks to assist the agriculture sector which is an important driving force of the economy, i.e. in IDA countries.  The Program will promote the commodity backed lending skills among local banks and avail more working capital to farmers to finance their harvest inventory management; (ii)	The Program will contribute significantly to private sector development of the local banks lending to the agriculture sector and job creation by supporting farmers side of the agricultural value chain; (iii)	The Program will also enable IFC to identify other investment opportunities such as supply chain financing and financing of warehouses; and (iv)	In the countries where IFC will facilitate the Advisory Services to establish the WHR system, IFC can play a catalytic role to infrastructure the investment climate for an efficient and transparent agriculture market system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed Project, Global Warehouse Finance Program (GWFP or the Program), aims at assisting the IFCs existing and prospective client banks increase their pre-export financing to the agriculture sector in emerging markets.  IFC intends to support pre-shipment financing needs of the agriculture industry by offering a warehouse financing facility to local banks.    Commodities are stored in warehouses before shipment, and in most of the cases, farmers/traders/exporters need to sell the production earlier than they desire to meet their urgent financial needs or are forced to arrange financing through credit lines with local banks with fixed assets as collateral.  IFC aims to support the agriculture sector by encouraging banks to introduce the commodity backed lending skills.   In particular, IFC intends to promote such commodity financing skills to local banks in the countries where tradable and negotiable Warehouse Receipts (WHR) exist, since WHR-based financing will encourage the move toward a more transparent agricultural marketing system for export markets.  A WHR is an instrument which can be used as a form of portable collateral to request a loan from a bank, and is issued by the warehouse operator, when the commodities are stored.  In those countries where WHR system does not exist, the Collateral Management Agreement (CMA) or Stock Monitoring Agreement (SMA) is currently used by banks.  CMA or SMA is a trilateral agreement signed between a bank, a commodity owner, and a warehouse operator.  Although this is not a transferable/negotiable instrument, for the initial stage, IFC will accept financing requests from those countries that are using other forms of securities, such as CMA or SMA.    The Program takes the local bank risk in developing countries, and will be providing liquidity to those banks for on-lending to commodity owners against WHR or CMA/SMA as collateral or by providing guarantees to other funders to provide funding in local/foreign currency to banks.  The Program would focus on pre-export financing but also includes post-import financing and selectively inventory financing for domestic sales.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GWFP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28749" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since this is a global facility, individual borrowers under this facility will be identified only after Board approval.  Therefore, the clients contact details are currently not available.   Makiko Toyoda Global Financial Markets  IFC 2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433 Telephone: 202-458-0142</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a global facility.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AK - Commercial Banking - Short Term Finance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $200.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28749/global-warehouse-finance-program">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
