<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7472</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rabobank APFT Agribusiness Agency Line</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Rabobank APFT Agribusiness Agency Line              Region    Global        Sector       Project No007472   Projected Board DateJuly 18, 1996   Company NameRabobank International (Rabobank)   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Rabobank is the second largest bank in the Netherlands with a large international network. It has a triple-A credit rating and is recognized worldwide for its track record in financing agribusiness projects.  In 1995, 25% of all Rabobanks domestic loans and approximately 50% of its loan portfolio outside of the Netherlands were made to companies in the food and agribusiness sector.  The Agri-Project Finance Team (APFT) is Rabobanks dedicated group that provides project financing and financial advisory services to international agribusiness companies.  Since the Agribusiness Departments founding in 1992 to date, Rabobank APFT has made commitments of a total of US$125.3 million in IFCs B loan participation, of which US$92.0 million was the result of APFTs participation in 12 projects financed by the Agribusiness Department.       Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	US$100 million, to be jointly financed by IFC and Rabobank on a 50:50 basis.    Location of project and Description of site    	Global coverage of countries eligible for IFC investments, with a negative list to be issued by IFC from time to time.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The Project will provide long-term foreign currency loans ranging from US$1 million to US$10 million to small and medium enterprises (SMEs) to finance greenfield, expansion, and modernization/rehabilitation projects.  IFC will be the lender of record on each sub-loan.  Rabobank APFT will administer the facility under criteria and guidelines agreed with IFC.  The Facility will extend sound financing to SMEs in developing countries through loans with longer maturities and grace period, thereby better matching financial requirements of Borrowers needs and reducing project risks.  Through the creation of jobs and promotion of agribusiness industries in developing countries, the Facility will enhance economic growth and foster private sector development.  The Project will ensure that sub-projects comply with host country and applicable World Bank environmental policies and standards. IFC Environment Division will provide training to Rabobank staff for application of World Bank review procedures.      Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a Financial Intermediary (FI) category project according to IFCs environmental review procedure.  Rabobank will be required to undertake an environmental review of eligible borrowers environmental performance and sub-projects compliance with the applicable host country environmental, health and safety requirements as well as applicable World Bank policies and guidelines.  Rabobank has designated a Senior Officer with overall responsibility for environmental affairs, as well as individuals who conduct environmental reviews, to participate in IFCs environmental management workshop.  Rabobank will provide to IFC an environmental management plan and an annual environmental report.       Date SPI sent to PIC     June 18, 1996      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPERATIEVE RABOBANK U.A.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7472" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1997-01-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-World Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.0000000000 -40.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5221" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Commercial Banking - General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $50.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1997-01-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1997-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1997-01-28">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1997-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1997-01-28">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPERATIEVE RABOBANK U.A.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7472/rabobank-apft-agribusiness-agency-line">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
