<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-KAM134</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promotion of community-based forest management and regenerate natural resources in deforested areas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is to support poor communities in Toek Phos district, Kompong Chhnang province and Krokor and Kondeang districts, Pursat Province to be able to manage their community natural resources through community-based forest management and to regenerate natural resources in deforested areas. In the project areas, there are about 3000 hectares of protected forests that have been gradually deteriorated to fulfil private economic interests every day. Meanwhile, the participation from community members to protect their local resources remain limited because they have concerned on their security and don&#x2019;t understand well on their rights in participating in community development. Moreover, the existing community forest committee is not function well due to lack of supports from other stakeholders and limitation capacity to manage their forest management plan. 
CAFOD has supported partner for both conducting an initial study and project implementations after development of accurate project proposal. The study will use the people led development approach (PLD) that provide opportunity to all community groups and local authorities to involve in the whole process of the project. 
The specific project objectives are to strengthen the capacity of local authorities and community forest management committee and local communities&#x2019; people to manage their community forest resources in a sustainable manner. 
To achieve the above goal, 3 main approaches have been proposed for this project implementation: 1).  support community-based activities to forest landscape development. This would scale-up from existing successful experience in participatory planning and sustainable resource management in both forest and grassland landscapes, 2). train key stakeholders to equip them with the required knowledge and skills on integrated forest management plan, and 3.) support implementing a sustainable livelihood scheme seeking to raise the household incomes of project beneficiaries. At the end of the project, communities will develop their capacity to mobilise and work on their own initiatives on natural resources management.
In response to CAFOD strategy-OCH, the project will respond to the interconnected of Cry of the Poor and Cry of the Earth and promotion of environment by promoting people livelihood sustainability. The project will provide opportunity to community people to actively participate in the planning, execution, and ensure safeguarding of all areas of project intervention.  Also, it is a thematic area of CAFOD Cambodia programme that will specifically focus on community livelihood development in connection to community natural resources management.
The allocation of grant is for both project study and project study and 9-month period of project implementation (Project design: &#xA3;8,350 and project implementation: &#xA3;34,650, total grant: &#xA3;43,000).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KAM134" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KAM134" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Battambang Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KAM134" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-01">43000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54730">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-10">43000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69456">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-10">10000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karuna Battambang Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
