<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="527" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/2237" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-IMC-SO-11-2237</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Emergency Nutrition and WASH Support Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Through the implementing partner recruit 12 qualified nutrition staff, (one nurse, one auxiliary nurse and one community mobilizer per SFP site) and  24 community nutrition workers (CNW) who are volunteers to  identify cases malnutrition, do nutrition screening, active case finding, defaulter tracing and appropriate referral and health promotion. These are the same staff under the sub-sector &#x2018;management of severe malnutrition&#x2019;. The same staff will work in both outpatient therapeutic program (OTP) and supplementary feeding program (SFP) since they are in the same facility. (2) Train 12 nutrition staff and 24 CNWs on the prevention and management of moderate acute malnturition (MAM). This training is not a stand alone training and it will be combined with the training on the prevention and management of SAM and these are the same staff to be trained under SAM. During this training, the staff will also be trained on disaster preparedness, mitigation and response; (3) Conduct community mobilization with key people in the community; (4) Establish 4 SFP sites in Abudwak District in Balambale, Dhabad, Bangale and Abudwak town; (5) Conduct nutritional screening and referral (as described above); (6) Continuous monthly SFP implementation activities, visits and monitoring; (6) Prepare monthly and quarterly data reports to share with stakeholders; (7) Train 12 nutrition staff and 24 CNWs on the prevention and management of SAM and disaster preparedness, mitigation and response; (8) Establish 2 new sites for OTP in Dhabad and Bangale town and strengthen existing 2 OTP sites in Abudwak and  Balambale,  town; (9) Continuous weekly OTP implementation activities, visits and monitoring; (10) Training of 20 Sheikhs, 20 traditional birth attendants (TBAs) and other 20 traditional/local leaders to promote appropriate knowledge and practices on breastfeeding; (11) Training of Community nutrition workers (CNW); (12) Nutrition education in schools; (13) Breast feeding campaign during breast feeding week 1st-7th August; (14) Reproduction of IEC materials on nutrition education from existing UNICEF IEC materials; (15) Offer caregivers health and nutrition education on existing problem areas of malnutrition, essential nutrition actions and infant and young child feeding; (16) A summary of the main proposed activities in schools are: sensitize school administrations, teachers,  parents and community leaders on proposed interventions; adopt culturally acceptable IEC materials for hygiene promotion; build capacity of teachers in 4 schools on the Child-to-Child and Child-to-Adult participatory methodologies; form hygiene clubs in 4 schools in Abudwak, Balambale, Dhabad and Bangale; conduct peer education among pupils in 4 schools; conduct hygiene education sessions with communities; promote hand washing practices in 4 schools; (17) Rehabilitation of 12 communal berkads; (18) Rehabilitation of 2 troughs and 2 water kiosks in 2 strategic boreholes in Abudwak and Balambale town; (19) Training of 12 berkads management committees and 2 borehole management committees; (20) Water quality testing and monitoring; (21) Household water treatment promotion (Distribution of  aqua tabs ); (22) Disaster preparedness, mitigation and response knowledge, skills, and capacity gaps assessment of water management committees; (23) Training of water management committees on disaster preparedness, mitigation and response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Severely malnourished</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this project is to mitigate the effects of the current drought and build the capacity of the local population and internally displaced persons (IDPs) to more effectively deal with natural and man-made disaster. This will involve carrying out a district wide nutrition survey to determine the prevalence of global acute malnutrition (GAM) and severe acute malnutrition (SAM) in the District at the beginning of the project. This information will be used to determine actual numbers of malnourished children that need treatment. Achievements by the end of the program will be measured against the numbers established from the prevalence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-95-3949646" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of Foreign Disaster Assistance (USAID/OFDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="IMC-SO-11-2237" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Commins</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategy Manager, Fragile States</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>scommins@internationalmedicalcorps.org</email>
   <website>http://www.internationalmedicalcorps.org</website>
   <website>http://www.internationalmedicalcorps.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_59362">
   <location-id code="59362" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galguduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galguduud, Somalia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="59362" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.0 47.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="18" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.internationalmedicalcorps.org/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="35114"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
