<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IM-CR-024714B-JE14-134</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IM-CR-024714B" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">openmindedly</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza and Israel Appeal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intense fighting in summer 2014 marked the worst unrest that Gaza had seen in several years. There was 51 days of violence before a ceasefire was brokered between Israel and the Palestinians on 26th August. The British Red Cross launched an appeal for which the Jersey Overseas Aid Commission contributed GBP 30,000 in response to the situation for medical disposables and non-food items, and to support the repair of water systems to allow 500,000 people to regain access to water in Gaza.  There has been a huge cost to human life. 2,257 people have been killed since July 2014, including 538 Palestinian children.  Meanwhile 100,000 people remain displaced due to the destruction of housing and infrastructure, with 96,000 housing units either entirely or partially damaged. Shelter for the displaced people, health care services, psychosocial support, rehabilitation services and livelihoods support are still major concerns for humanitarian agencies in the region. Severe winter weather has compounded the situation for internally displaced people, causing extreme flooding in Gaza City, while the closure of Gazas power plant due to lack of fuel has led to an energy crisis.  As part of the International Committee of the Red Cross longstanding partnership with the Palestine Red Crescent Societys emergency medical services, the International Committee of the Red Cross has continued to provide financial aid and supplies. They have distributed emergency food and non-food items to 25,000 families in Gaza and delivered medicines and medical supplies to public health facilities in order to treat those wounded in the conflict. As a neutral intermediary, the International Committee of the Red Cross maintains confidential bilateral dialogue with all parties involved in the conflict. The result of such coordination allows emergency access to people in need and the maintenance of vital infra-structure. The International Committee of the Red Cross has been working with the local authorities to rehabilitate damaged water and sanitation facilities and electricity supplies. As a result, they have ensured some 370,000 people have had renewed access to water and sanitation since the start of the conflict.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="JE-OAC" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALESTINIAN TERRITORY, OCCUPIED</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-01-01">30000</value>
   <provider-org ref="JE-OAC">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-202918">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
