<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-28901-2S2UI</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soa Aids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Challenging Intellectual Property Barriers to Ensure Access to Treatment for PLHIV</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Repel harmful provisions in free trade agreements;
- incorporate flexibilities in national patent laws;
- ensure that existing flexibilities are used, including the opposition to new patents or issuing compulsory licenses;
- secure political commitment to address medicine patent barriers.

To achieve these objectives civil society organisations use advocacy for the elimination of intellectual property obstacles to generic competition. They conduct research on the consequences of patent barriers on pharmaceuticals. Next to that, they strengthen community responses by mobilizing community groups, governments, media and medical professionals on issues around medicine patents, pricing and intellectual property for them to take a role in advocacy activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the past decade, there has been a significant increase in access to lifesaving medicines for diseases like HIV, TB and Hepatitis C in low- and middle-income countries, mainly due to increased generic competition. Unfortunately, the situation has been changed in the past years and the progress achieved is under threat.
 
Key countries where generics are produced now grant medicine patents, in order to comply with their international obligations as members of the World Trade Organization. As a result, new medicines enter the market at very high prices, and production of affordable generic medicines is now restricted. 

For HIV, this means that countries with successful treatment programmes face a severe financial risk when patients need to shift to newer, more expensive second line drugs. It also means that the affordability of HIV medication for the vast majority who needs it has been put under pressure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People living with HIV</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme supports civil society organisations addressing intellectual property barriers and holding their governments accountable for access to essential medicines and lowering costs of pharmaceuticals. Overall aim is to contribute to increased access to treatment for people living with HIV.

Seven projects in Bangladesh, Indonesia, Kenya, Mozambique, Myanmar, South Africa, Uganda, Vietnam and Zimbabwe have been implemented in 2017-2021. These were funded by Aidsfonds under a &#x20AC;1,5m grant from a private donations call for proposals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soa Aids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
   <website>https://aidsfonds.nl/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soa Aids Nederland, Condensatorweg 54, 1014 AX Amsterdam</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="20"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="13040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STD control including HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C07" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-15">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41207989-P-28901-2S2UI" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
