<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-21-MX-ME-516</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our vision of change: community museums and schools strengthening visions from the past and the future. N/A</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation is the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of programs and projects as a basis for judgments, to improve effectiveness and inform decisions about current and future programming. Evaluations are distinct from (a) needs assessments, which are designed to examine country or sector context to inform project design, (b) internal informal reviews of projects and (c) audits (conducted either internally or by an external audience). This program area should include all evaluations designed and funded with foreign assistance funding, including the components of contracts with task orders for evaluations (regardless of the mechanism). It should also include all independent contractors hired solely to produce an evaluation(s).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support civil society as an effective arena that empowers citizens to advance democratic values of citizen participation and governmental accountability. This includes supporting an enabling legal environment that protects and promotes civil society and civic action; providing capacity development assistance to CSOs; supporting civic participation; bolstering government oversight and accountability activities; strengthening a democratic political culture that values civic engagement, tolerance, and respect for human rights; and strengthening independent and democratic trade/labor unions. Civil society organizations includes, but is not limited to, human rights organizations, youth movements, informal groups, religious organizations, labor and trade unions, professional associations, indigenous organizations, women organizations, LGBT organizations, and think tanks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supports the following illustrative program-funded costs: salaries of US, FSN, and TCN and other staff such as PSCs, RSSAs, PASAs, CASUs working for the US Government managing, administering, and supporting programs and their program-funded benefits such as housing, travel, transportation, education allowances etc; institutional contractors that provide such staff, rent, IT services, the program-funded share of utilities, staff training costs and the cost of developing and administering training programs, equipment and supplies, ICASS, vehicle fuel and maintenance, maintenance contracts, janitorial services, operational unit web page development and maintenance, outreach such as publications and the cost of their preparation (including staff costs), and technical assistance to ensure USG compliance with regulations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to support civil society as an effective arena that empowers citizens to advance democratic values of citizen participation and governmental accountability. More specifically, this includes UMCO will partner with primary schools and high schools to develop the leadership, technical skills and cultural identity of marginalized children and adolescents in 15 rural communities of Oaxaca through a series of workshops, festivals, exchanges and exhibitions. Project activities will reach at least 2,700 children, 500 adolescents and 300 adults.. Uni&#xF3;n de Museos Comunitarios de Oaxaca, A.C. (UMCO) will partner with primary schools and high schools to develop the leadership, technical skills and cultural identity of marginalized children and adolescents in 15 rural communities of Oaxaca through a series of workshops, festivals, exchanges and exhibitions. Project activities will reach at least 2,700 children, 500 adolescents and 300 adults.. Uni&#xF3;n de Museos Comunitarios de Oaxaca, A.C. (UMCO) will expand its workshops to include additional middle and high school students interested in expressing themselves creatively through radio, video, murals and other media. UMCO will invite education policy makers to talks and a symposium where they will discuss UMCO&apos;s approach for developing leadership, technical skills and cultural identity among marginalized children and adolescents in rural municipalities of Oaxaca. UMCO will also develop a training manual for middle and high school teachers. Activities will involve an additional 530 teachers and adolescents.. Uni&#xF3;n De Museos Comunitarios De Oaxaca, A.C. (Umco) Will Partner With Primary Schools And High Schools To Develop The Leadership, Technical Skills And Cultural Identity Of Marginalized Children And Adolescents In 15 Rural Communities Of Oaxaca Through A S.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union de Museos Comunitarios de Oaxaca, A.C.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-24" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lesley Duncan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-360-4530</telephone>
   <email>lduncan@iaf.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.iaf.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1331 Pennsylvania Ave. NW, Suite 1200 North&#xC2;&#xA0;Washington, DC 20004</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MX">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In FY 2017, the United States will partner with Mexico to consolidate and institutionalize progress made as a result of ongoing bilateral cooperation, particularly through the Merida Initiative. By weakening transnational criminal organizations (TCOs), reforming the institutions that sustain the rule of law, protecting human rights, creating a 21st century border, and building stronger and more resilient communities, the United States and Mexico will ensure greater prosperity and inclusive economic growth on both sides of the border. To support the President&apos;s Global Climate Change (GCC) Initiative, a strong partnership with the Government of Mexico and other stakeholders will promote clean energy adoption, energy efficiency, low carbon development, and sustainable land use and forest management to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Mexico is a global non-proliferation partner and related assistance will focus on enhancing Mexico&apos;s capabilities and commitment. Mexico continues to be a strong partner of the initiatives that complement the United States&apos; programs to address the root causes of unlawful migration from Central America.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-24">24624</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement of funds to the Award Implementing Organization to carry out the activities set forth in Annex A of the grant agreement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="2004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="15150" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2016" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-13">28670</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8001" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Direct Administrative Costs</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2013" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-07-24">145134</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2012" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-11-26">47244</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2013" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-23">49312</value>
   <sector code="11230" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth and adults</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="2004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2016" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-27">69220</value>
   <sector code="2004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="15150" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2015" end="2016"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-01">73936</value>
   <sector code="2004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="15150" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2016" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2016-05-16"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
