<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41116-PROJECT-02086</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41116" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coherent Integration of the Environmental Dimension of the Sustainable Development Goals in Regional and National Policy Frameworks in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this project is to enhance the capacities of countries in Africa to implementation of SDGs in a more innovative manner by integrating environmental sustainability and resilience into policies, strategies and action plans through regional and nations approaches, taking opportunities offered by the UN reforms. Ultimately, the aim is to have stronger integration of environmental dimension in development processes at regional, sub-regional and national levels for a coherent implementation of SDGs and Agenda 2063 in Africa.  The project anchors on-going work in Africa Office on regional ministerial fora, such as AMCEN, Health &amp; Environment, gender and youth, UN Sustainable Development Cooperation Frameworks, Regional UN Sustainable Development Group, natural resources governance, environmental diplomacy, among others, into UNEP support to countries in the achievement of SDGs.

The project will ensure that enhanced coherent delivery of the environmental dimension, inclusiveness of the major groups, business, you and women in the delivery of SDGs.  The impact of this project is &amp;ldquo;stronger integration of environmental dimension in development processes at regional, sub regional and national levels for a coherent implementation and achievement of SDGs and Agenda 2063 in Africa by catalyzing investment in sustainable harnessing of Africa&amp;rsquo;s natural capital.  The project relies on the two major principles related to Agenda 2030 and SDGs, i.e.  integration and leaving no one behind/more resilient communities. This support, UNEP will contribute to catalyzing actions that can result in decreased environment degradation and cost on the continent. The project will serve as the principal delivery mechanism for relevant activities for UNEP to implement some already planned and funded interventions that support regional and national efforts on the Sustainable Development Goals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Robert Wabunoha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>robert.wabunoha@unep.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="3">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Ndeti</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>stephen.ndeti@un.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="3">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Ndeti</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>stephen.ndeti@unep.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4540699</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">173003.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-14">5690.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
