<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41116-PROJECT-02037</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41116" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secretariat services to support the delivery of the 10-Year Framework of Programmes on Sustainable Consumption and Production &#x2013; Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable consumption and production is one of the most effective ways to achieve economic development, reduce impacts on the environment and advance human well-being. The shift to sustainable consumption and production requires a systemic approach, through multi-stakeholder partnerships and collaboration across governments, businesses, civil society, scientific and technical institutions, international organisations, and citizens. 
The 10-Year Framework of Programmes on Sustainable Consumption and Production, adopted at the World Summit on Sustainable Development in 2012 and as affirmed by target 12.1 of the 2030 Agenda for sustainable development, is a global commitment for action to accelerate the shift towards sustainable consumption and production in both developed and developing countries. It generates collective impact through six multi-stakeholder programmes: Public Procurement, Buildings and Construction, Tourism, Food Systems, Consumer Information, Lifestyles and Education. In 2017, the 10year Framework of Programmes on Sustainable Consumption and Production reached its mid-term and underwent a stocktaking process through progress reporting 2012-2017 and an Independent external review, which highlighted achievements to build upon as well as challenges to be addressed.
The &amp;lsquo;One Plan for One Planet&amp;rsquo; strategy 2018-2022 defines a common vision, common objectives, strategic approaches and actions across the One Planet network. It is the One Planet network&amp;rsquo;s strategy to support the shift to sustainable consumption and production, to deliver the long-term vision and enable strategic use of the diverse strengths of the network, at a greater scale. The Secretariat has a key role in facilitating the implementation of the strategy across the network. The theory of change of this project derives from the stock-taking process; builds on the &amp;lsquo;One Plan for One Planet&amp;rsquo; strategy and reflects the contribution of the Secretariat in supporting and facilitating its implementation. The underpinning principle is that the strategy is implemented by the network and through their joint actions within the programmes.  
In alignment with these factors, the &amp;lsquo;One Plan for One Planet&amp;rsquo; strategy and the Ministerial Declaration of the High Level Political Forum in 2018, the project&amp;rsquo;s outcome is: countries implement Sustainable Development Goal 12 with the support of the One Planet network.
To achieve this, the project will deliver the following outputs: 1) The definition and promotion of a common agenda on the implementation of sustainable consumption and production and the delivery of sustainable development goal 12 is facilitated across the One Planet network; 2)  The use of tools and solutions for the shift to sustainable consumption and production is facilitated across the One Planet network; 3) The  ability of the One Planet network in demonstrating the impacts of sustainable consumption and production and its role in addressing key challenges is strengthened.
The One Planet network, formed to implement the 10-Year Framework of Programmes on Sustainable Consumption and Production, is an implementation mechanism for Sustainable Development Goal 12. Achieving sustainable consumption and production will deliver not just Sustainable Development Goal 12, but simultaneously contribute significantly to the achievement of almost all of the Sustainable Development Goals, directly or indirectly</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Israel</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Switzerland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charles Arden-Clarke</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>charles.arden-clarke@unep.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="3">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rima Dabbagh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>rima.dabbagh@un.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="1031" percentage="16" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="16" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="498" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="16" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="889" percentage="16" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="16" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4632488</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">4668928</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">4027602.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">1654166.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-14">388005.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
