<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41116-PROJECT-02088</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41116" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing sustainable policies, strategies and management tools on resource efficiency in tourism value chains</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the past six decades, the global tourism sector has become one of the largest and fastest growing economic sectors. This rapid growth has had major impacts related to depletion of natural resources, particularly water, Green House Gases (GHG) emissions, energy and land, whilst expanding tourism value chain operations. The Paris Agreement, and the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda sets ambitious targets for countries and private sector. Tourism monitoring systems should therefore emphasize and guide on the tracking of a consistent set of indicators and measures for businesses and tourism destinations alike. In order to achieve the targets and goals of the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda on tourism (in particular 12.b, 14.6 and 8.9) and the Paris Agreement, UNEP will support businesses and governments in institutionalising capacities and implementing policies, actions plans and monitoring frameworks to promote the transition to a low carbon, resource efficient tourism sector. To achieve this, the project will also work in collaboration with governments to create the enabling environment required to transform the tourism private sector towards a low carbon and resource efficient future. The overall approach of the project is premised on recognizing that there are already a range of policies, management tools and best practices promoting resource efficiency and sustainable tourism in regions and countries. These have however, brought limited progress and limited consensus on how sustainability actions should be mainstreamed into daily operations within the tourism businesses in order to deliver the desired economic benefits and environmental sector performance. Hence, building partnerships with tourism businesses, governments and NGOs, and piloting country specific campaigns on the identified issues, management tools and best practices, will facilitate the necessary adoption of the proposed approaches according to country and destination-specific needs and concerns. In order to address the issues identified above, the project will deliver the following outputs: Output 1- Information and knowledge management tools developed and implemented to influence stakeholders on key environmental hotspots and impacts in the tourism sector that generate pollution, increase GHG emissions and inefficient use of resources</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Playa Dorada Hotel Association (IP in Dominican Republic)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Philippine Centerfor Environmental Protection and Sustainable Development (IP in Philippines)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Travel Foundation(IP in Mauritus and Saint Lucia)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNEP-DTU Partnership (Global Partner)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="73">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste and Resources Action Programme(Global Partner)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="3">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fuaad Alkizim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>fuaad.alkizim@un.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Environment Programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helena Rey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>helena.rey@unep.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="DO" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="LC" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MU" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="33210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1286872</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">559250.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-24">130363.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure for 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
