<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/NFI/INGO/11683</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving shelter and non-food items to IDPs and affected populations in Rubkona and Koch Counties, Unity and Yei and surrounding areas, Central Equatoria, South Sudan 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">While 2018 saw the signing of the R-ARCSS with hopes of improvements in security, in Unity and Central Equatoria, localised insecurity persists with both new and protracted displacement. Concern&#x2019;s Shelter and NFI response will provide time-critical and life-saving SNFI assistance to populations facing greatest needs due to displacement through: 1) improved access to safe, dignified and appropriate emergency shelter and life-saving NFIs to newly displaced and vulnerable populations in secondary displacement and 2) improved living conditions to highly vulnerable IDPs in protected displacement, returnees and host communities unable to meet SNFI needs in Rubkona and Koch Counties, Unity and Yei County, Central Equatoria. In total, the response will support 10,755 people (5,593 female, 5,162 male) with life-saving SNFI assistance. The project also aligns to Strategic Objectives 1 and 2 of the 2019 HRP. 

Concern mobile teams based in Bentiu and Juba and Yei will implement mobile SNFI responses in Koch, Unity and Yei, Central Equatoria to 6,867 individuals (3,572 female, 3,295 male) for a cost per beneficiary of US$15.46. Due to the volatility of these areas there are no static partners present and mobile responses are necessary if alerts are raised for S/NFI needs. The mobile responses will be providing access to SNFI assistance through the distribution of emergency NFIs. These kits will be designed following assessments with consideration to needs of women, men, girls and boys as well as People with Specific Needs (PSNs). 3,542 individuals (1,842 female, 1,700 male) in Koch and 3,325 individuals in Yei (1,730 female, 1,595 male) will be targeted with this component of the project.

IDPs have resettled in Bentiu and Rubkona towns due to congestion in Bentiu PoC and having moved from more insecure locations in Unity. As Bentiu and Rubkona towns were destroyed during the conflict, rehousing opportunities remain low and SNFI needs are high. In Yei, there are IDPs in protracted displacement from other locations in Yei town due to continuing insecurity in surrounding areas. Concern piloted cash-based interventions (CBIs) in 2018/2019 under SSHF and will continue this approach in 2019 in Unity and in Yei. Concern&#x2019;s recent market assessments in Bentiu and Rubkona have found that suppliers can meet some demands for shelter materials but as the markets are still recovering other materials will be provided in-kind. Concern aims to focus more on CBIs in locations where security is more stable with functioning and accessible markets for provision of shelter materials and if feasible NFIs. This will allow more flexibility for beneficiaries in meeting needs and also contribute to market recovery. Concern mobile teams based in Bentiu and Juba and Yei will implement the mobile responses. AAP will be integrated throughout the project cycle. Concern will consult with beneficiaries prior to the project, to provide information on the project and entitlements to assistance and to ensure that materials are as per social and cultural norms. 2,388 individuals (1,242 female, 1,146 male) in Rubkona and 1,500 (780 female, 720 male) in Yei (total 3,888 individual beneficiaries for a cost per beneficiary of $25) will receive assistance through a combination of vouchers and in-kind distributions.

To ensure adherence to the principle of &#x2018;Do No Harm&#x2019; and to reduce community tensions, the response will also target the most vulnerable returnee and host community populations as vulnerability is not exclusive to IDPs. Beneficiaries will be selected based on community defined criteria identified to ensure needs are properly identified for women, men, girls and boys. The most vulnerable will be prioritised including: female-headed households, households with the largest number of children under 5 child-headed households vulnerable people with disabilities, elderly, widows and orphans. A CRM will be in place for beneficiaries to provide feedback or complaints.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elise Ponson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Director - Emergencies</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211914999006</telephone>
   <email>southsudan.pde@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Traynor</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Quality Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211916703523</telephone>
   <email>sthsud.progqcoord@concern.net</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-07">193333.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11683">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-07">193333.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="000805539">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-18">16012.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082965">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-06">177321.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concern Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
