<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/NFI/UN/11724</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life saving Shelter and Non-Food Items services to IDPs and returnees in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to contribute to preventing, reducing and mitigating protection threats for persons affected by crisis in South Sudan through the provision of lifesaving humanitarian assistance. The project will provide Emergency Shelter amp Non-Food Items (ES-NFI ) assistance through mobile and static teams and integrate and coordinate the response with other IOM departments, including water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH), Health, Camp Coordination and Camp Management (CCCM), Displacement Tracking Matrix (DTM), Pipeline and Logistics. IOM will further strengthen the capacity of the humanitarian aid system to provide timely and targeted humanitarian assistance through S-NFI Cluster coordination, information management and providing logistics support to S-NFI Cluster and Pipeline partners, namely transport for ES-NFI in-kind supplies from the main logistics hubs to the field locations to enable partners to distribute to beneficiaries.
IOM S-NFI response aims to reach up to 6,500 individuals considered extremely vulnerable (defined as those in acute and moderate need according to the Humanitarian Needs Overview (HNO) methodology) and whose capacity to anticipate, cope with and recover from conflict stresses has been eroded. Those considered extremely vulnerable include newly displaced persons, IDPs in Protection of Civilians (PoC) and collective centres, IDPs living with host communities, returnees, and members of host communities who have lost their income, shelter, assets and food sources. Proposed activities are in-line with Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) strategic objectives as well as S-NFI Cluster objectives.
IOM will provide emergency shelter and non-food items through in-kind. The mobile team based in Juba and static team based in Wau will implement the interventions jointly with national and international partners, specifically ES/NFI, WASH, Food Security and Livelihood and Protection actors, and in close coordination with S-NFI Cluster. State Focal Points (SFP) and Cluster coordinators will be involved in the planning, coordination and reporting of the interventions.
IOM Response team will conduct needs analyses through a combination of qualitative and quantitative data collection tools. Feedback from beneficiaries will be used for comparative analysis and to establish baselines and to analyze progress.
In its effort to strengthen evidence-based programming, IOM MampE team will conduct monitoring activities including rapid monitoring for at least 60 per cent of in-kind interventions at least one post distribution monitoring (PDM) every quarter for in-kind interventions as per Cluster recommendations. IOM will ensure AAP and cross cutting thematic mainstreaming in all programme. IOM will mainstream gender, protection GBV, HLP, environment and AAP in all activities. IOM has already modified all data collection tools to take into account the need of different population groups. IOM will undertake rapid monitoring during the distribution to collect community feedback and identify means to improve the intervention with specific focus on AAP. The gender specific needs will be taken into consideration in the provision of ES-NFI supplies to IDP in camps, returnees and host communities. IOM will prioritize households headed by women for ES-NFI supplies through in-kind Interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asar Ul Haq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">S/NFI Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211912379808</telephone>
   <email>mulhaq@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smith Harry</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 912 379794</telephone>
   <email>ssudanpsu@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.64523990 25.28375850</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-21">352338</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SSD_2019_1000035">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-20">352338</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11724">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-21">352338</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
