<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/FSL/NGO/11562</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency livelihood support for women, men, girls and boys at the brink of hunger in Fangak County through provision of main season crop kit, vegetable seeds, fishing equipment and capacity building.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fangak County has been affected by complex disasters ranging from internal and external displacements, droughts and destruction of livelihoods and means of survival for the inhabitants. 
To reverse the deteriorating food security situation and save lives of the people projected in IPC 5 (September 2019 IPC Update) in the County, CAFAD proposes an emergency project to support 4,000 Households (2,420 women, 900 men, 400girls and 280 boys) with fast maturing, nutritious and quality vegetable seeds, crop kits and fishing equipment. This is expected to benefit 24,000 persons estimating that each of the target household has 6 household members.
The most at risk population are IDPs (50% of the target beneficiaries) and returnees (20%) who have not been integrated into the community and settled mainly in the rural areas of New Fangak, Mareang and other locations on the Eastern side of the County along river Nile and its tributaries where they can access fish for consumption but they lack the requisite fishing hooks, nets and monofilaments. They also require capacity building on fish hygiene, preservation and marketing skills. Households hosting IDPs will also be targeted with the intervention making up 30% of the total beneficiaries. 
CAFAD plans to distribute quality main season crop, vegetable seeds and farming tools (maloda and sickle) to vulnerable women, girls, boys and men on time (between March and early April 2019) for early planting to ensure quality production to sustain their families. Each beneficiary is expected to receive a combination of crop kit (sorghum, cowpeas and maize), Vegetable kit (Okra, onion, watermelon, amaranthus, cabagge and carrot seeds), farming tools (maloda and sickle) and a fishing kit (Monofilament, box of hooks and a pair of twine for making fishing net)
CAFAD will liaise with UNFAO for the timely release of the above inputs and transport them (within three days upon notification as per FAO SOP in relation to release orders) from Juba warehouse to Bor for further shipment to the distribution points in Fangak by the logistic cluster via barge of airlifting.
For the purpose of project inception, CAFAD shall mobilize and sensitize the communities at County, Boma and payam level through their representatives women leaders, youth, payam administrators, commissioners and RRC to determine identification and beneficiary selection. Consultative meetings shall be carried out during inception, implementation and exit points of the project and reports submitted to relevant stakeholders. 
In collaboration with local authorities (RRC, payam administrators, boma heads) OCHA, FAO and other stakeholders CAFAD will identify and register the most vulnerable households in OCHA approved payams in Fangak County (Mareang, Phom, Old Fangak, Paguer and Manajang) in a format to be agreed between CAFAD and the local authorities and submitted to FSL secretariat and FAO for approval. 
During distribution, CAFAD shall provide technical information and guidance to the beneficiaries on best use of agriculture and fishing kits being distributed. This will cover handling of inputs provided with support of visual aids and captions with instructions. Also  good agronomic practices, seed production and preservation techniques, post-harvest processing and store management, family nutrition with special emphasis on food preparation, processing amp utilization will be covered in the trainings. Fisher folks will also be targeted for training on basic fishing and fish handling techniques that will be integrated with hygiene promotion WASH activities by Nile Hope, MEDAIR and other actors in Fangak County.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elijah Mwangi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FSL Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924073222</telephone>
   <email>cafad.southsudan.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Angelo Madhier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211915271263</telephone>
   <email>cd.cafad.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-27">120054</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11562">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-27">120054</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080233">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-13">70950</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00081844">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-10">49104</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
