<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/CCCM/UN/11492</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Camp Management Services to Vulnerable Populations in Hard-to-Reach Areas in Camp and Camp-like Settings in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will ensure camp management continues to contribute to preventing, reducing and mitigating protection threats for persons affected by crisis in South Sudan through the provision of lifesaving humanitarian assistance in keeping with the 2018-2019 CCCM Cluster Strategy, specifically Cluster Strategic Objective 4: Expand CCCM services to new and unreached populations. Following the CCCM Cluster strategy and prioritization and in keeping with the mandate of Camp Coordination and Camp Management, displaced persons residing in camp and camp-like settings

Target locations for this project include CCCM Cluster and OCHA prioritized areas. Areas identified have been cited by state-level OCHA and CCCM Cluster representatives, DTM and REACH displacement analysis, and Needs Assessment Working Group prioritization, and Solutions Working Groups as experiencing significant internal displacement and having a likelihood to persist as returnee corridors. In the current context, so-called &#x201C;returnees&#x201D;, displaced persons from within and outside the country, are moving across South Sudan in spontaneous movements, often in large flows occurring over short time spans. However, in prioritized areas, adequate services, support structures, and legal frameworks are lacking. These factors prevent many displaced persons intending to return or reintegrate into communities in South Sudan from achieving durable solutions to displacement, forcing them to form spontaneous settlements, collective centers, and self-settled camp and camp-like settings. These sites fall under the mandate of CCCM. Alongside this caseload are &#x201C;hard-to-reach&#x201D; camp and camp-like settings previously unserved by partners. The revitalized peace agreement has led to areas of stability emerging throughout the country, through which existing camp and camp-like settings, previously unreachable by humanitarian partners due to access constraints, are becoming accessible .

A one year project is requested due to the high likelihood of IDP sites persisting as &#x201C;returnee&#x201D; flows continue and IDPs in camp-like settings, spontaneous settlements, and collective centers fail to achieve durable solutions. Additionally, per CCCM Cluster guidance on mobile response and Global Camp Management standards, best practices in building and supporting community self-management and coordination structures in persistent camps mandates structured follow-up visits beyond the intensive intervention, stabilization, and capacity-building period. Per South Sudan CCCM Cluster Mobile Standard Operating Procedures (SOP), mobile interventions necessitate responses of between six weeks and three months. At the discretion of the CCCM Cluster, supported by regular response reviews from the CCCM Cluster Mobile Working Group, responses can be extended beyond this period pursuant to concretely identified needs and persistent protection risks. This response period is then followed by a structured handover period and regular follow-up visits to provide support to self-management structures and support in responding to newly emerged coordination challenges in coordination with partners. Given that road conditions and access will not persist year round for some sites, a longer project period is required to comply with Cluster guidance on response. A one year project period is thus appropriate to ensure program quality .

The revitalization of the South Sudanese peace process and recently signed agreements offer new opportunities for the country and its conflict-affected population in 2019. However, significant numbers of people remain in camps or camp-like settings in hard-to-reach areas outside of UNMISS PoC sites. This project therefore aims to extend CCCM services and lifesaving support through mobile responses and encompasses all of the four main activities of the CCCM Cluster allocation strategy in reaching new and displaced populations through mobile response, as follows: 1) Support site management by expanding</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCALCO Priscila</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator CCCM</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 (0) 91 237 9627</telephone>
   <email>pscalco@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harry Smith</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Support Unit Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 912 379794</telephone>
   <email>ssudanpsu@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.64523990 25.28375850</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-21">258791.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-21">41208.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SSD_2019_1000035">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-20">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11492">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-21">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
