<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA2/WASH/NGO/13371</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of equitable access to safe and adequate water, dignified sanitation, and hygiene practices to mitigate WASH related GBV and Malnutrition for the Internally displaced population (IDPs), returnee and crisis-affected communities through coordinated and integrated WASH response, reinforcing protection and enhancing resilience, communities coping mechanisms and sustainability in Pibor County, Jonglei State, South Sudan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CMC aims to provide timely, equitable access to safe and sufficient water, improved sanitation, and improving hygiene knowledge of the Internally Displaced Population (IDPs) and most vulnerable host communities in Likuangole, Gumuruk, and Verteth in Pibor County, Jonglei state through WASH emergency intervention to reduce WASH-related GBV and malnutrition through integrated lifesaving WASH activities mainstreaming protection, accountability to affected population (AAP) and strengthening beneficiaries copping mechanism and resilience through training of different groups of people in the community such as pump mechanics, Water management committee, Hygiene promoters, women groups, community leaders, integrated community-based protection network (CBPN) for protection mainstreaming, and integrated Community Nutrition volunteer (CNVs) for WASH-Nut, and the AAP focal persons. The project will target 16,000 (13,000 direct, and 3,000 indirect) beneficiaries facing IPC 3-5 and GAM rate of 20.8% customarily, the internally displaced population, most vulnerable host communities affected with conflict and natural disasters, and malnutrition patients with limited access to safe water supply, hygiene, sanitation practices and food insecurity, through supported coordination and complement of WASH gaps which other implementing partners in the targeted areas are limited to tackle through their interventions due to increase on the caseloads or inadequate integration. CMC purposes to address WASH gaps related to currently arising emergency needs assessed to achieve Sphere standards, the core humanitarian standards/principles and the WASH cluster objectives, contributing to 2019 SSHF SA2 tackling the 1st and 2nd HRP WASH CO. contributing to eradication of the IPC 3-5 throughout Pibor areas.

CMC targets vulnerable and crisis affected population with a structured, effective programming to improve access to safe water, enhancing community awareness on safe hygiene and sanitation practices to prevent and mitigate WASH-related diseases through WASH-Nut and WASH GBV tackling:
 Repairing and rehabilitating 20 identified boreholes, measurable by WASH cluster standards for water supply.
 Selection and Training of 30 pump mechanics, 100 water management committees, 30 hygiene promoters, 40 water point attendances, the 40 food vendors, and 15 AAP focal persons deeply involved in the participatory MampE, 15 CBPN and CNVs for WASH mainstreaming in protection and Nutrition facilities.
 Conducting hygiene promotion through house-to-house, OTP/SC and PHCC hygiene promotion, focused group discussions, schools MHM sessions and public outreaches.
 Identification and registration of 1500 (SAM patients, population at risk ) most vulnerable IDPs/host communities households targeted for the WASH NFIs, 600 women and girls for the menstrual hygiene kits.
 Distribution of the WASH non-food items, hygiene kits, menstrual hygiene kits, and IEC materials.
 Identification, registration and distribution of hand-washing facilities (at OTPs/SC and PHCCs), garbage bins to 40 food vendors.
 Conducting coordination for complementary, integration and mainstreaming purposes with JAM, RMF (for nutrition), and CIDO, INTERSOS, OXFAM GB, VOP (for GBV).
 Conducting rapid monitoring and evaluation (MampE) through the CMC&#x2019; AAP incorporation methodologies and the Post Distribution monitoring (PDM).
 Improving household waste management system through cat-methods, digging garbage pits and installation of 8 garbage bins in the public places.
 Reporting to the cluster and other actors on the progress of the implementation, highlighting lesson learned through effective information sharing.

Putting the affected population at the center of the response through gender-sensitivity and people with special needs (old age, children, pregnant women, disables), strong complains and feedback mechanisms influencing ACTIVE CITIZENSHIP, the DO NO HARM incorporating AAP scorecard</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD19-12-152901-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abe Manasi Lori</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211926568114</telephone>
   <email>amanasi@cmc-ss.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lekuru Ednah Jeremiah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211916086896</telephone>
   <email>charitymissioncorps@outlook.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luga Henry</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211928000147</telephone>
   <email>dodukanga@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-20">140292.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-20">140292.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-13371">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-20">280585.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00083833">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-25">92999.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00086072">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-30">187586.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
