<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/H/NGO/11466</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health In Emergency-  Canal /Pigi County Jonglei State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Extreme insecurity persists across the county of Canal Pigi in Jonglei State with 4 major Payams affected out of 6 Payams The affected Payams are Kurwai, Kaldak, Canal Town and Khorfulus. Pigi /canal County in general has history of in adequate health service as well as other services in General since the outbreak of the war in 2013. The county has also suffered from activities of armed factions since 2011.The general Infrastructure is destroyed.  according to the IRNA reports Canal, the major populations in canal Pigi are now located in the remote Kurwai and Canal town where infrastructure is very poor. These places are considered to be safe. In Kurwai, IRNA report recorded that, Conflict continues to disrupt normal health service delivery, and macroeconomic conditions remain very poor. There is no functional market, no water supply. The population relies on the Sobat river and also depends on wild fruits gathering. The other drivers of this deterioration are specifically cattle raiding and cycle of recurrent wars among different armed factions since 2016 up to Sept 2018.
This project is thus designed to cover this health service need in canal County following the signed peace in 2018. 
Two (2) mobile clinics will be established. Kurwai Mobile clinic and Canal town Mobile clinic. These mobile clinics will be accessed by populations from the four affected Payams. Kurwai, canal, Kaldak and Khorfulus. The remote villages of Kulanyang, Patai and Nibak will be served through weekly outreaches. 

 Canal Pigi population projection for 2019 according to National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) 2015 -2020 estimated Male 76248, Female 69706 making a total population of 145953.  The Sept 2018 IPC report indicates that, canal /Pigi especially Kurwai is catastrophe (IPC 5). The HRP People in need estimates are 39,475 while the HRP target is 22,106.  Health Action AiD (HAA) Target Direct Beneficiaries are Men 3,844, Female 4065, Boys 2258 Girls 2286 Total 12453. The Indirect Beneficiaries are Men 2980, Female 3151, Boys 1750, Girls 1772 Total 9653. The project will reach to a total population of 22106 which translate to 100% of the HRP target over the 6 Months period. Guided by the IRNA reports Cana/Pigi, 59% of the Population in canal are estimated displaced persons. This project will therefore target 59% IDPs and 41% Host communities with Provision of essential primary healthcare services focusing on major causes of morbidity and mortality. This service will be implemented through 2 rapid response services in service populations in Kurwai, Kaldak, Khorfulus and canal town Payams. Through this package, HAA will conduct 
 OPD Consultations 
 deliveries attended by skilled birth attendant at facility or home
 health Facilities providing SGBV/CMR services
Secondly, this project will Prevent, detect and respond to epidemic prone disease outbreaks through 
 Immunization services for children between 6 months to 15 years of age.
 Epidemic prone diseases Alerts verified and responded to within 48 hours
 Health education and promotion on availability and utilization of health care services.
 Training of staffs on disease surveillance and outbreak response.
Thirdly the project will Integrate in to essential primary health care services WASH, Nutrition, Food security and Protection and will conduct  Screening of under 5 years children with SAM+MC and treatment in stabilization centers ,training of health workers on infection prevention and control (Wash in health facilities), training of health workers on integrated disease surveillance and response
 identification of persons with mental health cases for referral for either treatment or psycho-social support. This project is complementary to already existing integrated emergency project for health and Nutrition under HAA through the support from UNFPA covering reproductive health , Global Fund through the National Malaria Control Program with ACTs supplies as well as UN W</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Action Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Action Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anthony Laki Wani (MPH)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 929838084</telephone>
   <email>anthonylaki@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taban Gwakih(MD)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 929875482</telephone>
   <email>healthactionaid@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-11">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11466">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-11">100000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Action Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080658">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-26">53299.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Action Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082191">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-25">46700.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Action Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
