<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/P/INGO/11524</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency child protection services to newly arrived IDPs in Yei Town, South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the proposed intervention, Tdh aims to contribute to the recovery and resilience of the IDP children and their communities in Yei town. Since 2016, as violence erupted in Central Equatoria, and more specifically in Yei River state, families were forced to flee and take refuge in Yei town. At the end of 2018, as the insecurity intensified, Yei town saw the arrival of vulnerable IDP children and their communities. Among the key unaddressed child protection (CP) concerns identified within these recently displaced communities are the high number of unaccompanied or separated children (UASC), children associated with armed forces or armed groups or at risk of being recruited, acts of sexual violence and exploitation, harmful child labour practices and cases of neglect and abuse. Tdh aims to support these children by responding to the identified protection needs through individualized case management services and psychosocial support, as well as train community leaders to identify and assist in responding to these needs and, by extension, further build the resilience of the targeted communities. Tdh will target current newly arrived and potential future IDP arrivals in Yei town, and integrate them into already existing CM and PSS services. The proposed response has been designed through a community-based approach, incorporating the input and involvement of IDPs so that activities are responsive to their needs. Sustainability of CP services will be built through strengthening the capacities of the community to draw on their own resources and networks to prevent and mitigate protection risks for children. This six-month intervention will directly benefit 1,400 individuals and be implemented through two complementary outcomes. First, Tdh will ensure that extremely vulnerable IDP children, with a specific focus on UASC, have improved access to holistic child-centred protection services. Second, Tdh will ensure quality community-based child protection interventions that aim to improve the psychosocial wellbeing of community members with a focus on children.
Tdh will provide comprehensive case management with referrals to specialized services available. Children without caregivers will be identified, registered and reported through Child Protection Information Management System in coordination with Save The Children and ICRC for national and cross-border family tracing activities. Tdh will facilitate alternative care for UASC by reinforcing community initiatives and supporting foster families. Tdh will also screen and select potential foster families to provide care for newly identified emergency cases. 
In order to improve the psychosocial wellbeing of children and caregivers, Tdh will also strengthen community-based child protection interventions. Tdh will ensure the provision of PSS activities for children and youth within Child Friendly Spaces, conducted by community PSS volunteers. Tdh will also conduct community awareness sessions on community-means to prevent child protection risks in IDP communities as well as on community cohesion and integration of UASC IDPs. Then, Tdh will strengthen the capacity of key community members to disseminate key messages on child protection issues and referral pathways. Finally, Tdh will establish and monitor Help desks in community services structures, playing a key role in the identification and referral of children in need. 
Tdh is uniquely positioned to address the child protection concerns mentioned above. Tdh has been implementing similar projects and will therefore build on its experience, expertise and the lessons learnt from past projects to ensure a quality implementation of activities. Furthermore, Tdh has been working with the communities targeted for this project and is well-accepted by the beneficiaries. Tdh will continue to collaborate with other international and national actors, coordination mechanisms, local and state level authorities to facilitate the implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes - Lausanne</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes - Lausanne</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ann Reiner</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 211 (0) 921 709 00</telephone>
   <email>Ann.reiner@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emanuele Bolognesi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 (0)956319031</telephone>
   <email>emanuele.bolognesi@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aliya Abidi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 (0)915000178</telephone>
   <email>syedaalia.abidi@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11524">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-01">100000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes - Lausanne</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080246">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-13">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes - Lausanne</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082432">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-08">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes - Lausanne</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="9344 / 9933">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-04">4657</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Terre des Hommes - Lausanne</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
