<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/WASH/NGO/11507</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of timely and appropriate access to safe and adequate water, dignified Sanitation, and enhancing safe hygiene practices for the Internally displaced population (IDPs), Returnee and crisis affected communities through integrated WASH interventions, reinforcing protection and enhancing resilience and communities coping mechanisms and sustainability of livelihoods.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project, CMC aims to provide timely, equitable access to safe and sufficient water, improved sanitation, and improving hygiene knowledge of the Internally Displaced Population (IDPs) and most vulnerable host communities in Likuangole, and Verteth (Vuveth,Lokormach, Gei) focusing on WASH emergency intervention to reduce morbidity and mortality resulting from WASH-related diseases and malnutrition through integrated lifesaving WASH activities mainstreaming protection, accountability to affected population (AAP) and strengthening the capacity of affected community on copping mechanism and resilience through training of different groups of people in the community such as pump mechanics, Water management committee, women groups, community leaders, and the AAP focal persons. The project will target 13,000 (10,000 direct, 3,000 indirect) beneficiaries mainly the internally displaced population, most vulnerable host communities affected with conflict and natural disasters, with limited access to safe water supply, hygiene,  sanitation practices and food insecurity with supported coordination and complementation of WASH gaps which others implementing partners in the targeted areas are limited to tackle through their interventions due to continuous increase on the caseloads. CMC purposes to address WASH gaps related to currently arising emergency needs assessed to achieve Sphere standards, the core humanitarian standards/principles and mainly the WASH cluster objectives contributions to 2019 SSHF SA1 tackling the 1st and 2nd HRP WASH CO.
CMC targets vulnerable and crisis affected population with a structured, effective preparedness and response programme through improving access to safe water, enhancing community awareness on safe hygiene and sanitation practices to prevent and mitigate WASH-related diseases through:
	Repairing and rehabilitating 20 identified boreholes, measurable by WASH cluster standards for water supply.
	Selection and Training of 30 pump mechanics, 100 water management committees, 30 hygiene promoters, 40 water point attendances, the 40 food vendors, and 15 AAP focal persons being deeply involved in the participatory MampE.
	Conducting hygiene promotion through house-to-house, focused group discussions, and public outreaches.
	Identification and registration of 1500 most vulnerable IDPs/host communities households targeted for the WASH NFIs, 500 women and girls for the menstrual hygiene kits.
	Distribution of the WASH non-food items, menstrual hygiene kits, and IEC materials.
	Identification, registration and distribution of handwashing facilities, garbage bins to 40 food vendors.
	Conducting continuous coordination for complementation, integration and mainstreaming purposes.
	Conducting continuous rapid monitoring and evaluation (MampE) through the CMC&#x2019; AAP incorporation methodologies and the Post Distribution monitoring (PDM).
	Improving household waste management system through cat-methods, digging garbage pits and installation of 8 garbage bins in the public places.
	Reporting to the cluster and other actors on the progress of the implementation, highlighting lesson learned through effective information sharing.
Enhancing the beneficiaries coping mechanism through capacity building to impact sustainability and resilience, sustaining livelihoods, linkages with development activities supporting protection, accountability by putting the affected population at the center of the response. CMC ensures gender-sensitivity and people with special needs (old age, children and pregnant women, disables) in service delivery, strong complains and feedback mechanisms, coordination and participatory monitoring (MampE), influencing ACTIVE CITIZENSHIP, the DO NO HARM through incorporation of AAP score cards. Addressing GBV/Protections constraints by involving protection team at all stages implementation and evaluation of every proposed activities to mitigate GBV and protection trea</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bida Alex Samuel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924153067</telephone>
   <email>charitymissioncorps@outlook.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nichola Wani Amos</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211911448743</telephone>
   <email>dodukanga@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Opeto</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ME officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211916268228</telephone>
   <email>opetodavid@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-06">204000.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="9417">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-08">150</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11507">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-06">204000.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080543">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-18">118538.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00081949">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-10">85461.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
