<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/NFI/INGO/11675</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Non-Food Items and Shelter support to conflict affected people in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Emergency Shelter and Non Food Items (ES/NFI) intervention that World Vision proposes to implement will respond to needs of vulnerable Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) that fled homes because of armed conflicts. The expected returnees, including some IDPs who have not received life-saving support interventions will be targeted. The objective of the response is to protect and save lives of the IDPs and returnees. WVSS will help vulnerable people with coping mechanisms that will have a combination of using locally available materials and in kind distribution. WVSS will reach these communities by using its experienced mobile team based in Juba. In some locations such as Upper Nile and Warrap the static staff will be used. The project will run from 1St March 2019 to 31st August 2019 (6 Months). The in Kind Shelter and Non Food materials that will be distributed from ES/NFI core-pipeline managed by IOM.
WVSS will respond in four States namely  Nyirol, Uror (Jonglei), Gogrial West, (warrap), Mayendit, Koch (unity), Ulanga and Maiwut (Upper Nile). WVSS will target 14,512 IDPs and returnees in the above-mentioned locations. These will comprise of 4,208 men, 4,063 women, 3,193 boys and 3,048 girls. For this response, IDPs are estimated to be about 60% while returnees are estimated to be 40% of the targeted population. 
WVSS will continue to be part of responses that are multi-cluster and multi-agency. Needs of the affected population will be served in a more holistic way with a high possibility of reducing on the response time. In selected locations with IDPs who are in transit and in need of protection and urgent assistance, multi-sector Survival Kits will be distributed through the Rapid Response Mechanism (RRM). World Vision will continue to participate in the Inter Agency Rapid Needs Assessments (IRNA) that would seek to determine the lifesaving needs of the affected populations. WVSS will continue to use its experienced staff to conduct the ES-NFI specific assessments, to facilitate the identification of affected IDPs, returnees and other vulnerable groups in the targeted areas.
WVSS will conduct Onsite Distribution Monitoring (OSDM) targeting in 50% of the locations where WVSS will conduct ES/NFI distribution. At all stages of the project implementation stages, WVSS will employ the Accountability to the Affected Population (AAP). Affected populations will be involved in the project from the time of needs identification to the point of the PDMs. WVSS will encourage information exchange with the affected population by ensuring that they are the ones who would the kind of assistance required.  WVSS will provide information on the amount resources available resources that will make them decide on the best type of assistance that should be distributed. Through the active two-way communication that will be created. WVSS look out for creative and sustainable community based solutions that are workable in those particular locations. In Locations where there are no community structure and representation World Vision will seek to train community representatives who will be part to the response and being part of the community representatives in the monitoring of the project progress and handling and management of complaints. WVSS will use its Protection and GBV specialist to ensure that matters related to protection are reported and actioned.  To improve the quality of assistance and determine the level of satisfaction among beneficiaries and usage of ES/NFIs a minimum of two Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) will be held in selected locations where World Vision will respond. Outcomes from the PDM will be used to adjust the response based on new identified needs among beneficiaries. WVSS will promote health and protection messages to improve programming in a multi-sector response. WVSS build the capacity of national NGOs especially SSUDA, LCED and ACKAP.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taonga Banda</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>211924751293</telephone>
   <email>Taonga_Banda@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thatcher Ng&apos;ong&apos;a</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>211925413943</telephone>
   <email>Thather_Ngonga@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Warrap</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.22093080 28.85968040</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">200004.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11675">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">200004.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080274">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-13">77102</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082265">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-26">122902.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
