<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/NFI/NGO/11493</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency shelter and lifesaving non-food items to vulnerable populations in Yirol East  Gogrial West</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCOSS proposes to provide life-saving ES-NFIs through Cash Based Interventions (CBI) to most vulnerable IDPs and host communities who haven&#x2019;t been reached with any response in settlement camps in Yirol East 2,200 individuals (367 HHs) both IDPs and host communities, disaggregated as follows (Men 396, Women 528, Boys 484 and Girls 792) for a CBI in Lakes state &#x2013; Yirol East county. The IDPs were displaced from Rumbek North and are also affected with the deepening economic crisis.

CCOSS has been engaging the targeted communities prior to the implementation of this project. Specifically, CCOSS has put mechanisms in place such as identifying key leaders in the community and other influential persons. Prior to project implementation, CCOSS will conduct community engagement forums to inform them about the project, especially the CBI that is a new initiative in the community. The beneficiaries will elect their representatives (committees) who will be trained on the project and also encouraged to provide community-led feedback on the project, specifically, the staffs receive, record, solve/address queries and give feedback to beneficiaries. This action will complement other humanitarian actions that are being implemented within the targeted locations such as WASH, health and livelihoods, Protection and Camp management. Specifically, CCOSS will work with ACTED and Plan International in Yirol East.

A detailed market assessment will be conducted to identify the availability of ES-NFIs in the market, assess the supply chain of items, check the quality of ES-NFIs, and identify the suppliers/vendors of products and to identify risks of the CBI programme and mitigation measures. Meetings will be contacted with the potential traders and the local authorities to explain the programme modality and contracts will be signed with the selected traders for the supply of the ES-NFIs. In order to mitigate the risk of double dipping, tokens will be distributed during registrations and then withdrawn during distribution of vouchers. The registration will be done simultaneously in all the settlement camps to avoid double registrations. The commodity vouchers will be printed with security features and an expiry date, serial numbers and duplicates that will remain in the voucher book. The beneficiaries will have a window of time to access the ES-NFIs from the vendors in the IDP settlements. The beneficiaries will redeem their vouchers for a selected number of ES-NFIs determined during the needs assessment. All beneficiaries will get the same types of ES-NFIs. At agreed times the traders will then redeem the vouchers for payment by CCOSS through an agreed payment method.

In order to mitigate the risk of beneficiaries colluding with the vendors to get cash, a detailed needs assessment will be done at the beginning of the programme to ensure that the most vulnerable households are targeted. Strong focus will be made to ensure that the most vulnerable groups (e.g. persons with disabilities, pregnant and lactating women, and unaccompanied elders/minors) in the community will be served appropriately according to their ES/NFI needs and in the manner not exposing them to additional stress.

In Warrap, Gogrial West, CCOSS proposes to provide life-saving ES/NFIs to 3000 individuals (500 HHs) vulnerable communities, disaggregated as follows (Men 540, Women 720, Boys 660 and Girls 1080) affected vulnerable populations both in the communities. The project will target most vulnerable populations in need (after an assessment). The target population comprises of displaced persons in need of shelter and NFI for their sustenance. The project will aim to meet the needs of the vulnerable IDPs, returnees and host community who become vulnerable as a result of conflict and continuous displacement as a result of conflict, food insecurity or due to economic deterioration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mabior Wel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ditrector</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0925029884</telephone>
   <email>info@ccoss7.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mundia Akala</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0921399960</telephone>
   <email>mundia.akala@ccoss7.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lakes</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.60307990 29.97405340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Warrap</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.22093080 28.85968040</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-27">100000.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NA">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-21">0.49</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11493">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-27">100000.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080192">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-07">33915.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082077">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-21">66085.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Care for Children and Old Age in South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
