<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/NFI/NGO/11530</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency Shelter  life-saving NFIs to vulnerable communities  in Ulang   Nasir Counties, Upper Nile State in 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to support the provision of and rehabilitation of emergency shelter and life-saving Non-Food-Items (NFIs) to vulnerable populations in Ulang and Nasir Counties in Upper Nile State. The core of this 6-month intervention is to improve the living conditions of vulnerable populations, mostly returnees and newly displaced people. 
Needs assessment in the target counties have been done and documented. In January-March 2018, REACH interviewed 267 Key Informants (KIs) from 75 settlements in Nasir and Ulang Counties in Upper Nile State and in May 2018  Joint Humanitarian teams that included TADO/SSUDA/IOM and other non-NFI partners conducted rapid assessments verification  that exposed huge needs in the affected population including lack of shelter for newly arrived returnees and IDPs, dilapidated shelter, lack of blankets, lack of mosquito nets, lack of water cans/pots to fetch water, lack of cooking utensils and lack of dignity kits for girls and women.
The project targets 6650 direct beneficiaries comprising of newly displaced people (IDPs) in protracted displacement, returnees and host communities unable to meet their S/NFI needs. Further, lactating and pregnant women, households with malnourished children, unaccompanied children and unaccompanied elderly and persons with disability will be targeted. The project will undertake timely delivery of life-saving assistance through the deployment of rapid response teams in line with humanitarian priorities for 2019 as outlined in the Humanitarian Response plan (HRP).
Nasir and Ulang in Upper Nile state are among the most severe conflict affected counties since the 2013 and 2016 crisis. Continued armed clashes between government and opposition forces and inter-communal fighting continue to impede humanitarian efforts and displace civilians throughout and within the target counties. Ulang and Nasir counties for the last two years 2017-2018 received and hosted a huge number of displaced persons from Jonglei and from within Nasir.  Protracted internal conflicts in South Sudan and the fact that Ulang and Nasir counties are geographically located on the flight path to Ethiopia refugee camps, make them vulnerable counties in this humanitarian crisis. Recent displacement from February 2018 fighting in Nasir and March 2018 fighting in Uror, Niyirol and Akobo counties has further worsened the situation of IDPs in these areas.
This project will be implemented in close collaboration with the Shelter Cluster and project activities will be crafted taking into account the gaps identified through the multi-sector assessment missions which TADO will participate. TADO will dynamically adapt the project to the specific needs of men, women, girls and boys and respond accordingly.
The distribution of Shelter and NFI kits will take into consideration the minimum protection standards and be undertaken at sites to be identified together with the beneficiary communities. TADO will seek to enhance synergies between this intervention and the Education intervention it is implementing in the target areas.
Steps to protect women and girls against sex and gender-based violence (SGBV) will be undertaken including but not limited to positioning distribution points within short walking distances from the beneficiaries&#x2019; place of residence. Special attention and priority will be accorded the elderly, people with disability, pregnant women and children to enhance reach and access. Feedback desks will also be provided at each distribution site so that beneficiaries can share their feedback.
TADO will work closely with SSUDA the state focal point organization on S/NFIs and other clusters partners for better inclusiveness, effectiveness and efficiency implementation of the Project. TADO will complement its distribution by community awareness campaigns and information sessions on proper usage of the distributed items. Post distribution Monitoring (PDM) will be done</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Touch Africa Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Touch Africa Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mathew May Gai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0927240078</telephone>
   <email>mathew.gai@tado-ss.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head Of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0929204713/091562826</telephone>
   <email>tadoprogrammes2017@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-12">100000.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11530">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-12">100000.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Touch Africa Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080518">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-18">54100.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Touch Africa Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082688">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-18">45900.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Touch Africa Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
