<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/P/INGO/11501</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upscaling lfe-saving integrated Child Protection interventions for vulnerable children and their caregivers in Nyirol County</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children will continue implementing a package of life-saving integrated child protection interventions in 3 Payams of Nyirol County (Pading, Nyambor, and Pultruk). The project is a continuation of emergency activities currently undergoing in the hard to reach conflict-affected communities, including displaced and possible returnees in Nyirol County, with urgent needs. It will continue building on and benefitting from existing work being undertaken by its Education, Nutrition, and Health programmes in the same payams as well as the other, similar Child Protection work in other Nyirol payams. The critical life-saving child protection activities will reduce violence against children and increase access to quality child protection services by the most vulnerable children including adolescent girls and children with disabilities. The project will target a total of 5,419 affected people (1,734 girls , 1,799 boys, 921 women, 965 men). The project will undertake comprehensive case management of children by trained and supervised case workers who will also use the new updated information management system (CPIMS+) as it goes live in South Sudan. Children will be identified through a) Child Protection Help desks functional at SC-supported schools, medical and nutrition facilities, b) CFS, where children access structured and non-structured PSS activities and c) Case Workers and Community Mobilisers do community and homes visits and meeting with community groups and families. Case management will be undertaken using the national Case Management SOPs and will target children at high protection risk including UASC,   boys and girls at risk of child marriage, recruitment or hazardous labour  , and boys and girls who are at risk of or have experienced violence. Case workers will work closely with health, nutrition and education colleagues on referrals of cases such as UASC, SGBV and other children at risk. Approximately 250 children will benefit from case management services. CFS will be run by community volunteers and promoting engagement of caregivers and communities in the management of the spaces. Volunteers   will receive refresher training in Child Safeguarding, CFS management, PSS and PFA, in line with SC&#x2019;s Child Friendly Space manual and standards putting a strong emphasis on activities, physical considerations, that will help the most vulnerable children to participate including at risk children with different disabilities and adolescent girls. Sessions with children and caregivers on SRH, hygiene, education and others will be run with sector colleagues.SC will also support 6 children&#x2019;s play areas in locations where CFS are not established, or very remote areas far from running CFSs by providing recreational and sports materials and orientation to keep space safe and inclusive. Approximately  3533 children and adolescents (1,799 boys, 1734girls) will benefit from gender and inclusive community-based PSS activities. Finally, existing community-based groups will be assessed according to agreed criteria and supported through capacity building to better protect children by using preventative measures, raising awareness and mobilizing communities and making referral of serious cases. They will be supported by SC&#x2019;s Community Mobilisers to implement community action plans with focus on the protection of children including campaigns that will take place in each payam. Community Mobilisers will have joint monthly mobilization and awareness plans with health and nutrition promoters and education outreach workers. Campaigns will reach approximately 5419 people (1886 adults, 3533 children). In all interventions efforts will be made to ensure the most vulnerable and excluded children are actively supported to attend and will be monitored through existing beneficiary feedback and complaints&#x2019; mechanisms. The project will be guided by SC&#x2019;s CSG Policy and Code of Conduct, and humanitarian principles do no harm,and best interest of the child</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lizzy Ongoro</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposal Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0922700750</telephone>
   <email>Lizzy.Ongoro@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Finance Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Saruni</telephone>
   <email>Oloishorua</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Silvia Onate</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection Technical Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0922800801</telephone>
   <email>silvia.onate@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-26">130057</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NA">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-16">21</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11501">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-26">130057</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080227">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-26">32466.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00082040">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-17">97590.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
