<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/WASH/INGO/11763</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to WASH services contributing to the Health, Nutritional and Protection status of conflict and malnutrition-affected IDPs and Host communities in Fangak and Gogrial West Counties, South Sudan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will focus on lifesaving and early recovery of conflict affected communities of Gogrial West and Fangak Counties through provision of access to safe water, sanitation facilities, and improved hygiene practices. This project is aligned with the 2019 HRP, WASH Cluster priority activities and locations, and the Action Against Hunger Country Strategy for combatting the underlying causes of acute malnutrition. The proposed intervention highlights the integration of WASH services with nutritional services to provide a holistic response for the malnutrition emergency in the area. Moreover, we have mainstreamed protection concerns into all activities to improve upon GBV indicators for the IDP and host communities. 

Gogrial West is located in Warrap State, where 26.3% of the population in area is classified as in crisis (phase III), emergency (phase IV) and catastrophe (Phase V) phases according to IPC Classification for September through March 2019. Our SMART survey conducted by Action Against Hunger in Gogrial East and West in June 2018 calculated a GAM rate of 26.6%, and our SMART survey in Fangak found a GAM rate of 16.1%: both are alarmingly above the WHO emergency threshold of 15%. In order to address the situation, through mitigation of the underlying causes of malnutrition, Action Against Hunger proposes a WaSH response focusing on IDPs, Returnees and Host Communities. Integration with nutrition sector against the 3rd WASH Cluster Objective (CO3) will be prioritized in Gogrial West County where the organization has its presence with 12 OTP/TSFP sites and Stabilization center. Furthermore, in Fangak County Action Against Hunger will collaborate with local partner organization Hold the Child for provision of a minimum WASH package at 6 Nutrition Sites in Old Fangak Payam. During the project, 10 water sources/handpumps at nutrition sites will be rehabilitated with addition of rehabilitation of 10 community-based handpumps within catchment areas of 10 nutrition sites in both Gogrial West and Fangak Counties. 2 new boreholes will be drilled and installed with India Mark II handpump in Toch Payam of Fangak County to improve the community&#x2019;s access to safe drinking water sources based on the recommendations from RNA (Rapid Need assessment) survey in the area. Action Against Hunger will motivate 400 caregiver families of SAM and MAM cases to build household latrines through provision of digging tool kits and material for construction of latrines. Thus, the organization will encourage the use of local materials for construction of toilets, as the material will be acquired from National WASH Core pipeline. 10 new gender segregated latrines will be constructed (6 Fangak, 4 Gogrial West) at Nutrition Sites to improve the functionality of nutritional centers and incorporate protection sensitivity in program activities. A Door to Door hygiene promotion campaign will be launched to promote the knowledge and practice of improved hygiene behaviour in both target areas. Additionally, 1000 Hygiene Kit items will be distributed among the caregiver families of SAM children and 1000 dignity kits will be distributed among PLWs registered in both areas to provide for healthy menstrual hygiene management and SRHR. Hygiene sessions will be organized at Nutrition Site level to increase related awareness among the caregiver families. Nutrition Site sessions for usage of hygiene kits and dignity kits will be arranged to familiarize the beneficiaries with the kit items and their purpose.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anika Kristic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0911072918</telephone>
   <email>cd@ssd-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarmad Rana</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of WaSH Department</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0914348335</telephone>
   <email>washco@ssd-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Warrap</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.22093080 28.85968040</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-27">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11763">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-27">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080184">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-07">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="000824223">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-04">150000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACF - USA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
