<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-19/HSS10/SA1/WASH/NGO/11709</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision and improving access to sustainable WASH services for vulnerable host communities and IDPs to mitigate GBV cases associated with WASH among 10506 individuals in Kajo Keji County, Central Equatoria State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NSDO through this project will focus on mitigating risks of protection associated with access to WASH services in areas affected by conflict in Kajo Keji County. Timely access to water, sanitation and hygiene services for community members will be ensured in the first two quarters of 2019 to meet needs of IDPS, host communities and returnees. The project will ensure WASH facilities are safe, gender appropriate and maintained in secure locations as discussed with affected groups (especially women, girls, disabled and the elderly).

This project aims at rehabilitating 20 community water collection points in areas assessed jointly by NSDO team and  the Department of the Water and Sanitation- kajo Keji: Leikor, Kangayi, Kangapo, Kiri, Pamoju, Wudu, Shera-Jale, Ramogi, Mere, Lire, Litoba, longira and Saregor.
4 latrine blocks of existing latrines will be rehabilitated with separate stances for women and men for mitigation of GBV at health/school facility blocks  and to strengthen protection for females during access to sanitation facilities. This will include design improvements for safety and dignity and creating space for Menstrual Hygiene Management and installation of hand-washing space for prevention of GBV risks and spread of diseases.
This activity will be strengthening with WASH software activities to improve sustainability and proper utilization of facilities. 160 female and male community members will be trained to form 20 Water User Committees. 10 female and male community members will be trained to support sensitization during hygiene promotion campaigns. Community members will be engaged during Focused Group Discussions to participate in identifying needs and participating in WASH-GBV prevention in the community.
At least 8000 community members including IDPs, host community members and returnees will re-gain access to safe water supply in secure locations (boreholes) and Mini Water Yard. At least 820 direct beneficiaries will have access to secure sanitation services.
WASH facility design repairs and rehabilitation will include design improvements to accommodate the disabled, child friendly facilities for small boys and girls, and considering privacy, dignity and protection (secure with door locks inside for latrines). Handwashing facilities will be fixed and soaps provided to promote habit of handwashing at critical times. 

To fix cross cutting WASH needs, 4 volunteers will be recruited to monitor basic WASH services at nutritional OTP centers (including children under nutrition programmes at homes), report hygiene activities and , and identify WASH gaps during hygiene campaigns and monitor water quality.
School hygiene promotion clubs will be formed and trained in 2 primary schools and weekly school hygiene promotion sessions will be conducted in schools in-order to use children to as ambassadors of good practices. MHM kits will be provided for 600 girls of menstrual age accompanied with Menstrual Hygiene Management Sessions so that girls will not miss classes during their periods.

During the project cycle, NSDO field team will coordinate with key partners represented in state cluster who are providing WASH, health, nutrition and protection services. Regular joint activity monitoring sessions will be conducted and will involve County Department of Water and Sanitation and Education and partners like TTF, The Rescue Initiative and ARC. NSDO will also prioritize reporting all the project activities and share information with other partners intending to provide humanitarian services in Kajo Keji Country. NSDO will encourage active participation of the local community including women and children in the implementation of the proposed project in the target villages and encourage community monitoring and evaluation and accountability to beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jimmy Jamba Joseph</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211921704011</telephone>
   <email>jimmyjamba5@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Repent Taban Daud</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211912566019</telephone>
   <email>rtabanus@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-01">263000.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-11709">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-01">263000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00080435">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-13">93312.63</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00081942">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-14">169687.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
