<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1135156-EC0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1135156" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TREE AID</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frankincense: a root to climate smart resilience for vulnerable communities in West Gondar Zone in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to strengthen the governance and regulatory frameworks of local authorities and 6 PFM cooperatives to support management and protection of Boswellia forest (output 1). The project will work closely with the PFM cooperatives to strengthen their governance, organisational capacity and service delivery. PFM and development plans will be drawn up to help guide the PFMgroups to address the ongoing degradation and deforestation. The existing forest task force will be strengthened and judiciary, police, local administration and PFM cooperative representatives will be added. They will also be trained to ensure enforcement of the forest law. Regular meetings between different stakeholders will also be organised in order to discuss forest governance. The project will also protect and rehabilitate the Boswellia forest through the promotion of sustainable regeneration, enrichment planting and adaptation practices (output 2). To complement the management plans, PFM members and local communities will be given the requisite skills and tools to best manage and protect the Boswellia forests. Further training will be given to improve grazing practices, agricultural practices and bushfire management, in order to reduce human pressures on the forest. Woodlots will also be established by the PFM cooperatives and fuel saving stoves produced by women and distributed to further reduce these pressures and creating sustainable source of income. The PFM groups will also support the regeneration of the B.papyrifera stocks through the identification and demarcation of high regeneration zones and enrichment planting in the forest. These practices will be supported by a study by the University of Gondar to ensure their sustainability. Finally, the capacity of primary actors in the frankincense value chain will be strengthened in post-harvest handling, quality control and market linkages (output 3).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will enhance the management of existing tree stocks, increase the populations of B.papyrifera within the Metema area and enhance the value realised from the stock as a viable climate smart income generator for 2,852 smallholder farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The tappers aggregate their products at the PFM cooperative level who then sell them through the union. In order to realise a greater value of the frankincense available, 3 existing and 3 new PFM cooperatives, as well as a union, will follow a business development programme including the mobilisation of financial resources, technical financial acumen, and linkages with buyers. The cooperative union will also be supported to increase the value and the quality of the frankincense products through an equipped warehouse that allows grading. The tappers will be trained to improve their tapping practices to increase the quality of their product while conserving the trees. Two women groups will be created and trained to ensure the grading providing a new source of income for women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1135156-EC0" crs-channel-code="20000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUNARMA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1135156-EC0" crs-channel-code="21000" ref="GB-CHC-1135156" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TREE AID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1135156-EC0" crs-channel-code="11001" ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project (Actual) Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tree Aid</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programmes</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>441179096363</telephone>
   <email>info@treeaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.treeaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tree Aid, Brunswick Court, Brunswick Square, Bristol, BS2 8PE</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
