<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="1.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="1.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IM-CR-024714B-GG11-004</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IM-CR-024714B" type="70">openmindedly</reporting-org>
  <title>Community Life Improvement Project (CLIP), Banteay Meas and Chum Kiri Districts (Kampot Province), Samraong Tong District (Kampong Speu Province)</title>
  <description>The project will reduce poverty and increase livelihood options for 98 very disadvantaged families and poor farmers (a total of nearly 900 people) in the Kampot and Kapong Speu provinces of Southern Cambodia - where the majority of the population is dependent on agriculture for subsistence and income - by providing them with chickens, materials for constructing chicken cages, training and organic fertilisers.  Among the needs identified in these areas are: 1) a lack of adequate water supply for agriculture, and vulnerability to both flooding and drought annually which leads to uneven agricultural output; 2) a lack of skills and capital to improve farming and initiate alternative income generating activities; 3) family disruption which has left many widows and orphans solely responsible for income generation; 4) high rates of school dropout due to poverty.  The project will: 1) Increase the agricultural output of 30 poor farmers in the Kampong Speu province by training them in the use of low-cost organic fertiliser and sustainable agriculture techniques e.g. crop diversification and disease resistance; 2) Provide 98 landless families in the Kampot province with the opportunity to begin chicken farming, through offering chickens on a loan basis, materials for building pens, and training; 3) Offer training to 20 village chiefs from Kampot province in chicken farming and project management to monitor the activities and replicate them in their communities once the project ends.  The project will directly benefit 148 individuals, with priority given to women, orphans, widows and people living with HIV / AIDS, and indirectly benefitting 740 family members. It will help provide food and will increase the incomes of landless families and farmers, indirectly helping them to improve their homes, improve their nutrition, pay for healthcare and to send their children to school. Funding - which represents 48.7% of the project total - is requested for the purchase of chickens, materials for constructing chicken cages, chicken farm training, organic fertiliser and sustainable agriculture training.</description>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING" type="21">Methodist Relief and Development Fund</participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GG-OAC" role="FUNDING" type="10"></participating-org>
  <participating-org role="EXTENDING"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="START-PLANNED"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-31" type="END-PLANNED"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">CAMBODIA</recipient-country>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">Agriculture/Fisheries</sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-01-01">12756</value>
   <provider-org ref="GG-OAC"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-291691"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110">GRANT</finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
