<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ET-CSA-3994-Triggerise</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ET-CSA-3994" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triggerise Ethiopia</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing Ecosystem Motivational Platform to Improve Health and Wealth</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target audience includes: Adolescent girls and young women ages 15-24; and Indirect beneficiaries including all other women of reproductive age and their male partners (who will benefit from access to condoms, emergency contraceptives, and STI/HIV tests).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Tikosystem will aggregate service provision partners, demand creation channels, and product stockists to cost-effectively generate and meet SRH demand. The Tikosystem will use Tiko Miles; virtual reward points, to reward positive behaviours like initial choice, consistent use, and continued participation. 1 - Tiko Pro: Aggregating Demand Creation and Catalysing Income Generation Tiko Pro provides community mobilisers, peer educators, and entrepreneurs with a platform to manage their businesses and generate income. By leveraging partnerships with stockists, retailers, and providers, Tiko Pro allows entrepreneurs to earn through referrals, product sales, and basic service provision. In this project, Tiko Pros will refer adolescents for SRH services during outreach sessions. They will also sell fast-moving products - including menstrual hygiene management products - which provide less stigmatising entry points to taboo SRH conversations. 2 - Tiko Explore: Accessible, Destigmatised SRH Choice Service providers will provide free SRH services as part of Tiko Explore, Triggerise&#x2019;s membership program, which positions SRH in the context of a broader lifestyle brand. Tiko Explore provides adolescent girls and young women with the opportunity to access lifestyle deals across five categories: living well,, earning, learning, saving, and looking good. Since the fundamental insight behind Tiko Explore is to provide benefits beyond SRH - to build relevance among adolescents - Tiko Explore will include SRH offers as well as broader lifestyle offers. Already established partnerships with FGAE, MSIE and PSI facilities will provide our target (15-24-year-old adolescent girls and young women) with access to free and discounted contraceptives and other SRH products and services. We will also explore partnerships with other private and public facilities, pharmacies, and direct-to-consumer channels. Service provider partners and other technical experts will be responsible for key SRHR messaging that we include during Tiko Pro outreach sessions, provider consultations, and in marketing materials. We will partner with retailers and organisations who will provide lifestyle offers that broaden Tiko Explore beyond SRH.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To build ecosystems that trigger sexual and reproductive health and economic impact in targeted geographic areas in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" ref="ET-CSA-3994" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triggerise Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This year the main focus was around getting all Tikosystem elements in place to insure a healthy Tikosystem that will enable adolescents to become a part of a membership program and impact them both in health and wealth. Improving service uptake numbers, Tikosystem offering communication by Tiko pros and cooperation with partners was the core activities done for improved impact. It took quite a long time to put everything in place due to the difficulty we faced to onboard FGAE clinics, there was a lack of proper communication on the project which makes it time consuming and difficult to coordinate with each clinic. As anticipated we couldn&#x2019;t work with all 6 of the FGAE clinics, as they closed one immediately when we started and one being not available as a result of upgrading it to MCH clinic (as stated by FGAE management team) Out of the Four clinics we were allowed to refer in FGAE, two are exclusively serving the commercial sex workers which limits the number of clinics to serve the general population to two. After working for months to collaborate with different players that focused on youth with similar objectives, we manage to add Michu St. Paul clinics , Dkt clinics and youth centers recreational places as hotspot areas to reach out the youth.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triggerise is responsible for scaling up the Tikosystem for adolescent girls and young women by aggregating service provision partners demand creation channels, and product stockists to cost-effectively generate and meet SRH demand. In addition, Triggerise will create a solution responding to the needs of commercial sex workers (CSWs) and linking them to SRH products and professional services like psychosocial and legal service providers</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Department that is responsible for the scaling up of the Tikosystem, aggregation of service providers, creating the solution for the commercial sex workers and linking them to SRH products and services is the Management team.</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lidya G. Mulat</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Lead</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911773236</telephone>
   <email>lidya@triggerise.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity is set to operate in Addis Ababa, the capital city of Ethiopia. It is expected to cover 6 sub-cities in the first year, and 8 sub-cities in the second year.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The implementation of the project is in Addis Ababa.</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.9806 38.7578</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our platform allows young adolescents age 125-24 to be informed about the choices they have and where they can access contraception choices. The platform provides a membership program which enables the girl to have access to free and discounted family planning services along with a reward that allows her to unlock many offers in the Tikosystem.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-01">1002733</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-26">1000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001803" ref="xm-dac-7" type="10"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.CUPS-PDF" url="https://triggerise.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Triggerise_2018_Annual_Report.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Report for 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EKN Annual Report(January - December 2019)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the annual report that is the output of our activities including all the relevant details.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/EKN-Annual-Report-(January---December-2019)(1)-20200625080627.pdf">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">EKN Annual Report(January - December 2019)</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-06-25"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The measures are in units.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Results (Jan 01 2020 - July 31 2021)</narrative>
   </title>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.MS-EXCEL" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/SRH-IATI-Results-%28Jan-20---Jul-21%29-20211201091257.xlsx">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">SRH Project IATI Results</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="A08"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Measured in units</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
