<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">The Bright Sight: prevenzione delle Malattie Tropicali Neglette  (NTD) e cura della Vista per le persone con disabilit&#xE0; e pi&#xF9;  vulnerabili</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto ha come finalit&#xE0; il miglioramento dell&#x2019;accesso a servizi di prevenzione delle Malattie Tropicali 
Neglette (NTDs) e di cura della Vista negli Stati Central Equatoria, Eastern Equatoria e Lakes, in Sud Sudan in 3 
anni, in linea con il target 3.3 e 3.8 dell&#x2019;Obiettivo di Sviluppo Sostenibile n.3. 
La proposta si rivolge in particolar modo alle categorie pi&#xF9; vulnerabili della popolazione, quali persone con 
disabilit&#xE0;, donne e bambini, ed &#xE8; stata definita direttamente con i Ministeri statali della Salute, controparti di 
progetto, grazie alla pluriennale partnership di CBM Italia, CUAMM e CORDAID e presenza sul territorio. Queste 
premesse garantiscono il pieno endorsement della proposta da parte delle autorit&#xE0; governative, l&#x2019;allineamento
alle priorit&#xE0; tematiche e geografiche del Paese e risposta ai bisogni della zona di intervento. 
In tema NTDs, nonostante l&#x2019;integrazione delle politiche di prevenzione delle Malattie Tropicali Neglette (NTDs) 
nei servizi di salute primaria, i bisogni rilevati in Sud Sudan sono allarmanti: il WHO classifica il Sud Sudan al 41&#xB0; 
posto, su 49 paesi africani per copertura di servizi sanitari di contrasto alle NTDs. Per le 5 principali e pi&#xF9; comuni 
NTDs in Sud Sudan (oncocercosi e tracoma, filariasi linfatica, vermi intestinali e schistosomiasi) la prevenzione &#xE8; di primaria importanza: il 90% delle NTDs pu&#xF2; essere infatti trattato con screening e farmaci di base. Nel 
Paese queste patologie infettive colpiscono le persone pi&#xF9; povere e vulnerabili che vivono in contesti di grande 
povert&#xE0; e nelle zone pi&#xF9; remote dove la disponibilit&#xE0; di servizi sanitari, risorse igieniche (acqua pulita, servizi 
igienici) &#xE8; inadeguata. Le NTDs possono aumentare l&#x2019;impatto di altre malattie (malaria, tubercolosi) e se non 
identificate per tempo portano a disabilit&#xE0; permanenti e cecit&#xE0;. 
Oltre alle NTDs, le altre malattie visive (come cataratta, glaucoma) sono le principali cause di disabilit&#xE0; tra la 
popolazione (23,5%). L&#x2019;80% dei casi &#xE8; prevenibile ma se non curate le patologie pi&#xF9; gravi portano a cecit&#xE0; e 
disabilit&#xE0;, il target pi&#xF9; colpito sono le persone pi&#xF9; vulnerabili. 
I bisogni riscontrati nel contesto sud sudanese grazie al need assessment effettuato sul territorio, hanno 
evidenziato 3 principali problematiche legate all&#x2019;alta prevalenza di NTDs e malattie visive che portano a 
disabilit&#xE0; e cecit&#xE0;: a) forte carenza di prevenzione ed educazione sanitaria; b) grave carenza di servizi sanitari 
di base e oculistici; c) totale assenza di servizi specialistici rivolti alle categorie pi&#xF9; vulnerabili. Inoltre, la 
pandemia COVID-19 ha avuto un forte impatto negativo sul sistema sanitario nazionale sulle problematiche 
evidenziate, in particolare sulle categorie pi&#xF9; fragili. 
Nei 3 anni di implementazione previsti dalla proposta, il Soggetto Proponente CBM Italia, in collaborazione con 
CUAMM e CORDAID e i Ministeri della Salute statali, controparti del progetto, intendono potenziare il sistema 
sanitario sud sudanese, lavorando su 3 pilastri strategici: 
&#x2022; l&#x2019;educazione sanitaria e il rafforzamento di pratiche di prevenzione inclusive e contrasto alle NTDs 
nelle comunit&#xE0;, attraverso formazione, sensibilizzazione e interventi di monitoraggio funzionali anche 
al contenimento della pandemia COVID-19. 
&#x2022; il rafforzamento dei servizi sanitari di prossimit&#xE0; con il decentramento e diffusione capillare sul 
territorio di servizi oculistici e di prevenzione inclusivi e accessibili. L&#x2019;intervento &#xE8; in continuit&#xE0; con il 
potenziamento del sistema sanitario governativo iniziato da CBM Italia negli anni precedenti e 
proseguito con CUAMM e CORDAID nel progetto co-finanziato AICS (AID11448), la presente proposta 
vuole migliorare la qualit&#xE0; dei servizi gi&#xE0; presenti e estenderli a nuove aree del Paese.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at improving access to Neglected Tropical Diseases (NTDs) prevention services and Eye Care 
services in a 3-year time span in Central Equatoria, Eastern Equatoria and Lakes States, South Sudan, in line 
with targets 3.3 and 3.8 of Sustainable Development Goal no. 3. 
The proposal is aimed particularly at the most vulnerable categories of the population, such as people with 
disabilities, women and children, and it has been agreed upon directly with the States&#x2019; Ministries of Health, 
partners of the project, thanks to the long-standing presence and expertise of CBM Italy, CUAMM and CORDAID
in the country. These preconditions guarantee the full endorsement of the proposal by government authorities, 
its alignment with the country&apos;s thematic and geographical priorities, and its response to the needs of the area 
of intervention. 
Despite the integration of Neglected Tropical Diseases prevention policies in primary health services, the needs 
identified in South Sudan are still alarming: the WHO ranks South Sudan 41st out of 49 African countries in terms 
of coverage of health services to contrast NTDs. The 5 main and most common NTDs in the country 
(onchocerciasis and trachoma, lymphatic filariasis, intestinal worms and schistosomiasis) can be easily treated, 
and prevention is of utter importance: 90% of NTDs can be treated with basic medicines and simple screening. 
In the country, these infectious diseases affect the poorest and most vulnerable people living in severe poverty 
and in remote areas, where the availability of health services, basic hygiene resources (clean water, sanitation) 
is inadequate. NTDs can worsen the impact of other diseases (malaria, tuberculosis) and, if not identified in 
time, lead to permanent disability and blindness. 
In addition to NTDs, visual diseases constitute the majority (23.5%) of the most common causes of disability 
reported among the South Sudanese population; 80% of cases are preventable but, if left untreated, the most 
serious of these diseases can lead to blindness and permanent disability; not surprisingly, the most affected are 
the most vulnerable people. 
The needs identified in the South Sudanese context during the field assessments, highlighted three main 
problems related to the high prevalence of NTDs and visual diseases leading to disability and blindness: a) 
major lack of prevention and health education; b) severe shortage of primary health care and eye care services; 
c) total absence of specialized services addressed to the most vulnerable groups. In addition, the COVID-19 
pandemic had a strong negative impact on the national health system with regard to the above-mentioned
issues and harmed especially the most fragile categories. 
During the 3 years of implementation foreseen by the project proposal, the leading organization CBM Italy, in 
collaboration with CUAMM and CORDAID and the State Ministries of Health, partners of the project, intend to 
stregthen the South Sudanese health system, working on 3 strategic pillars to fight NTDs and promote eye 
health:
- Health education, strengthening inclusive NTDs prevention practices in local communities, 
training, raising awareness and promoting COVID-19 pandemic prevention and containment 
interventions, under the conviction that health promotion is key to monitoring and 
containment. 
- Strengthening community health services with continued decentralization and dissemination 
of inclusive and accessible Eye Care and prevention services. The diffusion of proximity health 
services is in continuity with the strengthening of the South Sudanese health system initiated 
by CBM Italy in previous years and continued with CUAMM and CORDAID in the project cofunded by AICS (AID11448), improving the quality of the already existing services and extending 
them to new areas of the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBM ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/01/6" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="12230" percentage="34" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic health infrastructure</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="23" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="43" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.8" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve universal health coverage, including financial risk protection, access to quality essential health-care services and access to safe, effective, quality and affordable essential medicines and vaccines for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-11">2558703.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBM ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">1535221.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBM ITALIA ONLUS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
