<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2019000622</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Europe Energy Efficiency and Environment Partnership Fund</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Energiatehokkuus- ja ymparistokumppanuusrahasto E5P</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Euroopan jalleenrakennus- ja kehityspankin (EBRD) hallinnoima Energiatehokkuus- ja ymparistokumppanuusrahasto (E5P) toimii  EU:n itaisissa kumppanuusmaissa. Suomen rahoitus rahastolle on miljoona euroa ja se kohdistuu Armeniaan Azerbaidzhaniin Georgiaan Mo
ldovaan ja Valko-Venajaan.  Rahaston kautta Suomi on aikaisemmin tukenut myos Ukrainaa kahdella miljoonalla eurolla.E5P-rahasto tukee kunnallisia investointeja jotka lisaavat energiatehokkuutta tukevat uusiutuvaa energiaa ja parantavat ympariston tilaa. Ha
nkkeet liittyvat myos kaupunkiliikenteeseen katuvalaistukseen jatehuoltoon seka veteen ja jateveteen. Rahasto perustettiin Ruotsin vuonna 2009 tekeman aloitteen pohjalta. Sen paaoma on nykyaan yli 200 miljoonaa euroa ja suurimmat rahoittajat ovat EU ja Ruo
tsi. E5P on ainutlaatuinen sen vuoksi etta hankkeita vastaanottavat maat osallistuvat rahoitukseen. Heinakuussa 2019 julkistetussa evaluaatiossa todettiin rahaston olevan merkittava rahoitusinstrumentti itaisen kumppanuuden maissa. Rahasto on pystynyt vahe
ntamaan hiilipaastoja ja lisaamaan energiatehokkuutta. Hankkeissa on ollut 8 miljoonaa hyodynsaajaa ja hiilidioksidin paastovahenema miljoona tonnia vuodessa. Alussa hitaasti alkaneet maksatukset ovat kasvaneet merkittavasti.Rahaston toimintaa on paatetty 
jatkaa seuraavalle 10-vuotiskaudelle. Lontoon rahoittajakokouksessa 22.11.2019 EU lupasi jatkolle 20 M? Ruotsi 18 M? ja Norja miljoona euroa. Useat maat ilmoittivat olevansa kiinnostuneita jatkorahoituksesta.E5P tarjoaa alkupaaoman hankkeille joita sitten 
rahoittavat kansainvaliset rahoituslaitokset kuten EBRD Euroopan investointipankki (EIB) Pohjoismaiden ymparistorahoitusyhtio (Nefco) ja Euroopan neuvoston kehityspankki (CEB). EBRD noudattaa toukokuussa 2019 vuosikokouksessa paatettyja hyvan hallinnon pol
itiikkoja jotka ovat ymparisto- ja sosiaalipolitiikka paasy tietoihin ja hankkeiden vastuullisuuspolitiikka. Niissa on kattavasti huomioitu myos syrjaytyneet ryhmat. Hanke tukee kehityspolitiikan painopistealuetta 4 ?Ilmastonmuutos ja luonnonvarat? ja erit
yisesti ilmastonmuutoksen hillintaa.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Eastern Europe  Energy Efficiency and Environmental Partnership Fund (E5P) managed by the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) operates in the EU&apos;s eastern partner countries. Finland&apos;s funding for the Fund is EUR 1 million and target
s Armenia Azerbaijan Georgia Moldova and Belarus. Through the Fund Finland has also supported Ukraine with EUR 2 million in the past. The E5P fund supports municipal investments that increase energy efficiency support renewable energy and improve the state
 of the environment. The projects also relate to urban transport street lighting waste management and water and waste water.  The Fund was set up on the basis of an initiative taken by Sweden in 2009. Its capital today exceeds EUR 200 million and the large
st financiers are the EU and Sweden. E5P is unique because the countries receiving projects are contributing to the funding.   The evaluation published in July 2019 found the Fund to be a major financial instrument in the Eastern Partnership countries. The
 Fund has been able to reduce carbon emissions and increase energy efficiency. The projects have had 8 million beneficiaries and a reduction in CO2 emissions of one million tonnes per year. In the beginning slow-starting payments have increased significant
ly. It has been decided to extend the fund&apos;s activities for the next 10 years. At the London Donors&apos; meeting on 22 November 2019 the EU pledged 20 M? Sweden EUR 18 million and Norway EUR 1 million. Several countries expressed an interest in further funding
. E5P provides initial capital for projects then financed by International Financial Institutions such as the EBRD the European Investment Bank (EIB) the Nordic Environmental Finance Corporation (Nefco) and the Council of Europe Development Bank (CEB).  Th
e EBRD will implement Good Governance Policies accepted at the Annual Meeting in May 2019 which are Environmental and Social Policy Access to Information and Project Accountability Policy. Policies also take full account marginalized groups. The project su
pports priority 4 Climate change and natural resources of Finnish development policy in particular climate change mitigation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="46016" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Euroopan jalleenrakennus- ja kehityspankki - technical co-operation and special funds (ODA-eligible</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development ? technical co-operation and special funds (ODA-eli</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2019000622" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-04-06" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Eastern Europe"></location>
  <sector code="23183" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the main priority area in this act
ivity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="11" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="7" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">1000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">1000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">1000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2019000622" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
