<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020- 2020000108</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH and Grow! - Ecological sanitation in Kenya</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">WASH and Grow! - Puhdasta kasvua Keniassa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">WASH and Grow! -hanke parantaa sanitaatio- ja hygieniaolosuhteita seka edistaa kestavaa maanviljelya Keniassa. Hanke tuo yhteen innovatiivisen ryhman toimijoita: 24 rekisteroitynytta naisryhmaa (community-based self-help group) Keniasta Mifuko Trust ry:n R
eilun kaupan design-yritys Mifuko Oy:n sanitaatioasiantuntija Kaymalaseura Huussi ry:n ja kestavan rakentamisen asiantuntija Ukumbi ry:n.Hankkeella halutaan puuttua puutteellisiin sanitaatio- ja hygieniolosuhteisiin seka maaperan huonontumiseen joka haitta
a viljelya. Nama ongelmat lisaavat sairastelua ja heikentavat ruokaturvaa joka johtaa koyhyyden lisaantymiseen ja toimeentulon menetyksiin. Hankkeen ensisijaisia edunsaajia ovat 715 naista jotka ovat 24 naisryhman jasenia Keski-Kenian syrjaisella maaseudul
la. Toissijaiset edunsaajat ovat heidan perheitaan jotka hyotyvat hankkeen eduista ja ovat osa sen taytantoonpanoa. Hankkeen tietotaidosta hyotyvat myos perheiden yhteisot jonka odotetaan parantavan terveytta ja elinkeinoa koko alueella.Hankkeen tarkeimmat
 tuotokset ovat:1. Naisryhmien jasenten ja heidan yhteisonsa sanitaatio- ja hygieniaolosuhteet paranevat ja he ovat terveempia mika parantaa heidan mahdollisuuksiaan tyoskennella viljella ja osallistua yhteiskuntaan.2. Maaperan laatu paranee sadot suurenev
at ja ravinto paranee mika tukee ilmastonmuutokseen sopeutumista.3. Ekologinen sanitaatio tuo uusia tulonlahteita edunsaajille.Hankkeen tarkeimmat toiminnot ovat:? 24 sanitaatiolahettilaan koulutus? 24 tyopajaa ekologisen kuivakaymalan toimintaideasta erit
teiden kaytosta lannoitteina kasihygieniasta kuukautishygieniasta seka saippuan valmistuksesta? 24 ekologisen kuivakaymalan kayttoliittyman rakentaminen (ks. 17.1)? Kampanjointia ekologisen sanitaation puolesta? Yrittajyyskoulutus lahettilaille ja liiketoi
minnan kehittaminenHanke on kolmevuotinen ja sen aikana on tarkoitus luoda ekologisen sanitaation ymparille yrittajyytta joka takaa toiminnoille jatkuvuutta hankkeen loputtua. Hanke tukee erityisesti kestavan kehityksen tavoitteita 6 (Puhdas vesi ja sanita
atio) ja 5 (sukupuolten valinen tasa-arvo).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wash and Grow! raises awareness about ecological sanitation and creates business opportunities out of it in rural parts of Kenya. The project contributes to healthier communities that have improved living conditions and livelihoods. It brings together a di
verse group of actors: 24 women?s savings groups in Kenya three Finnish NGOs and a company. The implementation of the project is done by women&apos;s groups and Mifuko Trust supported by the expertise of the Global Dry Toilet Association (GDTF) and Ukumbi ry ex
pert in sustainable architecture.The key development problem addressed by the project are poor WASH conditions and degrading soil that hampers small-scale farming. These problems cause ill health and food insecurity that lead to increased poverty and loss 
of livelihoods. The primary beneficiaries of the project are 715 women who are part of 24 self-help groups in 17 remote rural villages in Central Kenya. The secondary beneficiaries are their families and local communities in the area will benefit from the 
know-how which is likely to improve livelihoods in the whole region.The main outcomes of the project will be:1.  Women of self-help groups and their communities improve their hygiene and sanitation and suffer less of illnesses which improves their possibil
ities to work farm and participate in society.2. The quality of soil improves the harvests increase and nutrition improves which supports climate change adaptation 3. Ecological sanitation creates new sources of income for beneficiariesPrincipal activities
 include:? Training of 24 sanitation ambassadors ? 24 workshops on the concept of ecological dry toilets on the use of excreta and urine as fertilizers on hygiene on safe menstruation hygiene and on soap making? Construction of 24 interfaces for ecological
 dry toilets for demonstration (see 17.1)? Awareness raising in communities and to county authorities? Business skills training and business development with beneficiariesThe project is planned to last 3 years during which it aims to create business opport
unities around ecological sanitation. This ensures ownership and sustainability of the project&apos;s outcomes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mifuko Trust ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the main priority area in this act
ivity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">61713</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">50953</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">159199</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
