<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2012000442</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOPAN</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOPAN (Multilateral Organisation Performan&apos;ce Assessment Network) is a network of 19 countries who share a common interest in assessing the effectiveness of the major multilateral organisations that they fund. MOPAN generates collects analyses and presents
 relevant and credible information on the organisational and development effectiveness of multilateral organisations. This knowledge base is intended to contribute to organisational learning within and among multilateral organisations their partners and ot
her stakeholders.MOPAN members increasingly rely on MOPAN data to support their multilateral programming governance and accountability needs. With the help of MOPAN assessments multilateral donors may steer multilateral organisations for instance in their 
governing bodies. MOPAN assessments are conducted according to the MOPAN 3.0 approach that is a rigorous comprehensive and transparent methodology that seeks a holistic understanding of multilateral organisations&apos; systems policies and practices at the glob
al regional and country level. The organisations are assessed against five performance areas: strategic management operational management relationship management performance management and results. For the next Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) 2020-22 mem
bers have agreed to increase the annual contribution to 198 000 EUR/member because of the high expectations e.g. for the quality of assessments require adequate resources. The members also agreed on a shorter duration of the MoU of three years.The recent p
ositive developments of MOPAN has been enabled by the professionalism of its Secretariat and the hosting of the Secretariat at the OECD.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">MOPAN (Multilateral Organisation Performance Assessment Network) on monenkeskisten jarjestojen arviointiverkosto johon kuuluu talla hetkella 19 jasenmaata. Se tukee jaseniaan kehitys- ja humanitaarista rahoitusta saavien monenkeskisten jarjestojen tehokkuu
den arvioimisessa. Jarjestojen tuloksellisuuden vahvistamiseksi verkosto tuottaa kokoaa analysoi ja tuo esille monenkeskisten jarjestojen toimintaa koskevaa keskeista ja luotettavaa tietoa. Tiedon pohjalta halutaan tukea jarjestojen samoin kuin niiden kump
panien ja eri yhteistyotahojen oppimista.MOPAN-arviointien ansiosta Suomella on kaytettavissa ajankohtaista arviointitietoa rahoittamistamme monenkeskisista jarjestoista mika tukee tietoon perustuvaa paatoksentekoa ja monenkeskisen kehitysyhteistyomme vaik
uttavuutta. MOPAN-arvioinnit antavat tietoa Suomen monenkeskisten jarjestojen vaikuttamissuunnitelmien tavoitteiden asettamiseen ja niiden tulosten seurantaan seka tukee Suomen vaikuttamista monenkeskisten jarjestojen toimintaan ja paatoksentekoon jarjesto
jen hallintoelimissa.Arvioinneissa kaytetaan ns. MOPAN 3.0 ?metodologiaa joka pyrkii ymmartamaan monenkeskisten jarjestojen systeemeja politiikkoja ja kaytanteita kokonaisvaltaisesti globaalilla alueellisella ja maatasolla. Metodologiaa tarkistetaan ja pai
vitetaan jatkuvasti sen toimeenpanossa saatujen kokemusten perusteella ja jotta se vastaa mahdollisimman hyvin monenkeskisen jarjestelman ajankohtaisiin haasteisiin.Jasenmaat paatyivat rahoituksen kasvattamiseen 198 000 EUR/vuosi/jasenmaa  tulevalla ohjelm
akaudella 2020-22 johtuen mm. siita etta jasenmaiden odotukset mm. arviointien laadun osalta ovat kasvaneet mika edellyttaa lisaresursseja. Jasenmaat paatyivat myos MOPAN:in ohjelmakauden lyhentamiseen 3 vuoteen (aiemmin 4 vuotta) koska MOPAN:in hallintoma
lli halutaan arvioida uudelleen. Lisaksi MOPAN:sta tehdaan ulkoinen evaluaatio vuosina 2020-21. Tulevan ohjelmakauden jalkeen mm. MOPAN:in rahoitustarve arvioidaan uudelleen.MOPAN:in toiminta ja sen tuloksellisuus on kehittynyt viime vuosina positiivisesti
 minka on mahdollistanut mm. ammattitaitoinen sihteeristo ja OECD:n tuki jonka yhteydessa sihteeristo toimii.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="3" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multilateral Organisation Performance Assessment Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2012000442" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-17" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.16" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">198000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">198000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">198000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">110000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">198000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2012000442" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
