<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2015152843</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid Global Programme 2018-2023 Just and resilient societies</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kirkon Ulkomaanavun Globaaliohjelma 2018-2023 Oikeudenmukaiset ja muutoskykyiset yhteiskunnat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid (FCA) is the largest Finnish development cooperation organisation and the second largest provider of humanitarian assistance. FCA?s new programme continues its long-term work in fragile contexts while at the same time introducing new elemen
ts that make work more contextually relevant and results-oriented. The impact goal for FCA&apos;s programme is derived from our vision: People in fragile contexts are empowered to act for positive and sustainable change in creating resilient and just societies.
  The need to address human rights violations discrimination inequality and exclusion in a comprehensive manner was already part of our work in the previous strategy period and is a fundamental principle of our transformative rights-based thinking.FCA?s pr
ogramme architecture is using four dimensions (sectors themes modalities levels) in a ?whole-of society? logic. Our Theory of Change is structured in a way that it supports civil society governance and private sector interventions. Strongly anchored in the
 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) the programme considers three thematic areas as central to sustainable change. The themes are associated with sets of rights: people have the right to live in peace and acquire quality education and sustainable livelih
oods. To promote positive and sustainable change FCA will work through different modalities namely development cooperation humanitarian aid and advocacy. During the programme period FCA will develop a fourth modality investment. The dimensions are interrel
ated and interdependent and form our holistic programmatic approach which also includes gender equality and inclusion-specific concerns. The realization of these rights is most challenging in fragile contexts; therefore working and being present in such co
ntexts remains a priority. Working on the development and humanitarian nexus also means that we are well positioned to work across funding instruments. FCA puts people?s resilience their wellbeing and the fulfilment of their rights at the center of its wor
k. People globally are on the move. To protect their rights FCA moves with them.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kirkon Ulkomaanapu on Suomen suurin kehitysyhteistyojarjesto ja toiseksi suurin humanitaarisen avun antaja. Ohjelmamme jatkaa Ulkomaanavun pitkajanteista tyota hauraissa ymparistoissa kehittaen edelleen ohjelman laatua ja tuloksellisuutta.Ulkomaanavun ohje
lman pitkan aikavalin tavoiteltu kehitysvaikutus perustuu visioomme: Hauraissa ymparistoissa elavat ihmiset ovat voimaantuneita toimimaan positiivisen ja kestavan muutoksen hyvaksi luoden sopeutumiskykyisia ja oikeudenmukaisia yhteiskuntia. Ulkomaanapu jat
kaa tyotaan ihmisoikeuksien toteutumisen edistamiseksi seka syrjivien kaytantojen ja epaoikeudenmukaisuutta aiheuttavien tekijoiden poistamiseksi. Tavoitteemme on toteuttaa oikeusperustaisuutta mahdollisimman transformatiivisesti.Ohjelmassa hyodynnetaan ne
ljaa ulottuvuutta (sektorit teemat modaliteetit ja tasot). Muutosteoria on jasennelty sektorien kautta (ihmiset ja yksityinen sektori; ihmiset ja hallinto; ihmiset ja kansalaisyhteiskunta). Ulkomaanapu on suunnitellut ohjelmansa hyodyntaen kestavan kehityk
sen tavoitteita (SDGs) ohjaavana viitekehyksena. Kolme teemaamme ovat keskeisia kestavalle muutokselle ja liittyvat yksilon oikeuksiin: kaikilla on oikeus elaa rauhassa saada laadukas koulutus ja hankkia kestava toimeentulo. Edistaakseen myonteista muutost
a Ulkomaanapu toimii eri modaliteettien kautta: kehitysyhteistyo humanitaarinen apu ja vaikuttamistyo. Ohjelmakauden aikana Ulkomaanapu kehittaa neljatta modaliteettia: investointeja. Ohjelman eri ulottuvuudet ovat toisiinsa liittyvia ja toisistaan riippuv
aisia ja muodostavat kokonaisvaltaisen lahestymistavan johon kuuluvat myos sukupuolten valiseen tasa-arvoon tyttojen ja naisten aseman parantamiseen ja yhtalaiseen osallistumiseen liittyvat ulottuvuudet. Naiden oikeuksien toteutuminen on haastavaa etenkin 
hauraissa ymparistoissa joissa tyoskentely ja lasnaolo sailyvat prioriteettina. Ulkomaanavun tyo tukee humanitaarisen tyon ja kehitysyhteistyon valista  linkkia(nexus) mika mahdollistaa myos eri rahoitusinstrumenttien hyodyntamisen. Tyon keskiossa on ihmis
ten kyky selvita katastrofeista (resilience) hyvinvointi ja yksilon oikeuksien toteutuminen. Tyo liittyy yha enemman muuttoliikkeeseen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kirkon Ulkomaanavun saatio</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2015152843" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-03-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Cambodia;Central African Republic;Eritrea;Jordan;K"></location>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights transformative</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeushaasteisiin tarttuva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="9" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">6750000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">6750000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">4400000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2700000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">6750000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2015152843" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
