<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2020200279</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICJ ACHIEVING JUSTICE FOR GROSS HUMAN RIGHTS VIOLATIONS PHASE 2 Global Redress and Accountability through the Rule of Law</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In all regions of the world perpetrators of gross human rights violations continue to enjoy impunity while victims especially the most marginalized and disadvantaged remain without effective remedies and reparation (redress). Building on the ICJ&apos;s MFA-supp
orted project on &apos;Achieving justice for gross human rights violations&apos; (Phase 1) this project aims to deepen the ICJ&apos;s work to enhance the ability of justice actors victims and their representatives and other human rights defenders (HRDs) to seek and provi
de redress and accountability for gross human rights violations (Phase 2). The desired long-term objectives of the project are that in the focus countries (Cambodia Colombia Eswatini Tunisia and Turkey) justice through the rule of law becomes entrenched an
d complied with such that they remain or transform into peaceful and inclusive societies providing access to justice and redress for all holding perpetrators of human rights violations to account and providing effective accountable and inclusive institutio
ns at all levels. The expected outcomes are that: (1) judges prosecutors lawyers and other HRDs in the focus countries are better able to act independently/ and accountably and or to hold perpetrators of human rights violations to account and deliver promp
t and effective justice and redress to victims of human rights violations; (2) victims of human rights violations and abuses in the focus countries and their representatives are better able to demand redress and accountability; and (3) law policy and decis
ion-makers are prompted to align and where necessary reform legal and institutional frameworks in the focus countries in line with international law and standards on redress and accountability and on independence competence and accountability of judges and
 lawyers. The target groups include victims and their representatives judges prosecutors investigators lawyers CSOs and HRDs in the focus countries together with law- and policy-makers and intergovernmental organizations. The final beneficiaries are victim
s of gross human rights violations and their families especially the most marginalized and disadvantaged and all rights-holders in the countries. The project be implemented by the ICJ (https://www.icj.org) with its sister organization ICJ-European Institut
ions working closely with in-country stakeholders.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kaikkialla maailmassa torkeiden ihmisoikeusloukkauksien toteuttajat pysyvat vapaina seuraamuksista samalla kun uhrit erityisesti marginalisoiduimmat ja huono-osaisimmat jaavat ilman tehokasta apua ja korvauksia tai hyvitysta. Hanke jatkaa siita mihin ICJ:n
 aiempi UM:n tukema hanke ?Vakavia ihmisoikeusluokkauksia koskevan rankaisemattomuuden torjunta? jai ja pyrkii syventamaan ICJ:n tyota oikeudellisten toimijoiden uhrien ja heidan edustajiensa seka muiden ihmisoikeuspuolustajien mahdollisuuksien hakea hyvit
ysta ja tilivelvollisuutta ihmisoikeusloukkauksien toteuttajille tukemiseksi. Hanke tavoittelee pitkan tahtaimen tavoitteinaan oikeusvaltion periaatteiden juurtumista ja toteutumista kohdemaiden (Kambod?a Kolumbia Swazimaa Tunisia ja Turkki) muuttamiseksi 
tai pysymiseksi rauhanomaisina ja osallistavina yhteiskuntina jotka tarjoavat paasya oikeusprosesseihin ja hyvityksiin kaikille laittavat ihmisoikeusloukkauksien toteuttajat vastuuseen teoistaan seka pitavat instituutiot tehokkaina vastuullisina seka osall
istavina kaikilla tasoilla. Tavoitellut tulokset ovat etta (1) tuomarit syyttajat juristit ja muut ihmisoikeuspuolustajat kohdemaissa voivat toimia itsenaisemmin ja/tai vastuullisemmin seka tuomaan ihmisoikeuksien loukkaajat vastuuseen teoistaan seka harjo
ittamaan ripeaa ja tehokasta oikeutta seka tarjota hyvitysta ihmisoikeusloukkauksien uhreille; (2) ihmisoikeusloukkauksien uhrit ja heidan edustajansa kohdemaissa pystyvat paremmin vaatimaan hyvitysta ja vastuuta loukkauksista; (3) laki kaytannot ja paatta
jat johdetaan noudattamaan kansainvalista lakia ja standardeja koskien hyvitysta ja vastuullisuutta loukkauksista seka koskien juristien ja tuomarien itsenaisyytta patevyytta ja vastuullisuutta. Kohderyhma sisaltaa uhrit ja heidan edustajansa tuomarit syyt
tajat rikosten tutkijat juristit CSOt ja ihmisoikeuspuolustajat kohdemaissa yhdessa lainsaatajien poliitikkojen ja kansainvalisten jarjestojen kanssa. Lopulliset hyotyjat ovat torkeiden ihmisoikeusloukkauksien uhrit ja heidan perheensa erityisesti marginal
isoiduimmat ja huono-osaisimmat ja kaikki oikeuksien haltijat maissa. Hankkeen toteuttaa ICJ (https://www.icj.org) yhdessa sisarjarjestonsa ICJ-European Institutions kanssa tiiviissa yhteistyossa paikallisten sidosjarjestojen kanssa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Commission of Jurists (ICJ)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights transformative</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeushaasteisiin tarttuva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">400000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
