<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2019190250</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving sexual rights of persons with disabilities in Afghanistan Nepal and Tajikistan</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Vammaisten seksuaalioikeuksien edistaminen Afghanistanissa Nepalissa ja Tajikistanissa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although 15 % of the world?s population live with a disability many of the PwD are marginalized their human rights are violated and their SRHR are not fully recognized. Therefore this project brings together five expert organizations on SRHR and/or disabil
ities in Afghanistan Nepal and Tajikistan to realize the sexual rights of PwD so that they can enjoy dignified lives.The project has five mutually supportive outcomes under the themes of capacity building of beneficiaries changing attitudes advocacy capaci
ty building of SRH service providers and learning. To attain OC1:PwD trainers peer educators and family members are trained and CSOs strengthened; OC2: awareness raising activities are held; OC3): political decision makers? capacity is increased; OC4:servi
ce providers are trained in disability issues; OC5: best practices to improve SRHR of PwD are identified shared and scaled.Gender equality is an inbuilt component of the project. Addressing the rights of WwD and GwD recognizing the multiple forms of discri
mination and mainstreaming gender in disability programming are key priorities. The project advocates for structures and services that are inclusive and accessible to WwD. Climate sustainability is ensured by the climate risk management by the POs. The pri
ncipal premise is reducing discrimination and inequality of PwD; e.g. targeting lack of access to SRH services and societal stigma.The project will be implemented by Vaestoliitto Kynnys MSIA FPAN and Ishtirok. Each partner has strengths and capacity gaps t
hus the core approach of the project is learning and sharing to identify new approaches to pilot and adopt. RBM and project management will be strengthened throughout the project. MSIA and FPAN are strong SRHR actors and Ishtirok?s strength is their expert
ise in PwD issues and advancing SRHR of PwD. Kynnys will strengthen the disability expertise and Vaestoliitto the SRHR expertise of all partners.Immediate beneficiaries will be PwD and their families disabled couples individuals and peer educators decision
 makers and government officials sexual health-care providers CSOs and POs in Afghanistan Nepal and Tajikistan.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Vaikka 15 % maailman ihmisista on vammaisia monet vammaiset ovat marginalisoituja heidan ihmisoikeuksiaan rikotaan eika heidan seksuaalioikeuksiaan tunnusteta. Tama hanke tuo yhteen viisi vammaiskysymysten ja seksuaalioikeuksien asiantuntijajarjestoa Suome
ssa Afganistanissa Nepalissa ja Tadzikistanissa toteuttamaan vammaisten seksuaalioikeuksia.Hankkeella on viisi toisiaan tukevaa tulostavoitetta jotka on teemoiteltu hyodynsaajien kapasiteetin vahvistamisen yleisen asennemuutoksen vaikuttamistyon terveysala
n toimijoiden kapasiteetin vahvistamisen seka oppimisen alle. Paaaktiviteetteja ovat 1) vammaisten kouluttajien vertaistukijoiden ja perheenjasenten kouluttaminen 2) tietoisuuden lisaaminen 3) paatoksentekijoiden kapasiteetin vahvistaminen 4) terveysalan t
oimijoiden kouluttaminen 5) parhaiden kaytantojen jakaminen. Sukupuolten valinen tasa-arvo on hankkeen tarkea komponentti. Naisten ja tyttojen oikeuksien edistaminen ja diskriminaation monimuotoisuuden tunnistaminen ovat hankkeen prioriteetteja. Hanke edis
taa inklusiivisia ja saavutettavia palveluja ja rakenteita. Ilmastokestavyys taataan kumppanijarjestojen riskienhallinnalla. Vammaisten kohtaaman diskriminaation ja epatasa-arvon vahentaminen on hankkeen ytimessa. Hankkeen toteuttavat Vaestoliitto Kynnys M
SIA FPAN ja Ishtirok. Jokaisella kumppanilla on omat vahvuutensa ja oppimistarpeensa ja siksi hankkeessa keskitytaan oppimiseen ja jakamiseen. Tulosohjauskaytantoja ja hankehallintoa vahvistetaan koko hankkeen ajan. MSIA ja FPAN ovat vahvoja seksuaaliterve
ystoimijoita ja Ishtirokin vahvuutena on vammaisosaaminen ja vammaisten seksuaalioikeuksien edistaminen. Vaestoliitto vahvistaa kaikkien kumppaneiden seksuaalioikeusosaamista ja Kynnys kumppaneiden vammaisosaamista. Hankkeen hyodynsaajia ovat vammaiset ja 
heidan perheensa vammaiset parit ja vertaiskouluttajat paatoksentekijat ja viranomaiset seksuaaliterveyspalvelujen henkilokunta vammaisjarjestot seka kumppanijarjestot Afganistanissa Nepalissa ja Tadzikistanissa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vaestoliitto</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2019190250" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Afghanistan;Nepal;Tajikistan"></location>
  <sector code="13030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is the main priority area in this activ
ity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">170000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">170000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">150000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2019190250" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
