<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2020000410</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kuulo- ja nakovammaisten lasten terveyden ja koulukaynnin edistaminen Baran ja Parsan maakunnissa Nepalissa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unlocking doors to basic health and education for children with Sensory disabilities in Bara and Parsa districts of Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Nepal children are not screened for visual or hearing impairments and knowledge of eye- and ear health is generally poor. Having a disability is still greatly stigmatised. Although the majority of children in Nepal have access to education children with
 disabilties (CwD) are mostly excluded from it which is a major risk for marginalisation. The project is a follow-up of a 2-year pilot in Bara district (2017-18) which will be extended in Bara and Parsa. The aim is to increase the enrollment of 3 to 14-yea
r-old children with vision or hearing impairment in public schools. Districts have high rates of poverty and school attendance is very low. Also the human right&apos;s of CwD&apos;s are largely violated. The majority of pupils are boys therefore the project promotes
 girls&apos; right to education. The project will educate female community health volunteers (FCHVs) to identify children with vision or hearing issues. The children identified through screening are examined at Eye + Ear Camps to diagnose the impairments found.
 It is estimated that the most of these impairments can be easily cured with simple treatments. Children with a severe visual or hearing disability will undergo a 4-6 month rehabilitation to enable life outside home and attending school. Awareness raising 
campaigns regarding eye- and ear health as well as rights of persons with disabilities (PwD) will be organised among local citizens during the camps. Advocacy on inclusive education and human rights of CwD will be promoted. Eye + ear care and rehabilitatio
n centers will be established in Bara. The local project partner is B. P. Eye Foundation (BPEF) that has 3 decades of experience in rehabilitation of CwDs and training of ophtalmologists and optometrists. For improved access to treatment and rehabilitation
 and to increase awareness on human rights gender equality and inclusive education the project will strengthen the collaboration with other NGO&apos;s: IMPACT Nepal Nepal Association for the Welfare of the Blind Nepal Apanga Sewa sangh Bara and Loo Niva. A refe
rral system will be developed with Patan CBR to reach a larger scale of PwD&apos;s. In Finland we will collaborate with Interpedia ry.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Nepalissa lasten kuuloa tai nakoa ei seulota rutiinisti ja tietoisuus kuulon ja naon terveydesta on heikkoa. Vammaisuuteen liittyy suuri stigma ja nako- ja kuulovammaiset lapset jaavat edelleen vaille koulutusta ja ovat suuressa syrjaytymisriskissa. Hankke
en tavoitteena on lisata tietoisuutta naon ja kuulon terveydesta seka edesauttaa kuulo- ja nakovammaisten 3-14-vuotiaiden lasten mahdollisuuksia koulunkayntiin Baran ja Parsan maakunnissa Etela-Nepalissa. Talla alueella koulua kaymattomien lasten osuus on 
suuri ja vaesto on koyhaa. Suurin osa alueen koululaisista on poikia ja hankkeen kautta tuetaan myos tyttojen tasa-arvoista oikeutta koulunkayntiin. Hanke toimii vuosina 2017-2018 toteutetun hankkeen jatkona. Uudessa hankkeessa koulutetaan vapaaehtoisia te
rveyssisaria tunnistamaan lapsia joilla on kuulon tai naon ongelmia. Seulonnoissa loydetyt lapset lahetetaan leireille joissa lapset tutkitaan tarkemmin. Suurimmalla osalla identifioiduista lapsista arvioidaan olevan sellaisia kuulon tai naon ongelmia jotk
a ovat hoidettavissa yksinkertaisin hoidoin. Osalla lapsista on kuitenkin vaikea kuulo- tai nakovamma jonka vuoksi he tarvitsevat erillisen 4-6 kuukauden pituisen hoito- ja kuntoutusjakson kodin ulkopuolisen elaman ja koulunkaynnin mahdollistamiseksi. Leir
ien yhteydessa alueen asukkaille jarjestetaan tietoiskuja kuulon ja naon terveydesta ja vammaisten lasten oikeuksista. Lisaksi paikallisille vaikuttajille jarjestetaan tiedotustilaisuuksia vammaisten lasten oikeuksista. Projekti keskittyy myos opettajien j
a perheenjasenten kouluttamiseen vammaisten oikeuksista ja tuen tarpeesta. Baraan perustetaan naon ja kuulon hoitokeskus seka kuntoutuskeskus. Paikallisena yhteistyokumppanina toimii B. P. Eye Foundation-jarjesto jolla on vuosikymmenien kokemus aistivammai
sten lasten kuntouttamisesta ja silmalaakarien ja optikoiden kouluttamisesta. Vammaisten oikeuksia kuntoutusta ja inklusiivista koulutusta koskevan tietoisuuden lisaamiseksi paikallisina yhteistyokumppaneina toimivat IMPACT Nepal Nepal Association for the 
Welfare of the Blind Nepal Apanga Sewa sangh Bara ja Loo Niva. Yhteistyo Patan CBR-jarjeston kanssa tavoittaa laajempia vammaisryhmia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laakarin Sosialinen Vastuu ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2099-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">125000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">460000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
