<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2018180073</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">ODF2030 ? Kestavan sanitaation kehityshanke Ghanassa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ODF2030 ? Sustainable sanitation for Ho Municipality Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">ODF2030 ? Kestavan sanitaation kehityshanke Ghanassa lisaa Hon kunnan paikallishallinnon ja instituutioiden kapasiteettia seka mobilisoi asukkaita sanitaatiotavoitteiden saavuttamiseksi. Hankkeen tavoitteet on linjattu kansallisten ja alueellisten kehityss
trategioiden seka YK:n kestavan kehityksen tavoitteiden mukaisesti. Talla hetkella alle 20 prosenttia Hon vaestosta on kehittyneiden sanitaatiopalveluiden piirissa ja avoimeen maastoon ulostaminen (Open Defecation) on yleista. Tama aiheuttaa merkittavan ri
skin asukkaiden terveydelle ja ymparistolle. Hanke tukee paikallishallinnon toteuttamia ECOSAN -kampanjoita kaupunki- ja maaseutualueilla. ECOSAN -ratkaisut parantavat hygieniaa ja terveytta lisaavat ruokaturvaa ja vahentavat koyhyytta orgaanisten lannoitt
eiden kayton kautta seka parantavat ympariston tilaa ja vahentavat kasvihuonekaasupaastoja. Hankkeen toimenpiteet kohdistuvat kaikkiin neljaan Suomen kehityspolitiikan painopistealueeseen. Naiset ja tytot ovat projektin paakohderyhmia. Paikallisten kumppan
eiden kapasiteetin vahvistaminen sisaltaa mm. peruskartoituksia koulutuksia alueellisten sidosryhmien dialogia pilotteja vertaisarviointeja seka toiminnan tuloksellisuuden arviointeja.  ECOSAN -kampanjoiden seurauksena yksityiset sanitaatioinvestoinnit lis
aantyvat saadaan 14 uutta Open Defecation Free (ODF) ?statuksen saanutta kylaa seka 16 kylaa ja 2 asuinaluetta tuottavat ja hyodyntavat orgaanisia lannoitteita. Keskeisimmat tuotokset sisaltavat kurssit kouluttajien kouluttamiseksi vuosittaiset sidosryhmaf
oorumit ja yleisotilaisuudet teknologia- ja palvelupilotit seka ECOSAN liiketoimintamallit. ODF2030 ?hankkeen suoria hyodynsaajia ovat Ho Municipal Assembly ja Ho Technical University joita tuetaan myos alueellisessa verkostoitumisessa. Muita suoria hyodyn
saajia ovat ECOSAN ?kampanjoihin osallistuvat kylat ja kaupunkialueet. Hon paikalliset kumppanit ovat sitoutuneita edistamaan ECOSAN ?ratkaisuja joita on jo pilotoitu kouluissa seka maaseudun kotitalouksissa osana Hon ja Lahden kaupungin pitkaaikaista kunt
ayhteistyota. Kaymalaseura Huussi ry seka Lahden ja Jyvaskylan ammattikorkeakoulut tuovat kukin projektiin omaa erityisosaamistaan.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ODF2030 ?Sustainable sanitation for Ho Municipality Ghana ? project empowers and capacitates public authorities and institutions and mobilises the citizens for the achievement of total sanitation in line with Ho local development strategies and UN SDG&apos;s (e
specially SDG 6). Current level of access to improved sanitation in Ho is less than 20 per cent and open defecation is prevalent which is causing severe threat on people&apos;s health and environment.  ODF2030 will ensure that public authorities can effectively
 implement ECOSAN campaigns in urban and rural areas. The ECOSAN solutions not only improve hygiene and health but also create opportunities for improved food security and poverty reduction through organic fertiliser use improves state of environment and d
iminish greenhouse gas emissions. Project includes activities within all Finland&apos;s 4 priority areas as well as improve gender and equality since women and girls are the main target groups. The capacity building is a continuous process that includes eg. bas
eline studies training courses regional stakeholder dialogue pilots peer learning and evaluations.As a result of ECOSAN campaigns we expect to see increased private investments to sanitation 14 new rural communities with Open Defecation Free (ODF) status a
s well as 16 communities and 2 peri-urban housing areas mobilized for production and use of organic fertilisers. Main outputs of ODF2013 include train-the-trainers courses annual stakeholder forums and public awareness events technology and service pilots 
and a feasibility study for ECOSAN business model. ODF2030 benefits directly the Ho Municipal Assembly and Ho Technical University and supports teaming up with institutions like the CWS Agency of Volta for reaching total sanitation. Other direct beneficiar
ies include the communities involved in ECOSAN campaigns. The partners in Ho are committed to the promotion of ECOSAN solutions following the local government cooperation with the City of Lahti that has involved several pilots for schools and rural househo
lds.To ensure availability of diverse expertise needed GDTF LAMK and JAMK opted to join forces in implementing the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaymalaseura Huussi ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2018180073" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights transformative</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeushaasteisiin tarttuva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the main priority area in this act
ivity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">80000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">80000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2018180073" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
