<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2018180293</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ch&apos;ama warmi strong woman: reinforcing Aymara-women&apos;s political social and economic rights in the Bolivian Altiplano</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ch&apos;ama warmi: Aymara-naisten poliittisen sosiaalisen ja taloudellisen aseman vahvistaminen Bolivian Altiplanolla</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Hanke Ch&apos;ama warmi: Aymara-naisten poliittisen sosiaalisen ja taloudellisen aseman vahvistaminen Bolivian tasangolla on kaksivuotinen ja sen hyodynsaajat ovat naiset seuraavista Aymara-yhteisoista: Jucuri Ninacho Pastogrande Pizacavina Caluyo and Jucumarca
. Hankkeen kautta naiset saavat yhtaalta ammattikoulutusta seka tyokaluja kehittamaan viljelytuotantoaan ja toisaalta tukea ja koulutusta omien pienhankkeiden suunnitteluun kansalaisjarjestojen perustamiseen ja pyorittamiseen seka rahoituksen hakemiseen. N
aisten saama koulutus ja sen ansiosta kasvava tuotanto parantaa heidan taloudellista samoin kuin sosiaalista asemaansa yhteisoissaan. Hanke tavoittelee seuraavat konkreettiset tulokset:- Naisjarjestojen perustaminen: jokaiseen yhteisoon on perustettu naisj
arjesto jolla on oikeudellinen asema on demokraattisesti johdettu ja pystyy pyorittamaan pienhankkeita yhteison hyvaksi.- Aymara-naiset kehittavat osaamistaan viljelytuotannossa mika nostaa heidan tulojaan ja vahvistaa asemaansa yhteisoissa.Hankkeen paatoi
minnot ovat seuraavat:- Seminaarit ihmisoikeuksista ja tasa-arvosta. - Koulutustilaisuudet naisjarjestojen perustamiseksi ja johtamiseksi. Tilaisuuksia seuraa jatkuvaa asiantuntijoiden tarjoama tuki ja ohjaus.- Seminaareja pienhankkeiden toteuttamisesta.- 
Koulutusseminaareja viljelytuotannosta joissa tehostetaan tuotantoa kymmenessa eri viljelylajissa. Seminaarit sisaltavat koulutusta kestavasta tuotannosta jalostamisesta pakkaamisesta brandayksesta myynnista osallistumisen paikallisiin markkinatapahtumiin 
yms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two-year project to help Aymara women from 6 communities: Jucuri Ninacho Pastogrande Pizacavina Caluyo and Jucumarca. The beneficiaries will be provided with tools such as greenhouses that enhance their production possibilities. They will receive training 
in agriculture that improves their autonomy social role and environmental sustainability. The women will take part in workshops about running associations designing and implementing micro-projects applying for funds and making agreements. Planned Results:R
1. Creating Women&apos;s Associations (WA) that are legally established democratically organized and can run micro-projects. R2. Aymara women get competences in agriculture production that reinforce their social status. Activities by result:R1.A1. Workshops abo
ut human rights and gender equality. Topics include equality self-esteem leadership legal resources against domestic violence negotiation and fair division of responsibilities in the family.R1.A2. Workshops to form legally established Women&apos;s Associations.
 Supervised by legal experts that help designing statutes and rules registering the association. We will also support the WA&apos;s leaders to learn to run manage and organize the associations. R1.A3. Training about designing and implementing micro-projects. R2
.A1. Training in agricultural practices. The aim is to foster 10 concrete agricultural practices that aim to foster production and environmental sustainability.R2.A2. Workshops to improve marketing of products and designing new brand for their products. R2
.A3. Participation in Agricultural Meetings in the Urban and Suburban area and making contracts with firms and distributors to access new markets.R2.A4. Trainings in processing of vegetables I II and III.R2.A5. Introduction of new products to the market.AY
MI&apos;s Project Coordinator will be in charge distributing the materials hiring personnel and services keeping contact with the Women&apos;s Associations and local authorities. Inter-Cultur will monitor and support from Finland and through annual visits.These skil
ls together with the fact that distributed materials and competences are durable guarantee sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-Cultur ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2018180293" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights transformative</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeushaasteisiin tarttuva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the secondary priority area in t
his activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is the main priority area in this activ
ity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">51000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">51000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2018180293" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
