<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2019190746</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kauppa ja kehitys: Suunnittelu seuranta ja vaikuttaminen</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade and Development: Planning Monitoring and Influencing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Hankkeen paatavoite on tukea kauppapolitiikan ja -hallinnon kehittamista kehitysmaissa. Hankkeen valiton tavoite on edistaa Suomen monenkeskisen kauppaa tukevan kehitysyhteistyon suunnittelua seurantaa ja vaikuttamista. Hankkeesta voidaan rahoittaa:1) kaup
an ja kehityksen ml. kehitysmaiden kauppapolitiikan kiertotalouden ja yritysvastuun alaan kuuluvia tapahtumia joissa Suomi voi olla jarjestelyvastuussa yhdessa muiden toimijoiden kanssa ml. EU-puheenjohtajuuskauden aikaiset tapahtumat;2) kehitysmaiden edus
tajien tai kansainvalisten puhujien matkakuluja tarkeisiin kansainvalisiin kaupan ja kehityksen seka kauppapoliittisiin tapahtumiin;3) kehitysmaiden kauppapolitiikkaan ja talouteen ml. kiertotalouteen liittyvia selvityksia tutkimuksia ja seurantamatkoja;4)
 Suomen rahoittamien monenkeskisten kauppa ja kehitys -jarjestojen hankkeiden ja ohjelmien evaluaatioita seka hankkeiden ja ohjelmien suunnitteluun seurantaan ja vaikuttamiseen liittyvia matkoja.Hanke vahvistaa Suomen monenkeskisten ja kansainvalisten vaik
uttamistavoitteiden saavuttamista esimerkiksi avoimen vakaan ja kestavan kauppajarjestelman vahvistamista seka tuo kansainvalista nakyvyytta ml. EU-puheenjohtajuuskaudella. Hanke tukee kehitysmaiden osallistumismahdollisuuksia monenkeskisiin ja kansainvali
siin kauppaneuvotteluprosesseihin ja korkean tason poliittisiin asiantuntijatapahtumiin. Hanke tuo arvokasta informaatiota seka korkealta poliittiselta etta tekniselta tasolta kehitysmaiden kauppapolitiikasta kauppaneuvotteluista taloudellisesta integraati
osta ja taloudellisesta kehityksesta. Hanke mahdollistaa lisaksi Suomen tukemien monenkeskisten kaupan ja kehityksen jarjestojen kanssa tehtavan tulevaisuuden yhteistyon seka paremman seurannan ja vaikuttamisen Suomen tavoitteiden mukaisesti.Hankkeesta mah
dollisesti tehtavat hankinnat ovat rahallisesti kooltaan pienia alle suorahankinnan rajan jaavia selvitystyyppisia hankintoja.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the project is to support the development of trade policy and administrative management in developing countries. The immediate objective of the project is to advance the planning monitoring and influencing of Finland&apos;s multilateral Ai
d for Trade. Potential components to be financed from the project may include:1) Workshops and conferences in the field of trade and development incl. trade policy circular economy of developing countries and corporate responsibility in which Finland may h
ave a co-organizing role together with other actors incl. events during Finland&apos;s EU Presidency;2) Travel expenses of developing country representatives or international speakers to international events in the field of trade and development as well as trad
e policy;3) Papers research and monitoring missions of the developing countries&apos; trade policy and economy incl. circular economy;4) Evaluations as well as travel expenses of the planning monitoring and influencing missions related to the Finnish funded pro
jects and programs of the multilateral trade and development organizations.The project helps to achieve Finland&apos;s multilateral and international influencing objectives e.g. strengthening of open stable and sustainable trading system and brings internationa
l visibility incl. during Finland&apos;s EU Presidency. The project improves the participation of developing countries in multilateral and international trade policy negotiation processes and high-level political expert events. The project gathers valuable info
rmation on the trade policy trade negotiations economic integration and economic development of developing countries both from the high political and technical levels. In addition the project improves the future cooperation with as well as the monitoring a
nd influencing of the Finnish funded multilateral trade and development organizations in accordance with Finland&apos;s objectives.Potential procurements will be of minor financial value such as small research papers remaining well below the limit of direct pro
curement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor Government</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Suomen julkinen sektori</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2019190746" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-20" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Developing countries"></location>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ei maaritelty</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not defined</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muut momentit</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other budget lines</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="12.C" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="13.B" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="17" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">31891</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2019190746" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
