<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-1999993693</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Children hold the Future!</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tavoitteena tulevaisuus ? turvallinen koulutuspolku ja elinymparisto lapsille ja nuorille</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida?s 2018?2021 development cooperation programme Children hold the Future! consists of 17 country programmes that are implemented with local partners in Eastern Africa Asia and the Middle-East. The Programme also includes a project in Finland which compr
ises of development communication global education and advocacy components. In addition planning and evaluation projects support the Programme.The long-term impact of the Programme is Increased justice and strengthened human dignity of children and peace i
n the programme countries. The outcomes for the Programme are: 1) Increased fulfilment of the rights of children to health education and adequate living standards in Fida?s programme countries including the crosscutting objectives: 1a) Improved equity of w
omen and vulnerable groups especially people living with disabilities and 1b) Improved environmental sustainability and coping with climate change.2) Increased capacity of Fida?s partners to advocate for the rights of children to health education and adequ
ate living standards.3) Increased awareness and willingness of Finnish civil society and decision-makers to influence the fulfilment of children?s rights in Fida?s programme countries.The country programmes focus on three rights of children: health educati
on and adequate standard of living. The programmes strengthen the advocacy financial and administrative capacity of partners. The rights-holders and the duty-bearers take part in every stage from planning to implementation. Change is measured on individual
 civil society and state administrative levels. The main beneficiaries are children and youth as rights-holders. To fulfil their rights action is directed at the duty-bearers which include parents teachers health care workers and government authorities. Th
e Programme supports open and equal dialogue between the state and civil society. There are about 290 000 direct beneficiaries in the Programme of which 155 000 are children and youth and 14 000 people living with disabilities. About 53 million people are 
estimated to benefit from the Programme indirectly.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Fidan kehitysyhteistyoohjelma 2022-2025 ?Tavoitteena tulevaisuus ? turvallinen koulutuspolku ja elinymparisto lapsille ja nuorille? muodostuu 11 maaohjelmasta joita toteutetaan paikallisten kumppaneiden kanssa Itaisessa Afrikassa Aasiassa ja Lahi-idassa se
ka Kotimaan ohjelmasta johon sisaltyy kehitysviestinta globaalikasvatus ja vaikuttamistyo.Ohjelman pitkan aikavalin kehitystavoite on Lasten ja nuorten parantuneet mahdollisuudet koulutukseen ja turvallisempi elinymparisto ohjelmamaissa.Ohjelman valittomat
 tavoitteet ovat1) Lasten ja nuorten erityisesti tyttojen ja vammaisten lasten oikeus koulutukseen ja sen toteutuminen on vahvistunutFida International | Ohjelmamuotoisen kehitysyhteistyon valtionavustushaun 2022-2025 vaihe 2.2) Lasten ja nuorten erityises
ti tyttojen ja vammaisten lasten oikeudet turvallisen elinymparistonsaavuttamiseksi ja niiden toteutuminen ovat vahvistuneet3) Kumppaniorganisaatioiden hallinto- ja talouskaytanteet ovat parantuneet ja heidan sitoutumisensatoimia innovatiivisesti lasten ja
 nuorten erityisesti tyttojen ja vammaisten lasten oikeuksientoteutumiseksi on vahvistunut.4) Kotimaan ohjelman kohderyhmien lisaantynyt sitoutuminen edistaa lasten oikeuksia laadukkaaseenkoulutukseen ja turvalliseen elinymparistoon globaalisti.Maaohjelmis
sa keskitytaan lapsen oikeuksiin saada koulutusta seka liittyen turvalliseen elinymparistoon.Koulutus keskittyy laadukkaan ja inklusiivisen opetuksen kehittamiseen informaaliin ja jatkuvaanoppimiseen. Turvallinen elinymparisto huomioi henkilokohtaisen yhte
ison ja terveydellisenturvallisuuden seka ruoka- ja taloudellisen turvan. Lapileikkaavat tavoitteet gender vammaiset henkilotseka ymparisto ja ilmastokestavyys ovat osa jokaista teemaa.Oikeuksienhaltijat ja vastuunkantajat ovat osallisena Ohjelmassa suunni
ttelusta toteuttamiseen.Paahyodynsaajina ovat lapset ja nuoret oikeuksienhaltijoina joiden oikeuksien toteutumiseksi toimintojakohdistetaan myos vastuunkantajiin ml. vanhemmat opettajat ja viranomaiset. Ohjelma tukee avointaja tasa-arvoista valtion ja kans
alaisyhteiskunnan vuoropuhelua. Valittomia hyodynsaajia on n. 484 000joista lapsia ja nuoria 269 000 ja vammaisia henkiloita 32 300. Valillisia hyodynsaajia arvioidaan olevan 35miljoonaa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida International ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-1999993693" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-03-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Afghanistan;Bangladesh;Bhutan;Burundi;Cambodia;Eth"></location>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ei maaritelty</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not defined</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is the main priority area in this activ
ity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.3" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">5600000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">5600000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">7100000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">1800000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">13828</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-1999993693" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
