<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2015150163</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP: Building Resilience in Response to the Syrian Crisis</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">UNDP: Paikallisyhteisojen kantokyvyn vahvistaminen Syyriassa ja sen naapurimaissa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Syyrian konflikti on aiheuttanut valtavan humanitaarisen kriisin vaikuttaen miljoonien ihmisten elamaan. Yhteisojen kantokyky eli resilienssi on koetuksella Syyriassa ja sen naapurimaissa. Myos haavoittuvassa asemassa olevien vammaisten ihmisten maara on k
asvanut konfliktin vuoksi. Syyriassa arvioidaan olevan 2.8 miljoonaa vammaisiksi luokiteltavaa ihmista.Suomi tukee Syyrian kriisista karsivien yhteisojen ja Syyrian naapurimaiden resilienssin vahvistamista Suomen Syyrian ja Irakin kriiseja koskevan apustra
tegian (2017?2020) painopisteiden mukaisesti. Suomi on tukenut etenkin YK:n kehitysjarjeston UNDP:n toimintaa resilienssi-ajattelun valtavirtaistamisessa YK:n toimintaan. Nyt alkava hanke on jatkoa Suomen tukemalle UNDP:n resilienssityolle ja etenkin vamma
isten oikeuksien edistamiselle Syyriassa. UNDP?Syyrian toteuttama osuus hankkeesta tukee syyrialaisyhteisojen kantokykya edistamalla vammaisten toimintamahdollisuuksia kuntoutuksen psyko-sosiaalisen tuen tyollistymismahdollisuuksien ja tietoisuuden lisaami
sen kautta. Suomen tuella yllapidetaan keskuksia jotka tuottavat vammaisille palveluita kuten apulaitteita ja terapiapalveluita. Erityishuomiota kiinnitetaan vammautuneiden naisten tukemiseen. Suomen tuella on aiemmin tyollistetty Syyriassa tuhansia haavoi
ttuvassa asemassa olevia nuoria seka autettu tuhansia vammaisia. Esimerkiksi vuoden 2018 aikana Suomen tuella autettiin 1035 vammaista parantamalla naiden osallistumisedellytyksia yhteiskuntaan ja tukemalla heidan elinkeinojaan.Hankkeen rahoitus tulee Afri
kan ja Lahi-Idan osaston vuoden 2019 valtuuksista vuosille 2020 ja 2021. Hankkeen 4 MEUR budjetti kanavoidaan UNDP Syyrialle vammaisten oikeuksia edistavan hankkeen toteutukseen vuosina 2020?2021.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Syrian conflict has created a huge humanitarian catastrophe affecting the lives of millions of people. The resilience  of people is under extreme pressure in Syria and its neighbouring countries. People with disabilities are amongst the most vulnerable
 groups within the society. As a result of the conflict the number of PWD&apos;s has increased dramatically. It is estimated that around 28 million peoplein Syria suffer from different sorts and levels of disability.Finland supports the resilience of communitie
s affected by the conflict in both Syria as well as in neighbouring countries as outlined in the Strategy for Development Cooperation and Humanitarian aid in response to the conflicts in Syria and Iraq. Finland has supported the work of the UNDP in mainstr
eaming resilience-thinking into the work of the UN.This project is set to continue Finland&apos;s support for the resilience work with a specific focus on the rights of PWD&apos;s. This is done by supporting the resilience of communities within Syria through support
 to PWD&apos;s such as physical rehabilitation psychosocial support and the provision of prosthetic services and disability aids. In addition the project aims to improve the socioeconomic integration of PWD&apos;s through livelihood support and the promotion of acce
ss to labour market basic services. A special target group of the project are women with disabilities as well as women-led households that include PWD&apos;s. In 2018 over 1000 Syrian PWD&apos;s benefitted from Finland&apos;s support.The overall budget of the 2-year proj
ect is 4 million Eurowhich will be allocated to the PWD work of UNDP Syria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n kehitysohjelma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2015150163" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="74020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2015150163" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
