<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2020000003</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowerment and Social Justice for Roma Women</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Romaninaisten vaikutusmahdollisuudet ja sosiaalinen oikeudenmukaisuus</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Hankkeen ensisijainen kehityspoliittinen painopistealue on ?Naisten ja tyttojen oikeudet ja asema vahvistuneet.? Kehitysongelma johon hanke pureutuu on romanityttojen ja -naisten moniperustainen syrjinta Kosovon yhteiskunnassa: romaninaiset kohtaavat arjes
saan syrjintaa sukupuolensa etnisyytensa ja taloudellisen tilanteensa vuoksi.Hankkeen lapileikkaavana tavoitteena on lisata paikallisen kumppanin ja kansalaisyhteiskunnan osaamista sukupuolten tasa-arvon valtavirtaistamisessa. Taman lisaksi hankkeen tavoit
teina on 1) vahentaa romanityttojen koulupudokkuutta 2) edistaa romaninaisten tyollistymismahdollisuuksia 3) lisata tyovoimaviranomaisten kapasiteettia edistaa vahemmistojen tyollistymista 4) parantaa romaninaisten asemaa yhteisoissaan ja yhteiskunnassa.Ro
manityttojen koulupudokkuutta vahennetaan mentorointiohjelman avulla jossa hankkeen kouluttamat vapaaehtoiset tukevat tyttoja koulunkaynnissa ja uravalintojen tekemisessa. Nuorten romaninaisten tyollisyytta edistetaan tarjoamalla yksiloitya tukea yhteistyo
ssa Kosovon tyovoimatoimiston kanssa. Naisia tuetaan ja ohjataan ammatilliseen koulutukseen lisaksi jarjestetaan elamantaitovalmennus harjoitteluohjelma ja yrittajyysvalmennus. Samanaikaisesti hanke kouluttaa tyovoimaviranomaisia vahemmistojen tyollistymis
een liittyvissa erityiskysymyksissa.Romaninaisten yhteiskunnallista vaikuttamista edistetaan kouluttamalla paikallisia jarjestoja ja poliittisia puolueita vahemmistonaisten osallisuuden lisaamisesta. Romaninaisten asemaa yhteisoissaan parannetaan paitsi ju
lkisilla kampanjoilla myos ryhmilla joissa eri teemoihin pureutuen lisataan tietoisuutta naisten oikeuksista ja mahdollisuuksista pohditaan naisen asemaa yhteisoissa ja pyritaan murtamaan tasa-arvon esteita. Tahan osallistetaan seka miehia etta naisia.Hank
keen toteuttavat Diakonissalaitos seka paikallisesti romanien elinoloja edistava kansalaisjarjesto VoRAE. Lisaksi paikallisina kumppaneina ovat Kosovon tyovoimatoimisto ja Kosovar Gender Studies Centre joka paikallisena naisjarjestona tuo hankkeen eri toim
intoihin naistyoasiantuntemuksensa.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project&apos;s primary development policy priority is The rights and status of women and girls have been enhanced. The development problem addressed by the project is multiple discrimination against Roma girls and women in Kosovo society: Romani women face 
discrimination in their daily lives because of their gender ethnicity and economic situation.The cross-cutting objective of the project is to increase the capacity of the local partner and civil society in gender mainstreaming. Additionally the project aim
s to 1) reduce school drop-out of Roma girls 2) promote employment opportunities of Roma women 3) increase the capacity of employment agencies to promote minority employment 4) improve the status and position of Roma women in their communities and in socie
ty.The dropout rate of Roma girls is reduced through a mentoring programme where volunteers trained by the project support girls in their schooling and career choices. The employment of young Roma women will be promoted through the provision of personalise
d support in cooperation with the Kosovo Employment Agency. Women are supported and referred to vocational training; additionally the project provides life skills training an on-the-job training programme and entrepreneurship coaching. At the same time the
 project is training the employment authorities on specific issues related to the employment of minorities.The empowerment of Romani women is promoted by training local CSOs and political parties on inclusion of Roma women. The role of Roma women in their 
communities is enhanced not only through public campaigns but also through social groups that address different themes in order to raise awareness of women&apos;s rights and opportunities to reflect on the role of women in communities and to break down barriers
 to equality. Both men and women are involved.The project is being implemented by the Deaconess Foundation and VoRAE an NGO promoting Roma issues locally. In addition local partners include the Kosovo Employment Agency and Kosovar Gender Studies Centre whi
ch as a local women&apos;s organisation brings its gender expertise to all project activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deaconess Institute in Helsinki</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Helsingin Diakonissalaitoksen saatio</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights transformative</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeushaasteisiin tarttuva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is the main priority area in this activ
ity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">124000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">137000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2099-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">137000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">532000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
