<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2018180770</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Hankekehitys-komponentti Suomi-IFC -ilmastorahasto-ohjelmaan</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Coponent to the Finland - IFC Blended Finance for Climate Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identify and develop high potential projects for the Finland-IFC Blended Finance for Climate Program that would not otherwise materialize. The overall objective of the Project Development Component is consequent investment(s) in these projects from the Ble
nded Finance for Climate Program.Finland channels 114 million euros for climate investments via a trust fund administered by IFC (International Finance Corporation). The life of the fund is 25 years. Finland?s capital will be invested solely into climate r
elated projects in developing countries. The financing required for a transition to a low-carbon resilient globaleconomy is counted in the trillions not billions. People living in poverty are the most vulnerable to the effects of climate change. IFC is tar
geting its efforts to bring climate solutions where they are needed most. The main objectives of the Program are to address market barriers that prevent the faster more widespread or longer-term sustainable adoption of low-carbon technologies and business 
models in developing countries leverage and bring private capital that will helpdeveloping and emerging countries grow on a low carbon path and catalyze investments with strong development and climate benefits that would not happen otherwise. A key element
 of the Program will be enhancing and increasing the cooperation and relationship between the IFC and Finnish stakeholders in the critical climate change fora. By making this investment Finland delivers on its intention to use a bulk of its development pol
icy investments for climate financing announced at the Paris Climate Summit in 2015. IFC is a member of the World Bank Group and the largest global development institution focused exclusively on the private sector in over 100 developing countries. In addit
ion granting loans mezzanine financing and guarantees IFC also makes capital investments inpromising private firms in developing countries. IFC has 186 member countries including Finland.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Taman hankekehittely-komponentin tarkoituksena on mahdollistaa hankekehitysrahoitus sellaisille hankeraakileille jotka ovat potentiaalisia investointirahoituksen saajia Finland-IFC Blended Finance for Climate ? sijoitusrahastosta (kuvataan alla).Suomi kana
voi Kansainvalisen rahoitusyhtio (International Finance Corporation) IFC:n kautta 114 Meuroa sijoitusmuotoista maararahaa ilmastorahasto-ohjelmaan jonka kesto on 25 vuotta. Suomen varoja sijoitetaan rahaston kautta ainoastaan ilmastohankkeisiin kehitysmais
sa. Vahahiiliseen ja kestavaan globaaliin talouteen siirtyminen vaatii biljoonaluokan rahoituksen. Miljardit eivat riita. Koyhyydessa elavat ihmiset ovat kaikkein haavoittuvaisimpia ilmastomuutoksen vaikutuksille. IFC kohdistaa rahoituksensa sellaisiin ilm
astoratkaisuihin joita eniten tarvitaan. Suomen rahoituksella perustettavan IFC-ilmastorahaston tavoitteenaon luoda markkinoita katalysoida innovatiivisia sijoituksia ja houkutella yksityista paaomaa yksityisen sektorin ilmastohankkeisiin kehitysmaissa joi
ssa sijoitustoimintaa ei tapahdu tai se on hyvin vaikeaa haasteellisen toimintaympariston ja markkinoiden kehittymattomyyden takia. Yksi tarkea tavoite on myos lisata IFC:n jasuomalaisten toimijoiden yhteistyota ilmastotoimissa. Sijoituksella Suomi lunasta
a Pariisin ilmastokokouksessa 2015 tekemansa lupauksen kayttaa merkittava osa kehityspoliittisista finanssisijoituksistaan ilmastotoimiin. IFC on maailman suurin AAA-luottoluokituksen saanut yksityisen sektorin kehitysrahoittaja. Se on osa Maailmanpankkiry
hmaa. Lainojenvalirahoituksen ja takuiden myontamisen lisaksi IFC tekee suoria paaomasijoituksia kehityskelpoisiin yrityksiin kehitysmaissa. IFC:lla on 186 jasenmaata mukaan lukien Suomi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44004" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2018180770" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-22" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="23210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muut momentit</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other budget lines</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">740000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2018180770" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
