<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2011110113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Oikeus koulutukseen: Nepalin kouluhallinnon ja koulutuspolitiikan kehittamishanke</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Education Policies and Ensuring the Right to Education in Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Oikeus koulutukseen: Nepalin kouluhallinnon ja koulutuspolitiikan kehittamishankkeen toteuttavat lasten oikeuksien ja koulutuksen asiantuntijajarjestot Loo Niva Child Concern Group and Interpedia. Jarjestot ovat aiemmin tehneet yhteistyota Dadeldhuran alue
ella Nepalin Kaukolannessa vuosina 2012-2014 ja 2015-2017 Concern for Education ?hankkeiden kautta.Dadeldhuran alue on yksi Nepalin vahiten kehittyneista ja siella esiintyy yha koulunkayntia vaikeuttavaa syrjintaa tyttoja etnisia vahemmistoja seka kastitto
mia kohtaan. Peruskoulutuksen edistamisen menestyksekkaina keinoina ovat hankkeissa toimineet lasten opettajien vanhempien seka paikallisten viranomaisten kouluttaminen lasten oikeudesta koulutukseen lasten osallistumisen vahvistaminen lapsille suunnatuill
a kerhoilla paikallisten toimintaryhmien perustaminen laadukkaan koulutuksen ja koulutusmyonteisten tavoitteiden edistamiseksi seka hyvien opetuskaytantojen levittaminen. Samalla kouluista on pyritty tekemaan levottomuuksista vapaita poliittisesti sitoutum
attomia tiloja.Hankkeessa tehdaan tyota paikallisella kunnallisella ja provinssin tasolla mahdollistaen oikeus laadukkaaseen koulutukseen Nepalin uudistuneissa hallintorakenteissa. Vuonna 2015 Nepalissa saadettiin uusi perustuslaki ja myos federalisaatio o
n siirtanyt koulutuspoliittista paatosvaltaa paikalliselle ja provinssitasolle. Uudistusten keskella muovautuu myos Nepalin kansalaisyhteiskunnan rooli ja mahdollisuudet vaikuttamistyohon. Hanke edistaa parempaa koulutuspolitiikkaa provinssissa nro 7 seka 
kahdessa alueen kunnassa kouluttamalla paikallishallinnon ja provinssitason paattajia. Aiemmin syntyneiden hyvien kaytantojen turvaamiseksi ja levittamiseksi hanke keskittyy paikallisyhteisojen vahvistamiseen ja vahvan kansalaisyhteiskunnan kehittamiseen k
oulutukseen kysymyksissa. Lisaksi hanke parantaa oppimistuloksia ja vahentaa koulupudokkuutta kahdessa kunnassa tavoittaen yli 4000 oppilasta 32 koulussa heidan perheensa ja 60 opettajaa. Hanke vastaa hyvin Suomen kehityspoliittisia tavoitteita silla vahva
 oikeusperustainen lahtokohta ja fokus sukupuolten valisen tasa-arvon edistamisessa seka epatasa-arvon poistamisessa.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Education Policies and Ensuring the Right to Education ?project has been planned by Loo Niva Child Concern Group and Interpedia expert NGOs on child rights and education. The NGOs have previously partnered in the Far-West Dadeldhura district 
through Concern for Education -projects in 2012-2014 and 2015-2017.Dadeldhura is one of the least developed areas in Nepal where vulnerable groups such as girls ethnic minorities and Dalits face discrimination and have lower access to education. The projec
ts have improved the status of education through sensitizing children parents teachers and local authorities on their role in promoting education; strengthening child participation in society; forming and supporting local action groups for supervising and 
promoting quality education and raising awareness about good educational practices. The projects have also promoted peaceful education and avoiding misuse of schools as an instrument of politics.This project works at local municipal and provincial levels w
ith the objective of enabling efforts on realizing the right to education in the new provincial structure of Nepal. In 2015 Nepal ratified a new constitution and the recent federalization process has reformed structures related to education policy shifting
 decision making to local and provincial levels. The civil society now has an opportunity to strengthen its role in policy-making and to advance the democratization process.The project will work to ensure better educational policies and programs at provinc
e No. 7 and two municipalities through training local government leaders and provincial assembly members. For ensuring good practices developed are sustained and spread this phase will focus on empowering and engaging local civil society to ensure the sust
ainable redistribution of roles and responsibilities. In addition the project will improve learning achievements and reduce dropouts in two municipalities reaching over 4000 school-going children in 32 schools their families and 60 teachers. The project is
 in line with Finnish development policy objectives has a strong rights-based approach and focus on gender + reduction of inequality</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Interpedia rf</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interpedia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2019-2011110113" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-11-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">110000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">90000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">110000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2019-2011110113" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
