<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2020-2020000593</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki Maailmanpankin globaalille evaluointikapasiteettia vahvistavalle aloitteelle (GECI)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WB Trust Fund for Global Evaluation Capacity Initiative GECI</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kestavan kehityksen tavoitteiden (KKT) saavuttaminen edellyttaa mailta vahvoja seuranta- ja evaluointijarjestelmia ja kapasiteettia johon kuuluu i) toimintaymparisto jossa ymmarretaan evaluoinnin rooli tietopohjaisessa paatoksenteossa seka sita tukevan saa
dosymparisto;  ii) institutionaaliset puitteet ja kaytannot sille etta parlamentit ministeriot ja valtionhallinto seka kansalaisyhteiskunta tuottavat ja kayttavat evaluointitietoa; iii) yksilotason kykya tuottaa korkeatasoista ja tarkoituksenmukaista arvio
intitietoa. Seuranta ja evaluointijarjestelmien ja kapasiteetin vahvistamiselle on kasvava kysynta nousevien talouksien kehittyvien ja hauraiden talouksien valtionhallinnon ja muiden sidosryhmien parissa. Global Partnership for Effective Development Cooper
ation (GPEDC) selvitys osoitti etta vaikka 91 % kansallisista kehitysstrategioista viittaa Agenda2030:een ja KKT:iin vain 35 prosentilla on olemassa tietoa ja jarjestelma jolla seurata toimeenpanoa. Globaali evaluointikapasiteettialoite (Global Evaluation 
Capacity Initiative GECI) on inklusiivinen monitoimijakumppanuus jonka tarkoitus on vastata kysyntaan kokoamalla yhteen teknisia ja taloudellisia resursseja useilta maailmanlaajuisilta toimijoilta yhteiseen rahastoon (Multi-donor Trust Fund). Rahaston avul
la pyritaan nostamaan niiden maiden ja instituutioiden maaraa joilla on korkealaatuuiset seuranta- ja evaluointijarjestelmat ja kapasiteettia parantaa edistymista KKT saavuttamisessa. GECI pyrkii vahvistamaan seka valtionhallinnon instituutioita kansallisi
lla ja paikallisilla tasoilla etta paikallisia kansalaisjarjestoa ja mahdollisesti myos yksityissektorin toimijoita lahtien paikallisesta kulttuurista ja kaytannoista mutta tarjoamalla kayttoon globaaleja alueellisia ja paikallisia hyvia kaytantoja. Toimin
nan tuloksena GECI&apos;n kumppanit maat ja instituutiot nousevat edellekavijoiksi tilivelvollisuudessa tietopohjaisessa oppimisessa ja paatoksenteossa maatasolla. GECI kokoaa yhteen useita toimijoita mukaan lukien Maailmanpankin evaluointiryhma UNDP OECD-DACin
 evaluointiverkosto ja  kehityspankit. Kahdenvalisia toimijoita edustavat Ruotsi Uusi Seelanti Alankomaat Saksa Tanska ja Norja. Suomen tuki on kaynnistysvaiheessa 250 000 euroa kaytettavaksi vuosina 2020-21. Jatkorahoitusta harkitaan toiminnan tulosten va
lossa.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To achieve the SDGs countries need strong Monitoring and Evaluation (M+E) systems and capacities encompassing i) an adequate enabling environment with high levels of awareness of the role of evaluation in evidence-based policy-making as well as the necessa
ry regulatory environment in place to support the use of evidence in program design and decision-making; ii) institutional frameworks and practices for evaluative evidence to be generated and used in parliaments ministries government agencies and civil soc
iety organizations; iii) and individual capacities to generate high quality and relevant evaluative evidence.  There is a growing demand from governments and other stakeholders in Emerging Developing and Fragile Economies (EDFE) to strengthen their M+E sys
tems and capacities. A recent study by the Global Partnership for Effective Development Cooperation (GPEDC) showed that while 91 % of national development strategies referring to the Agenda2030 and the SDGs only 35 % of them have data and systems to track 
implementation. The Global Evaluation Capacity Initiative (GECI) is an inclusive multi-stakeholder partnership aiming to create a bridge between evaluation capacity demand and supply by pooling technical and financial resources of several global actors thr
ough a multi-donor TF with the objective to increase the number of countries and institutions equipped with high quality M+E systems and capacities to improve their performance and progress towards the SDGs. Further GECI aims to equip governmental institut
ions (at national and sub-national levels) as well as local NGOs and (potentially) private sector organizations with strong M+E systems and capacities anchored in local cultures and practices and informed by global regional and local best practices. As a r
esult GECI&apos;s partner countries and institutions will become champions of accountability evidence-based learning and informed decision-making at country level. GECI collaborators include World Bank IEG UNDP IEO OECD_DAC EvalNet Multilateral Development Bank
s (MDBs) bilateral donors such as Sweden New Zealand The Netherlands; Germany Denmark and Norway (TBC).  Finland&apos;s support  at mobilization phase is of 250 000 euros for use in 2020-2021. Further funding will be considered on the basis of achieved results.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44000" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maailmanpankkiryhma</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-22" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430667" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation and internal audit of development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kehitysyhteistyon evaluointi</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ei maaritelty</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not defined</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">250000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">250000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
