<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-CG-F16AP00532</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TRIDOM Cameroon Transboundary Elephant Security Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. Programs in this element should be integrated with the Agriculture Area under Economic Growth and Conflict Mitigation and Reconciliation Area under the Peace and Security Category, when applicable and appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. This includes The purpose of this project is to support a conservation effort in Minkebe National Park in Gabon and the Nki Messok Dja transboundary complex between Cameroon and the Republic of Congo by establishing multi-agency law enforcement actions and strategic coordination in order to dismantle criminal transboundary networks. This project is intended to conserve forest elephants by addressing the impacts of ivory trafficking and poaching networks in the core of the Tri-national Dja-Odzala-Minkebe (TRIDOM) forest landscape. Specific activities include: (1) Consolidating informant networks in Cameroon to collect actionable intelligence on ivory trafficking; (2) supporting operations of special arrest teams to disrupt ivory networks in southeast Cameroon; (3) providing legal support to the Ministry of Forestry and Wildlife (MINFOF) for the prosecution of arrested wildlife criminals; (4) communicating arrests and court outcomes through various media; (5) documenting and mapping poachers&#x2019; access routes into Minkebe National Park and the periphery; (6) holding strategic meetings between the Agence Nationale des Parcs Nationaux (ANPN), MINFOF and WWF staff to develop collaboration, information exchange and a patrol strategy during the first quarter of the project; (7) providing logistical, material and financial support to Cameroonian guard teams to conduct joint and/or coordinated patrols along the Gabon-Cameroon border; (8) providing logistical support for supplying ANPN&#x2019;s Assok Allat satellite camp; (9) providing information on movements of ivory poachers and ivory across the border so as to improve the efficiency of patrols; (10) holding a second strategy meeting between ANPN and MINFOF/WWF Cameroon to learn from the collaboration and plan for the future; and (11) supporting patrols in southern Nki National Park, along the border with Congo..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WORLD WILDLIFE FUND, INC.</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>074845447</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-19" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CG">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (Brazzaville)</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. assistance to the Republic of the Congo (Congo) focuses on promoting regional peace and security in this post-conflict country. Boasting Central Africa&apos;s only deep water port, the Congo&apos;s financial capital of Pointe-Noire maintains its International Ship and Port Facility Security (ISPS) certification. This certification creates significant economic opportunity for the Congo - which seeks to turn the coastal city into a regional shipping hub - while requiring a modern, professional security posture in accordance with strict ISPS standards. To help promote this growth and encourage regional stability, U.S. foreign assistance focuses on development of the Congo&apos;s professional military capabilities and provides foundational training for development in this area, in keeping with post&apos;s Integrated Country Strategy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-01">130000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-22">130000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2015" end="2016"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1021">Development Assistance, Agency for International Development, Funds Appropriated to the President</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="72"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2016-07-19"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
