<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2013130253</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">DEVCHULIN KUNNAN KEST&#xC4;V&#xC4;N VESIHUOLLON JA TOIMINTAEDELLYTYSTEN KEHITT&#xC4;MISEN HANKE</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nawalparasi and Palpa Districts Sustainable Water Supply and Sanitation Project (NAPA WASH)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Finnish water projects have supported the government of Nepal in developing decentralized community based water and sanitation approach and working modalities since 1990. Project in Devchuli Nepal is an extension to WaterFinns NAPA WASH project in Nepal in
 2014-2016. There is great potential in developing the area to the next level in water quality and sanitation by capacity building in municipality and ward level trainings and minor construction to ensure the long term sustainability based on self-reliance
 of the communities. There is a need to increase understanding and awareness of sustainability of WASH services and facilities in user committees ward and municipality level. There is a clear demand for a continuation project after NAPA WASH; Devchuli area
 has basic level water and sanitation services however the quality of water and skill of maintaining WSP are not still sufficient and therefore causes health issues.  The overall project objective is to improve the self-reliance of Devchuli communities to 
sustain their WASH services at acceptable good level to ensure safe drinking water and healthy hygienic environment for the whole community. This is done by applying tested Operation + Maintenance and Management practices new technologies and capacity buil
ding at the community ward and municipality level. The project is situated in Devchuli municipality in Nawalparasi Nepal. Devchuli has a population of 34912 with 6336 individual households which all are direct or indirect beneficiaries of the project. Proj
ect management is done by WaterFinns Finland with the local partner Center for Appropriate Technology Nepal (CATN) in Nepal in addition to the Devchuli municipality. Project?s beneficiaries are the users of WASH services in Devichuli Municipality.The proje
ct is designed also to support the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) especially of 5. Gender equality 6. Clean water and sanitation 10. Reduced inequalities and 13. Climate action. The project will integrate Climate Change Adaptation and Disaster Risk Re
duction measures in the WASH process e.g. the WSP aiming to minimize the impacts of weather induced disasters.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project NAPA WASH is a continuation of WaterFinns involvement into WASH sector development in Nepal. It aims to complement the past and ongoing water sector support of Finland to Nepal. The Project Purpose is two-fold:1. Improved well-being an
d reduced poverty in Project areas2. Enhanced understanding of long-term sustainability of WASH servicesThe Project aims to achieve its Purpose through three interlinked results (outputs):Result 1: Lessons learned from success and failure of long-term sust
ainability of rural WASH services reported and benchmarks of best practices promotedResult 2: Capacity building of selected UC?s and VDC?s in their management and efforts of further improving the WASH servicesResult 3: Strengthened institutional structure 
to support communities and UC?s in O+M and Management of WASH services focusing on private sector service provision.One very important element of the proposed project is to create opportunities for the future water sector professionals (both Nepali and Fin
nish) to have a very interesting possibility to participate to monitoring related work that focuses on long-term learning of the sustainable schemes.The proposed project is three years long (2014-2016) and its proposed budget is 270000 EUR. The project geo
graphic area is Nawalparasi and Palpa Districts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-106" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WaterFinns ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2015-2013130253" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Nepal"></location>
  <sector code="14081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edist&#xE4;v&#xE4;</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the main priority area in this act
ivity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muut momentit</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other budget lines</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">76500</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">81500</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2015-2013130253" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
