<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2010100021</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mental health services for refugee children in South Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project focuses to the South of Lebanon where the Palestinian refugee population suffers from large scale poverty and lack of basic services. Damages of the Israeli-Hezbollah war 2006 are still there and the camps are surrounded by military forces. Since 2
012 South has got an influx of displaced Syrian and Palestinian people from Syria. One third of the population is under aged 18. Treatment of the developmental and mental health difficulties of the children and adolescents is crucial for their future.Long-
term goal is the psychological well-being of the Palestinian community. The purpose of the project is to assist Palestinian-Lebanese NGO Beit Atfal Assumoud to develop mental health program for the children and adolescents living in Palestinian communities
 in South Lebanon. BAS has opened two Family Guidance Centers (FGC) in the region (Tyre 2007 Saida 2010). Centers support the families in parenting tackle the maltreatment and negotiate with parents in family conflicts. The continuation project combines th
e experience of these two centers to start a new phase. Crucial is the implementation of the community-based mental health (CBMH) working model, specialists support the social workers in home interventions. Project enables mental health services yearly for
 ca 250-300 new patients and continuation of the treatment for 400-500 children. The quality of service is maintained and the adoption of new working model is supported by staff training. For the local staff in children&apos;s services FGCs arrange training ses
sions. For parents siblings and other caregivers FGCs arrange awareness group sessions workshops about required themes and encourage to the peer support. The work of BAS is environmental friendly. Recycling and nature protection are common themes in activi
ties. Due to the water problem in the region the inhabitants use bottled water. The gender is added in the activity statistics to be able to monitor the equality in service. Fathers are actively invited to share the efforts for the well-being of their chil
dren. Unfortunately Palestinians in Lebanon do not have civil rights and no possibility to join in democratic decision making in the host country. State of Lebanon defines the Palestinian child only as recipient of UNRWA assistance (Al-Yassir + Khalidi 200
6). In this context to familiarize children with children&apos;s rights is important to build future perspectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-307" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Psychologists for Social Responsibility</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="85202501" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">136000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">136000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
