<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2016161145</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Rights Based Empowerment Project (RBEP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through an empowerment approach, LWF will work with more than 130 villages in Chin, Kayin, the Delta and Magway Regions to facilitate the communities? ability to claim their rights and build sustainable livelihoods. This will increase their participation a
nd importance as a constituency as well as work closer with local authorities. All 130 villages belong to the most disadvantaged communities and harbor vulnerable groups in terms of livelihood and exercising active citizenship. The 2014 census revealed in 
project areas that 42.2% of the poorest households depend further on unimproved sources of drinking water and a third applies substandard sanitation practices. The Main Objective: Rights Based Empowerment Project will contribute to the alleviation of pover
ty in Myanmar and to the promotion and maintenance of peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development. Expected Results: ? Villages are able to manage disaster risks while applying environmentally friendly measures? Households have sustainable
 diversified means of livelihood and food security, have increased access to primary health care and WASH facilities, and girls and boys of school age have access to quality basic education ? Rights-holders are active in their households and village develo
pment and empowered through effective coalitions working at/towards national level? LWF will do this responsibly and effectively ensuring quality and sustainability in its programmes and organisationRights-holders/beneficiaries: 50,000 people in 130 villag
es (VDCs, Interest groups, Partner Households) Duty-bearers: local (village/township) authorities, Village level health volunteers, school teachers, school PTAs/SMCs, Township level Government line departments.Implementing partner: Lutheran World Federatio
n (LWF) Myanmar. LWF Myanmar works effectively with local authorities and civil society organisations and has been active in the area since 2008. It works at the grassroots with partner households and interest groups and the VDCs (Village Development Commi
ttees). Increasingly in a changing institutional environment LWF stresses more cooperation and involvement with local leaders/authorities and traditional leaders. They play a crucial role in enhancing or blocking innovation and change. Thus, networking and
 advocacy are part of the Rights Based Empowerment approach LWF applies in Myanmar.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Ayeyarwaddy Delta area, Matway Region, Kayin State"></location>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
