<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2015150087</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMSCO/Accelerated Development of Selected Farmer Enterprises in Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Management Service Company (AMSCO) implements a one year project Accelerated Development of Selected Farmer Enterprises in Zambia (funding EUR 149000) on the following farmer owned enterprises: 1. Manyonyo Irrigation Company Limited ? sugarcane ? N
egaNega, 2. Nzenga Irrigation Company Limited ? Irish potatoes and soya beans ? Sinazongwe. Overall this project has been designed to consolidate the work done by the GRZ/Finnish funded Smallholder Irrigation Project (SIP) focusing specifically on the ente
rprise development aspect of the two farmer enterprises. The project will be implemented at two levels, company/enterprise and farmer levels. The goal of this project is to address the business and management gaps identified at enterprise and farmers level
s. In summary the key outcomes expected over the project are: 1) boards of directors are properly constituted and trained to oversee the business of the companies, 2) administrative operational and finance systems are established enhanced and operate effic
iently, 3) practical scalable business models addressing sustainability beyond project phase are developed, 4) farmers have gained adequate skills to change their view to farming as a business and are better placed to utilise household incomes, 5) women ar
e mainstreamed into the activities of the boards of directors management and operations of the two companies. Some of the key challenges that persist and are to be addressed are low farmers&apos; appreciation of the business lack of guiding structures of govern
ing boards low readiness for the management of incomes gender empowerment inexistent or outsourced business processes and systems at MICL and NICL, and low business and management skills amongst staff at the two companies. Beyond the project period it is e
nvisioned that the targeted farmer enterprises or cooperatives will become financially viable having established fully functional relevant business models supported by strong governance structures optimal business processes and systems and skilled staff an
d farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-19" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">14000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
