<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2012000343</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing the children&apos;s mental health and special services in ongoing crisis: Beirut and South Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is a continuation but the work continues in a quite new and adverse situation due to the war and political violence in Middle East. Lebanon has launched the Crisis Response Plan to find the stabilizing ingredients in every action. The project 
Developing the children&apos;s mental health and special services in ongoing crisis responds to the long-term problem the marginalisation of Palestinian refugees in host country and the hardships of the poor families. Normal services are not only actual service
 but recognition to the right to exist to enjoy the civil rights to gain resources for decent life. Annually hundreds of Palestinian children have got high quality help and families relieved when seeing the progress of the child. BAS proceeded to take seri
ously the right to education of the children with intellectual and psychological disabilities. Because of the staff&apos;s negotiations with special schools small number of institutions offering places for Palestinian children has already increased to almost 40
. It is a break through: Palestinian children with disabilities are visible now. In all actions the sustainability was respected in human environment and ecologically. Concerning gender boys were major beneficiaries but the prevalence of disability of boys
 in young age is more than of girls. The main partner is Finnish Arab Friendship Society which works also to support the families by sponsorship program and for children&apos;s mental health. FiPSR works in South Lebanon FAFS in North Lebanon. There are 5 partn
ers of BAS with whom Finnish NGOs are in continuous contact. The beneficiaries are 260 children with disturbancies in mental health behavior and development new referrals to the Family Guidance Centers and ca 400 children who continue in treatment. The for
merly separate disability project which was pioneer in its field is now included in the new project. 60 children with multiple special needs (disabilities) will benefit from special education and rehabilitation. The staff will be supported by various HR me
asures. Other beneficiaries are those around the child with difficulties: family activity educational and stakeholder network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-307" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Psychologists for Social Responsibility</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="85202503" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muu</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">255000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">255000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">510000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
