<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2014141200</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Reinforcement of local communities and networking with activists to stop the Areng hydro dam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mother Nature organization, a volunteer movement made up of local indigenous communities, youth activists, and members of civil society, has been successfully opposing the proposed Areng hydroelectric dam, which would seriously damage the unique biodiversi
ty of the Central Cardamom Protected Forest in Koh Kong province, and seriously infringe on the human rights of local indigenous communities. During this project, Mother Nature will continue taking advantage of its rapport with influential community member
s to ensure that the communities at large are fully informed of what their rights are, and feel empowered enough to publicly oppose the project. Also, Mother Nature will increase its media campaign to highlight the massive inconsistencies with the dam, als
o highlighting the fact that it has been classed as ?uneconomical? by two large dam builders. This will be done through the use of a newly created network, which will concentrate its efforts in punctual, public, and innovative activities / campaigns. Mothe
r Nature organization was created in February 2013 in the village of Ta Tay Leu, Koh Kong province, which was seeing massive deforestation of its ancient sacred spirit forests. Mother Nature has successfully campaigned against illegal logging. The goals of
 Mother Nature are: 1) To prevent the proposed Chhay Areng hydroelectric dam, or any other-large scale development projects, from being approved inside the Central Cardamom Protected Forest (CCPF), 2) Protect, reinforce, and promote the unique culture, tra
ditions, and livelihoods of the Cardamom Mountain&apos;s remaining forest-dependant indigenous communities, 3) Lobby the Cambodian government to declare the whole of the CCPF area a UNESCO World Heritage Site, 4) Increase international pressure on protecting th
e forest area by leveraging national and international civil society networks, social media and mainstream media, 5) Encourage tourists and researchers to visit the Cardamoms in order to learn more about these unique and endangered landscapes as well as he
lp create jobs and income in the area, 6) To become Cambodia?s first green movement, made of environmentally aware Cambodians. Mother Nature does not have paid full-time personnel. As a volunteer-led non-profit movement, the members agree to remuneration t
hat covers only their basic living costs, and no salaries are paid out. www.mothernature.pm</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-86" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Siemenpuu</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="14014AAS" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Koh Kong province"></location>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1183</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
