<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2015150167</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FLC: ICB - Palestinian Youth Leadership Training Project /Phase III</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Betlehemil&#xE4;isen Diyar-j&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;n hankkeen tavoitteena on identifioida motivoida ja voimaannuttaa uusia nuoria palestiinalaisia johtajia. Palestiinassa nuorisoty&#xF6;tt&#xF6;myys on korkeaa ja nuoret ovat marginalisoituneita yhteiskunnasta ja p&#xE4;&#xE4;t&#xF6;ksenteosta.
 Toiminnassa kulttuurisella ilmaisulla on keskeinen rooli. V&#xE4;litt&#xF6;min&#xE4; tavoitteina on noin 100 nuoren naisen ja miehen kapasiteetin kehitt&#xE4;minen koulutusten ty&#xF6;pajojen ja seminaarien kautta joiden teemoina ovat johtajuus kansalaisyhteiskunta kulttuuri
 ja palestiinalainen kansanperinne. Lis&#xE4;ksi ohjelma tarjoaa ty&#xF6;harjoittelumahdollisuuden 20 nuorelle. Hankkeen osana tuotetaan my&#xF6;s kaksi kulttuuriperinnett&#xE4; esittelev&#xE4;&#xE4; julkaisua. Diyar on  luterilaispohjainen mutta koko palestiinalaisyhteis&#xF6;&#xE4; pal
veleva j&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;jen ja koulutuslaitosten konsortio. Suomella on pitk&#xE4; yhteisty&#xF6;suhde sen kanssa. Kulttuurikeskus Dar Annadwa on rakennettu Suomen kehitysyhteisty&#xF6;varoin (2003) ja paikallisen yhteisty&#xF6;n m&#xE4;&#xE4;r&#xE4;rahoin on rahoitettu sen toimintaa usean 
vuoden ajan. J&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;n web-sivusto: www.diyar.ps.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Palestinian Youth Leadership Training Project-Phase III is an initiative that was started in 2011. It seeks to identify motivate and cultivate young Palestinian leaders to become more informed engaged and proactive citizens since the youth are among th
e most marginalized groups in the Palestinian society by empowering them to articulate and organize around significant civic issues through using the powerful medium of culture. It also plans to build on the success of the first year and expand the outreac
h and network. The project in its third phase intends to continue making the needed change in the situation of the youth by employing its 3-part approach which consists of the following: (1) Activating the potential of and developing the capacities of youn
g future Palestinian leaders. The methods used to achieve this segment is (a) a series of intensive training workshops for 100 young men and women from different areas in Palestine with emphasis on rural areas as they are considered among the most marginal
ized parts of Palestine on leadership culture and civil society issues. (b) Internship training opportunities for a maximum of 10 young people who participated during the first and second phases of the project where their leadership organizational research
 and communication skills are further developed and cultivated. (2) Enhancing the civic and cultural understanding of the young people and helping to evolve their involvement in and appreciation of the importance of civil society and culture in Palestine. 
The methods used to fulfill this particular part of the approach are (a) Holding 2 national seminars where significant issues and cultural figures and role models are highlighted discussed and debated. (b) Carrying out 2 cultural field visits for the parti
cipating trainees to expose them further to the issues at hand through a different approach which is to be physically present at different locations. The cultural visits consist of Hebron or Ramallah (depending on the political situation) and Nablus Distri
cts (3) Strengthening the young people?s consciousness of the past and heritage and increasing their sense of ownership of their history and culture as this is fundamental to the formation and evolvement of a dynamic and inclusive identity. This section wi
ll be focusing on developing 1 cultural resource which comprises of re-discovered Palestinian cultural figures and heritage of the old city of Bethlehem.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="23000" ref="23000-1" role="3" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kehitysmaan kansalaisj&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2015-2015150167" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-09" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-09" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteisty&#xF6;</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="0" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ei m&#xE4;&#xE4;ritelty</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not defined</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">40000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2015-2015150167" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
