<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2015150792</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Actions for Advancing Freedom of Freed Haliyas, Kamaiyas and Kamlaharis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Freed Haliyas, ex-Kamaiyas and Kamlaris (HaKK) have not yet fully realised the true sense of freedom. They are aware but still lacking desired level of empowerment. Thousands of right-holders are still denied their rights and entitlements. Therefore, right
-holders need to be further supported to empower them to claim and enjoy their rights. The duty-bearers require enough support in formulation policies, strategies, guidelines and implement those aiming the just rehabilitation of freed HaKK. The project, th
us, focuses on livelihood, education, capacity building and advocacy to facilitate duty-bearers? and right-holders? efforts to end this bondage system permanently. The overall goal of the project is to enhance the dignified living of freed Haliyas, Ex- Kam
aiyas and Kamlaris. The project aims at advancing socio-economic condition of freed Haliya, ex- Kamaiyas and Kamlaris enhancing their access to livelihood assets and promoting equality and non-discrimination Expected results:? Increased access of the right
s-holders (i.e. freed Haliyas, ex-Kamaiyas and Kamlaris), their groups and associations to services and resources, and fulfillment of their rights ? Enhanced access of the rights-holders to resilient livelihood and employment opportunities ? Increased acce
ss of children and youth among the rights-holders to uninterrupted quality education ? Improved harmony and relations between freed bonded labourers and their ex-mastersRights-holders /beneficiaries: Freed Haliyas, ex- Kamaiyas and Kamlaris.Implementing pa
rtner:  The Lutheran World Federation Nepal (LWF Nepal)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-03-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
