<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2013130460</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forest + Farm Facility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forest and Farm Facility (FFF) is a partnership programme launched in 2012 between Food and Agriculture Organisation of the UN (FAO) the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) and the International Institute for Development and Environment (
IIED).FFF engages producer organisations of small holders women communities and indigenous peoples in decision-making and financing solutions related to forest and farm landscapes. FFF aims to enhance multi-sectoral stakeholder policy platforms involving s
takeholders and government at local and national level. FFF promotes the investment capacity of local communities and organisations in the area for sustainable agriculture and forestry as well as practicing and development of sustainable forest management.
 This would improve the income level and food security for small producers women and indigenous peoples&apos; communities. Moreover the FFF strengthens linkages between the local knowledge and experience and national and global agenda and initiatives.FFF looks 
in a holistic manner into links between forest ecosystem services poverty reduction food security and climate change impacts. It can be considered to be well in line with the integrated approach required by the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. Buil
ding on the existing capacities in developing countries allows sustainable results. FFF is currently operational at country level in 10 countries: Bolivia Gambia Guatemala Kenya Liberia Myanmar Nepal Nicaragua Zambia and Vietnam. There are synergy effects 
that can be gained in countries where Finland also has bilateral development cooperation. Until now results in different countries have included: organising among small producers has contributed to higher producer prices, strengthened cooperation between t
he producers and stakeholders, more women in leadership positions in producer organizations, realising functioning business plans, and achieving recognition of land rights for communities. FFF has also supported the process of preparation of the national p
rograms in several countries and provided the opportunity for training and peer learning both at country and regional levels.FFF&apos;s overall performance is evaluated through a monitoring and learning framework. The mid-term evaluation which was carried out i
n 2016 was very positive for the FFF. Finland&apos;s support to the FFF in 2016 is EUR 700 000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41301" ref="41301-2" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agricultural Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="89892232" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-19" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="31220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">700000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">700000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">700000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
