<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2010100603</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Tekoja Magazine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tekoja-magazine is published four times a year. It covers themes linked to development policy discussion, provides deeper analysis on themes linked to FCA&#x2019;s strategic themes (Right to Peace, Right to Education, Right to Livelihood), and makes the results
 and impacts of our programme work visible. All articles and photos are produced by following professional guidelines for journalists.The magazine increases knowledge of development issues among our supporters and also a larger audience; the magazine can b
e found on-line and can be ordered free of charge in print or electronic form by anyone.The objective is to motivate Finnish people to support development cooperation, humanitarian assistance and participate in our advocacy work. One of the main objectives
 is to raise discussion and interest on development issues. Tekoja is also a tool for FCA&#x2019;s advocacy work and through the magazine FCA can transparently explain its ideas to decision-makers as well as to general audience. The aim is to strengthen FCA&#x2019;s
 networks in Finland and inspire our supporters and the general public by reporting about the results and achievements of development cooperation. The magazine provides materials and inspiration to parish staff and school teachers to support them to includ
e the themes of international diaconia and global education in their work. Activities and expected results:- The Tekoja magazine is published four times a year (February, April/May, September and December). Each number has 24 pages, with an average print r
un of 38 000. The magazine can also be found on-line.- The magazine is available for teachers in SubjectAid service. - Some of the content is shared on our webpages and through social media channels.- The magazine is available in our events.- Through Tekoj
a-magazine FCA participates in topical discussion in Finland.- As a result of active sharing and of good journalism, themes and stories presented by Tekoja are also picked up by journalists in Finnish media. At least one story in every issue is quoted by s
ome other media organisation. - As a result of innovative and topical analysis our experts and specialists are better known by Finnish media and by general audience. They are invited to speak in different occasions and interviewed in media.Target groups:  
The general public, parishes, teachers, journalists, decision-makers and FCA&#x2019;s supporters.Implementing partner:  FCA. Graphic design, printing and delivery as out-sourced services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-3" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finn Church Aid</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kirkon Ulkomaanavun S&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2015-2010100603" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99820" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisj&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;jen kehitysyhteisty&#xF6;lle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="H01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">116953</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2015-2010100603" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
