<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2015150827</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Mekong Energy and Ecology Network 2015-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During 2015-16, MEE Net will continue its ongoing activities such as capacity building, country power sector development advocacy and Community Centred- Strategic Environmental Assessment (C-SEA), and give more strategic priority to Salween trans-boundary 
advocacy and promoting Salween ethnic council. It works closely with Save the Mekong Coalition members to include energy and following the money trail dimensions into Mekong campaigns. MEE Net?s goal is to ensure that energy development in the Mekong regio
n is democratic, sustainable, economically rational, environmentally sound and socially just. MEE Net?s project objectives: 1) to add energy and finance factors analysis into the debate and campaign on hydropower dams in the Mekong, Salween and Irrawaddy, 
which have been focused on EIA framework, 2) to challenge centralized power sector planning based on large-scale and destructive energy infrastructure projects to increase public participation and transparency, 3) to build capacity among partner organizati
ons to enable them to undertake more effective advocacy and engage in energy policy reform, and 4) to strengthen the network of local communities, activists and researchers in Irrawaddy, Salween and Mekong, who are working on the C-SEA approach to dissemin
ate information and exchange strategies with the aim of increasing public participation and influencing policy planning. MEE Net?s capacity building activities will target to MEE Net?s network of partner organizations and energy/environment researchers and
 advocates throughout the Mekong region. 26 Irrawaddy communities on C-SEA, Salween ethnic council in China, Myanmar and Thailand, Save the Mekong Coalition, Salween research studies network of Universities in Salween basin and NGOs partners are project be
neficiaries. Other stakeholders also include local movements and groups, local people who are affected by power development projects, especially vulnerable groups. In addition, representatives from government, donors and development financing institutions 
are MEE Net?s target to advocate. Throughout the project period, MEE Net will act as a facilitator, coordinator and resource for its partner organizations, researchers and activists by monitoring power sector developments in the region, distributing inform
ation, communicating regularly through emails and using the website and by collaborating on projects where requested.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Siemenpuu</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Mekong region: Cambodia, China/Yunnan, Laos, Myanm"></location>
  <sector code="23110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">58218</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
