<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2014140088</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Cooperation for Women?s Economic Development (CWED)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Women?s Economic Development (CWED) project is aiming at women?s empowerment, economic development, and building their confidence to make decisions. The CWED project is a follow-up for the 4-year project ?Women: Hope and Growth? that established 24 Wom
en?s Agriculture Cooperatives (WAC) and built their capacity on governance, leadership and management, as well as technical skills of bookkeeping and business management. The project will promote entrepreneurship, continue to support vulnerable women to pl
ay an active role to lead and manage Agriculture Cooperatives and establish market linkages through value chain concepts. The project continues to build WACs capacity, while further strengthening the coordination with various stakeholders for additional su
pport and market linkages. The selection of the 12 WACs was done in late 2014, based on their potential to growth according to the result of the final evaluation of the WHG project and capacity assessment conducted after the completion of the project. The 
excepted results are:? Improved business capacity of women leaders in micro and small business group through provision of capacity building and mentoring on business plan to WAC management committee and small business groups and setting up the operational 
model for micro and small business groups.? Strengthen business networking of WACs and business actors and duty-bearers? Improve project staff capacity in providing business mentoring, Training course on the business and value chain based on the capacity a
ssessment aimed at passing on this knowledge and related skills to WACs.Rights-holders /beneficiaries: At least 2,331 direct beneficiaries who are the members of 12 WAC?s in 4 provinces will benefit from this project. Indirect beneficiaries are the familie
s of the WAC members and community residents. At least 80% of the direct beneficiaries are women.Implementing partner: Life with Dignity (LWD) is FCA?s long-term in Cambodia. LWD has good experience in implementing livelihood projects through rights based 
empowerment approach. The participation and community mobilisation experiences are the strengths of LWD.Technical or specialised institutes, especially on business sector, will be hired to conduct a series of capacity building and mentoring to agricultural
 cooperatives to ensure that the business plan and operation are smoothly applied and benefit AC members, particularly smallholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Provinces of Kampong Spue, Kampong Chhnang, Pursat"></location>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
