<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2014140893</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civic skills via media education in Palestine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at offering media literacy education to Palestinian non-governmental organization (NGO) practitioners journalists and municipality workers by arranging hands-on workshops and theoretical training on media literacy and the importance of med
ia ethics social media and marketing in the new media context.In Palestine where an enabling media system is still in its infancy professionally adopting new media tools is very challenging. The use of social media for information sharing and civic activis
m is very much on the rise in the area and there is wide demand for social media education among local media professionals. By arranging workshops and trainings in cooperation with Birzeit University&apos;s Media Development Center (MDC) responsible for the rec
ently developed Palestinian National Media Strategy different kinds of target groups can effectively be reached.Main goals of the project are:1. To encourage public debate as part of an open and democratic society and effective market economy. 2. To streng
then local participants? know-how and professionalism.3. As a result of the first two goals and as cross-cutting goal to promote equality democracy and human rights.These goals are formulated in cooperation with the MDC and are based on local needs and obj
ectives defined by local actors. The overall objective is to support Palestine not to be left out of the fast-paced development of global media. The project directly supports the implementation of the ground-breaking National Media Strategy.Main outputs of
 the project are:1. Training courses (with a distance learning option) on media literacy ethics tools and marketing in a social media context in two West Bank locations.2. Permanent online learning environment in Arabic and English.The concrete output of t
he project in addition to training courses is creation of a permanent open access learning environment where also a newly established Media Literacy Manual will be available both in Arabic and in English and can therefore be used for various situations reg
ardless of time and place. A print manual has successfully been used in MDC?s trainings. This manual however is somewhat obsolete and needs updating.Online material has almost unlimited dissemination potential and this would help us disseminate our project
 results outside the Palestinian Territories. (For more on the Finnish utilization of the results please see section on Dissemination).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Finnish Lifelong Learning Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">124345</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">124345</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
