<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2015150102</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Finnish Tax Administration&apos;s Technical Assistance to African Tax Administration Forum (ATAF)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The work on global tax agenda also from developing countries perspective is getting increasing attention. One of the most effective forms of support identified is the provision of technical expertise from experienced tax inspectors to developing countries&apos;
 tax administrations. Commissioned by the Ministry for Foreign Affairs the Finnish Tax Administration has launched technical assistance to the forum of African tax administrations ATAF in regional capacity and knowledge building. The Ministry for Foreign A
ffairs already supports ATAF with a 1 million euro core contribution for the period 2014-2016. Technical assistance (TA) provided by Finnish Tax Administration in 2015-2016 focused on applying new global tax rules and Base erosion and Profit Shifting work 
in the area of transfer pricing. Within the framework of ATAF assistance to its member countries the experts of Finnish Tax Administration (FTA) visited Namibia. During the first phase of cooperation the baseline situation and risk assessment were carried 
out and tax administrations drafted a work plan that Namibia is committed to. Plan included the establishment of large taxpayers (LTO Large Taxpayers Office) which was realized in 2015. Other results include training on transfer pricing and starting a syst
ematic collection of data on large taxpayers.The Ministry of Finance of Namibia Inland Revenue Department (IRD) requested ATAF and MFA Finland to continue the cooperation. In the next phase TA will focus on developing LTO&apos;s capacity.The objective is to int
roduce a risk analysis and based on that mobilize tax audits on large companies. In addition to Namibian Inland Revenue office ATAF will benefit from the experience the lessons learned of which become available to other ATAF member countries in similar sit
uation. Indirectly the project benefits citizens of Namibia in the form of increased tax revenue. MFA has reserved 300000 euros for the purpose to be used in 2016-2018.Core support to ATAf and complementary technical assistance is a cost effective way to s
trengthen taxation capacity in Africa and aligned with ATAF members&apos; priorities. Finnish Tax Administrations expert assistance to ATAF is part of the Finnish Tax and Development action plan and it complements the Finnish support to OECD-UNDP joint initiati
ve Tax Inspectors Without Borders. The chosen cooperation modality public institution assignment is the most reasonable way to continue the cooperation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="47141" ref="47141-1" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Tax Administration Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="29892383" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15114" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP3 is primary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">300000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">66027</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
