<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2016160192</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowerment of Women with Disabilities through peer groups and improvement of health services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has two main components: 1. Supporting wheelchair users in forming peer groups. The Emancipatory Disability Research (EDR) method is experimented for this purpose. 2. Strengthening the access of women with mobility impairments to health service
s during pregnancy and delivery.1. PEER SUPPORT. The main partner the Mongolian National Association of Wheelchair Users (MNAWU) has active members in Ulaanbaatar and in 5 regional branches. MNAWU would like to pilot in this project how to empower wheelcha
ir users themselves by giving them tools to solve their daily life situations by forming peer groups socialization and training of trainers. Some of the trainings take place in Ulaanbaatar but also training in the branch offices is necessary.A joint projec
t and MNAWU website is included in the project to connect to wheelchair users and to distribute information to them. (Please see appendix for a description of EDR methodology.)2. Equipping a MATERNITY WARD to enable mothers in wheelchairs to receive approp
riate health care during pregnancy and delivery . The lack of such a facility has been experienced as a significant problem by wheelchair-bound mothers. Trainings for medical staff about pregnancy and birth of women with disabilities is planned for this pu
rpose and also trainings for social workers. Based on our experiences we also want to send our recommendations to decision makers and discuss how the materials of the training and this service model can be used for policy development and implementation in 
Mongolia. Advocacy work is also important aspect of this project. Training will be given to local wheelchair users on themes such as how to influence government policy human rights and reproductive rights. The significant aim of this project is to have a c
ourse on disability included in the syllabus of the National Medical University. We will also produce material on reproductive health rights that can be used by local Disabled People&apos;s Organizations both during and after the project period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Evankelis-luterilainen Lahetysyhdistys Kylvaja ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">162353</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">166164</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">328517</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
