<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2014140782</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Groups of women producing and selling avocados in Guatemala</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Guatemala indigenous peoples and women are both vulnerable groups. It is especially important to improve the education and income level of women living in the countryside. When the income and the skills increase their opinions also need to be taken bett
er into consideration in the society and families.The project which is currently applied for is based on the best results of the previous 2012-2013 co-operation projet between AMEU and SYL. The direct beneficiaries of the project are the 30 indigenous maya
 women in the project areas of the previous project and 120 women in two new project municipalities: Acatenango and Parramos.The long-term objective of this project is to improve the social status and income of women. The direct objective of the project he
lps to achieve that: Women are able to start selling the Hass avocados in the previous and later in new project municipalities and receive income. These objectives are reached by the following results:1.The avocado nurseries are established and used2. Wome
n have the theoretical knowledge and practical skills necessary to grow Hass avocados.2. Women have the knowledge and the skills to turn avocados into commercial products.Thus the women aqcuire the knowledge and skills to establish avocado nurseries and ta
ke care of the plants which are completed with skills to commercialise avocados. In addition the nurseries will be established.The women participate in key project activities the regular trainings by AMEU. The theoretical and practical sessions are divided
 into modules.This way AMEU wants to create a training model which could be replicated.The cross-cutting objectives are in line with the project: The project attempts to increase gender-equality by showing indegenous peoples&apos; women means to increase their 
income. This would diminish the differences in income in an environmentally sustainable way.Trees absorb carbon dioxide and bind the land that is vulnerable for erosion. The project has a human rights based approach as the project aims at improving womens&apos;
 possibilities to decide on their own matters and to create income and thus to implement womens&apos; rights. On the other hand they have the duty to do their share and the local administration has obligations towards the women. Diveristy is respected and the p
roject attempts to reduce discrimination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen ylioppilaskuntien liitto ry.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">49582</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">46272</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">49582</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
