<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2013130306</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A profession for all: professional training for countryside women - Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Phase II of the project addresses women owners of micro-enterprises in the rural areas in order to strengthen their socio-economic capacities by offering them capacity building and professional training that will strengthen their economic stability. In ord
er to take preventive action due to increasing migration of youth from rural areas in to the cities a training program addressing young women and girls will be also implemented.The project will be implemented in 24 months. During the first three months the
 action will be launched among stakeholders the material will be further elaborated some team members will be recruited and cooperation agreements will be signed. Awareness campaigns will be done during 9 months every year. The training program will be del
ivered twice following the academic year calendar: vocational training program (9 months) entrepreneurship (3 months) and soft skills (6 modules of 1 month). The CSO?s trainings will be delivered in the villages on the first year. And the second year the t
hree selected projects will receive the sub-granted and will be implemented. The activities will be the following:1- Implementation of a professional training program in the sectors of Tourism and Hospitality Management through a competency based vocationa
l training program (800 hours) a modular training of Entrepreneurship (100 hours) and a work experience internship (400 hours) in the Institute of Management and Services (IMS) in Maad- Jbeil.2- Implementation of 2 cycles an Intensive Entrepreneurial Train
ing Program in ?Professionalization of rural micro-businesses in rural areas? of 20 hours implemented in local rural areas. Each cycle includes 5 workshops of 4 hours each, participants will get practical managerial and financial tools such as Financial ki
t completed written Business plan and Entrepreneurship workbook.3- Implementation of 8 awareness campaigns in schools and 1 orientation session in IMS for a total of 150 young girls towards orienting them to the sectors of Tourism and Hospitality Services 
as new sources of job opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-Cultur ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-03-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">37500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">37500</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">75000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
