<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2014141159</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Protection of the Ecology and the Environment in Tiruvannamalai District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aim is to enhance the skills and capacities of Dalit and Tribal communities on lobbying and advocacy for assertion of their traditional rights, to sensitize the communities on issues pertaining to the environmental degradation of the base of li
velihoods, and to mobilize them to address those issues and protect the ecology and environment collectively. Project activities are: Baseline study of Conservation Protection and Management Plans with two studies, Local sensitization on Conservation and M
anagement Plans, Sensitizing the community on and involving them on promotion of ecology, 4. Capacity building workshops for cadres on environmental legislation, Promoting sustainable agriculture, Formation of Environment Protection Forum /EcoClubs, Streng
thening the existing platform of Dalit women movement and other movements, Strengthening the community on advocacy for policy decisions, Lobbying carried out with the officials and policy makers regarding the implementation of the projects that are infring
ement to the rights of the communities, Issue based (need based) campaigns like petitions, media work and demonstrations, Review meetings for compiling the results and improvements. RWDS was established in 1985 and it works for protection and promotion of 
the comprehensive rights of the Dalit and tribal women and children of Tiruvannamalai district. The main focus of the organisation has been sustainable environment and protection of the livelihood rights. The organisation is run by women. It has received f
unding from many local and foreign donors, including the Embassy of Netherlands, HIVOS and Siemenpuu. RWDS has cooperated with many local NGOs and networks, including VCDS and JASuL.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Siemenpuu</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Tamil Nadu state, Tiruvannamalai district"></location>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">33</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
