<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2016-2006060115</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan, UNDP, Law and Order Trust Fund (LOTFA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finland provides financial support to the Law and Order Trust Fund for Afghanistan (LOTFA) established by the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) in 2002. LOTFA has been the most important funding channel supporting and reforming the police forces 
in Afghanistan. The current phase VIII is ongoing until the end of 2016.LOTFA consists of two Projects. One Project the Support to Payroll Management Project provides exclusively for full MOIA payroll management. The second LOTFA Project is centred on deve
loping national capacity for self-sustained reform and improvement of the MOIA as an institution and the police services as instruments for citizen safety and maintenance of the rule of law.LOTFA continues to administer the funds for the payment of salarie
s of more than 150000 Afghan National Police officers and over 6000 uniformed personnel employed by the Central Prisons Department and develops electronic pay roll system. Based on the results of LOTFA&apos;s previous phases 87% of payees are paid through elect
ronic transfer directly to their bank accounts. The remaining 13% live in areas without access to banking services and so are paid in cash through a ?trusted agent? system which is also now subject to much more rigorous oversight under the new project. LOT
FA supports MOIA reforms that include focus on capacity building and accountability and development of national institutions including support to updating laws. LOTFA supports MOIA to improve training infrastructure for police professionalization and provi
des support to police service delivery and outreach activities to develop public services and Police Women Councils. Support is provided also to the training and retention of female police and the creation of a safe and supportive working environment for m
ale and female officers.Finland?s support to LOTFA is EUR 45 million in 2016 and between 2007 and 2015 the financing has been a total of EUR 1135 million. The overall budget for phase VIII is US$ 883561564. Donors are: Australia Canada Denmark the EU Finla
nd Germany Italy Japan the Netherlands New Zealand Norway the Republic of Korea Switzerland the United Kingdom and the United States.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="41114" ref="41114-2" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="62505101" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-07-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">4000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">4500000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
