<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25898</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEF Azel Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azerbaijan Electronics (Azel or the company), a joint-stock company owned by two systems integration engineers, is one of the most successful computer and office equipment suppliers and systems integrators in Azerbaijan.  The companys main clientele is in the corporate sector and its main lines of business, all of which are related to the procurement, supply and maintenance of computers and office equipment, include:   - systems integration;  - retail;  - post-sale service;  - software development; and  - computer assembling.  The project is to secure the necessary basic physical infrastructure for the company to develop and grow in a conducive business environment by way of the following main project components:   - purchase of 1,300m2 of new office space, currently under development, in the center of Baku; and  - expansion of the companys computer/office equipment retail network to four stores by purchasing two new locations of 150m2 each.    Total project cost is expected to be $5.1 million, and IFC has been requested to provide an A Loan of $2.5 million, with the balance to be financed by new equity and internal resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will have the following key development impact for the following stakeholders:  - Consumers:   Through improved retail network, the project will bring closer and better service to the customers.  - Employees:   The project will significantly improve the working conditions of existing staff who are currently working in an old run-down leased Soviet-era building; and will help the company create about 40-50 new permanent jobs in the next several years.  - People:  The project will help a local company which supplies small businesses and home users with lower cost locally assembled computers.  This will stimulate further computer penetration and lead to higher education, employment opportunities, economic growth and income generation.  - Demonstration effect:   Azeri enterprise sector is in its early stages of development and most companies have significant room to improve their corporate governance regimes.  The project will help Azel upgrade its business practices, by, among other things, adopting international accounting standards.  The adoption of more rigorous business standards will provide an example to other companies in the sector.  - Corporate Governance:   Azel was selected as a pilot of IFCs corporate governance program.  IFC will assist the company become more transparent and advise on improvements in corporate governance thereby assisting it with its goal of raising finance in international markets.  The project will help establish a secure foundation of basic infrastructure to permit the company to grow and develop, including in neighboring markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AZERBAIJAN ELECTRONICS CJSC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25898" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-08-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-11-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Igor I. Yakovenko, President Azerbaijan Electronics 5th Floor, 65 Fizuli Street Baku AZ1014, Azerbaijan Republic  Telephone: +(99412) 497 4040 Fax: +(99412) 497 4042 E-mail:    IY@azel.net</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azerbaijan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AZ-Azerbaijan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main aspect of the project entails the purchase of the 1,300 m2 new office space of the company that makes up the second floor of a brand new building that is currently under construction near the center of Baku. The building will be one of the modern ones in the city, and will have convenient access to the main streets of the city. The company currently continues its headquarter operations from an old, run down, Soviet-era building that can no longer match the companys needs. Both of the companys two retail stores are located in the center of the City of Baku, near most of the economic activity. Specific sites for the purchase of additional two retail stores are also expected to center around heavier pedestrian traffic in urban areas.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.5000000000 47.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Other Services (Including IT Enabled Services)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $2.70 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-08-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-08-13">2700000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-08-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-08-13">2700000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AZERBAIJAN ELECTRONICS CJSC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25898/sef-azel-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
