<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-24867</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rabita MSME Line</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rabitabank (Rabitabank or the Bank) is a medium-sized commercial bank based in Baku, Azerbaijan, focused on providing financing to Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises (MSMEs) in Azerbaijan.  Rabitabank had equity of $9 mln and total assets of $43 mln as of the end-June 2006.   Rabitabank was established in 1993 by public sector companies controlled by the Ministry of Communications in order to provide new banking services to communications sector companies. Since then the Bank was privatized and currently 97% privately owned.  Since its formation, Rabitabank managed to expand to 12 branches throughout Azerbaijan, diversify its client base beyond what originally used to be a mainly communications sector niche.  Today the Bank provides a full range of banking services, including corporate banking, retail banking and trade finance.  However, the primary focus of the Bank from the outset has always been MSMEs and the Bank has identified the MSME sector as their primary target market in their long-term strategy.  

The Bank became IFCs client in 1998 after receiving the first $400 thousand credit line fully repaid by now.  Subsequently Rabitabank received the second $1.2 million credit line in 2003 with currently outstanding amount of $900 thousand. The previous loans and technical assistance provided as an integral part of the investments helped the Bank to grow its balance sheet and become a profitable medium-sized bank focused on the MSME sector. 

In order to grow further, the Bank approached IFC with a request to provide a new loan in order to expand further its lending to MSMEs.  

IFC is considering a new credit line Loan to Rabitabank up to $2 million with a convertible option.  The long term funding would allow the Bank to strengthen its balance sheet in view of the expected expansion and increased demand for funding from MSMEs, entrepreneurs and individuals.  The investment will be accompanied by targeted technical assistance to contribute to the institutional capacity building of the Bank and improve such areas as Risk Management, Strategic Planning, and MIS.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank Group strategy in Azerbaijan is to support diversified economic growth and maintain macroeconomic stability, as a necessary condition for reducing poverty.  In recent years, Azerbaijan has achieved strong economic growth largely as a result of oil sector development and high international oil prices.  The World Bank Group strategy is focused on achieving balanced development in the non-oil sector across Azerbaijan&apos;s regions.  Sustainable economic development can be achieved if driven by a dynamic private enterprise sector outside the oil sector and stronger financial sector intermediaries, supported by a more streamlined efficient and transparent public sector.  Within this context, IFCs strategy in Azerbaijan is focused on broadening financing opportunities for MSMEs linked with as well as outside the oil and gas sector and financial sector development.

This project is highly complementary to the World Bank Group country strategy. The project will enable IFC to play a tangible role in promoting MSME development in Azerbaijan by supporting an MSME focused medium-sized local bank willing to improve it risk management practices, structures and procedures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OPEN JOINT STOCK COMPANY RABITABANK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-24867" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-04-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Zakir Nuriyev, Chairman of the Supervisory Council
1, B. Sardarov Str.
Baku, Republic of Azerbaijan, AZ 1001
Telephone: +994 12 4925761 or +994 12  4926157
Fax: +994 12 4971 101 or +994 12 4972462</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azerbaijan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AZ-Azerbaijan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Bank operates in the Republic of Azerbaijan and headquartered in the capital city of Baku.  The Bank has 12 branches throughout Azerbaijan and the majority of operations are concentrated in Baku.  The Bank will use the IFC investments for financing MSMEs throughout Azerbaijan.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.5000000000 47.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5221" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Commercial Banking - General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $2.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2007-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-03-15">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-03-15">2000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OPEN JOINT STOCK COMPANY RABITABANK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/24867/rabita-msme-line">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
