<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/FS/NGO/17127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing adverse affects of disasters on the lives and livelihoods of the vulnerable population  of district Pishin at Balochistan province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To assess the need of district Pishin the selection of UCs were based on the criteria fall under VAM report and targeting people residing border areas and afghan refugee population. VAM finding shows that Buying power of most of the common people is very low. Traders sell on credit as well, since many of the of the residents cannot afford to buy on cash. About 43 percent of the traders sell more than 50 percent of their sales on credit, VAM also suggest that  cash interventions would be preferred option. The report also shows that Saranan and Barshore and prioritized tehsils of the area.  Overall, prices are controlled by the traders in the bigger markets from where the smaller/local markets get their supplies. While in local markets, prices are generally set by traders themselves - after adjusting their minor profit margins. WESS also interacted with UNHCR to finalize the case load of population of afghan refugees  of the target area of Saranan. 

WESS RNA is also inline with VAM finding.  The RNA revealed that overall, around 42% of households have &#x2018;acceptable food consumption&#x2019;. Overall, the proportion of all surveyed households with moderate dietary diversity , and major HH have no experience of hunger. WESS RNA also illustrates that access to market is not a major issue. The availability of commodities in the markets is  sufficient but buying capacity is week of poor livestock holders, while 50% reported inadequate agriculture inputs. Common coping strategies is to contract debt for the household&#x2019;s immediate needs like agriculture inputs. WESS RNA also indicate that moderate level of reduction in family income.  Women role comprise working at home, caring livestock, embroidery work by some women for income. Women cannot take decision to use money they earn. Gender violence in lock down was increased due to presence of male at home.  women need support to involved in livelihood activities and be awared on their rights.  The assessment revealed that overall, around 22% of households have &#x2018;acceptable food consumption&#x2019;, 18% have &#x2018;poor consumption&#x2019; and another 60% have &#x2018;borderline consumption. Overall, the proportion of all surveyed households with low dietary diversity was 26%, rest falls in medium diet diversity 59% HH have no experience hunger, 18% have slight hunger, 21% feel moderate hunger whereas 2% faced sever hunger. Overall, about 46% of the surveyed households have to travel more than 20 km to buy food and non-food items from the nearest markets, whereas 17% of the households have to travel 11 to 20 km to the nearest markets, while 37% have to travel less than 10 km to reach to the nearest markets. Same is distance to livestock input markets. The availability of commodities in the markets is a significant problem for families keeping livestock as about 57% of the livestock holders reported &#x2018;inadequate availability&#x2019; of livestock inputs, while 62% reported inadequate agriculture inputs.. one of the common coping strategies was to contract debt for the household&#x2019;s immediate needs. borrowed amount is for survival of life.. 

Highly vulnerable food insecure population will be targeted for the proposed project. This will be in accordance with VAM and food security cluster and PHPF vulnerability priority criteria in 02 tehsils Saranan and Barshore.  WESS will focus around 17500 households of district Pishin . The families will be supported through different activities with the objective to address immediate food insecurity problems. Protection is mainstreamed to help reduce risks or harm to the beneficiaries. District Pishin has been prioritized and appeared in most vulnerable category  due to lockdown and putting additional pressure on  food security situation following various shocks resulting from consecutive climate related hazards like droughts, snowfall and locust swarms etc.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amanullah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager ME</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>923073730613</telephone>
   <email>amanullah@wess.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghulam Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager Finance</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>92812863826</telephone>
   <email>ghulam_ali@wess.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Naseebullah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager Program and Operation</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03008384573</telephone>
   <email>naseebullah@wess.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balochistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.32720000 65.89310000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-24">185792.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-24">238340.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-17127">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-24">424132.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304752199">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-01">339306.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305037496">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">84826.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
