<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-20/DDA-3474/PAK/WASH/INGO/17444</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH assistance to flood affected families of District Mirpurkhas, Sindh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The planned intervention, led by NCA with Research and Development Organization (RDF) as implementing partner, will address emergency WASH needs of the flood affected families in 4 Union Councils, named Hingorono, Tajo Khaskheli, Makhan Samoo, and Ismail jo Goth of District Mirpurkhas, Sindh. Prior coordination is established with PHPF partner in Mirpurkhas for equitable geographic distribution of targeted areas. Rapid need assessment in the field by NCA and RDF has helped to validate the secondary data available from NDMA and PDMA. The proposed humanitarian action will provide WASH assistance to support 35,850 individuals (men 6,535, women 6,415, boys 11,525, girls 11,375) and 5,121 families. Response plan includes continued operationalization of two mobile water treatment units with the capacity of daily assisting 5,000 individuals through provision of clean drinking water. Ease of access to clean drinking water will be ensured through water tankering in flood affected areas through installation of 30 water storage tanks at key locations. 4,000 jerry cans / buckets would also be provided to flood affected families for safe storage of water. For sustainable water supply, repair of 20 damaged hand pumps will be undertaken in flood affected areas. There are villages where it is possible to repair hand pumps, as some water has receded from some villages but due to rain the pumps are damaged. Rain and flood affected out of order hand pumps will be selected for repair.  Sanitation needs of the most affected families, specifically women, girls, children and disabled, will be met through installation of 80 Ventilated Improved Pit latrines at communal and household levels. Towards hygiene promotion, NCA and RDF will distribute 4,000 hygiene kits at household level coupled with 2 hygiene promotion trainings/campaigns at communal level. Families living in make shift arrangements, govt camps and flood affected villages will be given the kits, including vulnerable groups like agriculture farmers belonging to minorities, women led families, and child led families will be selected. 
Carpet coverage will be given in case of camps and, villages populated by landless poor families. 80 camp cleaning kits and 680 debris removal kits to WASH committees and volunteers (youth) would be provided. Also, from protection from malarial and vector borne disease, 3,250 mosquito nets are planned to be distributed among most vulnerable families. In addition, protection of the most vulnerable families will be ensured through provision of 350 tarpaulin sheets. 
The provision of technical advice and supervision by NCA and its partner staff will also enable the beneficiaries to meet their other emergency needs for future. Targeted beneficiaries will be encouraged to adopt improved hygiene practices, including menstrual hygiene management.
NCA and RDF will ensure equitable assistance of different age and gender groups as per their needs. For example, women&#x2019;s inclusion in selection of water point and sanitation facilities will be ensured through utilization of already formed women WASH committees. Also, prioritization of elderly, disabled and children will be emphasized during communities&#x2019; mobilization and sensitization sessions. 
This proposed relief action addresses the immediate WASH needs of women, girls, men and boys of different ages and people with disabilities. The intervention provides access to them to safe drinking water, sanitation facilities separately for women and men to protect their dignity. Hygiene kit items are also designed considering gender. The participation and protection of women, girls and children will also be taken care during distribution process. Female hygiene promoters are also proposed to be hired to take care of women needs and their participation in the activities. Further, the location of transitional latrines will also be selected considering the privacy of the women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research amp; Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anne Masterson</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0518317406</telephone>
   <email>Anne.Masterson@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sajjad.Ali@nca.no</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0518317406</telephone>
   <email>Sajjad.Ali@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shah Khalid</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator CR WASH</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>03468562310</telephone>
   <email>Shah.Khalid@nca.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK8">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sindh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00970000 68.77360000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">186813.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">13186.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-17444">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">199999.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304804197">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-23">199999.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Church Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
