<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="49" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13856" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-SOLID-DO-15-13856</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominican Republic and Haiti: Building Worker Demand for Strengthened Rule of Law</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the Dominican Republic (DR), the Solidarity Center promotes workers&#x2019; awareness of their rights&#x2014;including to be paid their full wages and work in a safe environment&#x2014;and supports their right to demand enforcement of laws designed to protect them. The Solidarity Center works with local organizations to promote union-driven advocacy for better working conditions and the protection of rights for workers and their families in compliance with Dominican law. In Haiti, the Solidarity Center builds trade union capacity to organize and democratically represent the interests of Haitian garment workers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Solidarity Center provides guidance to unions as they educate and organize workers to advocate for expanded protections for migrant workers and government compliance with international human rights law. In the Dominican Republic, the Solidarity Center organizes workshops with migrant workers, Dominican workers of Haitian descent, and Dominican labor and community leaders to raise awareness of the rights they have as workers under Dominican law. This training program includes the distribution of educational materials in both Spanish and Creole about worker rights and the contributions of migrant workers to Dominican society. The Solidarity Center also accompanies migrant workers throughout the current &#x201C;regularization&#x201D; process, as well as brings together labor and migrant rights leaders and major media outlets. In Haiti, the Solidarity Center legal support as trade unions file for registration and remediate rights abuses. The Solidarity Center also conducts leadership trainings for new and existing union leaders to strengthen their capacity to manage as their unions continue to develop.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AUMOHD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federacion Nacional de Vendedores de los Mercados (FENAVEMER)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Endowment for Democracy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Federation of Workers in the Construction, Wood and Construction Materials Industries (FENTICOMMC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-52-1984713" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarity Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SOLID-DO-15-13856" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarity Center</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.solidaritycenter.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="DO" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Democracy and Governance</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
