<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="49" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13984" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-SOLID-MZ-11-13984</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Labor Program: Africa Regional</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tailored to each country or region&#x2014;and reaching workers in garment factories, home service, seafood processing, mining, agriculture, informal marketplaces, manufacturing, the public sector and beyond&#x2014;USAID-funded Solidarity Center programs:

Support the development and strengthening of independent labor unions and other labor-related organizations in their efforts to support and enhance democratization, equitable economic development and a democratic political culture by promoting effective citizen participationDevelop and strengthen national and local union leadership and programmatic capacity, including encouraging internal leadership opportunities for women and youthImprove the institutional and financial capacity of labor unions and labor civil society organizationsStrengthen the observance of internationally recognized core labor standards by advocating their adoption into law and regulation and promoting effective enforcement once adopted.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with more than 300 labor unions, pro-worker nongovernmental organizations, legal aid groups, human rights defenders, women&apos;s associations, and advocacy coalitions around the world, in more than sixty countries&#x2014;including South Africa and Zimbabwe&#x2014;Solidarity Center&apos;s professional staff of more than 200 support and stand in solidarity with social-change activists around the world as they strive to build a global network of worker rights defenders and exercise their rights, including organizing for safer work sites, demanding living wages and improving laws (and the enforcement of existing laws) that protect working people, and fighting exploitation and abuse, and stand as a force for shared prosperity and inclusive economic development.

Under the Global Labor Program&#x2014;a five-year cooperative effort by the Solidarity Center and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to promote worker rights, gender equality and democracy worldwide&#x2014;Solidarity Center&#x2019;s Africa regional program provides training, mentorship and legal support to mine workers, farm workers, migrant workers and working women, with an emphasis on strengthening labor protections, improving access to justice for migrant workers and promoting gender equality in the workplace.

Learn more about Solidarity Center&apos;s work in Africa</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-52-1984713" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarity Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SOLID-MZ-11-13984" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarity Center</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.solidaritycenter.org/</website>
   <website>http://www.solidaritycenter.org/where-we-work/africa</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="9" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Democracy and Governance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="19" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mining and Extractive Resources</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.solidaritycenter.org/where-we-work/africa">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
