<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011755-03-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">La filiera della moringa per lo sviluppo delle comunita&apos; rurali in SNNPR - Art. 7 L. 125/2014</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the Ethiopian context, the links between agriculture, agroindustry development, gender and nutrition have important implications on poverty reduction, biodiversity conservation and environmental sustainability; therefore, rural women&apos;s role is critical and necessary in all development agendas. This project is aimed at building on the achievements of the initial pilot phase implemented by UNIDO, to scale-up moringa production &amp; productivity (M. stenopetala and M. oleifera), strengthen the value chain through integrated utilization of natural resources, and improve value addition through processing and marketing in a sustainable way. To realize its objectives, the project will focus on improving food and nutritional security and livelihood of rural households, targeting especially rural women, through the development of an inclusive and sustainable moringa Value Chain. In particular, the project will: i) Enhance sustainable production and productivity of moringa through integrated utilization of natural resources; ii) Improve value addition of moringa through processing and marketing of moringa products; iii) Strengthen a nutrition-sensitive moringa value chain through inclusive agri-food systems, promotion of nutritious products and a conducive enabling environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Nel contesto etiope, i legami tra agricoltura, sviluppo dell&apos;agroindustria, genere e alimentazione hanno importanti implicazioni sulla riduzione della povert&#xE0;, sulla conservazione della biodiversit&#xE0; e sulla sostenibilit&#xE0; ambientale; pertanto, il ruolo delle donne nelle aree rurali &#xE8; fondamentale e necessario in tutti i programmi di sviluppo. Questo progetto mira a basarsi sui risultati della fase pilota iniziale implementata da UNIDO, per aumentare la produzione e la produttivit&#xE0; della moringa (M. stenopetala e M. oleifera), rafforzare la catena del valore attraverso l&apos;utilizzo integrato delle risorse naturali e migliorare il valore aggiunta attraverso l&apos;elaborazione e la commercializzazione in modo sostenibile. Per realizzare i suoi obiettivi, il progetto si concentrer&#xE0; sul miglioramento della sicurezza alimentare e nutrizionale e del sostentamento delle famiglie rurali, indirizzato in particolare alle donne rurali, attraverso lo sviluppo di una catena del valore moringa inclusiva e sostenibile. In particolare, il progetto dovr&#xE0;: i) migliorare la produzione e la produttivit&#xE0; sostenibili della moringa attraverso l&apos;utilizzo integrato delle risorse naturali; ii) migliorare l&apos;aggiunta di valore della moringa attraverso la trasformazione e la commercializzazione dei prodotti della moringa; iii) Rafforzare una catena del valore della moringa sensibile all&apos;alimentazione attraverso sistemi agroalimentari inclusivi, promozione di prodotti nutrienti e un ambiente favorevole favorevole.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="12001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="12001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="12001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRY OF FINANCE ETHIOPIA ALT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011755/03/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31191" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education or training</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people and persons with disabilities, and equal pay for work of equal value</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end all forms of malnutrition, including achieving, by 2025, the internationally agreed targets on stunting and wasting in children under 5&#xA0;years of age, and address the nutritional needs of adolescent girls, pregnant and lactating women and older persons</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-17">1000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRY OF FINANCE ETHIOPIA ALT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-05">443165</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRY OF FINANCE ETHIOPIA ALT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011755-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011755-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011755-04-1" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
