<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011400-01-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Sviluppo inclusivo e sostenibile delle filiere agricole in Oromia e SNNPR - gestione diretta</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Questa iniziativa mira a contribuire alla modernizzazione dell&apos;agricoltura e allo sviluppo del settore agroindustriale in Etiopia migliorando in modo sostenibile la produttivit&#xE0; e gli standard qualitativi di determinate catene del valore agricole in Oromia e SNNPR . L&apos;iniziativa si concentra sulle catene strategiche del valore agricolo nelle zone di approvvigionamento di materie prime agricole di due parchi agricoli integrati: rispettivamente grano e pomodoro da lavorazione in Oromia, avocado e ananas in SNNPR. Queste materie prime sono state definite prioritarie dal Ministero etiopico dell&apos;agricoltura e delle risorse naturali, in consultazione con le autorit&#xE0; regionali, l&apos;Agenzia italiana per la cooperazione allo sviluppo e la FAO. La selezione si basa anche sugli studi di fattibilit&#xE0; dei due parchi agro-industriali integrati, che hanno identificato le catene agro-valore pi&#xF9; promettenti nelle due zone di approvvigionamento dei Parchi. L&apos;iniziativa sar&#xE0; strutturata secondo sei componenti principali: 1) lo sviluppo di capacit&#xE0; di attori pubblici e privati lungo le catene del valore; 2) lo sviluppo delle agro-infrastrutture e della connettivit&#xE0; rurale; 3) il miglioramento dell&apos;accesso al credito e ai servizi finanziari per le catene di valore selezionate; 4) genere; 5) agricoltura sensibile alla nutrizione; e 6) la gestione sostenibile delle risorse naturali. La prima componente sar&#xE0; rivolta a soggetti pubblici e privati a diversi livelli delle catene del valore: istituti di ricerca, fornitori di input, servizi di estensione, organizzazioni di produttori, fornitori di servizi come raccolta, trasporto, valutazione e conservazione e agro-processori. Questi attori saranno rafforzati nelle loro capacit&#xE0; organizzative, tecniche e di orientamento strategico / commerciale. La seconda componente sar&#xE0; incentrata sulla connettivit&#xE0; rurale e lo sviluppo delle agro-infrastrutture, al fine di migliorare le capacit&#xE0; di aggregazione, trasporto, stoccaggio e trattamento e conservazione nonch&#xE9; i flussi di informazione lungo le catene del valore (strade, ponti, impianti di stoccaggio, pre- impianti di refrigerazione, celle frigorifere e congelatori, impianti di classificazione e imballaggio, macchinari e attrezzature per la lavorazione primaria, unit&#xE0; di elaborazione mobili, veicoli di trasporto refrigerati / specializzati, pacchi, attrezzature per la lavorazione, centri di prova, centri di analisi del mercato e mercato sistemi di informazione e tecnologia dell&apos;informazione e della comunicazione). La terza componente si concentrer&#xE0; sul miglioramento dei servizi finanziari per le catene del valore agricole rafforzando il dialogo tra gli attori che rappresentano l&apos;offerta e la domanda; fornendo assistenza tecnica per la progettazione e l&apos;attuazione di nuovi prodotti finanziari (ovvero leasing, finanziamento collateralizzato su merci e assicurazione contro gli agenti atmosferici basata su indici); e fornendo un supporto finanziario selettivo ai sistemi di assicurazione contro gli agenti atmosferici basati su indici. La quarta componente sar&#xE0; incentrata sulla promozione della partecipazione delle donne nelle catene del valore, in particolare nelle cooperative agricole e nel settore agro-alimentare. Il quinto componente garantir&#xE0; che la dieta dei produttori e delle loro famiglie sar&#xE0; migliorata e diversificata. Infine, la sesta componente, affronter&#xE0; la gestione sostenibile delle risorse naturali. Sar&#xE0; prestata particolare attenzione al fine di migliorare la fertilit&#xE0; del suolo, gestire le risorse di managewater e conservare la biodiversit&#xE0;. Complessivamente, le azioni intraprese contribuiranno alla modernizzazione del settore agricolo creando catene di valore agricole efficienti, efficaci, inclusive e sostenibili, orientate al soddisfacimento dei requisiti della domanda di mercato esistente e potenziale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This initiative aims to contribute to the modernization of agriculture and the development of the agro-industrial sector in Ethiopia by sustainably improving the productivity and the quality standards of selected agricultural value chains in Oromia and Southern Nations, Nationalities, and Peoples&apos; Region (SNNPR).The initiative targets strategic agricultural value chains in the Agro-Commodities Procurement Zones of two Integrated Agro-Industrial Parks: respectively wheat and processing tomato in Oromia, avocado and pineapple in SNNPR. These commodities have been prioritized by the Ethiopian Ministry of Agriculture and Natural Resources, in consultation with the regional authorities, the Italian Agency for Development Cooperation, and FAO. The selection is based as well on the Feasibility Studies of the two Integrated Agro-Industrial Parks, which identified the most promising agri-value chains in the two procurement zones of the Parks.The initiative will be structured along six main components: 1) the capacity building of public and private actors along the value chains; 2) the development of agro-infrastructure and rural connectivity; 3) the improvement of access to credit and financial services for the selected value chains; 4) gender; 5) nutrition-sensitive agriculture; and 6) the sustainable management of natural resources.The first component will target private and public actors at different levels of the value chains: researchinstitutes, input providers, extension services, producers&#x2019; organisations, providers of services like collection, transportation, grading and storage, and agro-processors. These actors will be strengthened in their organisational, technical, and strategic/business orientation capacities.The second component will focus on rural connectivity and development of agro-infrastructure,in order to improve the aggregation, transport, storage and processing and conservation capacities as well as the information flows along the value chains (roads, bridges, storage facilities, pre-cooling facilities; cold storage units and deep freezers; grading and packing facilities; primary processing machinery and equipment; mobile processing units; refrigerated/specialized transport vehicles; pack-houses; processing equipment; testing centres; training centres; market intelligence cells, and market information systems and information and communication technology).The third component will focus on the improvement of financial services for agricultural value chains bystrengthening the dialogue between actors representing the supply and demand; by providing technical assistance for the design and implementation of new financial products (namely leasing, commodity collateralised finance, and index-based weather insurance); and by providing selective financial support to index-based weather insurance schemes.The fourth component will focus on promoting the participation of women in the value chains, especially in the agricultural cooperatives and in the agro-processing sector. The fifth component will ensure that the diet of producers and their households will be improved and diversified. Finally, the sixth component, will address sustainable management of natural resources. Specific attention will be given in order to improve soil fertility, to managewater resources, and to conserve biodiversity.Overall, the actions undertaken will contribute to the modernization of the agricultural sector by creating efficient, effective, inclusive and sustainable agricultural value chains, oriented toward the satisfaction of the requirements of the existing and potential market demand. This in turn will constitute an enabling factor for the establishment of the Integrated Agro-Industrial Parks in Central-Eastern Oromia and in Eastern SNNPR, where the agro-manufacturing enterprises will be located.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011400/01/2" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018000168" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31150" percentage="40" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural inputs</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agro-industries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end all forms of malnutrition, including achieving, by 2025, the internationally agreed targets on stunting and wasting in children under 5&#xA0;years of age, and address the nutritional needs of adolescent girls, pregnant and lactating women and older persons</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, eradicate extreme poverty for all people everywhere, currently measured as people living on less than $1.25 a day</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, reduce at least by half the proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End poverty in all its forms everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-11">750000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-03">217837.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-23">198410.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-04">305565.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-19">7554</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://openaid.aics.gov.it/activity_attachment/5878%20-%20Delibera-119-Etiopia.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delibera del Direttore</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="IT"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://openaid.aics.gov.it/activity_attachment/4104%20-%20Schema%20Proposta%20di%20finanziamento%20-%20FINALE.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposta di Finanziamento</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="IT"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://openaid.aics.gov.it/activity_attachment/4102%20-%20AGREEMENT%20-%20Oromia%20and%20SNNPR%20Value%20Chain%20Project.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
   <language code="IT"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-011400-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
