<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011881-01-5</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Tecnologie sostenibili per l&apos;accesso all&apos;acqua potabile e miglioramento dell&apos;efficienza energetica delle comunit&#xE0; Rurali in 8 Woreda dell&apos;Etiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto mira a dare un contributo importante ai servizi di base 1.Assicurando accesso ad acqua pulita al 10% della popolazione tramite 103 nuovi impianti e la riattivazione di altri 100; 2.Avviando una campagna, insieme al personale sanitario deputato, per promuovere l&apos;uso delle latrine mirando a raggiungere il 20% delle famiglie; Provvedere acqua pulita a 30 scuole e sanitation adeguata ad altre 10. Promuovendo un ruolo pro-attivo delle comunit&#xE0; stesse Assicurer&#xE0; la sostenibilit&#xE0; delle strutture idriche rafforzando la capacit&#xE0; delle comunit&#xE0; di gestire, formando 1.211 membri di comitati di gestione, 406 addetti alla cura e manutenzione, 18 artigiani locali per manutenzioni straordinarie. Gli Uffici Idrici di Woreda svolgono un ruolo strategico di congiunzione con il territorio ed &#xE8; fondamentale che si dotino di strumenti adeguati per mappare il territorio, sia gli impianti esistenti che le potenzialit&#xE0;, costruendo un database che consenta di gestire adeguatamente i dati del loro territorio. Il software consentir&#xE0; anche agli uffici Regionali di accedere ai dati delle diverse Woreda che lo utilizzano e potranno anche, promuoverne l&apos;adozione presso altre Woreda, ampliando la rete di informazioni su tutta la Regione, senza costi aggiuntivi. Le Universit&#xE0; di Arba Minch (Saula Campus) e Debre Markos parteciperanno a questo processo, acquisendone la piena conoscenza e la capacit&#xE0; di sostenere la formazione di altri utenti. Avere fonti idriche stabili &#xE8; cruciale per il benessere delle comunit&#xE0; di queste 8 Woreda e questo richiede un efficace lavoro di conservazione dell&apos;acqua e del suolo in un territorio a forte rischio idrogeologico e particolarmente sensibile agli impatti della siccit&#xE0; e del cambiamento climatico. Gli Uffici Agricoli delle Woreda operano in questo senso ma manca una azione comunitaria efficace e costante. Il progetto interverr&#xE0; in diversi modi su queste problematiche: Formando 600 leaders perch&#xE9; siano coscienti e promuovano una risposta comunitaria duratura Sensibilizzando 2.400 donne con ruoli chiave nelle loro comunit&#xE0; su gestione delle fonti, igiene, preservazione del terreno, acqua e patrimonio arboreo Intervenendo sul consumo domestico di legname promuovendo l&apos;adozione di 30 impianti di biogas e di stufe per il risparmio energetico Studiando, in collaborazione con l&apos;Universit&#xE0; Politecnica delle Marche, l&apos;accettabilit&#xE0; tecnico-sociale, di forni e fornelli solari che consentirebbero, se ampiamente diffusi, l&apos;abbattimento della domanda di legna e carbone. La costituzione di 18 cooperative femminili promuover&#xE0; un modello di business che mette insieme empowerment femminile, sostenibilit&#xE0; ambientale e sostenibilit&#xE0; economica.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to make an important contribution to the basic services ensuring access to clean water to 10% of the population through 103 new facilities and the reactivation of another 100; Launching a campaign, together with the Community Health Workers, to promote the use of latrines aiming to improve Sanitation coverage by 20%; Providing clean water to 30 schools and adequate sanitation for 10 others. Promoting a pro-active role of the communities themselves It will ensure the sustainability of water structures by strengthening the ability of communities to manage them, training 1,211 members of Management Committees, 406 Care-Takers, and 18 local  raftsmen for extraordinary maintenance. The Woreda Water Offices play a strategic role connecting with the territory and it is essential that they are equipped with adequate tools to map the territory, both the existing schemes and the potentials, building a database that allows to properly manage the data of their territory. The software developed will also allow the Regional offices to access the data of the Woredas that use it and they will be in a position to promote its adoption in other Woreda, expanding the network of data management on the entire Region, with no additional costs. The Universities of Arba Minch (Saula Campus) and Debre Markos will participate in this rocess, acquiring full knowledge and capacity to support the training of other users. Having stable water sources is crucial for the well-being of communities of these 8 Woreda and this requires effective water and soil conservation work in an area at high hydrogeological risk and particularly sensitive to the impacts of drought and climate change. The Woreda Agricultural Offices operate in this direction, but there is a lack of effective and constant community action. The project will intervene in different ways on these issues: Training 600 leaders to become aware and promote a lasting community response; Raising awareness of 2,400 women with key roles in their communities about water source management, hygiene, soil conservation, water and trees preservation; Intervening in the domestic consumption of wood by promoting the adoption of 30 biogas plants and energy-saving stoves; resercing, with the Polytechnic University of Marche, the technical-social acceptability of solar ovens and stoves that would allow, if widespread, the reduction of the demand for and charcoal. The establishment of 18 women&apos;s cooperatives will promote a business model that combines women&apos;s  mpowerment, environmental sustainability and economic sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CVM - COMUNIT&#xC0; VOLONTARI PER IL MONDO ONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011881/01/5" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2019000261" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="72" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="16" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="23183" percentage="12" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy conservation and demand-side efficiency</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, combat desertification, restore degraded land and soil, including land affected by desertification, drought and floods, and strive to achieve a land degradation-neutral world</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, enhance international cooperation to facilitate access to clean energy research and technology, including renewable energy, energy efficiency and advanced and cleaner fossil-fuel technology, and promote investment in energy infrastructure and clean energy technology</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, increase substantially the share of renewable energy in the global energy mix</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="7" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure access to affordable, reliable, sustainable and modern energy for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protect, restore and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt biodiversity loss</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support and strengthen the participation of local communities in improving water and sanitation management</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-22">1693870.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CVM - COMUNIT&#xC0; VOLONTARI PER IL MONDO ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">556563.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CVM - COMUNIT&#xC0; VOLONTARI PER IL MONDO ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-08">706737.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CVM - COMUNIT&#xC0; VOLONTARI PER IL MONDO ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://openaid.aics.gov.it/activity_attachment/5672%20-%20delibera_49_del_05_06_2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delibera del comitato congiunto</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="IT"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://openaid.aics.gov.it/activity_attachment/5673%20-%20Proposta-CVM-ETIOPIA.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Documento di progetto</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <category code="A05"></category>
   <language code="IT"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://openaid.aics.gov.it/activity_attachment/5674%20-%20011881_Contratto_CVM_ETH_firmato_da_OSC_signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contratto con CVM</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <language code="IT"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
