<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012510-01-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Ethiopian agribusiness development operating in the  coffee value chain, through de-risking investments and  institutional support to the Ethi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;intervento ha come obiettivo principale lo sviluppo del settore 
caff&#xE8; in Etiopia. Cercher&#xE0; di sostenere il settore privato che opera 
nella filiera del caff&#xE8; facilitando in questo modo una crescita 
economica pi&#xF9; sostenibile nel paese. In questo contesto, e facendo 
seguito alla richiesta delle autorit&#xE0; governative etiopiche &#x2013; 
Ministero delle Finanze (MoF) e Autorit&#xE0; Etiope per il Caff&#xE8; e il T&#xE8; 
(ECTA) - il presente progetto &#xE8; stato sviluppato con l&apos;obiettivo di 
aumentare i volumi, la qualit&#xE0; e il valore del caff&#xE8; etiope. 
La filiera del caff&#xE8; si integra nel contesto socio-economico dei 
parchi agro-industriali (IAIP) situati nelle regioni di Amhara, 
Oromia, e Sidama. L&#x2019;incremento del valore del caff&#xE8;, tramite la sua 
lavorazione e trasformazione, far&#xE0; s&#xEC; che i prodotti finali del caff&#xE8; 
avranno una maggiore qualit&#xE0; che permetter&#xE0; la loro vendita sui 
mercati nazionali e internazionali. 
6 
Il presente progetto segue e pu&#xF2; beneficiare dell&#x2019;esperienza 
dell&#x2019;ultima iniziativa finanziata da AICS: &#x201C;RAFFORZAMENTO 
DELLA SOSTENIBILIT&#xC0; E INCLUSIVIT&#xC0; DELLA FILIERA DEL
CAFF&#xC8; ATTRAVERSO PARTNERSHIP PUBBLICO PRIVATE&#x201D; 
(AID 11003), che ha usufruito un budget totale di EUR 2,5 M per 
assistenza tecnica dalla parte di UNIDO. 
L&apos;iniziativa, formulata in stretta collaborazione con attori pubblici e 
privati, locali e internazionali, (ECTA, illycaff&#xE8;, Organizzazione 
Internazionale del Caff&#xE8; &#x2013; ICO, ecc..), promuove un modello di 
business che prevede la condivisione del rischio dell&#x2019;investimento 
nella filiera del caff&#xE8;. In questo contesto, la strategia generale 
dell&#x2019;iniziativa si baser&#xE0; sulla facilitazione dell&apos;accesso al credito, 
attraverso la creazione di una linea di credito specifica dedicata al 
finanziamento di proposte d&#x2019;investimento selezionate per il loro 
positivo impatto ambientale, sociale ed economico nel settore del 
caff&#xE8;. Tale linea di credito minimizzer&#xE0; il rischio d&#x2019;investimento 
attraverso il finanziamento di iniziative, tra partners pubblici e 
privati (nazionali ed internazionali), che collaboreranno nel 
sostenere, tecnicamente e/o economicamente, lo sviluppo del 
settore privato che investe nella filiera del caff&#xE8; in Etiopia. 
Il progetto verr&#xE0; realizzato grazie a un prestito di EUR 10M da parte 
del Governo Italiano al Governo Etiopico (MoF), per stabilire una 
linea di credito dedicata (che verr&#xE0; gestita dalla Commercial Bank 
of Ethiopia - CBE). Tale linea di credito faciliter&#xE0; l&#x2019;accesso ai 
finanziamenti per specifiche proposte d&#x2019;investimento selezionate 
da ECTA e CBE con l&#x2019;assistenza tecnica dell&#x2019;UNIDO e la 
supervisione di AICS. Le proposte selezionate avranno 
l&apos;opportunit&#xE0; di accedere alla linea di credito con un tasso 
d&#x2019;interesse agevolato ed usufruire di una percentuale di valuta 
estera. 
In parallelo, AICS finanzier&#xE0; l&#x2019;assistenza tecnica dell&#x2019;UNIDO con 
EUR 2M e sosterr&#xE0; l&#x2019;Autorit&#xE0; Nazionale Etiope del Caff&#xE8; (ECTA) 
tramite un contributo a dono di EUR 0,5 M con l&#x2019;obiettivo di 
promuovere l&#x2019;internazionalizzazione del caff&#xE8; etiope e sostenere i 
servizi di formazione offerti dall&#x2019;Ethiopian Coffee Training Center
(CTC), creato dall&#x2019;ECTA con il supporto tecnico dell&#x2019;UNIDO 
attraverso un precedente finanziamento di AICS (AID 11003).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention&#x2019;s primary objective is the development of the coffee sector in Ethiopia. This intervention aims to contribute to support the private sector operating in the coffee value chain, to become a real engine of sustainable economic growth and wealth 
creation. 
Following the official request received from the Ethiopian Coffee and Tea Authority (ECTA), the present project has been developed with the objective to increase volumes, quality and the value of Ethiopian coffee. 
Coffee, and the coffee value chain, fit within the framework of the existing agro-processing clusters within the Integrated Agro?Industrial Parks (IAIPs) which are presently built in Amhara, Oromia and Sidama. Value addition through processing will also increase the quality of coffee products both for internal and export markets. This project follows up and capitalizes on lessons drawn from the Italian Development Cooperation funded UNIDO initiatives 
&#x201C;Improving the Sustainability and Inclusiveness of Ethiopian Coffee Value Chain through Private and Public Partnership&quot; (AID 11003), with a contribution of respectively EUR 2.5 M for technical assistance. 
The initiative, formulated in close cooperation with local and 
international public and private stakeholders, operationalizes a risk sharing business model. In this context, the general strategy will be based on facilitating access to finance, through the establishment of a specific credit line dedicated to funding investment proposals 
selected for their high impact on the coffee sector as well as on the social and environmental context. The project will minimize investment risk by establishing a responsive framework, in cooperation with public and private counterparts, to enable the development of private sector initiatives operating in the Ethiopian coffee value chain. 
The present project will be implemented thanks to a EUR 10 M soft oan from the Italian Government to the Ethiopian Government 
(Ministry of Finance - MoF) for the establishment of one credit line 
- managed by the Commercial Bank of Ethiopia (CBE). The line will be dedicated to facilitate access to finance to selected investment project proposals. The selected business proposals will have the opportunity to easily access credit at a limited interest rate and a percentage of foreign currency. 
To complement the credit component, the Italian Agency for 
Development Cooperation (AICS) will provide a grant of EUR 2 M to UNIDO for technical assistance. Moreover, this intervention will also support the Ethiopian Coffee and Tea Authority (ECTA) with the aim of ensuring the continuous improvement and full sustainability of the Ethiopian Coffee Training Center (CTC) &#x2013; set up and developed by the ECTA through the previous UNIDO project funded by AICS (AID 11003) - and promote the international recognition of the Ethiopian coffee sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012510/01/2" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="7.4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25030" percentage="15.4" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business development services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="24030" percentage="77.2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Formal sector financial intermediaries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">75300</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-05">450000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
