<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27689</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uniminuto Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased Access to Tertiary Education Services  Colombia has made significant advances in gross enrollment ratios at all education levels over the past 5 years yet access and coverage for certain segments of the population remain weak. While average gross enrollment ratios for tertiary education are estimated at 29%, government data indicates that coverage in Bogota may exceed 50%, yet remain below 10% in various departments. Additionally, schooling has traditionally been less accessible to students of lower socioeconomic backgrounds. Through its network approach, commitment to distance learning technologies and presence in more than 11 departments, Uniminuto is expected to contribute to increased coverage for students in more remote areas of the country.     Support for Key Productive Sectors of Colombia  In addition to offering high demand professional degrees (e.g. Computer Science, Accounting, Business Administration, Civil Engineering), Uniminuto will continue to develop programs of applicability to particular regions of the country (e.g. hotel management, agroecology, livestock business management), as well as technological programs of shorter duration but high employability prospects (e.g. web design, occupational health).     Support for Public-Private Partnerships in Education  The private sector represents approximately 45% of tertiary enrollment levels, yet its participation has typically focused on the capital and larger cities of Colombia. Under an innovative public private initiative, CERES  Centros Regionales de Educaci&#xF3;n Superior, the government of Colombia has extended the reach of private higher education to more marginal urban and remote areas of the country. Currently operating more than 15 CERES centers, Uniminuto is expected to continue to participate under this initiative.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed IFC investment is an A loan of up to $8.0 million (to be disbursed as a Peso-linked loan) in favor of Corporaci&#xF3;n Universitaria Minuto de Dios (Uniminuto), a mid-sized, rapidly growing higher education institution based in Bogot&#xE1; offering technical, technological and university education in Colombia.  Uniminuto currently operates through a wide national network, offering flexible, cost-competitive and quality education to lower and middle income students.  In line with a five-year strategic plan (2008-2012) which targets expansion from a current level of 18,000 students to over 30,000 students by 2011, Uniminuto plans to undertake investments over the next 2 years which support the physical, technical, and institutional aspects required for such growth.  The total corporate program for this period is estimated at $18 million, of which $10 million will be dedicated to expanding student capacity in three key locations (Bogota, Soacha, Girardot), with an additional $4 million required for the technology infrastructure which supports the overall educational network.  Other important areas of investment relate to reinforcement of quality and efficiency throughout the system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CORPORACION UNIVERSITARIA MINUTO DE DIOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27689" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-09-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camilo Bernal Hadad General Rector Calle 81B No. 72B 70 Tel: +571-291-6534 / 46 Fax: +571-291-6534 / 46  www.uniminuto.edu</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CO-Colombia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The physical infrastructure component of the investment program consists of three projects in Cundinamarca, including expansion of two key facilities in Bogota and Soacha, as well as construction of a new (phase 1) facility in Girardot.  Land has been secured in all cases, and project planning is at advanced stages.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.0000000000 -73.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Colleges, Universities, and Professional Schools</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $8.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-09-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-09-07">8000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-09-07">8000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CORPORACION UNIVERSITARIA MINUTO DE DIOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27689/uniminuto-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
