<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30454</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Cardio</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i) High quality health coverage in an underdeveloped region: Colombia overall has 10 beds per 10,000 inhabitants, low as compared to Argentina and Brasil.  This low coverage is even less in remote regions, such as the ones FCV is targeting; Santander, coffee region and the Atlantic coast. (ii) Availability of hospital infrastructure for population for some frontier regions of Colombia (Norte Santander, Guajira, Magdalena, Cordoba, Choco),  (iii) Best practices redeployment in a network of smaller hospitals: FCV has JCI accreditation for its main hospital in Bucaramanga and plans to expand this standard to the new project as well to the hospitals under management. (iv) Improving coverage: FCV has a track record of operating 4 hospitals in different cities of Colombia and plans to continue expanding its network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion CardioVascular (FCV) is building a 468 bed high quality complex in the outskirts of Bucaramanga (Floridablanca) as part of a 10 year expansion plan. This hospital will increase FCVs current health offering; they operate 623 beds in 4 different cities of Colombia (Bucaramanga, Manizales, Ibague and Santa Marta). This new hospital will not replace the existing one but rather add new beds and medical specialties to FCV. The design of the hospital will be at the level of the best hospitals in Latin American and worldwide, and will have the latest technology in medical equipment.    The project fit with IFCs LAC strategy to support health care in the region through increasing access to high-quality health (especially for lower income groups), improving standards of quality and efficiency, facilitating the exchange of best practices, and creating jobs for skilled professionals. Aside from fulfilling these requirements, this project also fits with the Government of Colombias (GoC) priority to increase the provision of health services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FUNDACION CARDIOVASCULAR DE COLOMBIA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30454" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Cardiovascular de Colombia (FCV) Sonia Ramirez, FCV Director of Operations   Calle 155&#xAA; No. 23  58, Urbanizaci&#xF3;n El Bosque   Floridablanca, Santander Colombia     E-mail:     soniaramirez@fcv.org     Tel: (57 7) 639-9292</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CO-Colombia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is located within a green area protected by natural barriers that ensure the environmental quality of the project. Thanks to its privileged location, the project will provide excellent conditions for the patients, as well as an optimal working environment for the medical group and its partners. The Hospital will be built in the municipality of Piedecuesta, located 9 miles from the center of the city of Bucaramanga. Its neighbors are Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana and private residential condominiums.   Key environmental factors in the project will be the conservation and improvement of the current network of river water sources, respecting and applying local and international legislation. The low population density of the area helps to maintain natural green areas, as well as those areas to be created by the project. Impact on existing ecosystems will be minimal, through the implementation of a regulator plan during construction.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.0000000000 -73.2500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Hospitals and Clinics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-06-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-14">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-14">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FUNDACION CARDIOVASCULAR DE COLOMBIA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30454/fundacion-cardio">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
