<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8311</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Radfan Ceramic Tile Manufacturing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Republic of Yemen-Radfan Ceramic Tile Manufacturing              Region    Central Asia, Middle East and North Africa        Sector       Project No008311   Projected Board DateJuly 1997   Company NameRadfan for Manufacturing Ceramic &amp; Porcelain Co. Ltd.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The Companys major shareholders are five brothers of the Al Sawary family ---, Hussein Mohamed Al Sawary (Chairman), Ali Mohamed Al Sawary (General Manager), Ghalib Mohamed Al Sawary (Deputy General Manager and Relations Manager), Adel Mohamed Al Sawary (Sales Manager) and Ibrahim Mohamed Al Sawary (Manager) --- own and manage the Company.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total cost of the project is estimated to be US$7 million.  The Sponsors are expected to contribute US$2 million as equity.  IFC A loan will be about US$2.5 million.  IFC has started to solicit interest for B-Loan or co-financing from several financial institutions e.g. FMO, DEG and SITI.    Location of project and Description of site    	The manufacturing plant is located just outside of Sanaa, in the village of Matnah Bani Matar, about 25 km away, carries out the glazing operation.  Current production is 360,000 sq.m per year against a capacity of about 1 million sq.m.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    The objective of this project is to establish a first facility in the raw materials -- i.e., clay, sand, limestone and feldspar. The project will reduce the Companys total average ex-factory price from US$5.64 m2 to around US$3.60 m2, a competitive price by the international standards.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a Category B Project, according to IFCs environmental review procedure.  The following potential environmental safety and health impacts of the project were analyzed:  air emissions and dust control; solid and liquid waste management; storage and handling of glazing and pigment materials; and general employee health and safety.  The sponsor has presented plans to address these issues and has demonstrated that the proposed project will comply with applicable World Bank requirements.  The primary source of air emissions associated with the project will be dust generated during tile manufacturing operations and quarrying operations.  Dust collectors will be erected at the new production facilities to control particulate emissions generated during the process.  Dust collectors also will be installed to clean the exhaust gases of the kiln.  Wastes generated during the manufacturing process are either recycled back to the process or reused as construction aggregate.  Production areas are ventilated and appropriate safety equipment is provided by the employer.  Necessary personnel protective equipment will be provided to and procedures followed by those employees working in particularly dusty, noisy and high temperature areas.  All employees will be trained in the safe operation of equipment and proper responses for foreseeable emergency operations.  IFC will monitor ongoing compliance with World Bank environmental, health and safety policies and guidelines during the lifetime of the project by evaluating reports submitted annually to IFC by Radfan and by conducting periodic site reviews during project supervision.     The  is  from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     May 15, 1997      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RADFAN FOR MANUFACTURING CERAMIC AND PORCELAIN CO LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8311" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-02-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-05-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen, Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="YE-Yemen, Republic of">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.5000000000 47.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BB - Glazed Ceramic Tiles</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $3.80 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-02-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1998-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-02-15">3800000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-02-15">3800000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RADFAN FOR MANUFACTURING CERAMIC AND PORCELAIN CO LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8311/radfan-ceramic-tile-manufacturing">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
