<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-559785</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe Motherhood Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Queen of Sheba Safe Motherhood Program is a four year community based output based aid program that comprises the provision of a defined Mother-Baby package of essential quality services as defined by WHO, such as antenatal care, birth attendance by skilled birth attendants, postnatal care, complicated care services and family planning, to eligible women of reproductive age (15-49) in Sanaa, Yemen. The program will be largely subsidized by grant financing from the Global Partnership on Output Based Aid (GPOBA). There will be a minimal user fee charged to patients.   All services will be provided by the private sector:   - Two private Yemeni hospitals, the Saudi German Hospital (SGH) and University of Science and Technology Hospital (USTH) have been identified as appropriate clinical service providers for the first phase of the program. Primary and secondary care services will be provided by midwives at satellite clinics to be established in the districts and owned and managed by the hospitals. Patients requiring emergency or complicated care will be referred to the two private hospitals; - SOUL, a reputable local Yemeni NGO, will serve as project implementation and promotion unit responsible for program promotion, awareness campaigns and targeting of eligible pregnant women; and  - A fiduciary agent will be the recipient of the GPOBA grant and manage the fund flow in the project. The private providers will bear the operational risks of the program as they will be reimbursed retroactively post service delivery and performance target verification by an independent verification expert.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen has one of the highest maternal mortality ratios at 570/100,000 live births (2000 estimates) with only 27% of births attended by skilled birth attendants (2003). The project seeks to improve access and quality of services to women from poorer districts in Sanaa, Yemen and also aims to relieve some of the strain experienced by the overburdened public sector. The main expected estimated output will be to achieve approximately 40,800 safe child birth deliveries attended by skilled birth attendants amongst the target population over the project period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNKNOWN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-559785" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-01-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Arwa Yahya Al-Deram, Director SOUL P.O Box 18383   Sana&apos;&apos;a, Republic of Yemen       Telephone: +971 223999   Fax: + 967 1 223999   Working hours: Sat-Wed. 7:30 - 15:00   E-mail:    soul-yemen@y.net.ye    Website:    www.soul-yemen.org</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen, Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="YE-Yemen, Republic of">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program will commence in two underserved districts in Sanaa, Yemen in the first year. Primary care services will be provided at the level of the community by midwives at satellite clinics within these districts. In year 1, two satellite clinics will be established by renovating existing facilities in each of the two districts. The clinics will be owned and managed by private service providers. Patients with complications will be referred to in-house specialists based at the satellite clinics. Those patients requiring more tertiary or emergency care would be referred to two private hospitals for management using the emergency transportation systems of these private hospitals.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.5000000000 47.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Hospitals and Clinics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/559785/safe-motherhood-program">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
