<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-LEB-19/DDA-3604/SA1/E/INGO/13129</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Education program to support 500 children at risk in Mount Lebanon and Baalbek-Hermel (Syrian, Palestinian Refugees from Syria and Lebanon)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action will contribute to building the capacity of vulnerable children and their parents, to cope with conflict and displacement through its education, giving the possibility to 500 children to be enrolled in the public school system. It will address the gap in early childhood education and prepare young children to access formal education by providing CB-ECE for at least 500 children aged 3-5 years.
TDH will geographically focus on the high needs identified in Mount Lebanon (where TDH has been operating in education through a wider program funded by the European Union in partnership with AVSI and WarChild Holland) and expanding to the Bekaa Valley, where needs continue to rise. 
More specifically, in Mount Lebanon the action will focus in Jbeil, Khenchara in TDH community centres, being TDH the only education actor providing CB-ECE courses whilst these cadasters are not highly vulnerable in terms of refugee concentration, TDH has long waiting lists of children ready to be enrolled in CB-ECE courses. Furthermore, in Khenchara schools or institutes providing Prep-ECE are a long way from the refugees&apos; homes in winter, roads are often closed and schools become extremely difficult to reach. TDH will also run the proposed educational activities in Burj el Barajneh, in partnership with a local CBO and in coordination with other actors such as War Child. By working through a local partner (Fraternity Association) TDH aims at building local capacity to deliver targeted services at the source of the need this capacity-building is already evidenced by the fact that Fraternity, through the support of TDH, has already implemented several cycles of CB-ECE and has obtained the EOI permission from MEHE to implement CB-ECE and BLN activities in 2019.
In Bekaa, TDH will operate in its community centres in Arsal and Ain in the Baalbek-Hermel governorate, both classified among the most vulnerable cadasters. 
The target children will be selected through the preliminary outreach and identification phase that will be launched at the start-up of the action, in order to reach out to the most vulnerable children and their caregivers (for the complementing activities). Children &#x2018;at risk&#x2019; are defined as falling into one or more of the following categories: married or at risk of early marriage currently or at risk of becoming a child labourer unaccompanied or separated children children with special educational needs child victims or those at risk of violence, abuse, exploitation or neglect child carer. Vulnerabilities will be identified through a comprehensive needs assessment form applied by trained outreaching staff (see Documents), and follow-up household visits by a caseworker if necessary. Priority will be given to those children facing compound risks. Due to the equal gender balance of Out Of School Children (OOSC) in the target age range, priority will be given only on the severity of risk, taking into consideration that boys and girls may be vulnerable in different ways.
Light fresh meals with mineral potable water (TDH contribution) will be provided to each child during the implementation of the educational activities. To mitigate protection risks and for safety measures, transportation services will be provided to all CB-ECE children who are in need of transportation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondazione Terres des Hommes Italia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondazione Terres des Hommes Italia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fraternity Association for Social and Cultural  Work</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flavia Pugliese</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Delegate</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>70733510</telephone>
   <email>f.pugliese@tdhitaly.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LBN8">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baalbek El Hermel</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.39803800 36.38734200</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="LBN3">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mount Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.83330000 35.53330000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-08">65841.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-08">199158.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="LBN71-13129">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-08">265000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondazione Terres des Hommes Italia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304151837">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-15">159000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondazione Terres des Hommes Italia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304565482">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-14">106000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondazione Terres des Hommes Italia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-LBN71-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
