<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203030101-AME-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA MULTI-COUNTRY STRATEGY TO RESPOND TO GBV IN THE SYRIAN CRISES</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNFPA Regional strategi f&#xF6;r att motverka k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld i Syrienkrisen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA interventions are aiming to ensure the well-being and safety of women and girls affected by the Syria crisis through increasing the availability of and access to specialised gender-based violence (GBV) services, increasing the social safety nets for women and girls and challenging negative social norms that limit the empowerment of women and girls.
This multi-country strategy specifically addresses interventions aimed at reducing both the effects and occurrence of GBV in Syria, Iraq, Jordan, Lebanon and Turkey. An expected result of the UNFPA strategy is strengthened resilience, among women and girls, their families and communities, who are&#xA0;survivors of GBV, or are threatened by GBV due to negative social norms.
Overall Objective: Increase the sense of well-being of women and girls participating in the program by 80%
Results:&#xA0;Women and girls who participate in the UNFPA programme report an increased sense of well-being from participating in the programme (through accessing Women and Girls Safe Spaces and/or health services) &#xA0;
Findings of the assessment of beneficiary satisfaction:
A high level of beneficiary satisfaction of the services they receive in sexual and reproductive health (SRH) care service delivery points, women and girl&#x2019;s safe spaces, and outreach centres supported through Sida, is confirmed.
Access to both GBV and SRH services is generally easy to the vast majority of the respondents.
Despite some challenges reported on access for people with disabilities, a number of them have been reported to access the delivery points for services.
A majority of the beneficiaries have no other place where they would go to to receive these services and consider these services extremely essential to them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA proposed interventions are aiming to ensure the wellbeing and safety of women and girls affected by the Syria crisis over the next two years, through Increase the availability of and access to specialised GBV services, Increase the social safety nets for women   and girls and challenge negative social norms that limit the empowerment of women and girls.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNFPA&apos;s regionala GBV program omfattar Syrien, Jordanien, Libanon, Turkiet och Irak och har som m&#xE5;l att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla v&#xE4;lbefinnande och s&#xE4;kerhet f&#xF6;r kvinnor och flickor som p&#xE5;verkas av Syrienkrisen, genom att &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE5;ngen p&#xE5; specialiserade GBV tj&#xE4;nster, &#xF6;ka sociala skyddsn&#xE4;t f&#xF6;r kvinnor och flickor samt utmana de negativa sociala normer som begr&#xE4;nsar kvinnor och flickors egenmakt. Programmet fokuserar p&#xE5; kvinnors sexuella och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter, samt skydd och tillhandah&#xE5;llande av service f&#xF6;r kvinnor som utsatts f&#xF6;r v&#xE5;ld. Programmet tar sin utg&#xE5;ngspunkt i en konflikt med en humanit&#xE4;r kris som f&#xF6;ljd, och har som &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;l att arbeta p&#xE5; ett holistisk s&#xE4;tt genom f&#xF6;rebyggande och respondering (Prevention and response) i arbetet med GBV. Som ett exempel &#xE4;r m&#xE4;ns/pojkars involvering samt arbetet med media viktiga best&#xE5;ndsdelar i det f&#xF6;rebyggande arbetet med GBV.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">5843510.781277392</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">8541008.541008541</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2473994.292552702</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">5843510.781277393</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">8541008.54100854</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2473994.2925527017</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-01">16887746.157891</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">5843510.781277392</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">8541008.54100854</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">2473994.2925527017</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In its final report capturing results achieved between December 2016 and September 2019 with the Swedish contribution, UNFPA highlighted that :o 460,401 beneficiaries received SRH services, including outreach consultations, family planning supplies and counselling, gynaecological consultations, ultrasound diagnostics, antenatal care (ANC) including supplements, postnatal care (PNC), psychosocial support (PSS), referral for deliveries, and comprehensive emergency obstetric and neonatal care (CEmONC);o 181,083 women and girls have received GBV and empowerment services;o 89 women and girls safe spaces were supported;o 514,183 women, girls, boys and men were sensitised on SRH and GBV issues.
Including, for Syria (30% of the grant):? 209,612 beneficiaries received SRH services; this is above the target of 180,000 for the period.? 23,634 women and girls received GBV services; this is below the target of 28,231 for the program.? 26 Women and Girls Safe Spaces supported fully from Sida, meeting the target.? 116,298 beneficiaries were sensitised on SRH and GBV issues, below the target of 246,000.
For Iraq (27% of the grant):? 149,309 beneficiaries received SRH services? 74,694 women and girls received GBV services? 214,074 beneficiaries sensitized on SRH and GBV issues
For Lebanon (15% of the grant):? 6,458 beneficiaries received SRH services? 6,542 women and girls received GBV services? 52,892 beneficiaries were sensitised on GBV and SRH
For Turkey (14% of the grant):? 50,015 beneficiaries received SRH services.? 50,924 women and girls received GBV services, double the amount targeted.? 100,735 beneficiaries were sensitized on SRH and GBV-issues.
For Jordan (12% of the grant):? 45,007 beneficiaries were provided high quality SRH services? 35,520 women and girls received GBV prevention and response services.? 30,184 beneficiaries were sensitized on SRH and GBV issues directly in safe spaces or through outreach modality.
For coordination hub in Amman (2% of the grant)? regional media strategy, communication services, information management and impact assessments, elaboration of the adolescent girls&#x2019; strategy
The impact assessment report states the following: &quot;The findings from the assessment indicate that UNFPA services remain relevant to the needs of women and girls in all the areas of intervention and that they are having a positive impact on the lives of refugees, displaced and host communities.&quot; Sida considers this very positive, especially in light of the continued support granted to UNFPA 2019-2020 for similar activities.
The delivery of &apos;dignity&apos; kits and hygiene kits to conflict-affected and displaced populations made a huge difference for women and girls, but also designed for all, hygiene kits addressed the needs of the wider-households. They have been one of the essential relief services that this programme has supported, especially in Syria, a commodity often distributed together with food aid and non-food items in acute situations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030301" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110401" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3210000000" strategy-end-date="2023-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Syria Crisis 2016-2023</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Syrienkrisstrategin 2016-2023</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
