<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10402A0102-AME-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project support Ufm - Union for the Mediterranean</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektst&#xF6;d UfM - Medelhavsunionen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The support to the Union for the Mediterranen (UfM) will enable and strengthen the UfM regional dialogue towards and within the member states of the union&apos;s Southern area (MENA-countries), targeting three prioritesed themes of (1) women&apos;s economic empowerment (gender equality); (2) water, environment and blue economy; and (3) energy and climate change. The project document states &quot;The overall objective of the proposed agreement is to define a structured cooperation between Sida and the UfMS through a multi -year support framework targeted to UfMs core activities with a focus on MENA countries, allowing their deepening and amplification.
This is a process oriented programme with medium term goals in each of the three specific sectors of intervention, with annually defined monitoring indicators. The Union for the Mediterranean is a unique framework for cooperation and dialogue in the Mediterranean region with a clear mandate to foster regional cooperation and integration with a view to improve stability and social well - being. Political recognition and impulse through an increasing number UfM Ministerial Meetings have provided guidance in a number of areas. Within this context, the UfM Secretariat has increasingly been attributed the role of animating various regional dialogue platforms and/or expert groupsbringing together national counterparts but also donors, international financial institutions, experts, civil society, private sector, think tanks and academics.
An additional role in monitoring progress in implementing regional agendas has emerged alongside it,promoting concrete cooperation on the ground.Within this framework, the Secretariat acts as a facilitator to animate policy dialogues,exchange of experience, definition of priorities at regional level in sectors of its mandate,through building on national commitment of countries involved and gathering relevant stakeholders and actors that can promote changes on the ground.
The intervention logic of the proposed programme is therefore structured around three axes coherent with the UfMS&apos; core activities, which are key to the success of activities:a) Regional policy dialogues to consolidate (emerging) processes in the 3 selected sectors, ensure their sustainability, and enlarge the multi-partners approach;b) Promotion of regional gortfolio, activities of dialogue and coordination that may belinked to existing initiatives and programmes or may allow defining new concrete priorities.c) Technical support, coordination and monitoring of activities so as to plan, execute,coordinate, ensure follow- up and report on agreed activities to successfully implementand oversee the present agreement and its activities.2 More specifically, this implies the countries of Sida&apos;s MENA strategy that are also UfM Member countries. Expertise&#xA0;and technical assistance that could be mobilised are detailed in each of thethree proposed axes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Union for the Mediterranean, UfM, has applied to Sida for the funding of their project on Regional Dialogue and Cooperation towards the MENA region, with a purpose of strengthening the regional dialogue within the priority areas of women&apos;s empowerment/gender; water, environment and blue economy; and energy and climate change.

The Union for the Mediterranean is an intergovernmental organisation with a mandate to deepen the regional dialogue around the Mediterranean and the 43 member states. The UfM is one of few fora for meetings between representatives from Israel and the Arab world. The priority areas mentioned above coincides with the overarching prioritised areas within Swedish aid cooperation, as well as those given within the Regional strategy for Sweden&apos;s development cooperation with the Middle East and North Africa, MENA, 2016-2020. The intent of the contribution to the UfM apart from strengthening the regional dialogue, is to also strengthen  Sida&apos;s own dialogue with partners in the MENA region, whose projects to a large extent have been labelled by the UfM.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UfM, Medelhavsunionen, har ans&#xF6;kt om medel hos Sida f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet UfM Regional Cooperation Programme, i syfte att f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rka den regionala dialogen gentemot MENA-l&#xE4;nderna inom de prioriterade omr&#xE5;dena f&#xF6;r kvinnors egenmakt (j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet); vatten, milj&#xF6; och bl&#xE5; ekonomi; samt inom energi och klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar.

Medelhavsunionen &#xE4;r en mellanstatlig organisation vars syfte det &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rdjupa den regionala dialogen kring Medelhavet och de 43 medlemsl&#xE4;nderna. Sidas fokus f&#xF6;r samarbetet ligger p&#xE5; l&#xE4;nderna i MENA-regionen. UfM &#xE4;r ett av f&#xE5; forum f&#xF6;r m&#xF6;ten mellan representanter f&#xF6;r Israel och arabv&#xE4;rlden. De prioriterade omr&#xE5;dena ovan sammanfaller med b&#xE5;de &#xF6;vergripande prioriterade omr&#xE5;den inom svensk bist&#xE5;ndspolitik, s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l som de som &#xE5;terges inom den regionala strategin f&#xF6;r Sveriges utvecklingssamarbete med Mellan&#xF6;stern och Nordafrika, MENA, 2016-2020. Avsikten med st&#xF6;det till Medelhavsunionen ut&#xF6;ver att st&#xE4;rka den regionala dialogen, &#xE4;r att samtidigt st&#xE4;rka Sidas egen dialog med partners i MENA regionen, vars projekt i m&#xE5;nga fall har bejakats av Medelhavsunionen.

Sidas st&#xF6;d till Medelhavsunionen utg&#xF6;rs av projektst&#xF6;d under perioden 2017-2020. St&#xF6;det g&#xE5;r till organisationens k&#xE4;rnverksamhet inom tre prioriterade omr&#xE5;den (se ovan). Totalsumman &#xE4;r 63 220 000 MSEK, uppdelat p&#xE5; fyra utbetalningar. EU finansierar unionen med cirka 50% av den &#xE5;rliga budgeten och medlemsl&#xE4;nderna f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas bidra med &#xE5;terst&#xE5;ende 50%. Sidas st&#xF6;d &#xE4;r dock separat till denna budget, d&#xE5; st&#xF6;det riktar sig mot enbart MENA-regionen i enlighet med den regionala MENA-strategin. Ingen vidaref&#xF6;rmedling till tredje part ing&#xE5;r i st&#xF6;det.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UFMS Projects/Union for the Mediterranean Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UFMS Projects/Union for the Mediterranean Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.2 - Integrate climate change measures into national policies, strategies and planning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.2 - Integrera klimat&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder i politik, strategier och planering p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.1 - By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.1 - Senast 2030 uppn&#xE5; allm&#xE4;n och r&#xE4;ttvis tillg&#xE5;ng till s&#xE4;kert och ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomligt dricksvatten f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">18401.2098266691</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">18401.2098266691</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-23">20358.020358</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">16388.8154485559</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The annual report for 2018 presents the results under three main heading; 1. Women empowerment and gender equality; 2. Fostering a Regional agenda for Water Environment and Blue Economy; 3. Promoting regional dialogue and cooperation for Energy and Climate Change
Union for Mediterranean (UfM) has been instrumental to create regional platforms in these areas (1-3) where participants from both civil societies, think tank, enterprises and governments can meet and interact, and commitments has been made in Ministerial Declarations which has been presented and endorsed at the regional conferences. The UfM support is made in terms of Regional Policy dialog, Promotion of regional portfolio and Technical Support. A UfM label of a project implies that the governments and civil society stand behind the ideas proposed.
In October 2018 there were three Working Groups (WG) on gender presenting updates from UfM member countries on; a) Fostering Women Economic Participation, b) Combating Violence Against Women and c) Role of Women in Preventing Violence and Extremism. UfM labelled project has mobilized new financial commitments from; Italy with 9 mEuro on women entrepreneurship and a focus on Syrian women refugee in Jordan, Egypt and Lebanon; Spain 0,2 MEuro promoting women with disabilities in Morocco; Monaco 0,1 MEuro and a study on &quot;Challenges and Opportunities of Women Economic Participation in Rural Areas&quot;. The EU will provide 3,5 mEuro to UfM supported and labelled projects on Violence Against Women and Girls (VAWG). In collaboration with WHO, UfM is preparation an MoU on women access to health and provide an input to the baseline for the UfM follow-up mechanism on this matter.
UfM has been a key actor to promote a regional follow-up mechanism with gender equality indicators for the progress of the 2030 SDGs agenda. It is done in cooperation with EU, OECD MENA Programmed, UN Women/SDGs, League of Arab States, WHO, Civil society. A contentious issue has been the availability of gender sensitive data statistics including reliable sources. UfM also organized an event for 62 young (25-35yrs) women, coming from Algeria, Egypt, Jordan, Lebanon, Libya, Morocco, Palestine, Syria, Turkey and Tunisia, to share their field experiences, to reflect upon the impact of the training and brainstorm on their role in building inclusive societies.
UfM has commissioned a study &#x201C;Enhancing the civic and social engagement of women and youth in preventing violence and extremism&#x201D; in Morocco and Tunisia. In collaboration with UNDP and UN-Women, UfM is preparing a project on the role of women. The program was presented to the EU (DG near) and it will be promoted with other donors.
UfM has contributed in the formulation of a Regional Water Financial Strategy (FS), which identifies challenges that are shared by many countries in the region. It sets common strategic objectives, and a menu of actions, but individual countries will implement different actions according to their individual circumstances, priorities, and capacities.
The UfM Water Expert Group Meeting was held in February in Jordan, to proceed in the development of the UfM Water Agenda ensure ownership in the UfM Water Agenda. All MENA countries attended and 40% of the participants were women. Debates were held regarding the proposed draft Work Plans 2018-2019 on the Water-Energy-Food-Ecosystems Nexus (WEFE) and on Water-Employment-Migration (WEM) presented at the meeting. Initial discussions were also held on Water Access and Sanitation (WASH) and on Climate Change Adaptation and Water (CCA) on the basis of proposals submitted by Egypt and Malta.
In May the UfM Task Force on the Water FS met in Brussel to discuss investments that contribute access to water by protection against risk of droughts, floods or polluted water; and sustainable growth in the Mediterranean region. All MENA countries were represented among the 40 participants with an equal gender balance. There were debates on WEFE WEM and WASH, and the women&#x2019;s&#x2019; role in the water sector was highlighted. Besides International Financial Institutions (IFI) like EIB and EBRD, also OECD and EC attended the meeting.
In July and September EU hosted meetings on the initial financing instruments in the water sector requested by the participants UfM meeting (May). Some MENA case studies were presented i.a. adopting a proactive approach to facilitate financial sustainability in Palestine; reducing inefficiencies in the water sector in Egypt; mobilizing climate finance in Morocco; mobilizing funds from domestic development banks in Turkey, and mobilizing internally generated revenues in Israel.&#xA0;
UfM convened MENA countries representatives in January to gather their views to be presented at the World Water Forum in Brazil 2018. MENA/UFM region delivered a common message to be integrated in the global agenda. For the elaboration and implementation of the UfM Water agenda, a competitive procurement was made where the Mediterranean Information Office for Environment, Culture and Sustainable Development (MIO-ECSDE) which partners with the GWP-Med has won. MIO-ECSDE will draft concept notes, agendas, and all organizational on content for the task force.
A Water Knowledge Platform is prepared by UfM to create guidelines, based on lessons from pilot countries (Jordan, Lebanon, Monaco, Morocco, Spain and Tunisia) and the launch of a web portal. It would also include assessment of the Non-Conventional Water Resource (NCWR). The UfM labelled project will define which data, information and expertise are needed to plan an integrated water resource management (IWRM). It could also reinforce water regulation, ensuring data availability and ownership at local and national levels. The information provided by the project will allow for an evaluation of best practices and joint management of transboundary resources. The aim is to create National Water Information Systems (NWIS).
Meetings has been held in January by UfM Working Group on Environment and climate Change to facilitate the transition towards the post 2020 agenda on environmental action in the Mediterranean region and identify the regional priorities. It was requested (2017) by Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, Egypt, Lebanon, Jordan and Libya who brought their priorities to the debate and thus engaged in the setting of the long-term objectives.
A UfM Environmental task force meeting was held January in Jordan, back to back with the H2020 (Initiative for a Cleaner Mediterranean Sea) Steering Group Meeting on IWRM. It was organized to maximize synergies allowing the joint participation of different ministries from the UfM countries as well different Directorate-Generals of the European Commission (EU DGs). The MENA countries confirmed their intention to support the transition towards a Circular Economy, and to ensure pollution reduction/prevention (marine plastic litter), and Sustainable Consumption and Production (SCP) actions and related access to finance under a new to-be-shaped &#x201C;H2030 initiative&#x201D; (provisional name). Other themes discussed was landscape restoration, with links to droughts together with a strengthened focus on land sea-air interactions. Nature-based solutions supporting adaptation and mitigation to climate change were also addressed. Written contributions were received from Israel, Jordan, Morocco, Palestine and Turkey, though inputs were provided by all the Southern Med countries.
The 2nd UfM Working Group on Environment and Climate Change took place November back to back with 3rd Meeting of Environmental Journalists from News Agencies in the Mediterranean, organized by the UfM together with International Union for the Conservation of Nature (IUCN) on, and the EU funded SwitchMed (&#x201C;an initiative that supports and connects stakeholders to scale-up social and eco innovations in the Mediterranean&#x201D;). There were journalists from Morocco, Tunisia, Lebanon, Egypt and Algeria.
In collaboration with the EU funded SwitchMed Programme UfM has organized a program and workshops on circular economies in the Mediterranean. There were 125 industries from MENA advised on how to become more resource efficient and competitive by saving water, energy, raw materials and waste. In addition, creation of employment and supports to social innovations to foster sustainable growth was discussed. It is estimated that the program address 2,300 entrepreneurs (38% women and 62% men) coming from Morocco, Tunisia, Egypt, Lebanon, Palestine, Jordan, Israel and Algeria were trained and 200 of them managed to launch their sustainable businesses. Moreover, in order to be able to create a greater impact, 123 local trainers were trained. Out of those 200 newly launched businesses, 50 qualified to enter the incubation phase during which they received technical assistance to further develop their business models and gain access to finance. The UfM has supported a Switch Med Connect event for social innovators from MENA in November in Barcelona.
On Sustainable Consumption and Production (SCP), the UfMS supported with technical assistances to prepare &#x201C;Enabling access to finance to green entrepreneurs in the Southern Mediterranean countries described in a section above&#x201D; presented at SwitchMedConnect. The study also includes result of two national studies to explore the financial context for green entrepreneurs/start-ups in Jordan and Palestine; a study on the possibilities of crowdfunding.&#xA0;
A joint report &#x201C;Enabling access to finance to green entrepreneurs in the Southern Mediterranean countries&#x201D; by UfM, Regional Activity Centre on SCP of UN, and European Federation of Ethical and Alternative Banks and Financiers to support the growth of innovative green businesses in the Mediterranean was presented, has been produced. On the occasion, a joint report of UfMS, Regional Activity Centre on Sustainable Consumption and Production of UN Environment MAP, and European Federation of Ethical and Alternative Banks and Financiers to support the growth of innovative green businesses in the Mediterranean was presented during a dedicated session.
In the area of Blue Economy UfM has in 2018 focused on; the follow up on the sub-sea basin &#x201C;Western Med Initiative&#x201D;; Consolidation of the Virtual Knowledge Centre (VCK) as the digital platform for the emerging Mediterranean Blue economy community; Support to the extension of the Bologna charter on sustainable coastal tourism, coastal protection, integrated management, adaptation to climate change to UfM MS which have not yet adhered; Continued follow-up to the issue of marine litter and plastic waste in cooperation with institutional partners such as University of Siena and UNEP-Mediterranean Action Plan (MAP).
At the 4th UfM Blue Economy Working group meeting contributions were received from 10 countries, including Algeria, Morocco, Lebanon and Israel. Such exercise has provided inputs for emerging priorities (plastic litter) to be considered in the 2nd UfM Ministerial Declaration on Blue Economy. The contributions are built around three main themes: i) national development of the blue economy in general; ii) Research, technology, innovation, knowledge and skills in the blue economy sectors; iii) Maritime governance.
To &#x201C;Promote the regional dialog and cooperation on Energy and Climate Change in 2018 the UfM focused on Energy Platforms, to insure coherence and complementarity between regional activities and foster interconnectivity within the region; to strengthen local authorities&#x2019; efforts in energy efficiency and energy transition as well as the promotion of capacity building; a stronger involvement of the private sector, following up on the conclusions of the 1st UfM Energy and Climate Business Forum held in 2017 in Cairo; the promotion of emerging initiatives, exchange of experiences, capacity building and replication of best practices.
During 2018, the UfM organized Peer Dialogue for Local Authorities (LA) in Energy Transition and the Capacity Building Program. In September UfM organized a back to back meeting with Beirut Energy Forum and tackled the issue of &quot;Innovative and effective public-private-partnership (PPP) models&#x201D;. Technical experts holding decision-making positions, of which on third were female experts, from Jordan, Lebanon, Palestine, Tunisia and Turkey attended the dialogue and shared their experiences and work in progress on the PPP linked to regulation and financing.
In the UfM agenda on Climate Change a special emphasis has been put to climate finance, tourism, agriculture, and a regional analysis on Nationally Determined Contributions, and the scientific aspects of climate change.
UfM Secretariat organized a UfM Climate Week that included the sixth meeting of the UfM Climate Change Expert Group (UfM CCEG), two ad hoc UfM CCEG meetings on tourism and agriculture, UfM RCFC (Regional Climate Finance Committee) meeting; UfM Climate Change Scientific Meeting; and the hosting of the second MYCN (Mediterranean Youth Climate Network) General Assembly meeting.
The UfM CCEG is the official UfM Policy Platform tackling Climate Change, and has been established by the UfM Ministerial Declaration on Environment and Climate Change. The UfM Climate Change Expert Group (UfM CCEG) was held in Barcelona in April 2018 and the topics discussed were;
Among the identified 10 sectors (Energy, Transport, Buildings, Industrial activities (excluding tourism), Tourism, Agriculture and Fisheries, Coastal and blue economy, Land Use, Land Use Change and Forestry (LULUCF), Waste, Water), Tourism and Agriculture was identified as the less covered sectors. And it was proposed to launch a study on these topics in Algeria, Egypt, Israel, Jordan, Lebanon, Morocco, Palestine and Tunisia. An overall Regional analysis of countries National Determined Contributions (NDCs), covering all the above-mentioned sectors of the UfM Work Program, based on ClimaSouth analysis, and including MENA countries (analysis financed by SIDA).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10402" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
