<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203029203-AME-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDRC - regional support for water cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">MEDRC - regionalt vattenst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r samarbete</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall mission of MEDRC is to support the Middle East Peace Process through technical cooperation. As such the support to MEDRC should contribute to peace through technical cooperation at a government level on water resources so that conflict is prevented, and management and access to scarce water resources is improved. The technical cooperation is trilateral with activities including all core parties;&#xA0;Palestine, Israel and Jordan.
While this can be considered as a relatively &apos;process-oriented&apos; goal a number of more output oriented goals are identified in the result chain/theory of change, with a focus on bilateral activities in Palestine or Jordan with for example the development of PhD programmes for water specialists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet syftar till att st&#xF6;dja MEDRC, som &#xE4;r en del av den multilaterala fredsprocessen i Mellan&#xF6;stern, till att fr&#xE4;mja samarbete och kunskapsutbyte kring vattenfr&#xE5;gor i MENA regionen. 

MEDRC ber&#xE4;knas st&#xF6;djas av Sida under en tre&#xE5;rsperiod med 18,8 miljoner kronor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support MEDRC, which a part of the multilateral   peace process in the Middle East, to promote cooperation and          knowledge development on water issues in the MENA region</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDRC/The Middle East Desalination Research Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDRC/The Middle East Desalination Research Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.5 - By 2030, implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.5 - Senast 2030 genomf&#xF6;ra en integrerad f&#xF6;rvaltning av vattenresurser p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, n&#xE4;r s&#xE5; &#xE4;r l&#xE4;mpligt genom gr&#xE4;ns&#xF6;verskridande samarbete.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-4772.1204631044</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">-4882.3969033101</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDRC has performed its mandated role as a resilient and well-established medium for core party meetings, dialogue and co-operation. This occurs in a multilateral context where each party is an equal partner in a process mandated by all MEDRC member states. This status has been reaffirmed at all trilateral meetings and in MEDRC Executive Council meetings. MEDRC continues to work closely with colleagues in Israel, Palestine and Jordan to ensure clear, robust and strategically aligned programming.
On bilateral level, MEDRC&#x2019;s bilateral program in Palestine and Jordan was well received. At the start of 2019, MEDRC has requested nominations from Palestine and Jordan, who must attend and pass the five courses to make up the full award. Unfortunately, Palestinian colleagues were unable to join the course due to travel restrictions, however five Jordanians were able to complete the full set of courses.
MEDRC has organized some Alumni Forums in Palestine and Jordan. These events were a key example of bridging the pillars of MEDRC&#x2019;s bilateral programming&#x2014;from academia to government, and from long-term development strategies to short-term technical solutions. The events were well-received and had significantly greater outreach than previous events as they involved civil servants, practitioners, academics and others working within the sector, alongside the students.
In addition, Sida funded ten PhD students in Palestine and Jordan with a focus on water. The bilateral program was a vital part of MEDRC&#x2019;s wider remit as it demonstrated that MEDRC is considered a credible partner for confidence building measures in the water sector.
On trilateral level, the trilateral strategy specifically focuses on resilience and flexibility to ensure ongoing engagement when the external environment directly impacts programming.&#xA0;
Since 2017, all trilateral meetings have taken place in Europe. Whilst this provides an added dimension in terms of necessary visas, it has allowed meetings to take place which would not have been feasible had they been held in the region.
As part of the trilateral approach, MEDRC decided to convene technical workshops for representatives of governmental agencies and others; one was held on April-May 2019 focused on &#x201C;Responses to Climate Change&#x201D;, the expert level roundtable was attended by 13 individuals from government, academia and NGOs from the Palestinian, Israeli and Jordanian water sectors, where they focused on a variety of topics not previously discussed in MEDRC climate change meetings, including climate finance and green bonds, gender and climate change and groundwater resources in relation to climate change. The meeting was positively perceived, and the participants affirmed the importance of MEDRC as a space for discussion and cooperation, and the importance of the co-equality of the parties within the organisation.
By engaging with each of the core parties bilaterally, MEDRC was able to convene additional meetings to ensure continuity in the program.
In 2019, another trilateral meeting on &#x201C;Transboundary Water Management and Governance&#x201D; was held in Zurich, Switzerland. This expert level roundtable was attended by 13 individuals from government from the Palestinian, Israeli and Jordanian water sectors as well as international experts.
The event brought together mid-level management and senior practitioners from the Ministry of Water and Irrigation- Jordan, Water Authority Jordan, Israeli Ministry for Regional Cooperation, Jordan Valley Authority, Israeli Ministry of Environmental Protection, Palestinian Water Authority, West Bank Water Department, Israeli Water Authority and the Israeli Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
And a trilateral study tour was conducted to Spain, where a total of 12 participants were in attendance and all had engineering backgrounds and were predominantly Ministry employees. This tour was a success, from all three sides, in terms of core party engagement, and it was more useful and better value for money to incorporate field visits into trilateral meetings, rather than as standalone study tours.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030292" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110304" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2425000000" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2021-2025</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2021-2025</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
