<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203005502-AME-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNESCWA Climate change on water 2010-2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNESCWA Klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar/Vattenresurser 2010-2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">M&#xE5;let f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r att baserat p&#xE5; en regionspecifik klimatmodell g&#xF6;ra en bed&#xF6;mning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarnas p&#xE5;verkan p&#xE5;                f&#xE4;rskvattenresurserna i Mellan&#xF6;stern och Nordafrika. I insatsen ing&#xE5;r &#xE4;ven en socio-ekonomisk riskbed&#xF6;mning. UNESCWA st&#xE5;r f&#xF6;r projektledning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the project presented by UNESCWA are to assess the impact of climate change on freshwater resources in the Arab region through a consultative and integrated regional initiative that seeks to identify the socio-economic and environmental vulnerability caused by climate change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The core component of the UNESCWA project RICCAR aimed to assess the impact of climate change on freshwater resources in the Arab Region through a consultative and integrated methodological framework to identify the socio-economic and environmental vulnerability caused by climate change impacts on water resources in the region. The project also included the analysis of extreme weather events, with the aim to inform and build the capacity of Arab States to better predict, project and examine extreme weather events and climate-related disasters in the region.&#xA0;
The project was launched in 2010. An agreement was signed with Sida in December 2010 and amended in December 2011 to include additional activities. The project was initially designed as a three-year project with a budget of US$ 4,100 000. Since then, the terms of implementation and validity was extended four times, no additional funding beside accrued interest. The validity of the activity period was finally extended until December 2019. The continuation of the project has now been absorbed into the Sida - UNESCWA agreement under the REGEND&#xA0;contribution #10798.
The project was led by UNESCWA and implemented in partnership with the League of Arab States (LAS), Arab Center for the Studies of Arid Zones and Dry Lands (ACSAD),Swedish Meteorological and Hydrological Institute (SMHI), United Nations Office for Disaster Risk Reduction, and the World Meteorological Organization (WMO).
The core project sought to achieve the following immediate objectives: (a) Establishment of a regional knowledge hub for climate and water resource information and modelling in the Arab region;(b) Identification of expected climate change impacts on water resources in the Arab region and associated vulnerability hotspots;(c) Improved capacity and institutional networking for climate change and water resource monitoring and adaptation;(d) Increased awareness and access to information about climate change impacts on water resources in the Arab region; and(e) Identification and analysis of projected extreme events in the Arab region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41105" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-ESCWA/United Nations Economic And Social Commission For Western Asia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41105" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-ESCWA/United Nations Economic And Social Commission For Western Asia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">770511.0028971214</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">384109.6780865429</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">770511.0028971214</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">384109.6780865429</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-12-01">1055233.123212</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-28">770511.0028971214</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-28">384109.6780865429</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project endorsed an on-line Regional Knowledge Hub (RKH) with open access to regional climate, hydrological and vulnerability assessments, sectoral analysis, training tools, datasets and maps on climate change in the Arab region. The Arab domain was accepted by the Coordinated Regional Climate Downscaling Experiment (CORDEX)&#xA0; as an internationally validated domain for generating regional climate projections. The hub is hosted by FAO and can be found through the following link:
https://rkh.apps.fao.org/home/RICCAR/1
Another result of the regional knowledge hub was the adoption of the Arab Climate Outlook Forum (ArabCOF) 2017.&#xA0;The Arab Climate Outlook Forum (ArabCOF) has strengthened the capacity of Arab meteorological services to pursue regional climate analysis and seasonal forecasts, and to collaborate with other regional climate outlook forums. Women have been increasingly present in the work of the ArabCOF.
A RICCAR publication series is available that includes a 3-part core report comprised of a main report, technical annex and executive summary available in English and Arabic; technical notes, training manuals, and technical reports focusing on health, agriculture, floods, droughts and climate indices based on the RICCAR climate projections.
Moreover, RICCAR findings have been referenced in national water strategies and plans, agricultural sector assessments and management plans and UNFCCC national communications for several Arab States, including in Egypt, Jordan, Kuwait, Lebanon, Palestine and Tunisia, aswell as in several regional strategies and plans.
Over 100 peer reviewed journal articles, reports and publications reference RICCAR and/or the Arab/MENA Domain.
The sustainability of RICCAR is assured due to the continued requests for assistance received from Arab States, the substantive and financial support provided by several RICCAR partners, as well as the continued Swedish financial support for RICCAR activities within the context of the ongoing REGEND project (funded by Sida, contribution number: 10798) RICCAR has also been incorporated as a core initiative implemented under the auspices of the Arab Centre for Climate Change Policies that was established at ESCWA in June 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030055" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
