<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203012501-AME-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNESCWA - MDG+, 2011-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNESCWA - MDG+, 2011-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektets m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning &#xE4;r att etablera och institutionalisera en regional mekanism f&#xF6;r &#xF6;vervakning och rapportering om tillg&#xE5;ng till   vatten och sanitet i den arabiska regionen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective is to establish and institutionalize a regional mechanism for monitoring and reporting on access to water supply and sanitation services in the Arab region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &#x201C;Establishing a Regional Mechanism for Improved Monitoring and Reporting on Access to Water Supply and Sanitation Services in the Arab Region (MDG+ Initiative)&#x201D; was implemented by United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Western Asia (ESCWA) through the period 2011 and 2018 based on a request from the Arab Ministerial Water Council (operates under the League of Arab States). Core project activities was concluded in the period December 2011-December 2016, and Sida approved the use of the remaining project balance, and the generated interest, to support a set of follow-up activities through December 2018. Sida&#x2019;s support to the project sums to 10 MSEK.
&#xA0;
The goal of the MDG+ Initiative is to establish and institutionalize a regional mechanism for monitoring and reporting on access to water supply and sanitation services in the Arab region based on the regional context in view of developing a knowledge platform that provides reliable data, information and analysis regarding the quantity and quality of access to water supply and sanitation services in the Arab region. While the goal of the MDG+ Initiative follow-up phase is to build upon the lessons learned, experiences gained, and the data gathered during the initiative to inform regional preparations and efforts to achieve the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and particularly its water-related Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41105" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic and Social Commission for Western Asia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41105" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-ESCWA/United Nations Economic And Social Commission For Western Asia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">924613.2034765456</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">147734.4915717473</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">307068.7219799791</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">145774.7197481013</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">924613.2034765456</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">147734.4915717473</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">307068.7219799791</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">145774.7197481013</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-01">1541022.005794</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-28">924613.2034765456</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-28">147734.4915717473</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">307068.7219799791</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">145774.7197481013</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MDG+ Initiative was implemented through a series of activities that are organized with a view to achieving the four expected accomplishments. Below are some example results:
1. Enhanced regional and national monitoring capacity
The MDG+ Unit was established at The Arab Countries Water Utilities Association (ACWUA) in September 2012 and was fully staffed in February 2013. The unit successfully communicated with National Focal Points (NFPs) to collect and vet the national datasets that were included in the first and second MDG+ reports issued in 2015 and 2016. Moreover, technical assistance was provided through National Focal Points and country teams during the preparation and vetting of the national datasets.
&#xA0;
2. Established regional data management platform
The data included in the 2015 and 2016 MDG+ reports as well as the contributing datasets at the utility or sub-national levels, were developed into a website by ACWUA and is accessible through their website. The website provides access to information related to events, recent meetings and documentation available for download in both English and Arabic. A data portal was also developed and linked to the website to assist NFPs to be able to access their archived data and submit future datasets.
&#xA0;
3. Institutionalized regional monitoring program
The MDG+ unified questionnaire for water supply and sanitation indicators was completed at the country level. The questionnaire covers 14 countries out of the 18 Arab States engaged in the project. The data and information completed according to the MDG+ unified questionnaire are included in the second report.
In addition, consumer field surveys were conducted in selected countries at the request of the Arab Ministerial Water Council in countries experiencing crisis. The Council recommended that those surveys be conducted in Iraq, Jordan, Lebanon, Libya and Syria, while ESCWA decided to conduct it in Iraq, Jordan, Lebanon and Syria due the resources availability in these countries. The survey questionnaire included a question aimed at examining gender differences in water collection at the household level. The results of the field surveys were included in the first report.
ACWUA and the MDG+ Unit were responsible for providing regular reporting to the Arab Ministerial Water Council Technical Scientific and Advisory Committee on the progress achieved with respect to the initiative. Accordingly, the Ministers adopted a series of resolutions with respect to the MDG+ Initiative and its follow-up, which were initially drafted by ACWUA and reviewed by ESCWA for consideration by Arab Member States.
&#xA0;
4. Strengthened regional dialogue
A regional seminar to discuss lessons learned was organized by ACWUA in consultation with ESCWA in Amman in November 2015. Also, the initiative conducted an expert group meeting organized by ESCWA in cooperation with the League of Arab States and ACWUA in Beirut, April 2016 in view of discussing regional preparations for a set of water-related goals and targets.
&#xA0;
&#xA0;
Following the adoption of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development in 2015, with a new set of indicators and indicator methodologies for measuring and monitoring, it was agreed that the provision of technical assistance and capacity building support on the MDG+ Initiative indicators would continue through the validation and issuance of the 2016 MDG+ Initiative report. But the focus would then be placed on supporting Arab States pursue monitoring and reporting on the SDG6 (clean water and sanitation). Accordingly, the follow-up phase focused on the following three accomplishments:
&#xA0;
1. Continued monitoring and reporting on the MDG+ indicators;
ESCWA and ACWUA continued to be called upon to provide data and lessons learned from the MDG+ Initiative experience, for example, in a Regional Workshop on SDG 6 Indicators in Amman, 2018 aimed at presenting and validating baseline data and train national focal points.
&#xA0;
2. Informing the water-related SDGs
ESCWA supported and helped engage Arab States in global processes related to the collection and reporting of data related to the SDG6 indicator targets. The MDG+ indicators and governance structure have been acknowledged by the UN-Water Integrated Monitoring Initiative for SDG6 and the UNICEF/WHO Joint Monitoring Programme (JMP) since the adoption of the 2030 Agenda. This is because issues that Arab States prioritized under the MDG+ Initiative, such as water supply intermittency, affordability, quality, wastewater treatment and treated wastewater reuse are now central components of SDG 6.1, 6.2, and 6.3. The region&#x2019;s MDG+ datasets on wastewater treatment and reuse are also cited in global SDG6 reports as there is no other source of harmonized country data available on wastewater.
ESCWA issued two working papers with respect to SDG 6 entitled, &#x201C;Progress on the implementation of Integrated Water Resources Management in the Arab Region: A regional report for SDG indicator 6.5.&#x201D; and &#x201C;Progress on Shared Water Resources Management in the Arab Region: Regional Baseline for SDG Indicator 6.5.2&#x201D;.
ESCWA, in collaboration with the Technical Secretariat of the Arab Ministerial Water Council of the League of Arab States, organized an Expert Group Meeting on &#x201C;Improving Shared Water Resources Cooperation within the Framework of Global and Regional Agreements&#x201D; in Beirut, December 2018.
&#xA0;
3. Regular reporting to the Arab Ministerial Water Council
ESCWA presented a status report on 2030 Agenda follow-up and the need for country focal points on SDG6 to the Technical, Scientific and Advisory Committee session that advised the 11th session of the Arab Ministerial Water Council in June 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030125" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
