<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12054A0103-AME-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP- Climate finance facilty MENA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP- Klimatfinansiering MENA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Description of the intervention
Focused on the nexus between climate action and human security, the programme seeks to enhance the capacity of regional and national institutions to effectively take climate action in a way that brings benefits across SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery efforts, including support to scale-up climate finance for innovative local solutions. In doing so, the programme brings together multi-lateral institutions in the region such as the League of Arab States (LAS) and the Arab Water Council (AWC), and leading UN system partners active on climate actions in the region, including the UN Development Programme (UNDP), the UN Environment Finance Initiative (UNEP-FI), the UN Human Settlement Programme (UN-Habitat), the UN Office for Disaster Risk Reduction (UNISDR), the World Food Programme (WFP) and the World Meteorological Organization (WMO).
Through joint actions, the programme would address two main priorities in the region that have been identified during the formulation process - to promote more integrated solutions for climate action that brings benefits across SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals, and to scale up local partnerships and finance to this end. Through a combination of regional dialogues and technical assistance at the regional level, and innovation grants at the country level, the programme would generate three key outcomes:
Outcome 1: Increased awareness and understanding at the regional level of the benefits of a nexus approach to climate action for achieving benefits across the SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals
Outcome 2: Enhanced access to analysis, tools and strategies at regional level to support nexus approach to advancing climate action across the SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals
Outcome 3: Strengthened national and local capacities to effectively integrate climate change considerations into development and crisis prevention/recovery policies and to scale-up climate finance</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Description of the intervention
Focused on the nexus between climate action and human security, the programme seeks to enhance the capacity of regional and national institutions to effectively take climate action in a way that brings benefits across SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery efforts, including support to scale-up climate finance for innovative local solutions. In doing so, the programme brings together multi-lateral institutions in the region such as the League of Arab States (LAS) and the Arab Water Council (AWC), and leading UN system partners active on climate actions in the region, including the UN Development Programme (UNDP), the UN Environment Finance Initiative (UNEP-FI), the UN Human Settlement Programme (UN-Habitat), the UN Office for Disaster Risk Reduction (UNISDR), the World Food Programme (WFP) and the World Meteorological Organization (WMO).
Through joint actions, the programme would address two main priorities in the region that have been identified during the formulation process - to promote more integrated solutions for climate action that brings benefits across SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals, and to scale up local partnerships and finance to this end. Through a combination of regional dialogues and technical assistance at the regional level, and innovation grants at the country level, the programme would generate three key outcomes:
Outcome 1: Increased awareness and understanding at the regional level of the benefits of a nexus approach to climate action for achieving benefits across the SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals
Outcome 2: Enhanced access to analysis, tools and strategies at regional level to support nexus approach to advancing climate action across the SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals
Outcome 3: Strengthened national and local capacities to effectively integrate climate change considerations into development and crisis prevention/recovery policies and to scale-up climate finance</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the programme is to enhance the capacity of regional and national institutions to effectively integrate climate change considerations into development and crisis prevention/recovery interventions and policies, including support to scale-up climate finance for innovative local solutions.
Outcome 1: Increased awareness and understanding achieved among key policy makers and stakeholders at the regional level on a nexus approach for achieving climate action with co-benefits across SDGs and crisis prevention/recovery goals. Mapping regional and national strategies in the Arab region with goals related to water and food security, land management, social empowerment and peace and security, and ways climate actions under SDG 13 and NDCs can help achieve co-benefits across the SDGs. Building bridges among development and humanitarian goals, actors and initiatives, by bringing forth added-value of climate action for crisis prevention and recovery efforts.
This outcome seeks to set an enabling environment for other outputs and activities, by strengthening the understanding of the nexus approach among policy makers and other stakeholders. It will help foster regional dialogue to prioritize key policy development processes where the opportunities and value-added of the nexus approach are greatest.

Outcome 2: Enhanced access to analysis, tools and strategies at the regional level to support a climate nexus approach to achieving SDGs and prevention/recovery. Strengthening regional cooperation and inter-disciplinary knowledge networks, and responding to gaps in climate science and data needed to better understand and manage trends and risks of resource insecurity, conflict and displacement,
Outcome 3: Strengthened national and local capacities to effectively integrate climate change considerations into development and crisis prevention/recovery policies and to scale-up climate finance in a way that achieves local innovative solutions with benefits across the SDGs. Building local leadership and capacities for innovative, transformational change by integrating climate measures in development and crisis prevention/recovery policies and actions to make efforts more risk-informed and resilient, Supporting local grants to catalyse and accelerate of innovative solutions, for taking climate action in a way that engages an integrated approach to mainstream climate action benefits across SDGs and crisis prevention/recovery goals, Helping scale-up climate finance to achieve the vision of countries&#x2019; NDCs in a way that develops capacity to de-risk scaled up investments, expand use new innovative sources of finance, catalyse new partnerships with the private sector, and accelerates results across SDGs and for crisis prevention/recovery goals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.a - Fullf&#xF6;lja det &#xE5;tagande som de utvecklade l&#xE4;nder som &#xE4;r parter i F&#xF6;renta nationernas ramkonvention om klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar gjort g&#xE4;llande en m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning att till 2020 gemensamt mobilisera 100 miljarder US-dollar &#xE5;rligen fr&#xE5;n alla typer av k&#xE4;llor f&#xF6;r att tillgodose utvecklingsl&#xE4;ndernas behov vad g&#xE4;ller meningsfulla begr&#xE4;nsnings&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder och insyn i genomf&#xF6;randet samt s&#xE5; snart som m&#xF6;jligt finansiera och operationalisera den gr&#xF6;na klimatfonden fullt ut.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.a - Implement the commitment undertaken by developed-country parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change to a goal of mobilizing jointly $100&#xA0;billion annually by 2020 from all sources to address the needs of developing countries in the context of meaningful mitigation actions and transparency on implementation and fully operationalize the Green Climate Fund through its capitalization as soon as possible.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-04">805486.513854</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">740278.5562453072</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/jordan/decision-on-contribution-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contibution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/jordan/decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contibution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Below is a list of activties that were achioved during the first six months of the project: -&#xA0;Agreements were signed between UNDP and implementing partners of the project (League of Arab States, Arab Water Council, UNEP, UNDRR, UN Habitat and WFP) during a high-level signing ceremony conducted during the 5th General Assembly of the Arab Water Council, March 16th, Cairo, Egypt. - A draft annual workplan was developed by UNDP and the Implementing Partners at start of the year, based on the Multi-Year Workplan in the Project Document. Draft was reviewed with all Implementing Partners in March, after which updates were reflected and the 2019 Annual Work Plan finalized. - An initial launch event was held in late 2018, hosted by the League of Arab States as a side event on the SDG Climate Facility regional project during the 2018 Arab Sustainable Development Week event, November in Cairo, Egypt -&#xA0;Recruitment of project staff to implement the project -&#xA0;Consultations to confirm priorities for country activities, as basis to identify local partners and develop terms of reference for country grants -&#xA0;Consultations with Implementing Partners to confirm roles and establish partnership agreements -&#xA0;Undertake initial assessment of green finance status and gaps in the region as basis for climate finance related activities under the programme - conduct a conflict sensitivity analysis as basis for country actions. - To raise the profile of the regional project in the development community, a series of communication and outreach activities were also undertaken during the inception period. This included a series of blogs on the regional project posted on UNDP global website in end-2018 and early-2019 to raise awareness of the initiative among UNDP country partners, donors and the general public.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12054" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
