<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203017401-AME-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIDME Arab Women Policy Center,02013-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">AIDME Arabiska kvinnor Policy Arab Women Centrum  2013-2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med den f&#xF6;reslagna interventionen &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka kvinnors aktiva deltagande i det offentliga rummet i MENA-regionen f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbara och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;llda f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar i politik och praxis f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att kvinnors r&#xF6;ster p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, inklusive de fattigaste och mest marginaliserade, h&#xF6;rs. Projektet har fyra huvudsakliga resultatm&#xE5;l: i) Kvinnor i MENA-regionen har tillg&#xE5;ng till mekanismen f&#xF6;r beslutsfattande och deras r&#xF6;ster h&#xF6;rs. ii) Kvinnliga ledares kapacitet har &#xF6;kat p&#xE5; styrningsomr&#xE5;den och offentliga politikomr&#xE5;den f&#xF6;r att kunna spela en lika stor roll som m&#xE4;n i samh&#xE4;llsfr&#xE5;gor. iii) Icke-statliga organisationer i regionen kan st&#xE4;rka kvinnliga ledare och uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla WPC:s genomslagskraft; och (iv) Kvinnliga ledare och deras allierade har &#xF6;kat samspelet, och gemensamt p&#xE5;verkansarbete f&#xF6;r kvinnors offentliga deltagande p&#xE5; nationell och regional niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the proposed intervention is to increase women&#x2019;s active participation in public spheres in MENA region for sustainable and gender equitable changes in policies and practice to ensure that the voices of women at all levels, including the poorest and most marginalized, are heard. The project has four main outcome objectives: (i) women in the MENA region have access to policymaking mechanism and their voices heard; (ii) capacity of women leaders increased on governance and public policy areas in order to play equal role with men in societal affairs; (iii) NGOs in the region are able to empower women leaders and to maintain the impact of WPC; and (iv) Women leaders and their allies have increased interaction, mutual support and joint advocacy on women public participation at national and regional levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDA/International Development Academy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1903826.0762758704</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1903826.0762758704</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">3439169.686175</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1903826.0762758704</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2014Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: In essence, the Women&apos;s Policy Centre theory of change puts gender equality and its values at the heart of the policy-making and policy analysis mechanisms. Without boxing themselves in as a &quot;gender organisation&quot;, and in looking beyond the ideas and values regarding women in public life, to encompass issues across the board affecting all citizens, the WPC focuses instead on women&apos;s role and engagement in the policy of national and regional policy. Such a push epitomises the values and programming of gender mainstreaming, and uses the work to enhance the capacity and role of women in public life. Various sensational results have been recorded, including the recognition of the WPC in Jordan by Her Majesty Queen Rania, the success of 4 women in Egypt (part of the project), in winning parliamentary seats during the 2015 house elections, and access to the international community for policy analysts in Tunisia. The theory of change has focused well on  building the capacity, building the competence, knowledge and engagement of women in this arena. Teaching them, and equipping them with the tools, expert analysis and comparative policies of their regional counterparts, as well as building of regional networks and cross-regional ownership and sustainability of the programme. Women have, over the past two years, been equipped with skills, knowledge, experiences, and practice in formulating policy, media awareness, campaigns, and awareness-raising, as well as successfully building the capacity of civil society, strengthening civil society in the region, through national counterparts, and building strong relationships within the region amongst the women and civil society involved. The Heya Women&apos;s Policy Centre was successfully registered and established, with a working steering committee made up of the 5 partner NGOs in the identified countries: Tunisia, Egypt, Lebanon, Jordan and Yemen. Whilst varous issues related to access and capabilities of the Yemen PNGO have created some problems, due to the outbreak of war - the HEYA centre has continued to implement work, even in Yemen, and should be commended for its work in accessing female participants and building and enhancing their knowledge and capacity on issues of policy that cover a wide range of governance programming. 

The targets of women trained, policy papers drafted and presented were reached, despite minor deviations throughout year II owing to the upheaval recorded in the region - most notably in Yemen and in Egypt. The Centre&apos;s have worked well to better coordinate, presenting registered by-laws to organise and monitor the programming of the centre, as well as provided a well-updated online platform that goes to the heart of their regional work, whereby physical presence is not a decisive factor in their success - an important feature in work these days, whereby technology is aiding groups across the region to adjust to the physical lack of access and space across the region, particularly in relation to civil wars that are ongoing. 

Women were trained in various different capacities, showing the holistic approach by the HEAY centre, including Bridge, electoral manuals, aiding in providing a holistic and consensus-building manual for the governance and work of the HEYA centre, and the political awareness, policy experience and drafting skills required to present and prepare relevant policy papers on a variety of subjects, including, but not limited to: the environment, climate change, political participation, gender equality, human rights, economy and more.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030174" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
