<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203019201-AME-33112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISO MENA Star</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ISO MENA Star</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate and enviroment structures, trade related support to upgrade   in MENA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Klimat och milj&#xF6; strukturer, handels h&#xF6;jande st&#xF6;d i MENA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The &#x201C;Project to strengthen institutional infrastructure on standards and regulations to support business and industry in the Middle East and North Africa during 2013-2018&#x201D; primarily aims to strengthen institutions developing and using standards as well as the capacity of business and industry to apply standards within the context of sustainable development. The implementation of this project involves delivery of various forms of technical assistance and training activities to achieve the following three objectives:
a) Objective 1: Standardization pillar in the MENA region is strengthened &#x2013; aims tostrengthen the capacity of selected industry support institutions, such as the NationalStandards Body (NSB) and regulators as well as trade promotion organizations, toenhance the country&#x2019;s participation in international trade, while increasing international competitiveness and export performance through increased quality.
b) Objective 2: Promote good practices for sustainable development with focus onaspects related to climate change &#x2013; aims to contribute to the development of a soundbusiness enabling environment by encouraging the private sector and other stakeholders to use international standards to demonstrate their commitment to sustainable development.
c) Objective 3: Coordination and synergies with other related organizations andamong projects and countries are implemented &#x2013; aims to enhance the cooperationwith regional and sub-regional organizations, involved in standardization or standardrelated activities.
Furthermore, there is a focus on gender integration to standards in the region as well as climate change components that are of relevance to Swedish regional strategy for the MENA-region 2016-2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISO/International Organization for Standardization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISO/International Organization for Standardization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1074740.5269299268</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1074740.5269299268</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938393</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1170001.17000117</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-21293.7954081579</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">5680771.356629</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1074740.5269299268</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">1170001.17000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">-21293.8387673304</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISO has acted professionally in following the action plan and implementing the objectives of the project against the results. The development objectives of the ISO MENA STAR Project was to a large extent in line with Swedish government&#x2019; MENA strategy 2016-2020, and ISO Action Plan for Developing Countries 2011-2015.
ISO has implemented the agreed activities during the timeframe of the project from 2013-2018 (seminars, coaching, workshops, consultancy or awareness on topics related to standardization and its related activities). They have also been conducting needs assessment missions for the beneficiary NSBs under both objectives, institutional strengthening and sustainable development. The expenditures of the whole project activities of 4 381 551 CHF was nearly in line with the total budget planned at the beginning of the project. The remaining 20 000 CHF will be returned back to Sida.
A summary of the results include:
Under objective 1 &#x201C;Institutional Strengthening&#x201D;
The final report showed that all outcomes were mostly fulfilled; six countries have developed their national standardization strategy, based on the demonstrable needs of the public and private sector, while the Algerian and Lebanese&#x2019;s&#x2019; NSBs committed to do it during 2019. Due to conflicts and security situations, Syria has only partially participated whilst Libya and Yemen have been unable to take part in the project.
- Eight NSBs have developed a strategy plan to engage with relevant stakeholders identified in the standardization strategy. The NSBs, apart from those in Jordan and Tunisia completed the development of a marketing plan, to foster the understanding the use of the standards in broader society.
- Five of eight countries have prepared a communication plan, to promote standards development for 2 priority sectors in national standardization. Algeria, Lebanon and Morocco did not finish the plan.
- Six project countries (Algeria, Egypt, Jordan, Morocco, Palestine and Tunisia) developed a national collaboration plan to leverage synergies and linkages between NSBs and Trade Support Institutions (TSI), adding to National Workshops implemented under the project.
All the WTO-members in the project made efforts to strengthen the implementation mechanism of WTO TBT agreement to support the exporting sectors. Furthermore, plans were developed to use the transparency framework of the WTO to facilitate public-private sector dialogue in 4 countries (Algeria, Jordan, Morocco and Tunisia)
Lastly, strategies on how to use standards as a tool to improve market access have been established in Algeria, Egypt, Jordan, Morocco, Palestine and Tunisia.
 Under Objective 2 &#x201C;Sustainable Development&#x201D;
Which has been considered largely effective and implemented.
- Nearly 90 trainees across the region participated in trainings to establish expertise in the application of relevant International Standards related to Sustainable Development in the areas of energy, water and the environment. The overall outcome of the trainings were between &#x201C;good&#x201D; and &#x201C;very good&#x201D;.
- 26 companies, in various industrial sectors, from the eight beneficiary Countries (except Syria), were prepared to implement the relevant international standards to improve their practices and increase their market visibility- and hence their competitiveness. In the field of energy, four studies were produced, seven for water and eight for environmental management, i.e. 19 in total. Some companies were reluctant to have their information used in a publication, and the implementation process took more time than envisaged and was not ready for publication at project end.
- Total of 96 of national events held, in two rounds, in the eight participating countries to create awareness on each of the 3 focus areas, with more than 2000 people attending the first round. The number was reduced for the second round to 650 in order to make the learning process manageable.&#xA0;
-&#xA0; Raising awareness on International Standards relating to the green economy and Sustainable Development, ISO 31000 (Risk management), ISO 37001 (anti-bribery management-systems) and ISO 45001 (occupational health-and-safety management systems), resulted in most countries adopting or are on their way to adopting the&#xA0; International Standards as national standards. Many found ISO 37001 especially interesting due to the focus on this issue in the region. After the regional workshop on Green Economy, 7 national workshops and 12 consultative missions (additional to the planned activities of the project) were carried out to six of the NSBs, which resulted in them starting the process of implementing ISO 37001 in their own organizations.
The program successfully built the skills and knowledge of many National Standaridization Bodies by developing and optimizing their national standardization practices, standards development processes and standardization strategies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030192" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
