<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203024401-AME-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women MENA: Men and Women for Gender Equality</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Women MENA: M&#xE4;n och kvinnor f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional program for women&apos;s rights and gender equality in the Middle East and North Africa 2014-2017.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Womens regionala kontor i Kairo har l&#xE4;mnat in en ans&#xF6;kan om regionalt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter i Mellan&#xF6;stern och Nordafrika. Satsningen bed&#xF6;ms vara i linje med organisationens strategiska prioriteringar och kommer att komplettera/st&#xE4;rka redan p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende regionala verksamheter, samt flytta fram organisationens position ytterligare som en viktig resurs och akt&#xF6;r f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter i regionen. Verksamheterna kan delas upp inom tre omr&#xE5;den: 1) forskning och policyutveckling (kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter och Islam, m&#xE4;n och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, samt social media/kommunikation), 2) st&#xE4;rkande av civilsamh&#xE4;llet i fyra verksamhetsl&#xE4;nder och 3) identifiering av och st&#xF6;d till samh&#xE4;llsf&#xF6;rankrade l&#xF6;sningar/verksamheter f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter.  
S&#xE4;rskilt fokus kommer att ligga p&#xE5; Egypten, Libyen, Palestina och Marocko, och det finns anledning att tro att v&#xE4;rdefulla erfarenhetsutbyten och kunskapsuppbyggnad kommer att delvis som ett resultat av interaktion mellan akt&#xF6;rer i dessa l&#xE4;nder. Men satsningen bed&#xF6;ms kunna f&#xE5; ringar-p&#xE5;-vattnet effekter i fler l&#xE4;nder i regionen, delvis genom de &quot;kunskapsprodukter&quot; som ska produceras/genereras, delvis genom att framg&#xE5;ngsrika metoder genomf&#xF6;rs, uppm&#xE4;rksammas och sprids.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and men in Arab societies are given equal rights and opportunities to live a life free of violence, and to engage, equally, as active citizens in their communities and countries. The key intervention objectives are the following:&#xA0;
1. Legislation and public policies address the root causes of gender inequalities through evidence-based advocacy:&#xA0;
2. A strong civil society, including new and emerging movements, promotes gender equality at national and regional levels;&#xA0;
3. Communities engage in developing solutions to promote gender equality based on innovative approaches and best practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.C" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.c - Adopt and strengthen sound policies and enforceable legislation for the promotion of gender equality and the empowerment of all women and girls at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.c - Anta och st&#xE4;rka v&#xE4;lgrundad politik och genomf&#xF6;rbar lagstiftning f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och &#xF6;ka alla kvinnors och flickors egenmakt p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5119608.157553317</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2847211.5122252144</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1989001.9890019887</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">5119608.157553317</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2847211.5122252144</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1989001.9890019891</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-7402.7855624531</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-09">12554118.864706</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">5119608.157553317</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">2847211.5122252144</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">936000.936000936</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">1053001.053001053</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">-7430.1124165865</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women&#x2019;s regional programme Men and Women for Gender Equality focused on engaging men and boys to achieve gender equality in partnership with women and girls through a bottom-up approach. The programme focused on Egypt, Palestine, Lebanon, and Morocco.&#xA0; The programme aimed to work with conservative local communities in these four countries to reach vulnerable and marginalized groups. Two main research studies lay the foundation of this programme; International Men and Gender Equality Survey (IMAGES) and research on women&#x2019;s rights in Muslim family context conducted by the global movement Musawah.
Overall, the results achieved have been the following during the activity period 2015-2018:
- A social media campaign &#x201C;Because I am a Man&#x201D; was launched in 2017. The campaign received high visibility in media and spurred debated and discussions both online and offline. The campaign reached more than 13 million people in the four countries. By identifying and partnering with positive male role models and celebrities increased the campaign&#x2019;s outreach on social media. Worth noting is that the campaigns have been measured quantitatively. To measure how the content actually has reached the public is a difficult and time-consuming task. It is also difficult to know whether the content is received as intended, there might be a resistance involved in indulging in the campaigns.&#xA0;
- Several knowledge products, including the IMAGES reports, regional and country-level films, infographics, cartoons, social media films, and virtual reality films were produced and disseminated to illustrate the research findings and the policy recommendations. IMAGES MENA was launched regionally and subsequently nationally in each country. The research was cited in more than 475 media outlets, including in the Economist and the Guardian with an outreach of 1.48 billion persons globally. IMAGES research is being used as an input in the regional UN Women strategic note 2018-2021. In addition to this, the findings of IMAGES MENA were presented at more than 600 national, regional and international meetings.&#xA0;
-&#xA0; UN Women collaborated with Musaweh on organizing the course on Islam &amp; Gender Equality and Justice. The courses helped women&#x2019;s activists to engage with Islam constructively and to challenge the way religion is used to justify gender discrimination. An achieved result from the courses was that the participants developed 5 national action plans to promote gender equality in the family context by using alternative interpretations of Islam. Musawah produced and disseminated several knowledge products.&#xA0;Research on &#x201C;Family Dynamics in Muslim Contexts&#x201D; illustrating gender inequalities in the family context was conducted. The research has produced communication material and knowledge products which have been integrated into university curricula in Egypt and Lebanon.
- The establishment of the network the Youth Gender Innovation Agora (GIA) enabled regular dialogue with youth at the regional level. An advocacy toolkit was developed to enhance advocacy in the region with a focus on youth.&#xA0;
- 16 participants from 14 Community Based Organizations (CBO) strengthened their capacity to engage men and boys in gender equality as a result of their participation in a regional Training for Trainers on masculinities. The capacity-building component included working with faith-based leaders to integrate a gender-sensitive approach in Islam. In Egypt, CBOs have improved their organizational capacity. One CBO working on disabilities has managed to submit proposals to donors without external support.
- CBOs developed strategies and policies. For example the Sharek Youth Forum Palestine developed 2 strategies: 1. Paternal leave to male employees in the organization. 2. Advocacy Campaign Strategy &quot;We are Partners&quot; wich is part of the &quot;PRomoting Gender Equality through mobile theatre&quot; project. RDFL in Lebanon rolled out a national advocacy campaign against child marriage and CRTDA an advocacy campaign on nationality rights reached parliament members with the aim of changing the existing legislation. &#xA0;
- A comprehensive capacity-building toolbox for emerging CBOs and youth groups and a masculinities manual &quot;Outside the box&quot; was developed and used in all four countries. This is the first contextual and culturally validated tool on this subject in the region. A number of of CBOs started delivering sessions based guided by the manual on marriage counseling sessions to newlyweds and engages couples to raise awareness on the sexual and reproductive health as well as positive parenting and the advantages of engaging fathers.
- As a result of the engagement of the National Council for Women in Egypt in the programme, they integrated engaging men and boys in gender equality in the National Women Empowerment Strategy &#x2013; Vision 2030.&#xA0;
&#xA0;
The following unexpected results or potential results have been reported:
- The research will not only generate evidence-based data, but it will also impact individuals that participated in the studies and were exposed to the programme.
- National successes could lead to regional impact. National research could have an impact on all Arab and Islamic countries due to commonalities and the involvement of national religious organization, which in turn legitimizes changes in religious contexts.&#xA0;
- Intended long-term impact is minimizing patriarchal views, influencing behavioral change and changing social norms, including individual change as well as the relationship between men and women.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030244" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
