<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIC242</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contributing to the reduction of violence, sexual exploitation and discrimination against HIV in Le&#xF3;n</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commercial sexual exploitation of children and adolescents is a serious violation of human rights, a form of modern slavery, degrading and a crime against humanity, affecting the development of children, causing physical, psychological and moral damage, attacking their dignity, identity and self-esteem. It is a structural and multi-causal problem.
Currently, with the health crisis, restrictions, self-confinement and the fear of contagion, children are out of school, with less access to support networks and more virtualised with many hours in front of mobile phone screens, whether for online classes, homework or entertainment, without the supervision of an adult.
The project is a 4 year accompaniment process with adolescents in vulnerability to sexual violence and sexual exploitation, applying the Mary Barreda Association (MB) working method, with 32 years of experience. MB works on the reduction of risk factors and the increase of protective factors, to achieve emotional recovery, the strengthening of family ties, social and family reintegration. The approach differentiates those in a situation of sexual exploitation and those at risk, so that they do not reach the situation - preventive approach -, both with individual and group attention, the work with families being one of the main strategies, to develop a facilitating context to positively favour their processes. MB will work with adolescents and families in the peripheral neighbourhoods of Le&#xF3;n, Los Poetas sector. 
MB aims that people recognise all expressions of violence as not natural nor inevitable: trafficking, sexual exploitation, HIV, criminal acts violating the rights of children, adolescents and adult women, must be reported to the corresponding bodies guaranteeing their protection. This is done through campaigns with the general population: written, radio, tv, distribution of comms materials, mass awareness activities, social networks, website, promotion and testing of HIV, workshops, meetings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIC242" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association Mary Barreda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIC242" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIC242" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-01-01">25000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55490">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-11-30">25000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
