<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/SA1/H-APC-GBV/INGO/15056</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Health and Protection Response and Coordination Mechanism for Conflict Affected Communities in Kandahar Province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action will address the humanitarian needs of the most vulnerable conflict-affected population in Kandahar (Shahwalikot, Maywand and Zheray districts) and Kabul Province (Kabul and Qarabagh districts) through a multi-sector intervention encompassing: Health, including the scale up of trauma services, Sexual and Reproductive Health Care (SRH) and psychosocial support Protection, including case management for cases Gender Based Violence (GBV), Child Protection (CP) and People with Specific Needs (PwSN), protection monitoring, prevention activities such as community dialogues and the cross-cutting Area Based Response (ABR) Pilot, as part of a joint initiative with WHO, OCHA, INTERSOS and NRC.

Through the proposed action, INTERSOS will aim at tackling the identified needs by focussing on:

- Trauma care services in conflict-affected areas, by establishing First Aid Trauma Points (FATPs) - not included in the Basic Package of Health Services (BPHS) - in two Comprehensive Health Centers (CHCs) in Shahwalikot and Maywand districts in Kandahar province
- Provision of integrated Primary Health Care (PHC) services (including SRH) and protection services (GBV, CP and PwSN case management, community dialogues, protection monitoring) through two community centers in Zheray and Maywand districts, and one Mobile Health Team (MHT) roving between community centers established by NRC in Kabul and Qarabagh district to address the challenges with access to basic health support, faced in particular by displaced communities.
- Improved access to information and multi-agency services in hard to reach areas, through the establishment of two community centers in Maywand and Zheray districts based on the ABR approach. The centers will be hubs for integrated services provided by INTERSOS (health and protection) and other actors, as well as locations for humanitarian coordination and activities aiming at ensuring accountability to affected populations (AAP): inter-agency two-way communication with communities, feedback mechanisms and community engagement.

The project will address the gaps through an holistic strategy aiming at reaching the most vulnerable individuals living in remote areas through 1) provision of integrated services through the establishment of static centers, based on the ABR approach, offering a safe and confidential space where community members can seek comprehensive health and protection assistance, based on a case management methodology and 2) mobile approach providing basic health services to underserved communities. The intervention will be based on close synergies with other projects: in Kandahar, with the mobile teams already operated by INTERSOS in Zheray and Maywand districts (under an OFDA-funded project) in Kabul, with the existing community centers established by NRC. 
This mixed (static and mobile) approach has been developed based on the analysis of lessons learned from the field and aims at addressing the identified gaps in the most effective way, particularly towards confidentiality and case follow up. This particular project design will offer a unique access to the most vulnerable individuals within the targeted communities, protecting beneficiaries from the risk of stigmatisation for seeking protection assistance while offering a comprehensive range of services.
45,838 individuals, particularly women, GBV survivors, children at risk and people with special needs, will benefit from the foreseen services, which will directly tackle the needs identified through the lesson learned from previous programs, INTERSOS longstanding presence in the area and the recently conducted needs assessment (Annex 4).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alan Walusimbi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0791868583</telephone>
   <email>admin.afghanistan@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federico Soranzo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0791612524</telephone>
   <email>afghanistan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valentina Corona</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0728130407</telephone>
   <email>pc.afghanistan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kabul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.53333300 69.16666700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="33">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kandahar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.99606790 65.47573600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="77.78" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="14.22" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="8" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-19">432888.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-19">367014.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-15056">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-19">799903.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304617034">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-20">319961.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
