<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-20/3481/SA1/WASH/INGO/15080</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Response to address the critical needs of highly vulnerable affected people living in Daykundi and Ghor Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action&#x2019;s objective is to contribute to reduce mortality and morbidity amongst ongoing conflict and natural-disaster affected communities in Ghor and Daykundi by the provision of sustainable WASH infrastructures and hygiene activities.

Afghanistan has one of the highest rates of under-five mortality in the word, in large part due to high rates of malnutrition, diarrhea and other waterborne diseases among children. Ghor and Daikundi provinces are among the most affected provinces that are facing considerable challenges, including lack of safe drinking water, safe sanitation and correct hygiene practices in communities. Ghor province is particularly affected by cycles of heavy armed conflict and natural disaster like drought, heavy rain cause to flash flood. 

In response to the current WASH related difficulties in Ghor and Daykundi provinces, Action Against Hunger &#x201C;AAH&#x201D; is planning to conduct WASH interventions in communities which include men, women, girls and boys with different ages. The intervention will focus on Chaghcheran, Dowlatyar and Lalsargangal districts (in Ghor) and Gite and Kejran districts (in Daykundi) in order to reduce the incidence of diarrheal diseases in girl and boy under 5. 
This project will provide safe drinking water and Cash for work intervention to 2569 households making a total of 18,054 individuals (4778 men, 4967 women, 4106 boys and 4203 girls). They will directly benefit by the construction and rehabilitation of Water supply networks (gravity fed and solar-powered), water supply non-network system, spring catchment (protection), hand pump (borehole and shallow), public filtration system (Bio-sand technology), distribution and Cash for Work programming. 
Under this project, along with hard component, there will be soft component where AAH is planning to do community Hygiene promotion, house to house sensitizations, Water, Sanitation, User committee &#x201C;WSUC&#x201D; training and Family Health Action Groups training &#x201C;FHAG&#x201D; training in all targeted communities.
The whole site selection for all hard and soft components will consider the WASH-GBV checklist as advised by the clusters and endorsed by the humanitarian community. 

AAH integrated a strong cash component in its operational strategy in line with the 2020 HRP which aims at reinforcing cash as a modality to deliver assistance. Indeed, to rehabilitate WASH community infrastructures and in the same time reach to the most vulnerable men and women, Action Against Hunger will implement Cash for Work activities for 242 people in Ghor province. Indeed, given the results of the WASH Needs Assessment Report in Ghor Province, many needs were highlighted in the communities and the type of work could be done through cash for work. Moreover, the winter being harsh and long in Ghor province, people can only work around 6 months a year as they rely mainly on agriculture activities. Therefore, Cash-for-Work activities will be targeted to the most vulnerable and poorer members of the community who are unable to find alternative forms of employment on the local job market, with the objective of rehabilitation WASH community infrastructures. 

Based on the designed program, AAH will provide 18 target communities at least 15 litres of clean water for drinking and domestic hygiene per person per day, meeting the SPHERE standard for the total basic water needs of 7.5-15 litres of clean drinking water per person per day. In summary, these actions will ensure that the target population has access to clean and safe drinking water, reducing diarrhea prevalence, particularly among children under 5.

This project is designed to implement in period of 11 months start from May 01, 2020 to March 31st, 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kamil Kaminski</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Head of Department</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 730 709 180</telephone>
   <email>admin@af-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anais Hely-Joly</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director- Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0799017736</telephone>
   <email>dcd@af-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alice Moret</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant  Reporting Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0730709196</telephone>
   <email>gro@af-actionagainsthunger.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daykundi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.66949500 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-11">241967.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-11">149741.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-15080">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-11">391709</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304608723">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-18">235025.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
