<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-20093733-TZ-1-IG-15-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-20093733" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="NL">Heifer Nederland</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Netherlands</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Igunga Eco-Village Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.000 families, consisting of 36.000 individuals, are direct participant. These are the more vulnerable households of the villages, including people with disabilities, female headed households and those living with HIV/Aids. Another group of 6.000 families (36.000 individuals) is benefitting indirectly from the project, resulting into a total outreach of 72.000 people.


The other target group is the Igunga District Council. They take part in implementation and will integrate climat smart strategies in their different action and development plans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the Igunga Eco-village project local communities in 9 villages will be supported to increase their resilience towards the adverse effects of climate change. The project intervenes through an multidisciplinary approach integrating different sectors: agriculture &amp; livestock, water, sustainable energy, natural resource management and socio-economic resilience. Lessons learned will be used to upscale activities at local level and to improve legislation at district level. Good practices will also be shared in international fora. 

Through a Farmer Field School approach farmers will be trained on a wide range of proven climate adaptation technologies, including integrated pest control (push-pull), tree planting and renewable energy sources. Innovative techniques to Recharge, Retain and Re-use (3R) water will be tested and upscaled, in order to make more efficient use of available water resources. 

Farmers and district government will, in close cooperation, choose and adjust the most appropriate solutions to improve Natural Resource Management (NRM), increase agricultural production and strengthen socio-economic resilience. These strategies will be translated into bylaws, policies and budgets. Lessons learned will be shared locally with district communities and staff, and with a wider community of policy makers, development practitioners and academics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased resilience of vulnerable rural Tanzanian communities through reduced poverty and improved adaptation to the adverse effects of climate change. 

Specific objectives:
1.	Vulnerable communities in targeted wards and local/ district institutions in Igunga are capacitated to assess, plan and implement sustainable climate change adaptation strategies through the development of an eco&#x2013;village.
2.	Improved understanding of climate resilience strategies among policy makers and other key stakeholders at the local, district, national and international level</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project covers the period from 2015 &#x2013; 2019. The main results where the project focusses on are:
-	Adaptation of climate change adaptation strategies by 75% of the targeted farmers
-	Increase of the average yield of farmers by 40% to be attributed to climate smart technologies
-	Achieving that 80% of climate adaptation targets are integrated in the annual development plans of the targeted wards and villages.

To help resource poor households, at least 80% of the targeted 6.000 families, get livestock and materials according to the passing on the gift (POG) model.  POG is the hallmark of all Heifer-supported projects. Heifer donates animals or assets to farmers, who pass on offspring or the same material, including the acquired knowledge, to other families. Knowledge and skills on integrated pest management in combination with soil improvement methods will help farmers to increase productivity.

The innovative water management approach 3R is used. This offers appropriate, effective and sustainable solutions to Recharge, Retain and Re-use (3R) water sources, by buffering the landscape, leading to higher availability of (ground) water.

Sustainable energy solutions as cook stoves and biogas plants will be introduced. Regeneration of natural resources occurs also through reforestation.

In all 9 villages Farmer Field Schools are set up, 240 schools in total. Each group consists of 25 members. Members learn from each other by experimenting and reflecting. They have to understand the innovative practices that are introduced by the project and they also share their local expertise to test and evaluate these techniques. Per group two farmers are selected and trained as facilitators. Their farms serve as learning and demonstration sites.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua for All</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Nederland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICIPE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Igunga District Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sara Peeters</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+3165520123</telephone>
   <email>sara@heifer.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kade 23 4703 GA Roosendaal</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="7"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Igunga District</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Igunga District</narrative>
   </description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.31080756 33.88046265</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14081" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31220" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-04-01">2132480</value>
  </budget>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adoption techniques</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">40% of the targeted households (2400) adopting project introduced climate change adaptation strategies (either improved agriculture practices, or solar, or biogas) by the end of the project</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">adopting households</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="B1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2400"></target>
     <actual value="6000"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household access climate techniques</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">50% of the targeted households (6.000) accessing at least 3 of the project introduced improved technologies for sustainable water, forest and renewable energy</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household access climate techniques</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="B1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="6000"></target>
     <actual value="5760"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">non-benificiaries copying</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Portion of direct beneficiaries that know at least one non-direct beneficiary household that has also adopted one or more project innovations</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">non-benefiairies copying</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">25 % of direct beneficiaries (1.500 HH) that know at least one non-direct beneficiary households that has also adopted one or more project innovations</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="B1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1500"></target>
     <actual value="6000">
      <dimension name="households"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate strategies in district plans</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proportion of targeted villages that prioritize climate adaptation strategies in their annual development plans</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate strategies in district plans</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="B1" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
