<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30667</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CF Muscat SME/HF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is expected to achieve a significant development impact as it will allow IFC to enhance access to finance for job creation sectors such as SME and low-middle income households in Oman partnering with a strong bank with an established distribution capacity and reach.    Specific positive developmental impacts are expected to be:  -	Job Creation: Through this project IFC will increase access to finance for SMEs and housing finance  in Oman that play an important role in generating employment and economic growth. -	Enhance access to finance for SMEs: The project will support the underserved SME segment which in turn helps the industry diversification efforts. -	Enhanced Access to Affordable Housing and Social Impact: The project will promote the primary mortgage market enhancing the level of access to viable housing finance and the ability of the population to purchase their homes. The increased level of home ownership will also contribute to improve living standards in the country; -	Positive Signaling to the Market:  IFC&apos;&apos;s continued engagement at a time of global turmoil is expected to send a positive signal to markets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project, comprised of an investment in a subordinated loan in Bank Muscat SAOG (BM or the Bank or the Company), is designed to strengthen the Banks capitalization and support its lending program to low to middle-income housing households and small and medium enterprises (SMEs) in Oman (the Project).  Bank Muscat, a client of IFC since 2006, is the leading bank in Oman. The Bank is a universal bank providing corporate, retail, investment, treasury, private banking and asset management services to over one million clients through the largest branch network in the country.  The Bank also has international presence through its branches in Riyadh (Saudi Arabia), Kuwait and Representative Offices in Dubai (UAE) and Singapore. In addition, BM currently owns 49% of BMI Bank B.S.C, an independent bank with banking interests in East Africa; a 43% stake in Mangal Keshav Group, one of the oldest securities houses in India; a 98% stake in Muscat Capital LLC, a newly created brokerage and investment banking entity in Saudi Arabia; besides a minority stake in Silkbank Ltd. in Pakistan.   This new investment is aimed at supporting a bank committed to fulfill the funding needs of segments that play an important role in Omans economic growth and job creation as well as strengthening its capitalization for future growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BANK MUSCAT SAOG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30667" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">T. Ganesh  Financial Controller PO Box 134, Ruwi, P.C. 112, Sultanate of Oman E-mail:ganesht@bankmuscat.com Telephone: +968 44 768 241 Fax: +968 24 784 776</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="OM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oman</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="OM-Oman">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BM is headquartered in Muscat, Oman. The Bank also operates through its branches in Saudi Arabia, Kuwait and representative office in Dubai (UAE) and Singapore, and has further international presence through its associates in Bahrain, India and Saudi Arabia.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.0000000000 57.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5221" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Commercial Banking - Housing Finance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30667/cf-muscat-sme-hf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
