<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-30285304-ANG12-0030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-30285304" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humana people to people</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Academic and professional School (EPP) Caxito , team 2012</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal Overview: To offer Angolan youth a lower secondary education through which they acquire academic and practical skills, as well as general knowledge and life skills to enable them to become productive citizens, able to create a good life for themselves and their families and to contribute to the development of the country</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Plan:  The first year of the EPP program is a basic year, during which the students learn the academic subjects at 7th grade level through untraditional pedagogical methods link-ing theory with daily life and practice in the professions, learn to work in a group, to carry out investigations in the community, to speak in public and much more, and also try their hand at three professions, namely Community Health Agent, Food Producer, and Environment Pro-moter. 
During the second and third year the students will specialize in one of the three professions offered at EPP Caxito, which are: Energy Assistant, Food Producer, and Modern Cook.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary: : In cooperation with the Ministry of Education, ADPP is launching a new type of education in Angola: Basic Academic and Technical Education, known as EPP.  The three year courses will combine regular schooling with vocational subjects and successful students will graduate with a nationally recognized academic and vocational certificate, corresponding to 9th grade. On graduation they will be able to continue to the next level of education (upper secondary) or find employment / start their own enterprise.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Groups: The direct target group consists of 70 young people, 12 &#x2013; 18 years of age, from all municipalities in Bengo province, who have concluded primary school.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADPP Angola</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="CONTACTINFO PROGRAM MANAGER"></contact-info>
  <contact-info></contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="7"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Angola</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caxito, Angola</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-8.58781074593600413.665962219238281</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11320" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secondary Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value value-date="2012-01-01">184491</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
