<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5108011901-ETH-16010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESMI School Milk Project (2014-2016)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ESMI Skolm&#xE5;ltids-programm (2014-2016)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A pilot for a national school meal program with the goal to create a  sustainable school milk provision system, driven and implemented by   community resources. Theproject is based on a business model, with a  definite self-sustainability plan that multiplies itself from the     second year of the project.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">This assessment concerns a proposed project called Ethiopia School Meal Initiative &#x2013; Model School Milk Project. It derives from the Ethiopia School Meal Initiative (ESMI), that aims to facilitate a national school meal program, primarily benefiting school children in need of nutrition, but also local jobless poor women, farmers and society at large. The goal is to create a sustainable school milk provision system in selected pilot schools, driven and implemented by community resources, based on a business model with a definite self-sustainability plan that multiplies itself from the second year of the project.

School meals play an important role in addressing the physical, mental and emotional health concerns that impede learning, but also increase enrollment and reduce dropouts to contributing to family livelihoods, while contributing to national food security. 

The project is expected to reduce malnutrition, increase school performance and enrollment, reduce school dropout while also creating business opportunities for women and more job opportunities for community members. It aims at raising awareness among parents and authorities regarding nutrition and sustainability, supporting the development of a vibrant local community and serving as a model for potential national level replication. 

The organisation has currently applied for funding of a school meal program pilot of 11 schools (14,205,400 ETB) for 4,999,999 million SEK, to be carried out during 2014-2016. 

The overall objective of the project is to address the problem of malnutrition in Ethiopian schools, through facilitating a school meal project starting with sustainable milk provision for children at 11 primary schools in two regions. Improving nutrition is expected to increase cognitive performance of children, while creating jobs in local communities. 

The overall expected results of the project are articulated as follows:
&#x2022; Community and individual dialogues undertaken to engage key actors
&#x2022; School administration in 11 schools are trained in nutrition and leadership
&#x2022; School Meal Program Committees established and functioning in 11 schools
&#x2022; School milk project established in 11 pilot schools
&#x2022; 11 schools take responsibility for milk production and integrate nutrition in school programs, and promote nutrition in the communities
&#x2022; Fresh milk accessible daily to 5,500 school children in 11 schools
&#x2022; 5,500 children are not hungry during school hours
&#x2022; 5,500 children are motivated and attending school regularly
&#x2022; Mothers in the communities support the project and are empowered by engaging
&#x2022; Awareness created among parents, concerned authorities and local community on nutrition issues
&#x2022; 95 jobs created in poor communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESMI/Ethiopia School Meal Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">728873.4529657867</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">355901.4390281518</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">728873.4529657867</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">355901.4390281518</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-01">1166197.61221</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-28">349859.3273954431</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">379014.1255703436</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">355901.4390281518</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The number of children that have received the milk and bread at schools have in total been over 12 000. This has generated decreased school drop outs to almost nil and contributed to that the majority of the children have improved their performance. School administrators and local authorities have been trained in how to manage a milk farm and the important link between school food and drop outs and performance. The schools have themselves become self sustained and all school have continued their milk production with profit and with employment opportunities conntected to the milk production created in the target areas.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51080119" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
