<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13597A0101-ETH-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Forskningsgrupp f&#xF6;r Afrikas horn</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HESPI, Support to the Research Working Group on the Horn of Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Detta &#xE4;r ett bidrag till forskningsgruppen f&#xF6;r Afrikas Horn till st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r aktiviteter vid Afrikanska Unionens genomf&#xF6;randepanel p&#xE5; h&#xF6;g niv&#xE5; (AU-HIP) som f&#xF6;rberedelse till konferenser om fred, s&#xE4;kerhet, stabilitet, samarbete och utveckling p&#xE5; Afrikas Horn och i R&#xF6;da Havsomr&#xE5;det. Programmet best&#xE5;r av policyrelaterad forskning och engagemang p&#xE5; tre omr&#xE5;den d&#xE4;r workshops kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras och vars resultat slutligen presenteras i en rapport fr&#xE5;n AU-HIP till Afrikanska Unionens Freds- och S&#xE4;kerhetsr&#xE5;d (AU-PSC).

HESPI kommer att ansvara f&#xF6;r &#xF6;vergripande ledning, rapportering och organisera workshops. Arbetet inom de tre forskningsomr&#xE5;dena kommer att ledas av HESPI, World Peace Foundation (WPF) respektive Goldsmiths, University of London.

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;det &#xE4;r 14 641 200 SEK och kommer att t&#xE4;ckas av fyra partnerl&#xE4;nder, dvs. Danmark,  Norge, Schweiz och Sverige. Sveriges bidrag kommer att vara totalt 3 500 000 SEK som utbetalas 2019 d&#xE5; andra partner kommer att g&#xF6;ra utbetalningar senare. EU kommer ocks&#xE5; att bidra via Afrikanska Unionen (AU) till insatsen p&#xE5; s&#xE4;rskilt definierade omr&#xE5;den.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a support provided to the Research Working Group on Horn of Africa to support the activities of the African Union High Level Implementation Panel (AU-HIP), in preparation for the convening of the conferences on peace, security, stability, cooperation and development in the Horn of Africa and the Red Sea Arena. The programme consists of policy research and engagement in the three clustrs, leading to workshops and ultimatly to a report from the AU-HIP to the African Union Peace and Security Council (AU-PSC).

HESPI will be responsible for the overall management and reporting and organizing the workshops. There are three research clusters, each will be managed by the following: HESPI; World Peace Foundation (WPF); and Goldsmiths, University of London. 

The total budget for the intervention is  SEK 14 641 200 and will be covered by four partner countries including, Norway, Denmark, Switzerland and Sweden.  Sweden&apos;s contribution will be a total of SEK 3 500 000 that will be disbursed in 2019 as other partners will make disbursements later. EU will also contribute through the African Union (AU) to the intervention in specificallly defined areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention on, Research Working Group on Horn of Africa is to support the activities of the African Union High Level Implementation Panel (AU-HIP), in preparation for the convening of the conferences on peace, security, stability, cooperation and development in the Horn of Africa and the Red Sea Arena. The programme consists of policy research and engagement in the three clusters, leading to workshops and ultimately&#xA0;to a report from the AU-HIP to the African Union Peace and Security Council (AU-PSC).
The support provided to the Research Working Group in Horn of Africa have the overall objectives to:
&#x2022; Support the African Union High-Level Implementation Panel (AUHIP) in conducting research on priority issues of high relevance to provide inputs into a final report to the AU Peace and Security Council and to convene the conference on peace, security, stability, cooperation and development on the Horn of Africa.
&#x2022; Deepen understandings of the dynamics of conflict and development, and organize research around three pillars i.e. (i)&#xA0; developing a security community in the Horn of Africa (HoA) and Red Sea arena; (ii) Regional integration and trade, infrastructure development, and addressing environmental and resource challenges; and (iii) democratization, diversity and state fragility, with a particular focus on gender and women&#x2019;s activism.
&#x2022; Assist in the preparation of workshops, and provide final peer reviewed reports to assist in the preparatory work to convene the conference on peace, security, stability, cooperation and development in the Horn of Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HESPI/The Horn Economic and Social Policy Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HESPI/The Horn Economic and Social Policy Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">333357.2690066519</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">333357.2690066519</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-14">333357.269006</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">333357.2690066519</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/grant-agreement-between-sida-and-hespi.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement between Sida and HESPI</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/beslut-om-insats-forskningsgrupp-for-afrikas-horn.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut Om Insats Forskningsgrupp f&#xF6;r Afrikas Horn</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The report for the first year of implementation is more focused&#xA0;in providing&#xA0;update on the progress achieved so far, not really diving into results. This was due to two reasons, one is the project itself is research focused and second, it is also the 1st year of implementation, creating difficulty&#xA0;to assess what was achieved by the project and analyse the changes made.&#xA0;The reporting is in line with the overall outline of the programme design&#xA0;and the outcome framework.
In general, the project seems to have made good progress during the reporting period despite the COVID-19 context it was operating under. The deviation in this regard from the original&#xA0;plan has been justified in the report and different approaches and future plan of adjustment&#xA0;was also elaborated upon.&#xA0;
HESPI was able to produce the expected outputs including, under&#xA0;pillar one, the preparation seven research reports and the reports were expected to be completed the second year of implementation. Under pillar two, the project has produced the first draft reports of the planned four studies. Under pillar three, five research reports were under preparation, the pillar&apos;s&#xA0;implementation is lagging behind, but a plan was developed to ensure drafts were ready by the end of July 2020. HESPI&#xA0;produced these outputs despite the delay in signing the grant agreement by some of the funding partners until October 2020.&#xA0;
The financial report submitted is in line with the budget plan, with similar level of details. Sufficient explanation on some of the deviation from original&#xA0;plan was also provided.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13597" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
