<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10644A0101-ETH-12264</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">COVID-19 V&#xE4;rldsbanken - Ethiopia Social Accountability Programme III 2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 Worldbank - Ethiopia Social Accountability Programme III 2019-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Omprogrammerade medel f&#xF6;r att bek&#xE4;mpa covid-19
Denna insats genomf&#xF6;rs inom ramen f&#xF6;r ett stort social service projekt som etiopiska regeringen och V&#xE4;rldsbanken genomf&#xF6;r. ESAP programmet bidrar till att fr&#xE4;mja dialog, deltagande och samarbete mellan de som ska erh&#xE5;lla service och de som levererar social service i syfte att g&#xF6;ra &#xF6;ka kvalitet och kvantitet p&#xE5; servicen. Andra finansi&#xE4;rer till insatsen &#xE4;r USAID, Irish Aid, Austria Aid, EU and DfiD.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reprogrammed funds to address COVID-19
Support to improved service delivery at local level through strengthened dialogue and interaction between service providers and those receiving the services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expected result of the ESAP III is to &apos;Support strengthening the social accountability system and mechanisms for enhanced service delivery in Ethiopia&apos; by
- Expanding the uptake of social accountability tools including community empowerment and mobilization, community needs identification and prioritization processes, interface meetings and development of joint action plans.
- Building capacity and systems strengthening to gradually institutionalize through sectors, CBOs, councils and other citizens&apos; representative forums at federal, regional, woreda and community levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="122" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12264" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 control</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="10.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">10.3 - Ensure equal opportunity and reduce inequalities of outcome, including by eliminating discriminatory laws, policies and practices and promoting appropriate legislation, policies and action in this regard.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">10.3 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika m&#xF6;jligheter och minska f&#xF6;rekomsten av oj&#xE4;mlika utfall, bland annat genom att avskaffa diskriminerande lagstiftning, politik och praxis och fr&#xE4;mja lagstiftning, politik och &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder av l&#xE4;mpligt slag i detta h&#xE4;nseende.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.5 - Substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.5 - V&#xE4;sentligt minska alla former av korruption och mutor.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">191102.8589422022</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">191102.8589422022</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-08">202522.323483</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">191102.8589422022</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/10644_Agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/10644_Decision1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/ethiopia/decision-on-contribution-b201816.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESAP3&apos;s strategy shift in 2020 meant that the MA needed to terminate the agreements of the existing SAIPs and prepare a new request for expression of interest that is aligned to the new adopted strategy. As such, the MA managed to close out all agreements in the second quarter of 2021 with all SAIPs. It has however, simultaneously worked on on the REOI and then after RFPs that led to selection of best suited SAIPs for signing new agreements. As of the end of the year 2021, the MA had engaged eight SAIPs to operate in 107 woredas some of which are new woredas. In here, it is important to note that in 2022, the number of woredas will be increased to 416 from the existing 317 woredas. Therefore, the MA had already started including the new woredas in its new agreements that it entered with SAIPs. 

On a more technical level, at the beginning of the year 2021, the MA had started piloting new tools for SA such as the Citizen Report Card, CRC, to set minimum standards for various services. Moreover, various training modules have been developed and updated to be used as the pre-disbursement training for SAIPs that will enter into agreement with the MA. During this past year, there were several challenges including the escalation of the northern conflict and the declaration of the State of Emergency, which impeded the MA to re-start social accountability work in the selected woredas. MA&apos;s staff safety was a major concern to restart the work in woredas that are out of the capital, Addis Ababa. During the Joint Review and Implementation Support (JRIS) Mission in November 2021, donors and the government agreed that the MA should start SA work in areas that were not affected by conflict including in Addis Ababa. MA&apos;s fiduciary concerns with the WB needed to be addressed in order to fulfill the MEL limitation due to travel ban in parts of the country. The entire MEL was revisited in order for the MA to capture and report on results more efficiently. The MA will submit a revised MEL plan during 2022 which will be embedded in the annual workplan and budget for 2022. 

Other important achievements of the year include the drafting of the FTA-SA-GRM (financial transparency and accountability, social accountability and grievance redress mechanism) linkage guidelines and the guidelines for the transition of woredas from ESAP3 to MoF&apos;s managed ESAP IDA20. The latter is an exist strategy for ESAP3, that will slowly transition woredas under the current program to the government which is a step in the right direction to institutionalize Social Accountability in governance structure of the country. Sweden and other donors welcome the plan of phase one transfer of 60 woredas in 2022 from ESAP3 to IDA20, however, there are still unanswered question on how the IDA20 program will include CSOs in the SA work. This concern has been conveyed in several occasions and the World Bank, MoF and the MA will try and address this issue in consultation with ACSO, Authority for Civil Society Organizations. 

At the Steering Committee meeting in early 2021, donors agreed that implementation pace of program had been slow due to the pandemic and then the various conflicts in the country. As such, Sweden, like the other donors in the trust fund, agreed to a no-cost extension for one more year for the entire program, which meant that the new end date for ESAP3 is now November 2024.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10644" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1780000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Ethiopia 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Etiopien 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
