<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:budgetline="http://diplomatie.be/oda/currentbudget.xlsx" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-2-10-1142</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-2-10" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CD4E: Capacity Development for Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Development for Education
Capacity Development for Education
Capacity Development for Education De onderwijsuitdagingen zijn globaal (SDG 4). Ook Vlaanderen heeft uitdagingen op het vlak van gelijke onderwijskansen. VVOB wil via een dialoog met onderwijsstakeholders in het Zuiden, Vlaamse lerarenopleiders en pedagogisch begeleiders inspireren om onderwijspraktijken op vlak van gelijke kansen te verbeteren. In het eNSPIRED programma zet VVOB lerarenopleiders en pedagogisch begeleiders aan om onderwijsvoorbeelden uit het Zuiden te gebruiken als tool om de wereldburgerschapscompetenties van (toekomstige) leraren te ontwikkelen en gelijkeonderwijskansen te verbeteren. Er is binnen het thema van gelijke onderwijskansen bijzondere aandacht voor gender, milieu en mensenrechten. Via de dialoog ondersteunt VVOB de internationalisering van hoger onderwijs. Concreet organiseert VVOB workshops en trainingen met onderwijsdeskundigen uit haar partnerlanden, masterclasses met internationale onderwijsexperten, een community of practice &apos;Internationalisering@home&apos; en voorbereidings- en natrajecten Zuidmobiliteit. VVOB zet ook in op de ontwikkeling en het stimuleren van actief gebruik van een open source beeldbank en online platform door lerarenopleiders, (toekomstige) leraren en pedagogisch begeleiders. VVOB draagt hierdoor bij aan de doelstellingen van de GSK Belgi&#xEB;. In de uitvoering van het programma werkt VVOB in synergie met en complementair aan de programma&apos;s van partnerorganisaties en andere ontwikkelingsorganisaties. VVOB intends to start up operations in business, technical and vocational education and training (BTVET) in 2018, in order to increase its presence in JSF countries. VVOB&#x2019;s support is aligned with Ugandan policy priorities captured in &#x201C;Skilling Uganda: BTVET Strategy 2012/13-2021/22&#x201D; and builds on two running BTC education projects.1 The main stake &#x2013; defined in consultation with BTC &#x2013; is to strengthen the professional development of Uganda&#x2019;s BTVET instructors, many of whom lack the necessary trade-related technical and instructional pedagogic skills to provide quality BTVET. To address the issue, VVOB plans three lines of action: 1) enhancing the relevance and quality of initial BTVET instructor training by increasing alignment with the realities of BTVET schools &#x2013; esp. effectively teaching the (existing) BTVET curriculum; 2) developing effective and affordable early career support for experienced practitioners entering the BTVET instructor profession from the world of work; and 3) developing effective and affordable modalities for BTVET instructors&#x2019; continuous professional development. As the BTVET sub-sector is undergoing systemic reform, a gradual start-up is envisaged &#x2013; as advised by BTC and the Belgian Embassy &#x2013; and final decisions on the partnership structure will be made in 2017. The VVOB 2017-2021 programme in Cambodia will upgrade the capacity of teacher trainers and practice school supervisors at 4 Teacher Education Colleges (TECs) in the provinces of Phnom Penh, Battambang, Kandal and Kampong Cham. Teacher trainers and practice school supervisors will be supported in different ways to upgrade their content knowledge of and pedagogical skills in mathematics, and to manage their classroom to deliver differentiated instruction taking into account learning difficulties and learning disabilities of pupils. All of VVOB&#x2019;s capacity development activities will be gender-sensitive. A total of 120 teacher trainers and 540 practice school supervisors will be directly supported by VVOB&#x2019;s programme. By the end of the programme and each subsequent year, 1,000 student teachers of TECs will benefit from the programme, 6,200 pupils in practice schools will benefit from the upgraded teaching skills of their practice school supervisors, and last but not least, 45,000 pupils will benefit from the upgraded capacities of the student teachers who become teachers in primary schools throughout the country. Finally, the programme will deliver support to upgrade the skills of TEC managers and school leaders of practice schools to evaluate performance and support teacher trainers and teachers, and to manage their colleges and schools in a gender-sensitive and environment-friendly way. Referring to several policy documents of the Belgian Government on Quality Education (see also 6.4.1, Relevance) and in line with the Strategic Goal 3 of the Joint Strategic Framework of Vietnam, the programme will focus on improving the quality of learning of 3- to 5-year-old children in Early Childhood Education in poor ethnic minority districts in 3 provinces in Central Vietnam: Kon Tum, Quang Nam and Quang Ngai. One result will strengthen the competences of pre-school teachers on process-oriented child monitoring. A second result aims at enabling preschool teachers to address gender, environment and ethnic diversity barriers to learning and participation and to ensure deep level learning among all children. A third result will strengthen the needs-based/school-based in-service professionalization system for pre-school teachers. In each province, the programme will partner with the Department of Education and Training which will set up a Professional Teacher Development trajectory for the preschool leaders and teachers in their respective districts. To facilitate this the programme will build up the capacity of the Departments and Bureaus of Education and Training. Maximizing its impact and efficiency, the programme has mapped out its partnerships and collaborative/synergy efforts, both with respect to local, Belgian (such as PLAN) and international partners. The programme wil run from January 1, 2017 till December 31, 2021. In Belgi&#xEB; werken tientallen organisaties en individuen in de opleidings- of onderwijssector binnen ontwikkelingssamenwerking (OS). Aangezien er nauwelijks structureel overleg bestond tussen deze actoren, werd in 2010 Educaid.be opgestart. Het platform wil de capaciteit en expertise van haar leden versterken, bijdragen aan het bevorderen van complementariteit en synergi&#xEB;n tussen haar leden, en het Belgische beleid rond onderwijs en ontwikkeling verder helpen uitbouwen en ondersteunen. Het doet dit door het cre&#xEB;ren van een leeromgeving waar deelnemers kennis delen en waar kennis wordt opgebouwd rond specifieke onderwijsproblemen in het Zuiden en rond succesvolle methodes om deze aan te pakken. Verder wil het platform bijdragen aan de beleidsvorming, -uitvoering en -opvolging in Belgi&#xEB; aangaande onderwijs en OS. Specifieke aandacht gaat naar gender, milieu en ICT via projectgroepen aan deze thema&apos;s gewijd. Het platform benut ook volop verschillende ICT tools, zoals een interactieve website en de sociale media. Het gaat hier om een synergieprogramma tussen VVOB en APEFE, en een samenwerking met 48 andere organisaties en instellingen. Referring to several policy documents of the Belgian Government on Development Cooperation and Quality Education and in line with the Strategic Goal 3 of the Joint Strategic Framework of Zimbabwe, this programme focuses on continuous assessment of the wellbeing and involvement (CAWI) of all children in Early Childhood Development as the driver of the teaching and learning process. High levels of wellbeing and involvement ultimately lead to high levels of child development. Due to budget cuts decided upon by the Belgian minister of development cooperation VVOB has to close its operations in Zimbabwe and limit the programme to 1 year (2017). This programme pays specific attention to the rights of the child and the characteristics of the learner, such as gender, multilingualism and their environment. With a focus on improving teaching strategies (which include the use of ICT) and on classroom management and differentiated teaching, VVOB will provide information to ECD lecturers in 6 Teacher Education Colleges to enable them to improve competences of ECD student teachers. The large majority of pupils are in school in Rwanda. Go</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="1142" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-DAC-2-10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2876" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2879" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2880" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2881" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2882" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2884" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2885" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2886" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2887" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2888" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018C2889" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date effective de d&#xE9;but de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date pr&#xE9;vue de fin de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Date pr&#xE9;vue de d&#xE9;but de l&apos;activit&#xE9;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Direction-G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Coop&#xE9;ration au D&#xE9;veloppement et Aide humanitaire</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directorate-general Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>Info.DGD@diplobel.fed.be</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-13">44423366</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-05-18">8040946.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-02-20">8427985.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-23">193581.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-05">4401828.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-03">2434476.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-03">1967351.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-16">4682267.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-05">2589294.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-25">2092973.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="4500465868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-26">9592659.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0423616717" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VVOB - Vlaamse Vereniging voor Ontwikkelingssamenwerking en technische Bijstand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://www.diplomatie.be/oda/31572_KB_AR_MB_AM_2019_MB_VVOB.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019_MB_VVOB.pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <budgetline:code>5420356072</budgetline:code>
  <budgetline:descr>54 20 356072 NGO Programs</budgetline:descr>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
