<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-011598-02-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Progetto Agricolo Guinea Italia Paguita - gestione diretta</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto mira a ripristinare il sistema di produzione nelle regioni di Conakry e Kankan, in Guinea. I cambiamenti climatici e il degrado del suolo hanno infatti influenzato drasticamente il livello di produzione in quelle aree, diminuendo le opportunit&#xE0; economiche e provocando un aumento dei flussi migratori. La limitata capacit&#xE0; dei governi locali e della societ&#xE0; civile di coordinare le azioni e far fronte alle esigenze locali sono problematiche, specialmente per i gruppi vulnerabili colpiti dai cambiamenti climatici. Ripristinando il sistema di produzione, l&apos;obiettivo del progetto &#xE8; contribuire alla sicurezza alimentare e nutrizionale delle regioni oggetto di intervento migliorando la resilienza delle famiglie vulnerabili, aumentare la produttivit&#xE0; orticola e i redditi dei gruppi vulnerabili interessati. Pi&#xF9; specificamente, questo creer&#xE0; automaticamente pi&#xF9; opportunit&#xE0; di lavoro, scoraggiando la migrazione. La strategia di attuazione include un approccio basato sulla comunit&#xE0;, con un coinvolgimento diretto dei giovani, dei potenziali migranti e dei migranti che ritornano in quelle regioni. Incorpora inoltre un&apos;attenzione specifica per le questioni di genere e la partecipazione delle donne. Garantire una partecipazione diretta delle popolazioni locali e un approccio dal basso verso l&apos;alto per la gestione della produzione e dell&apos;uso del suolo non solo aumenter&#xE0; il livello di consapevolezza locale, ma migliorer&#xE0; anche il senso di comunit&#xE0; in quelle regioni. Il primo obiettivo atteso &#xE8; chiaramente l&apos;aumento della produzione orticola insieme alla creazione di piccole societ&#xE0; di servizi, legate all&apos;incremento delle attivit&#xE0; economiche benefici per i gruppi vulnerabili, come donne e giovani. Il secondo obiettivo &#xE8; il rafforzamento della coesione sociale nelle comunit&#xE0; locali, raggiunto attraverso il rispetto dei diritti delle donne e dei giovani.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to restore the production system in the regions of Conakry and Kankan, in Guinea. Climate change and soil degradation have in fact drastically affected the level of production in those areas, diminishing economic opportunities and resulting in an increase of migration flows. The limited capacity of local governments and civil society to coordinate actions and cope with local&lt;br&gt;challenges is also problematic, especially for vulnerable groups affected by climate change.&lt;br&gt;By restoring the production system, the aim of the project is contribute to the food and nutrition security of the intervention regions by improving the resilience of vulnerable families, it intends to sustainable increase the horticultural productivity and incomes of the vulnerable groups concerned, as well as areas of the initiative. More specifically. This will automatically create more job opportunities, discouraging migration. &lt;br&gt;The implementing strategy includes a community-based approach, with a direct involvement of the youth, potential migrants and migrants who come back to those regions. It also incorporates a specific attention on gender issues and women participation. Ensuring a direct participation of local people and a bottom-up approach for the management of the production and the use of the soil will not only increase the level of local awareness, but also enhance the sense of community in those regions.  The first expected impact is clearly the increase in horticultural production together with the creation of small service companies, linked to the increase in economic benefits for vulnerable groups, such as women and youth. The second is the strengthening of social cohesion in local communities, achieved through the respect of the rights of women and young people.&lt;br&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="011598/02/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="2018000329" type="A2"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural land resources</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business policy and administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, maintain the genetic diversity of seeds, cultivated plants and farmed and domesticated animals and their related wild species, including through soundly managed and diversified seed and plant banks at the national, regional and international levels, and promote access to and fair and equitable sharing of benefits arising from the utilization of genetic resources and associated traditional knowledge, as internationally agreed</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-06">453600</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
