<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="12" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/5190" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-spn-TJ-14-5190</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Nutrition amongst Vulnerable Orphans in Tajikistan&#x2019;s Baby Homes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ministry of Health (MOH) would like to expand a 2013 SPOON assessment to include rural communities where health indicators are expected to be worse, as well as typically developing children. Two key benefits of expansion will be a broadened understanding of the overall problem, and in turn better informed and designed solutions. This data will also serve to promote sustainable change by forming the evidence base for catalyzing national policy reform for improving diets for children living in institutional care both now and in future.

Next, SPOON will customize and implement a Nutrition Screening System (NSS) in all baby homes. This system enables early detection of malnutrition related risk factors amongst children and guides caregivers through the correct steps for appropriate action - ultimately preventing the permanent consequences of malnutrition. The NSS is comprised of five key components: a nutrition screening form, treatment and referral decision tree flow charts, a customized simple Access database for information management and reporting, training materials and NSS user guides, and M&amp;amp;E protocols for assessing overall NSS performance. Training will be conducted to equip baby home staff who will be responsible for maintaining the NSS, with the skills needed to use the system as well as assess and monitor a child&#x2019;s growth. 

To improve caregiver knowledge, attitudes, and practices related to nutrition and feeding, SPOON&#x2019;s technical team will conduct trainings covering topics such as: nutrition basics and understanding malnutrition; hygiene, sanitation and safe food preparation; safe feeding practices for children in institutional care and for CWD. SPOON utilizes a Training of Trainers (TOT) model to establish and expand local partner competency on technical nutrition and feeding content and effective techniques for teaching others.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to improve the nutritional status of vulnerable infants and young children living in all baby homes in Tajikistan through evidence-based and scalable interventions. Interventions will focus on building caregiver knowledge and skills and institutional systems for improving ability to detect malnutrition risk factors, delivery of appropriate care, and diet quality. Given the increasing number of children with disabilities (CWD) in Tajikistan baby homes, all interventions will be tailored to be inclusive of CWD by also addressing their unique nutrition and feeding needs. 

SPOON expects to directly reach 800 children (500 through Tajikistan&#x2019;s 4 baby homes and 300 served by the community support centers adjacent to the baby homes for CWD) by the end of year 2, followed by approximately 250 additional children (expected new baby home admissions and new child enrollment at the community centers) annually thereafter. To promote sustainability, SPOON will work closely with local government and our partner HealthProm, a NGO with extensive experience working with the Tajik government to improve social care for vulnerable children, to build local capacity to own the problem and solutions over the long-term by ensuring their involvement in all aspects of project design and implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">children with disabilities, children under 5 living in orphanages</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HealthProm</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-26-0712302" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SPOON Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vibrant Village Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="spn-TJ-14-5190" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SPOON Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tammy Teske</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>tammy@spoonfoundation.org</email>
   <website>http://www.spoonfoundation.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TJ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">142698</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vibrant Village Foundation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-26-0712302">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SPOON Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="800"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
