<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>PS-MOI-QR-1385-M-GB-GOV-1-300366</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="PS-MOI-QR-1385-M" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Quds Public Health Society</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People for Peaceful Change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Quds Public Health Society (AQPHS) will carry out activities to deliver the following:
1. MECIDS Research: Implement a joint mapping of Leishmaniasis spread across Israel, the occupied Palestinian Territories and Jordan as a baseline including &quot;hot spots of exposure&quot; resulting in a baseline research and mapping document that can be used as resource for the three health sectors.
2. Training of Trainers (TOT): Train 21 public health professionals from the three health sectors in a 5-day joint TOT workshop on Leishmaniasis and conflict mitigation skills. Train participants to become trainers in standardizing procedures across Ministries and sharing information on the detection and prevention of Leishmaniasis, as well as becoming skilled in conflict mitigation.
3. MECIDS Palestinian Coordinator: The coordinator is the main Palestinian MECIDS contact person. He/she is responsible for liaison with the Palestinian Health Ministry, and representing Palestine in all MECIDS board meetings and activities. He/she will work closely with the Israeli and Jordanian MECIDS coordinators, and will be in charge of project activity coordination and implementation including participant recruitment, facilitator recruitment and workshop curriculum design.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the project include, but not limited to:
- Strategic: Seeking greater impact through strategic collaboration; fostering learning and sharing good practice in our respective areas of expertise; stimulating innovative, entrepreneurial and creative approaches; and opening new space for different interactions;
- Collaborative partnership: Seeking and responding to new opportunities; strengthening mutual learning; common action and synergy; shared capacity-building between the organizations; assistance with addressing challenges; and flexibility in responding to unforeseen problems.
- Operational: Implementation of joint activities towards a common objectives, seeking cost efficacy, respecting security norms, and harnessing experience in Jerusalem to cultivate foresight and risk management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Quds Public Health Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Department of International Development through Search for Common Ground (INGO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IL" percentage="33.33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="33.33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="33.34"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
