<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/RA1/HNC/NGO/14957</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to adequate health and nutritional care services for children under five and women in Access restricted areas of Gaza Strip.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project overall objective is &#x201C;To ensure that more vulnerable children and mothers have access to a quality comprehensive health and nutritional system and are better able to survive and reach their optimal development.&#x201D; PMRS partners with RCS4GS and Ard El- Insan to ensure geographical coverage and complementarity in providing essential medical supplies for under five children and pregnant/lactating mothers, including micronutrient supplements towards making incremental changes in their situation as reflected in project outcomes:1. Children under the age of 5 have enhanced health and nutritional status from integrated community case management of childhood illnesses and malnutrition. The provision of essential medical supplies and micronutrients supplements are accessible for children under 5 at primary health care in ARA 2. Increased access to and use of quality maternal and nutrition services for women in reproductive age, pregnant and lactating women and 3. Saved lives of children with major childhood illnesses such as acute respiratory infections and diarrhea as well as causes of neonatal morbidity and mortality. The project targets 14,000 direct beneficiaries (4000 womengt18 years, 4900 girls and 5100 boyslt18 years) selected based on vulnerability criteria: women and children with reduced mobility (with physical disabilities, and bed-ridden) and with non-mobility related disabilities (blind, hard of hearing, intellectually) women and children in ARA according to their location, status, protection risks and needs severity. Beneficiaries are selected from most affected locations in Gaza North (Jabalya Camp, Jabalya, Izbat Beit Hanoun, Beit Lahiya, Arab Maslakh Beit Lahya, and Al Qaraya al Badawiya al Maslakh) Gaza (Ash Shati&apos; Camp, Gaza City, Juhor ad Dik) Deir ALBalah (Wadi as Salqa, Al Musaddar, Al Maghazi Camp, and Al Bureij Camp), Khan Younis (Abasan al Jadida, Abasan al Kabira, Al Fukhkhari, Mawasi Khan Yunis, Bani Suheila, and Khuza&apos;a) and Rafah (Rafah, Al Bayuk, Shokat as Sufi, Al Mawasi Rafah). The project links to HRP 2020 Strategic Objective # 2 Health and Nutrition Cluster Objective # 1 2020 1st Reserve Allocation Strategy standard activities and indicators and cluster geographical priorities (in Gaza).  It forms a strong joint venture based on complementarity and synergy between PMRS, RCS4GS and Ard El Insan with long experience and 2 child (particularly under 5) health and nutrition clinics in Gaza and Khan Younis, 2 child and women health clinics at RCS4GS in Jabalia camp and Gaza city, and 3  child and women health clinics at PMRS in Fokhari, Gaza and Jabalia. They are well suited to implement responsive common and specialized activities (based on the specialization and experience of each partner) to address priority needs of under five children and pregnant/lactating mothers and achieve project outcomes. The project applies right based approach and &#x201C;do no harm&#x201D; principle. Its activities are: treating 10000 children under 5 years with malnutrition and providing them with regular medical supplies and micronutrient supplements providing quality maternal and nutrition services to 4000 women in reproductive age, pregnant and lactating women providing life-saving medication to 1000 children with major childhood illnesses training 20 health workers from PHCs facilities in nutritional protocols and community engagement mechanisms like 80 cooking demonstrations, 150 awareness raising sessions, radio ads, community meetings, media visits, FGDs, leaflets, fact sheets and satisfaction forms. Partners follow 4W activity tracking matrix to coordinate with organizations executing activities in project locations, complementarity with ongoing projects, resilience of beneficiaries, participatory monitoring, GENDER/AGE differences, inclusion of women and children with disabilities, environmentally neutral, protection mainstreaming, security and full access to project services</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ard El Insan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RED CRESCENT SOCIETY FOR GAZA STRIP (RCS4GS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bassam Zaqout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0562020504</telephone>
   <email>pmrs.projects@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-03">501502.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400357548">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">4709.68</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-14957">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-03">501502.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304518868">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-04">401201.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304771634">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-22">100300.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Medical Relief Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
