<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-OPT-20/DDA-3482/SA1/PROT/NGO/15572</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection response mechanisms are in place to prevent and mitigate the effects of GBV on women and girls in Easter area of Khanyounis &#x2013; Southern Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This intervention will be implemented in marginalized areas (east of Khan Yunis) as it is considered one of the most areas that suffer from the lack of GBV services according to the GBV/SC mapping of services.  The project will target women amp girls according to the multi-sectorial services approach where the provision of sexual amp reproductive health services (SRHS) will be an entry point for detection of GBV cases, this in addition to strengthening psychological amp social support for women amp girls by providing individual psychological, social amp legal counseling, which is characterized by privacy, confidentiality, amp safety, in addition to implementation of open days amp trips for psychological debriefing.

Referral services upon SOPs referral pathway will be provided in order to obtain advanced services through cooperation with specialized NGOs in legal amp MHPSS. The project will also apply the theory of change with beneficiaries (males and females) by targeting men and boys as they are considered to be those responsible for the domestic violence, through the implementation of series of awareness sessions about women&apos;s rights, GBV amp protection mechanisms, for the same group in order to build cumulative knowledge, concepts, skills, attitudes and behaviors of target groups. 

To ensure the principle of accessibility amp availability of services for beneficiaries, transportation will be provided for the participants in the workshops, amp vulnerable women amp girls to access to multi sectorial services. The project will also include home visits in ARAs for women amp girls who couldn&#x2019;t access the center for different reasons.

Based on the importance of community participation, the community will be involved in all the project stages starting by the need assessment, design amp formulation of the project, planning, implementation and MampE. All these will insure accountability amp transparency to the targeted beneficiaries, this will come through the implementation of focus groups discussion in the middle of the project which will target 40 beneficiaries of women, girls, men amp boys to participate in monitoring the provided services where modification of the intervention may take place if needed. 50 Satisfaction questionnaires will be distributed to measure the beneficiaries&#x2019; satisfaction, it will be distributed all over the project life cycle in order to improve the quality of the services. 2 accountability sessions will be implemented at the end of the project to evaluate the interventions, document good practices amp document lessons learned to take them into consideration in future interventions, while noting that 38 women, girls, men amp boys participated in the project design through 3 focus groups which studied their needs amp priorities in eastern Khan Younis.

In the project we couldn&#x2019;t neglect the hard circumstances related to COVID19, as Gaza Strip nowadays works hard to prevent amp limit the dissemination of Coronavirus, so within this intervention, it will include the distribution of hygiene kits, these kits will be distributed to the most vulnerable groups including people with disabilities, amp elderly women, in addition to conducting radio spot targeting the local community to raise awareness of the mechanisms to prevent Coronavirus.

The quality of all previous interventions will be ensured by building the capacity of the project staff through conducting training course on SOPs amp referral pathway. 

It should be noted that the project will ensure accurate documentation of all interventions through GBV data collection sheet, field follow-up of the work site amp periodic meetings with the project staff, and due to our belief in the importance of coordination amp strengthening mechanisms for documenting amp sharing information, coordination will take place with GBV/SC amp the Protection Cluster by attending the meetings regularly in order to share experiences amp information about the interventions with all other members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jehan Al Aklouk</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00972599731994</telephone>
   <email>jehan.uhwc@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="2000">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gaza Strip</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.35644200 34.32704700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-04">129701.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-04">70346.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PSE67-15572">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-04">200047.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304600255">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-11">160038.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304905345">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-02">40009.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union of Health Work Committees (UHWC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">oPt BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PSE67-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
