<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-GLA181</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research: &quot;South-south migration: the dynamics of Salvadorian migration to Costa Rica and Panama&quot;.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project consists of a research initiative that seeks to understand one of the many aspects of the migratory flow in the south-south context as an alternative destination for Salvadorians who, faced with the strict North American migration policies, seek non-traditional destinations. A direct consequence of this work would be the strengthening of networking and collaboration between Jesuit works dedicated to the defense and promotion of human rights in the southern region of Central America. 

Certainly, the research could offer insights to generate an improvement in the accompaniment of the migrant population which, in specific terms, could translate into an impact on the work carried out by the Red de Atenci&#xF3;n de la Red Jesuita para Migrantes de Centroam&#xE9;rica, especially in the Panama chapter. 

The research proposal will be carried out in three phases. During the first three months, the partner will conduct a systematic literature review on the south-south migration flow in the Central American region. Once this foundation has been built, the conditions, techniques and instruments for fieldwork and data collection will be prepared. 

The second phase will consist of carrying out the fieldwork and organise the information gathered in order to get to know, understand and analyse the testimony of migrants in Panama. This work will involve travelling and directly collecting the reflections of the participants. The proposal is based on coordination with the Jesuit Migrant Service of Panama. It will be people from this institution who will facilitate contacts between the community of migrants they accompany. Similarly, it will seek to ensure the reflections of representatives of civil society organisations and the opinion of public officials from Panamanian migration institutions. 

The on-site visit and direct contact with the informants will allow researchers to generate trust and build an ethical relationship with the target group, after which a meeting will be conducted to compare the information gathered. For this purpose, two focus groups are planned: one among migrants and the other among the staff of the associations or NGOs.

The third and final stage will consist of analysing the information, developing the discussion, drafting the results and, consequently, drafting the planned final products.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GLA181" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GLA181" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Universidad Centroamericana Jos&#xE9; Sime&#xF3;n Ca&#xF1;as</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="GLA181" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-15">4988.0597</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55870">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-14">4988.0597</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
