<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-51756811-EUR-00002508</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RECLAIM Sustainability!</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The RECLAIM Sustaiability! Programme aims to contribute to inclusive sustainable value chains and trade in an innovative way, in which the interests, voices and rights of farmers, workers and citizens (m/f) are represented and heard in decision making for sustainable use of natural resources, decent work, fair value distribution, and sustainable consumption.
Our RECLAIM Sustainability! Theory of Change&apos;s premise is that IF we strengthen civil society; IF we increase and maintain civic space; and IF we apply a gender &amp; social inclusion approach - throughout all our interventions in trade and value chains -; THEN this will influence the public and private sector to adopt and implement sustainability norms that will ultimately alleviate the poverty of farmers and workers.
We need a strengthened interaction between:
- A Vibrant and Strong Civil Society that engages and debates with public and private  decision makers, monitors implementation and enforcement of policies and mechanisms, holds decision makers accountable, safeguards gender and social inclusion, and demands and consumes sustainable products;
- A Responsible Private Sector implementing comprehensive policies and innovative inclusive business models for truly sustainable sourcing, production, trade and investment;
- A Supportive Public Sector enforcing national, regional and international comprehensive norms and regulatory frameworks that ensure sustainable production, trade and consumption.

Strengthening civil society is an important precondition to deliver our strategic programme objective. We employ interrelated and mutually reinforcing approaches as a crosscutting strategy throughout our global programme

To increase and maintain civic space we will implement three impact pathways:
1. Advocate through Inclusive Dialogue: to influence agendas and develop evidence-based solutions to address socio-economic and environmental shortcomings in trade and value chains.
2. Accelerate disruptive innovations: to advocate for optimisation of the bargaining position of farmers and workers in the supply chain, through the acceleration of disruptive innovations (innovative, digital, circular, and fair production and trade models)
3. Amplify the voice of citizenry: to mobilise, activate and engage citizens and CSOs to change norms, and influence the policy agenda, on issues related to unsustainable and non inclusive trade and value chains. 

We will apply a transformative gender and social inclusion approach to challenge the underlying causes of social exclusion and gender inequality, such as norms, relations and institutional structures that perpetuate discrimination and power imbalances; as a result foster gender equality and social inclusion, and ultimately enable women, youth, indigenous groups across supply chains to empower themselves.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute to inclusive sustainable value chains and trade in an innovative way, in which the interests, voices and rights of farmers, workers and citizens (m/f) are represented and heard in decision making for sustainable use of natural resources, decent work, fair value distribution, and sustainable consumption</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">smallscale farmers and workers (m/f)  in the following sectors: Coffee, Cocoa, Tea, Palm Oil, Cotton&amp; Garments, Gold and local food production</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004331" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email></email>
   <website></website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">53712411.83</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-19">10551647.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004331" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-03">7624931</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004331" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">53712411.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004331" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1E4Je_ncZGgLnZOZtNgthULmrLANW_N_H">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RECLAIM Sustainability! Progress Report 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-05-30"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
