<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-51756811-EUR-PR-004212</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RECLAIM Sustainability! Grant/Fund Management Unit- Europe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The lead applicant Solidaridad Europe is the contract holder and ultimately accountable to the donor. As such, it is responsible for:
1) Account and grant management to the donor: Acting as the first contact point for the donor for any matter related to the administration and implementation of the grant and funds. This includes assuring that organisational integrity policies and frameworks are implemented and monitored.
2) Contracting &amp; transactions: Solidaridad Europe receives the grant from the donor. The grant is further distributed among the different Consortium Partners (projects), based on approved work plans and laid out in legal contracts between Solidaridad Europe and the Consortium Partner. Contracts and financial instalments are signed-off by Solidaridad Europe?s authorised signatory. Transactions are managed by Solidaridad Europe&apos;s Finance Administration team, Programme Officer and Partnership Coordinator (grant manager).
3) Finalising plans and reporting: Review, edit and final submission of all formal reports to the donor, including Annual Work Plans, Annual Narrative Progress Reports and Annual Audited financial statements, any additional ad hoc reports and providing any additional clarification upon request of the donor. Reporting to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MoFA) and CBF (the Netherlands Fundraising Regulator) about cases and handling of integrity breach in the Consortium.
4) Advising: Advising the Consortium?s PSC and PCU on MoFA developments and requirements, including Integrity, Sexual Exploitation and Abuse and Sexual Harassment (SEAH), and Mental Health and Psychosocial Support (MHPPS). Ongoing monitoring of Integrity policies of consortium partners (ORIA) and Development of a grievance mechanism &amp; confidentiality reporting system related to integrity breaches and sexual exploitation and abuse and sexual harassment (SEAH). Signal capacity and training needs, to increase capacity of the consortium partners and staff on prevention and response to SEAH, illegal practices and/or all forms of improper behavior.
5) Network and Representation: representing the Consortium in Dutch MoFA meetings, coordination of large external communications on behalf of the entire consortium with approval from the donor and Global Fundraising and Partnership development - leveraging the PoV grant and securing match funding from other donors &amp; funds.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email></email>
   <website></website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-51756811-EUR-00002508" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
