<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-51756811-NS-PR-000034</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Communication</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the beginning of 2021 Solidaridad and partners published a new edition of the Coffee Barometer. Together with our partners Solidaridad took up the promotion of the report. We developed an animated video, and organized an online launch event attended by 370 participants. To reach a wider audience than in earlier publication years, we translated the report to French and Spanish. The news about the Barometer was picked up in 28 countries, by way of 152 online articles, and created an online potential reach of 636 million, with Daily Mail and Yahoo Finance being the largest media channels, and Reuters and Bloomberg ensuring most of the distribution. In the Netherlands, the channels that published the report were NPO Radio 1, Telegraaf, AD, and Trouw. In addition, we continued to attract attention with the Cocoa Barometer that was published in 2020. For this barometer online potential reach hit 459 million.
We have also we developed a joint communication framework with Syngenta, which helps us to streamline joint messages around our partnership. With Henkel we started discussions on how our partnership can contribute to publicly accounting to consumers on the sustainability commitments of Henkel. We jointly developed a video that allows viewers to meet the farmers behind their shampoo, related to our joint project in Colombia. We entered into a partnership with Rabobank. Through their Acorn platform we will connect smallholder farmers to companies with climate zero ambitions that aim to offset their unavoidable carbon emissions. To draw interest to the platform, we developed a video with BBC Storyworks, featuring Rosa, a coffee farmer who captures and trades carbon emissions on the global market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41150939-00000952" ref="NL-KVK-41150939" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Network Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Network Secretariat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email></email>
   <website></website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sectors not specified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">193390</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">63000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41150939-00000952" ref="NL-KVK-41150939">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-30">4973.1</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
