<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-209131-GB-CHC-209131-A05822</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRITISH COUNCIL</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPower</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPower is a project that aims to promote the social enterprise and cooperative sector to young people as an alternative career pathway in Cyprus, Greece and Croatia. The 18 months programme was launched in March 2020 and it is funded by the EU as part of the DG GROW programme &apos;Reducing youth unemployment: setting up co-operatives to enhance working opportunities in the EU. The project is implemented by the British Council in partnership with the General Secretariat for Vocational Education, Training and Lifelong Learning in Greece and the Science and Technology Park of the University of Rijeka (STEP RI) in Croatia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of this project is to promote Cooperative and Social Economy Enterprises as an alternative, inclusive and innovative approach to tackle youth unemployment addressing young people regardless of their social, economic or educational background.
The specific objectives of this project are:
- To raise awareness about Cooperative and Social Economy Enterprises as a viable career choice for young people affected by the challenges of the current financial crisis;
- To explore effective approaches through the Media (traditional or social) for changing the perspective and cultural perception of the Cooperative and Social Entrepreneurship in Greece, Croatia and Cyprus and help bring it into the mainstream while still preserving its strong value-based nature;
- To promote Cooperative and Social Entrepreneurship as a movement and new approach, not as a sector (preventing it from being dispersed across different laws and segmented in various ministries) through the involvement of representatives of the sector;
To provide young people not in education and/or employment with opportunities, alternatives and hope through engaging them in activities that will help them unite with other young people and network, develop skills, get support and develop ideas for cooperatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project targets groups are: young people, especially those not in employment, training or education, stakeholders from the social economy sector, the general public.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will include the following activities: training of a team of young journalists, organisation of hackathon style events (COOPAthons and Country Final) in the three partner countries, a study visit to the UK for COOPAthon country final winning teams, an awareness raising campaign about the social economy sector, a final project conference.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Global Communications LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="2" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Secretariat for Vocational Education, Training and Lifelong Learning, Ministry of Education and Religious Affairs,</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;STEP RI Science and Technology Park of the University of Rijeka LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <telephone>00441619577755</telephone>
   <email>IATI@britishcouncil.org</email>
   <website>https://www.britishcouncil.com.cy/programmes/society/coopower</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Redman Place, Stratford, London E20 1JQ</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CY" percentage="34"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GR" percentage="33"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="HR" percentage="33"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-id code="146268" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nicosia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.1031  33.2151</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-id code="264371" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Athens</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>37.5902 23.4340</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-id code="3186886" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zagreb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>45.4847 15.5838</pos>
   </point>
   <location-class code="2"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities are offered online, covering three countries, including Greece, Croatia and Cyprus. The locations for the project refers to the capital cities: Athens, Zagreb, and Nicosia that the project is managed by the implementing partners at the country level.</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="11231" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="50"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-01">76176</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">162713</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
