<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-11-TJ-19T14019Y0095</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PR8051895/INL vehicles UGAI registration/PR8008189</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to help foreign partners professionalize their military forces through educational programs and technical support, ensuring that their force can develop and maintain the requisite capacity to effectively carry out its military mission through reliance on discipline, accountability, effective professional standards, and technical expertise. More specifically, this includes PR8051895/INL vehicles UGAI registration/Modif for PR8008189[Covers the repair and maintenance of motor vehicles including lubrication, washing, polishing, and mechanical repairs when performed by others. Excludes cost of U.S. Government-purchased fuels, lubricants, spare parts, etc., which may be furnished to the contractor. Includes insurance premiums (where applicable), vehicle permits, storage, and rental of parking space, etc. (See 2576 for Heavy Mobile Equipment)].</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through educational programs and technical support, help foreign partners professionalize their military forces, ensuring that their force can develop and maintain the requisite capacity to effectively carry out its military mission through reliance on discipline, accountability, effective professional standards, and technical expertise. In addition, activities assist foreign partners so that their military forces reliably demonstrate consistent support for adherence to norms of human rights; support the concept of civilian executive authority/control of the military; and have the capacity for institutional and security sector reform.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-30" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Office of the President</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Information Redacted</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-11" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-29" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-29" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-29" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-29" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Inquiry</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-647-8471</telephone>
   <email>foreignassistanceweb@state.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.foreignassistance.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2201 C Street Northwest, Washington, DC 20520</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TJ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="TJ">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tajikistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tajikistan faces many developmental and security challenges, including chronic food and energy shortages, poor water management, a long and porous border with Afghanistan, widespread corruption, underdeveloped democratic institutions, and inadequate health and education systems. With the drawdown of U.S.~combat troops from Afghanistan, security along the Afghanistan border has become increasingly important. Tajikistan remains one of the world&apos;s poorest countries, with its fragile economy dependent upon remittances, mostly from migrant labor in Russia -estimated in 2014 at an amount equal to 50 percent of gross domestic product-and commodity exports to a limited number of trade partners, which makes it susceptible to global market fluctuations and to any downturn in the Russian economy. The goals of U.S.~assistance to Tajikistan include improving the effectiveness and accountability of state institutions; building the capacity and professionalism of the security services; enhancing the bilateral security relationship with the United~States; increasing outreach to business and civil society; expanding trade and markets; enhancing regional cooperation on energy and water; and increasing the quality of social services, including health and education. These goals support U.S.~foreign policy priorities, including regional security, regional connectivity, and economic prosperity. U.S. assistance will build resilience and reduce vulnerability to Russian aggression, increase European integration, and provide continued support for enduring programs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="30"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-29">127.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Original - MOTOR VEHICLE M&amp;R</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="15220" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="1003" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stabilization Operations and Security Sector Reform</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2014" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1022">International Narcotics Control and Law Enforcement, International Security Assistance, State</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://sam.gov/content/home">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. General Services Administration Federal Government</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <category code="A11"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/U.S.-Department-of-State-Standard-Terms-and-Conditions-10-21-20.pdf</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
