<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/NFI-N/NGO/22204</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance the living conditions of people in campsites by providing dignified shelter and nutrition services focusing on children and pregnant and lactating women - envelope1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at providing integrated shelter and nutrition services to enhance protection from flood, malnutrition and protection risk for 72,126 affected people (roughly disaggregated as 8,626 men, 20,570 women, 20,413 boys, and 22,517 girls), especially for women, boys and girls under 5, and people with disabilities (roughly 1800 individuals disaggregated as 729 men, 642 women, 216 boys, and 213 girls) in Idleb governorate.

The main component will be the shelter components which will provide critical improvement to infrastructure and installation of dignified shelter in two IDP sites(Al-Karkat and Sham 9) (which will be also covered by the nutrition component for integrated intervention), covering the needs of 191 HHs of IDPs (roughly 315 men, 320 women, 340 boys and 389 girls, who suffered from floods last year. The activities will include the construction and maintenance of drainage systems, and roads, and installing 191 of new dignified fabricated shelter units (of steel structure and sandwich panel) with associated infrastructure in line with the dignified shelter guidance and case studies to mitigate the impact of weather conditions, prevent flooding and facilitate access to shelter and services in the camp to ensure better protection and dignified living conditions for IDPs. 
In nutrition components, SDI will continue running 7 RRTs for another 6months to cover 21 communities within 4 subdistricts, including 24 camps, two of them will be targeted with shelter in order to achieve the complementarity in delivering the humanitarian assistance, the rest were already targeted by SDI under other shelter projects.  
This intervention will bring the services close to those most vulnerable groups including PWDs and IDPs within remote camps, and increase their accessibility to essential life-saving curative and preventative nutrition services.
The pre-existing 7 RRTs: 2 in Harim, 1 in Maaret Tamisrin, 3 in dana, and 1 in Salqin sub-districts 
will provide nutrition services for 71800 beneficiaries targeting (20500 Pregnant and lactating women 42800 children under five years and 8500 other caregivers (men and women) (68200 IDPs, 3400 HCs and 200 returnees) (1800 PWDs).

The proposed 7 RRTs are planned to function according to the updated TORs and SOPs/2022 adopted by the nutrition cluster and CMAM TWG, and the intervention will include:
 (MUAC) screening and Edema for 56000 CU5 and 28000 PLWs by CNWs
 Referrals for specialized services by nutritionist as required according to RRT SOP.
 Treatment of severe acute malnutrition without medical complications.
Maternal, infant and young child feeding messages for 34000 caregivers including PLWs and IYCF and care practices one-to-one counseling for 5250 including PLWs.
Household Micronutrient supplementation for 21000 CU and  Iron folate acid supplementation for 7000 PLWs.
As well as, this project will ensure integration with other sectors:
With Health: Screen, refer CU5 with danger signs and medical problems, refer PLWs for ante-natal and post-natal clinics, ask for (EPI) cards for children under 5 and refer unimmunized children for children for immunization, Support Covid-19 (RCCE)
With (WASH): Support hygiene promotion- messages on hand-washing and safe disposal of baby&#x2019;s fecal matter.
With Protection: Identify visual signs of abuse/violence on children U5/PLWs and refer to the nearest case management site.
SDI will conduct staff capacity building for 35 frontline nutrition services providers on IYCF-E and CMAM.

MEAL team will closely monitor all activities and conduct PDM and satisfaction surveys to ensure timely delivery of services at the required quality and quantity while adhering to the humanitarian principles and standards.
COVID 19 prevention will be maintained through the delivery of all activities.
SDI will commit to share all required reports including 4Ws and other required reports.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-NUT-187989-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-SHL-188091-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="82" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">604787.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">194986.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22204">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">799773.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
