<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/ER-FS/INGO/21933</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase the resilience of affected communities by improving access to livelihood opportunities and basic services, through integrated multisectoral activities (Envelope 2)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The humanitarian situation in NW Syria remains dire for conflict affected population, with their needs set to dramatically increase throughout 2022 due to displacement, economic challenges and COVID-19. Further undermining this situation, the drought reduced water levels and negatively impacted agricultural livelihoods and livestock economy and created lower demand for agricultural labor (including working hours and wages). The food security situation has steadily worsened across NWS leaving 3.1 out of 4.4 million people in need of some form of food and agricultural assistance.

Under this project, CARE endeavors to enhance livelihoods and socio-economic self-reliance of conflict-affected population in Jarablus district, through integrated intervention between ERL and FSL clusters. Proposed activities aim to build the capacity of individuals, HHs and communities to boost resilience, economic well-being and social cohesion in the short and long term, as follow: 

FSL:
In line with cluster Objective 3: To improve communities&apos; resilience and capacity to sustain households&#x2019; livelihoods by improving linkages with value chain through the light rehabilitation of productive and economic infrastructure, CARE will carry out the following activities:
1) 650 vulnerable females will gain access to inclusive income generation opportunities integrated with agriculture value chains. Further 50 jobs will be created through the rehabilitation of basic community infrastructure. In total 700 workers (10% PWDs) will receive cash to address basic needs as well as set of skills and technical capacity building to help stabilize income on longer-term
2) CARE will purchase wheat from 800 farmers to support wheat-to-bread value chain and strengthen the local flour market . CARE will also strengthen the local flour market through wheat-flour processing and distribution to local bakeries, enabling these bakeries to sell 842,490 bread bundles at a subsidized price. Over 500 livestock herders (mostly female and PWDs) will benefit from wheat residues as animal fodder

ERL:
The designed activities are under cluster objective 2 Increase access to Livelihood and job opportunities
1) 150 youth and adults (60% women, 10% PWDs) will receive vocational or business skills trainings. 50 graduates will be paired with business grants to start their businesses and support local market and job creation. In parallel, to stimulate job creation and encourage market recovery CARE will support restoring and expanding 50 businesses mostly owned by women amp PWDs
2) 20 VSLA groups will be created in the targeted communities
3)Rehabilitate 12.5 KM of roads to improve camps residents access to markets and enable farmers to transport goods

The proposed project will contribute to and complement CARE&#x2019;s resilience-building approach by targeting the same geographical areas in Northern Aleppo where CARE has been already implementing sustainable livelihood programs through value chain approach under other projects.

Through the proposed intervention CARE will ensure community participation and planning and address specific needs, risks and concerns of diverse groups. CARE will ensure women and girls equally participate in community consultations and planning and address their specific needs, risks and concerns to mitigate GBV risks. CARE will emphasize diversity approach, considering that women and girls are not a homogeneous group and those with different vulnerabilities may face different GBV risks. To this end, CARE has developed a comprehensive gender action plan to apply gender lens at all project phases (Annex 1). Furthermore, GBV field workers will support GBV Risk Mitigation processes by providing the project participants especially VSLA groups with capacity building, information dissemination and awareness raising on GBV including women and girls&#x2019; empowerment, available services and how to access women&#x2019;s rights parenting skills and positive coping strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-ERY-188114-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="33.98" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="66.02" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">656741.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">649563.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-21933">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">1306304.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
