<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/P-ER/NGO/22087</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the resiliency of affected communities and the protective environment through integrated response of protection services related to GBV comprehensive support, child protection and empowerment by income-generating and livelihoods opportunities in Widows Camps (NWS.) - Envelope 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maram Foundation seeks to strengthen the resiliency of affected communities and the protective environment through continuing to provide the integrated response of protection services related to GBV 45%, CP 25% services, and ERL 30% empowerment by income-generating and livelihood opportunities under envelope 2 within 13 Widows Camps in NWS where MF has full access to 13 camps (Annex1)
The project will address some gaps in GBV services, especially GBV survivors, who may also have CP cases, and the role of early recovery will be to secure job opportunities that guarantee them income-generating work that survivors can rely on and mitigate the impact of child labor or exploitation of children or school dropout and family separation that may occur due to lack of incomes. MF will adapt activities that integrate PWDs with their peers as well as the project will ensure when targeting disabled children using accessible and inclusive communication methods, including alternatives to speech such as drawing, role-play and puppets ect. And by choosing activities that are suitable for everyone and places that are easily accessible to everyone
The project will consider CP cases and GBV cases in the process of selecting who will participate in the vocational training and the distribution of small grants
The project will ensure strong cooperation between CP and GBV in safe referrals, identification of cases, and implementation of GBV activities for widows and CP activities for their children like life skills, parenting programs, resilience programs and early marriage targeting both widows and children, considering PWDs, 
MF will make sure to balance between female and male staff to match the BNFs types considering the culture and situation on the ground
MF is still implementing its activities within 13 widows&#x2019; camps which showed a great positive impact on women and girls living in those camps and the surrounding camps, where it has achieved great success in vocational training activities and grants distributions (Annex 5)
This project will benefit these high-priority areas by reducing socio-economic vulnerabilities through ERL activities, strengthening and enhancing child protection services, enhancing the quality of gender-based violence services, preventing GBV, and strengthening community resilience. When providing training and a job opportunity for survivors through early recovery activities, it will reflect on their children who are exposed to separation, child labor, violence, or school dropouts.
The project will be implemented in the below stages: 
a) Coordinating with camp administration in order to keep on WGSS and CFs for the project activities
b) committees of women amp girls including PwDs amp elderly women (in each camp), the committees continue their work and participate in decision-making to determine the identity of the place and the type of activities.
c)13 mobile teams will implement the project&#x2019;s activities, consisting of caseworkers (GBV, CP) who will provide CM with both in-person and remotely, a female CM supervisor and female facilitator for each camp, and psychologists and PSS workers who will provide MHPSS activities. Also, a lawyer or paralegal will provide legal assistance. Male facilitators will target men amp boys who live near the widows&apos; camps and local authorities
d) the project will focus on Income-generating activities and livelihood opportunities to improve the self-reliance of vulnerable HHs and groups. It considers GBV cases and vulnerability criteria in the selection process of beneficiaries, this project will provide vocational training to women to administer a startup business grant program, especially those widows who have child protection cases the benefits of small grants will be reflected in widows who have children at the age of 14 and will not have to separate from each other and will ensure the reduction of cases of beggary and child labor</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-187530-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-187564-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-02">402437.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-02">398039.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22087">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-02">800477.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305692002">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-26">480286.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
