<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/H/NGO/22079</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelop 1: Strengthen the stability of health care in NWS by supporting the camps and schools with health services.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to enhance IDPs&#x2019; access to life-saving and sustaining essential health services for highly vulnerable households through:

Supporting Quenya Hospital (G0704011!Qunaya FH)

The hospital, which is highly recommended by the HC, is located in a highly prioritized area according to the allocation paper (Idleb --gt Jisr-Ash-Shugur --gt Janodiya --gt Qanniyeh), staffed and well equipped with all medical equipment in addition to a special incinerator for waste management and vaccination room that provides the routine vaccine and the COVID-19 vaccine by (SIG).

The hospital includes the following departments:
	Gynecological department: operation room, ICU, maternity room, postnatal room, and recovery room with a capacity of 8 beds.
	Pediatric department: pediatric clinic, incubators, and recovery room with a capacity of 10 beds.
	Orthopedic department: Orthopedic clinic, X-ray room.
	Outpatient clinics: general surgery, internal medicine, reproductive health, pediatric, and vaccination. 
	Emergency department.
	Admission department with a capacity of 22 beds.
	Surgical department: two operations rooms.
	Pharmacy, warehouse, laboratory, and ambulance car.

By supporting the hospital, UOSSM seeks to provide 77 K OPD consultations, 1650 Major surgeries, and 3,180 deliveries in densely populated sub-district, especially for IDPs, who live below the poverty line, and most of them are classified as the most vulnerable groups. The importance of the hospital comes from its location as it is surrounded by 23 formal and informal camps, at the subdistrict level, that lack health services, especially in light of the lack of public services such as sanitation and healthy heating methods in winter, which leads to the spread of respiratory and infectious diseases, especially with the ongoing COVID 19 pandemic and the overcrowding in the camps. Also, the hospital is surrounded by 141 schools, at the district level, where children spend most of their time in schools which makes them exposed to injuries and infection in the absence of health awareness and the spread of infectious diseases due to a lack of personal hygiene means. Also, the lack of periodic checks for pupils, especially new pupils, delays the detection of diseases among students that affect their educational attainments, like vision disorders, developmental delay, and psychological disorders, in addition to the absence of a healthy environment in the schools is one of the reasons behind the families&#x2019; reluctance to send their children to school.

Activating Outreach teams

To contribute to improving health, education, and protection awareness in the community and the surrounded schools, 10 CH teams will be activated in Hamama - kafr debbin and Janodiya communities (Janodiya sub-district --gt Jisr-Ash-Shugur District), beside and creating referral pathways between the hospital and other health facilities or specialized centers of other sectors. The CH team will be trained on the CH courses developed by WHO and GBV core concept to provide 41,250 beneficiaries with health and educational awareness messages by conducting home and school visits to raise the health awareness among students, families, and teachers in addition to referring the suspected cases to the hospital. In addition In addition to detecting and identifying GBV cases among the beneficiaries and referring them to the specialized center.


Supporting the Central Referral System

To ensure the integration and continuity of health services, UOSSM seeks also to sustain the functionality of the referral system through the provision of the fuel for referral vehicles within the central referral system in Idleb governorate which will coordinate referrals through 60 ambulances and 4 cars to transport cold cases between health facilities in Idlib and Aleppo western rural.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">695154.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">687557.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22079">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">1382712.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
