<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/P/NGO/22114</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelop 2: Support the resilience and access to early recovery and enhance access to life-saving community-based protection services (GBV )  for the Women, girls,  including Women with Disabilities in Idleb</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WSA runs WGSS in Hazano,Idleb, since 2018, and planning to continue implementing activities by providing GBV services for women and girls affected by the crisis, including GBV survivors, in addition to providing Apprenticeship Socio-Economic Recovery opportunities to the affected individuals and families in Idleb and in two widows&#x2019; camps in NWS.
Hazano WGSS is funded through HF until 31/5/2022 and we seek to continue to provide response and prevention services of GBV to women and girls survivors and the women and girls at risk.
Women and girls with disabilities will be targeted in all project activities according to the disability and their information will be collected from the registration form.
For WGSS we are proposing to continue providing the activities in Maaret Tamsrin Sub-District (Hazano and Kafr - Kafrehmul) following:
1-specialized GBV services, Case Management, specialized individual PSS, case workers will follow up with the WampG-GBV survivors, In addition to providing case fund to GBV survivors in accordance with the GBV SC Cash SOPs and referrals to other services(Medical, legal, CP, other referrals) according to the referral paths that are shared by the GBV sub-clusters and creating a service mapping for non-protection services through coordination with actors in the area.
2-Prevention activities: Life skills programs for women and girls (My safety my wellbeing), recreational activities, GBV awareness raising sessions (GBV-SC toolkit), training (literacy - computer-Languages&#x2019;) for women and girls.
3-Providing Individual Protection Assistance (IPA) to vulnerable women and girls According to specific criteria(widows and divorced, women-headed households elderly-headed households households with persons with disabilities(PwD) newly arrived displaced persons without shelter)total of 100$.
4-Conduct vocational training for women, such as hairdressing, sewing, wool fabric, Gift and accessory industry, pottery industry,.etc. based on needs,200 women will be targeted in the project.
5-provide 20 small grants and inclusive livelihood opportunities in WGSS and widows&#x2019; camps to a group of women who have been empowered or have ideas for small projects according to specific criteria, with high priority for GBV survivors and women at risk  including women with disabilities, the value for grant (500 USD) per
6-provide support for one local women&#x2019;s lead organization (We strive to women empowerment) in Maaret Tamsrin,it is an association licensed by the local council in Maarrat Misrin and works to empower women and girls).
7-Capacity building activities which include trainings for non-specialized GBV service providers, on GBV basic concepts focusing on health actors, cash and voucher distributors workers, and early recovery actors.
8-During the project will be targeted two widow camps to provide all project activities as needed, including:
- response services for women and girls GBV survivors
-safety audit activity to assess and address risk factors related to protecting women and girls from GBV in camps.
- Awareness sessions about: harassment and exploitation, forced and early marriage.
-prevention and empowerment activities to address denial of resources and opportunities.
  - referral male children to other services 
The camps that WSA will target are:
-Taiba camp for orphans in Kafr Deryan and Aisha&apos;s granddaughters camp in Al Foah
Services will be provided to widows within the WGSSs or activities halls in camps, according to the situation of each camp and the type of the services in accordance with Covid -19 prevention measures.
At the launch of the project, WSA will be held introductory sessions to introduce project activities and selection criteria with local councils, local leaders, Widows camp managers and organizations working in Project areas, the WSA will take into account the opinion of community and Women and girls in activities that meets the needs them of through registr</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-187919-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">165511.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">163702.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22114">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">329214.82</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
