<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/22130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope-2:Supporting Wheat Value Chain and Bread Distribution to the Most Vulnerable IDPs in NW Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at enhancing access to agricultural livelihood opportunities for vulnerable H.Hs by supporting wheat value chain marketing to improve long-term food security and local market resilience by purchasing wheat directly from farmers. 606  tons of wheat crops (around 75 % soft and 25 % durum) will be purchased from the most vulnerable wheat farmers (after testing crop samples using SOP before purchases) according to the market prices in Teftanaz sub-district PC(SY070004), Mhambal sub-district PC(SY070502)  and Maaret Tamasrin sub-district PC (SY070005) with selection criteria based on need and vulnerability with prioritizing women, disabled, elderly, and internally displaced farmers who cultivated lands or properties with wheat crops and meet the following criteria.
- Farmers who didn&#x2019;t benefit from any livelihood project for 2021-2022.
- Farmers who grew high-quality wheat crops.
- Smallholder farmers who own or rent land between 5 to 10 dunums 
- Farmers primary source of income is agriculture.
- Farmers reside in the targeted area. 
beneficiaries&#x2019; names and vulnerabilities will be identified through registration and verification procedures in coordination with Local councils and Farmer&#x2019;s Associations. MampE team will verify the data on the ground. Up to 220 farmers will be selected, each farmer can provide between 1 to 3 tons of wheat. Each farmer will receive support fees (25 $ per ton-WPTF suggestion).
The purchased wheat will be milled with 75 % extraction rate flour, and 25% bran (Which will be used to cover milling costs) to produce 454.5 MT of local flour, at the same time 778.5 tons of imported Turkish flour will be provided by IHH as a free contribution to the project. The total quantity of flour which is 1233 tons will be transported to the bakery for baking and producing 2,361,195 good quality bread bundles weight 600 g to be distributed to 4200 H.Hs of the IDPs in 31 camps in Maaret Tamasrin subdistrict in Haranbush and Kafr - Kafrehmul communities for 25 days a month up to 10 months. where one day at the beginning of each month will be allocated for replacing beneficiaries&apos; bread cards after verifying their ID documents.
Each ton of flour will produce 1915 bread bundles. The modality of bread distribution will be blanket modality that will cover all the H.Hs in the targeted camps based on the following distribution criteria:
-HH with 1-3 individuals will receive one bread bundle, HH with 4-6 individuals will receive two bread bundles, HH with 7-9 individuals will receive three bread bundles,HH with 10 individuals and more will receive four bread bundles.
IHH will be the direct implementing partner of the project while IC will be the sub-IP. IHH will be responsible for wheat purchasing, selecting farmers, signing MOU with LCampFA and farmers, storing wheat and flour in the warehouses, contracting mill and bakery, and providing 778.5 tons of flour as a free contribution to the project. While IC will be responsible for selecting beneficiaries of the IDPs in the camps, signing MOUs with camps managers, distributing bread to IDPs in the camps for up to 10 months and updating beneficiary lists on a monthly basis, and preparing a waiting list for filling gaps when beneficiaries move out of the area covered.
IHHampIC MEAL team will conduct field visits to check the condition of the warehouse, bakeries, the milling process, the delivery of bread, bread quality, and adherence to FSL guidelines and code of ethics during the implementation of activities. Project activities will be coordinated closely with local authorities, the FSL cluster, and other humanitarian actors in addition to the local councils, and Farmers&apos; Associations. This is to avoid any duplication and to engage stakeholders and beneficiaries in designing, implementing, and evaluating project activities.IHHampIC have a strong programmatic structure with a strong presence on the ground and excellent track records in delivering similar projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-FSC-188078-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-02">378545.65</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-02">374408.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22130">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-02">752954.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
