<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/FS-ER/NGO/22042</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the resilience of affected families in the western countryside of Aleppo. Envelope 2.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to conduct integrated and harmonized activities in the humanitarian field between the ERL and FSL clusters in the countryside of Aleppo governorate in Atareb Sub-district, which is considered an area with high needs. During 11 months, the project is designed to achieve integration at the community level as a whole, where farmers in the area will be supported through the process of purchasing wheat, and the food security situation will be improved for the families living in the camps by distributing free bread. In addition, olive farmers will be supported through a cash-for-work activity.
As an integrative community work, access from IDP camps to markets and from host communities to markets, as well as between IDP sites and host communities, will be improved through emergency repairs and rehabilitation of roads.

The Project will include the implementation of three main activities:
1-Purchasing 600 tons of wheat grain according to the market prices from 200 farmers at least (from 1 MT to 4TM from each farmer) in Atarib sub-district based on specific criteria to ensure the purity and quality of wheat. The purchased wheat will be milled to produce 480 tons of wheat flour and 120 tons of wheat bran. The mill wages will be paid through the resulting bran and the rest will be exchanged for flour estimated at 30 tons and added to the 480 tons to get a total of 510 tons of flour. 586.5 tons of bread will be produced (The extraction rate of produced bread to wheat flour is 1.15 per 1 kg of wheat). MASRRAT will select and contract with four bakeries to bake the flour and distribute bread free of charge to 1,589 displaced families in the camps for nine consecutive months. MASRRAT will contract with four bakeries to increase community participation and reduce work pressure so as not to exceed daily production capacity. 

2- CFW activity aims to secure temporary opportunity income-generating activities and access to livelihood opportunities, so this type of activity will be under the olive value chain approach. MASRRAT will target 300 olive farmers during the harvest period with 99 cash-for-work workers (all female based on specific criteria) from the host community and IDPs. Each beneficiary will receive $ 5 for every five working hours per day for 40 days. This activity will implement in three communities Batbu, Tawama, and Sahara. MASRRAT will provide the workers with the necessary tools and equipment to perform the work, in addition to personal protective equipment (PPE).

3- Rehabilitation of 7.83 km of roads including scraping, smoothing, traveling, and liquid asphalting (MCO), those roads are divided into three parts, the first road from Batbu community to Makbara with 2.77 km long this road will serve there camps (Alrahma, Alkarama, and Albir camps), the second one from Al-Jena community to Al-Tal community with long 3.35 Km, so will serve the Al-Tal camp, the third road with 1.71 km long, Jroon community and Tawama community road, This road connects Al-Islam camp to Al-Tawama village on one side, and Al-Dana Al-Atareb road on the other side. The total population from this activity 5933 people from the camps. 
This project will support 11698 beneficiaries affected by the Syrian crisis (3639 men, 3622 women, 2700 boys, and 2837 girls including 393 PWDs). All the people in the targeted villages and markets will benefit directly/indirectly from the project outcomes. The project is designed with consideration to protection cluster recommendations, wherein all the population in the targeted locations will benefit from MASRRAT protection Centers in Aleppo, in the event of any GBV referral cases.
The target villages are:
Jeineh 6272 HCs amp 2026 DPs
Batbu 4500 HCs amp 4445 IDPs
Tuwama 5100 HCs amp 4445 IDPs
Sahara 6005 HCS amp 3797 IDPs</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-FSC-187706-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="82" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">346173.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">285640.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22042">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">631813.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305691976">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-26">252725.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
