<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/ER-FS-P/INGO/22041</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 2 - Strengthening the resilience of affected communities in Afrin and Azaz</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to strengthen the self-reliance and resilience of the affected communities by improving their access to livelihood opportunities and basic services through the integration of ERL, FSL and Protection related activities. The intervention targets Jandairis and A&#x2019;zaz cities along with four camps, all locations classified as underserved according to the current OCHA allocation with identified needs aligned with Envelop 2 of 2022 SA-1. The project consists of 3 pillars: (1) delivery of vocational trainings (2) provision of livelihood opportunities in the form of small-business grants and apprenticeships and (3) provision of protection services to reduce the affected communities&#x2019; protection risks through the establishment of solidarity groups and delivery of case management.
Under the ERL component, 360 participants will benefit of vocational training in sewing, electricals, and baking and pastry, of which 160 will be selected to attend the apprenticeship program and 30 will receive small grants to start up businesses. Under the FSL component, 120 women participants will benefit of vocational training in food processing, of which 20 will be selected to receive small grants to start up businesses.
Several sectors of interest were identified through KIIs regarding vocational training focus. Based on the capacity of WHH team and available places for practice, four sectors were selected: food processing, sewing, electricals, and baking. Food processing will solely target female beneficiaries.16 groups with 30 unique beneficiaries each in 4 rounds will be provided with vocational trainings for 70-120 hours depending on the curriculum. The trainings will assist participants to develop market-relevant skills and self-confidence. During the training, participants will receive cash incentives worth $4 per day for their attendance. Out of 120 beneficiaries participating in the 1st round of training, 50 (30 females-20 males) will be selected to receive small business grants worth $1,000 and additional business support to establish their businesses. The grants will be delivered in 3 tranches to better monitor their progress and success according to the assumed milestones from the business plans. Out of 360 beneficiaries (120 in each round), 120 (40 in each group) will be provided with apprenticeship opportunities to enable them to acquire practical work experience. The apprentices will receive $120 per month for their work and their mentors will also be compensated for their supervision with 80$ per month per intern.
The protection component of the proposed project aims to enhance the availability, sustainability and accessibility of quality and integrated protection services with an extensive focus on community-based approaches, including i) awareness raising and communication with communities, ii) community engagement on protection risks and identification of risk mitigation measures through community-based protection committees, iii) tailored IPA to persons with specific protection, and iv) capacity building activities on risk mitigation and response interventions targeting humanitarian actors and national/local authorities to mainstream protection and maximize do no harm. In all targeted locations, community committees will be established with the participation of residents, camp managers, mukhtars, and representatives from local authorities with each group consisting of 8 members. The newly established committees will monitor the provision of community protection and refer individuals. Additionally, 1000 individuals at risk will be supported with case management, including 200 with cash assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-ERY-187918-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="67" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="17" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="16" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">284620.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-07-03"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">290945.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22041">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">575565.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
