<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/P/INGO/22092</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 1: Delivery of life-saving protection services to the most at-risk and marginalized women, girls and boys residing in IDP camps and host communities in Azaz sub-district, with particular focus on widows and persons with disabilities &#x2013; Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relief International (RI), in partnership with Ihsan Relief and Development (IRD), proposes to deliver Phase II of the current OCHA funded project, SCHF TUR-21/3559/RA3/P/INGO/18981, to deliver life-saving protection services to the most at-risk and marginalized women, girls and boys residing in IDP camps and host communities in Azaz sub-district. The project will have a particular focus on widows and persons with disabilities (PWD), expanding the presence in Azaz City through complementary activities at an established community center and Women and Girls Safe Space (WGSS) to meet protection needs at both camp and community level.
Phase II of this project will further the results achieved in Phase I to provide gender based violence (GBV) and child protection (CP) services as well as empowerment activities for women and children living in Azaz community and Shamarin camps in Aleppo governorate. Over the project period, RI will support 14,700 individuals: 9,850 female members of the community (4,600 girls and 5,250 women) and 4,850 males (1,675 men and 3,175 boys) in two locations : Azaz community : with 1 CFS and 1 WGSS center  targeting Azaz community and two widows camps (Qarit Mulham, Mulham Home and Aisha camps) . In addition the project will be operated in Shamarin community with   2 CFSs and WGSS centers targeting 10 camps in Shamarin with concentration of widowed women  ( (Al Harameen, Alshohda, Talgeben, Ewaa shamareen, Al Tawheed, Alarmota, Alandane, Alresalah, Ahl-al sham, Alresala/random


RI through Phase II will have a stronger focus on the provision of technical support and capacity building for IRD to provide technical and programmatical oversight of the action. In one hand programmatic compliance with donors standards and requirements, support monitoring and evaluation process as well as guarantee financial support. Additionally, technical supervision will be done through capacity building on key programmatic components such as PSS, CASH and Case Management service provision as well as support tools development (such as manuals, PSS Clinical Intake and scales to identify symptoms), upon request staff care sessions to case workers and PSS, and ongoing mentorship. With mentioned suppoer from RI , IRD will be responsible on direct   implementation of the project in the field , 

Following the findings of the Safety Audit and IRD led Needs Assessment, GBV activities are designed to meet the identified needs of the target population, to include case management with needed referrals, cash support, GBV training to frontline workers, focused psychosocial support (PSS) services as well as awareness-raising sessions, empowerment activities, including vocational training, young mothers clubs, robotic life skills sessions, safety audits, legal awareness raising sessions and legal counseling. Complementary income generating activities will also be delivered for women in accordance with the market assessment conducted by RI in Phase I. Under the CP component, the project will provide case management, PSS, parenting skills (including caregivers of children with disabilities (CwD)), CP awareness-raising, and training of education staff for a holistic service delivery package. Moreover, the project will support the existing CP Committees in order to facilitate awareness raising on CP in the camps, and the identification and referral of children at risk to the CFS. 

To strengthen the community-based approach, RI and IRD will continue supporting the 10 established women&#x2019;s committees to foster the participation of women in decision-making as well as build on community protective mechanisms. All protection activities will be implemented in line with COVID-19 prevention measures, with the focus on Accountability to Affected Populations (AAP), as well as mainstreaming gender and disability inclusion in line with relevant cluster guidance and considering local sensitivities to ensure a Do No Harm approach is maintained.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-187905-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">529689.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">260502.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22092">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">790191.83</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
