<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/P/NGO/22059</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelop 2: Ensuring the continuation of GBV, CP, and legal awareness and consultation on CSD/HLP in NWS, Afrin, and Jisr-Ash-Shugur (Darkosh, Jisr-Ash-Shugur and Janudiyeh sub-districts) with a focus on 3 widows camps and in coordination with Education, ERL, and Health SPs.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HRO applies individually under envelop 2, to continue increasing protection amp resilience of affected communities by improving access to integrated GBV, CP, GP: legal awareness consolations on CSD/HLP through its already existing three centers (Afrin, Darkoush, and Jisr Ash Shugur communities) and outreach teams along with close coordination with available service providers of Education, ERL, health, etc , and with a continuous focus on camps including so-called widows camps: Darkoush: Dorriyeh/&quot;Omahat Al-Moamenin camp&quot;, Sadiyeh-Bsentiya/&quot;Aytam Al-Sham&quot;. Janudiyeh/Hamama/&quot;New day camp&quot;. 3 sub-districts Afrin, Darkoush, and Jisr Ash Shugur, were re-confirmed based on HRO&#x2019; most updated RNA, clusters prioritizations, and HRO continuous implementation and observations which particularly indicated increasing risk of various forms of emotional abuse, physical assault, sexual harassment, early forced marriage, school-drop out, child labor, poverty, and other necessary needs due to prolonged conflict. It is worth mentioning that HRO has been focal point of protection emergency response and GBV referral pathway in Jisr Ash Shugur district, and 3 proposed centers have been funded by donors (1/Afrin amp 1/Darkoush have been funded by SCHF since 2018, 1/Jisr Ash Shugur has been funded by SCHF for 3 years and it lacked fund in June 2020 and has been funded by HRO up to now. HRO will continue providing 3 components as follows:
GBV services include case management linked with case fund, PSS, awareness raising, GBV actors training, life skills, SIR, safety audit, empowerment including vocational training and small grants, continuous follow up on already established and trained 2 women&#x2019;s committees in 2 widows camps in Darkoush (Dorriyeh/&quot;Omahat Al-Moamenin amp Sadiyeh-Bsentiya/&quot;Aytam Al-Sham), and training and follow up on a (new) women committee to be established in (Janudiyeh/new day camp)
CP services include case management linked with ECF and with a focus on child labor cases, PSS, Structures PSS/child resilience, awareness raising, recreational activities, SIR, as well as CPSM assessment. in this phase, we will add parenting skills with a focus on those with child labor cases, and establishment of CP committees ensuring their appropriate training and follow up.
GP services include legal awareness, consultations, SIR, and PM assessment. Outreach activities and established committees will be entry point for introducing project, promoting trust, monitoring, and identifying emerging GBV, CP, and GP needs and concerns, while enhancing referral pathways and access to services along with strengthening social network fostering in-place community protective mechanisms.
A continuous coordinate and collaboration will be followed throughout implementation period, based on recently signed MoUs between HRO amp available service providers under following sectors
Education (Afrin: Onder organization. Jisr Ash Shugur: Chemonics. Darkoush: SADAD), to strengthen referral pathways of drop-out children and child labor cases under CP component to formal and non-formal education, training teachers on basics GBV, CP, MHPSS and identification and referral. Vice-versa, these partners will refer CP, GBV, and GP cases to HRO.
ERL (Afrin, Darkoush, Jisr Ash Shugur: SADAD), we&#x2019;ll strengthen referral pathways of parents who have child labor case due to poverty, and women at risk of GBV due to lack of financial resources or independency to livelihood services, train and mainstream basics of GBV, CP, MHPSS among partners&apos; staff. Vice-versa, these partners will refer CP, GBV, and GP cases to HRO.
Health (Afrin, Jisr Ash Shugur, Darkoush: USSOM), same as mentioned, will ensure effective and timely referral between to health services and vice-versa. Overall target as 23000 (Men: 5360, Women: 9275, Boys: 3125, Girls: 5240) including (1150) PwDs. HRO commits to protection cluster&#x2019;/GBVampCP SCs&#x2019; SOPs, guidelines, tools, in addition to guidance note on Ethical Closure of GBV.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-188544-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-188571-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-PRO-188583-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">248894.29</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">246174.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22059">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">495068.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305691984">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-26">198027.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
