<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/P/NGO/22192</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 2: Empower and improve the lives of Syrian women and girls through increasing their resilience and enhancing access to quality specialized GBV services support, particularly vulnerable women and girls, at-risk and survivors of GBV.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has two main objectives 1st objective is to improve access to quality and lifesaving GBV response services for GBV survivors and women and girls at risk and to put measures in place to prevent and mitigate risks of GBV through providing a comprehensive package of GBV services for IDPs and HCs in Ma&#x2019;batli and Afrin sub-district in Afrin district-Aleppo governorate, while paying special attention to vulnerable women and girls, including those with disabilities.
The 2nd objective is to increase the resilience and strengthen self-reliance of vulnerable women and girls by improving their access to livelihood opportunities through integrated LH and empowerment GBV services.
Bahar will be contributing to the above-mentioned objectives through implementing a comprehensive package of GBV prevention, empowerment, and specialized response life-saving services through statics-based and community-based outreach approaches.
Under the 1st objective, Bahar will implement GBV prevention services including:
 Establishing and supporting 2 Women and Girls Safe Spaces (WGSSs) in Afrin and Ma&#x2019;batli sub-districts, one in each location.
 Life-saving response services for women and girls survivors of GBV, including case management services integrated with health particularly SRH and CMR services which are being provided within Bahar health facilities in Afrin and Ma&#x2019;batli communities. As well as, the response services include focused individual PSS, referral to other humanitarian services according to the service mapping and referral pathway, and finally case fund in the form of in-kind assistance and cash targeting the most vulnerable women and girls.
 WGSSs-based awareness raising (AR) program for women and adolescent girls using the GBV AR toolkit (TK).
 Outreach (OR) -based AR program and information sharing sessions targeting women, girls, men, and boys. The outreach AR program will be implemented by 4 OR teams, 2 in each location including male workers, and it will be composed of 12 sessions per group and will use the GBV SC AR TK while the information sharing sessions will be one-off AR sessions and will also target all community groups and it might include distribution of printing materials (brochures, flyers..etc) on GBV issues.
The OR teams will be referring survivors who disclose their GBV cases to the case management team in WGSSs while providing safe transportation. 
 Group Psychosocial Support (PSS) programs for: (1) women using Abaad and DRC &#x201C;Self-Support&#x201D; curriculum, and (2) adolescent girls using My Safety-My Wellbeing curriculum. Women and adolescent girls survivors and at-risk of GBV will be targeted in a non-stigmatizing way by the group PSS programs to improve their well-being and socialization with their peers.
Under the 2nd objective, Bahar will be implementing empowerment LH services to improve vulnerable women and girls&#x2019; resilience and ability to self-relay through conducting vocational training on sewing and hairdressing, given that these are the most VT that women and girls are interested in and consider as vocations that can rely on to improve their economic situation. In order to economically empower these women and girls who will attend the VT and support their self-reliance, The types of the VT (sewing and hairdressing) and the educational courses were selected in a participatory approach with women and girls through the needs assessment and also based on Bahar&#x2019;s previous experience in implementing GBV services in the targeted areas. Bahar will support the most vulnerable women with income-generating toolkits as small grants according to specific and transparent criteria (please refer to the &quot;VT Selection Criteria Annex&quot;) These toolkits will enhance these vulnerable women&#x2019;s access to market-based LH and production.
In addition, Bahar will be implementing education courses for women and girls on literacy and English language, to improve their ability to link with more job opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">227060.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">224579.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22192">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">451640.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305691997">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-26">270984.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
