<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/E/INGO/22190</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope1: Enhance education infrustructure in Idleb camps to ensure facilitated access to education activities that are well-tailored to meet children&apos;s demands (girls and boys aged 5-17, considering CwDs)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As per to Education cluster, 850+ camps are without a school after 11 years of the crisis in Syria. Children in these camps are forced to drop-out or to walk for a long distance to access schools in the nearby districts or camps. QQC will target 3096 children(1548 girls and 1548 boys including 25 CwDs 12 girls and 13 boys) in 9 camps in Idleb. Locations are Al-Hassoon, Al-Sabah, Al-Dyaa2, Abo Obaida, Fatih Dar camps in Dana- Al-Andalus1, Al-Dyaa5, Al-Omran, Nasaym Al-khair camps in Maaret Tamsrin.
QC acknowledged the needs before the call and launched a project, through Qatari fund to target more than 40 camps in Aleppo and Idleb with 285 learning spaces (90 in Aleppo and 195 in Idleb) that are semi-permanent, as per to the feedback of the shelter cluster technical advisor. QC also equipping all these spaces with the school furniture (24 individual desks, teachers chair and table, writing board, and wastebasket). The project is still on-going (ending in May 2022) in all locations. 

QC, and under envelope 1, is applying for a project to operate the installed centers in the most vulnerable camps where 7 out of 9 camps targeted, have no education services as per to ISIMM 2022. 

Through this project, QC seeks to provide an integrated educational services for children through:

1 - Launching BTL campaigns in 9 camps to motivate all children, especially dropouts, to return to education, and to raise awareness of caregivers about the importance of education. Teachers and PSS animators will conduct tent to tent visits and will talk to caregivers and children and explain to them project activities. No selection criteria will be set, and the centers will be open to all children. And for those who needs encouragement, QC will make sure that a clear message about CwDs, children affected with child labor and girls education to be convoyed. The team will consist of males and females to disseminate messages to both sexes. 
2- Formal and non-formal (ALP) activities using SIG amp curriculum B will go in parallel to target children as per to their vulnerability. As per to the need assessment results 1996 children (998 boys and 998 girls and 25 CwDs) are OOS for more than a year and need ALP courses to bridge their educational gab. For those who can join formal education (estimated 1,100 children 550 boys and 550 girls. age 6 or 7 in addition to those in-schools), they will start their formal education directly. ASER test (1 to 4) and other modified placement tests (5 grade and over) will be applied to children pre and post to measure the improvement in achievement. 
3- PSS activities that are structured are very important to normalize the children&#x2019;s behavior and to attract them to school. 16 session of I deal curriculum will be facilitated to all children. Referral pathways also are activated to specialized SPs.
4- WASH caravans that are disability and gender sensitive and Admin caravans are going to be established in the school. Also, a fence around the school and cement school yard will be built to keep children in protected environment. 
5- PTAs will be formed to make sure the community participation in the process.
6- Stationery kits and schoolbags are going to be distributed to children and teachers who will also benefit incentives and light training program. 
7- QC will provide winterization fuel to keep children in schools in winter. 
8- Teachers will be trained and provided with incentives (129 teachers 56 males and 93 females - 21 PSS animators - 2 PSS supervisors - 9 Education center manager - 9 guards and 9 cleaners).
QC will use assets given in previous SCHF projects (i.e. laptops, printers, etc.) to minimize the cost. The project is integrated with many sectors like WASH, Shelter and CP clusters and sub-clusters.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-EDU-188346-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">487030.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">399205.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22190">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-25">886236.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
