<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/NFI/INGO/22224</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Securing safe access to dignified shelter units and safer settlements for IDPs living in Jarablus district (Envelope 1)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under this project, CARE is targeting all IDPs that are still living in tents in Zoghara Camps with provision of dignified shelter units. CARE is also proposing to target IDPs that are living in existing shelters which are below cluster and sphere standards. CARE will address shelter and settlement needs of all IDPs in the camp, while ensuring other complementary multi-sector services continue to be provided by CARE under complimentary funding. 

Zoghara camps are located in Jarablus district, 23 Km out of the city, accommodating a total of 10,986 individuals (2,689 HHs). In 2020, CARE in coordination with AFAD (under SCHF funds) upgraded the new Zoghara camp to host more IDPs fleeing from the escalation of violence in Dec 2019. Since then, CARE has been managing and supporting the camps with WASH, Shelter, Protection and Livelihood services.

Building on CARE&#x2019;s experience, lessons learned and feedback from IDPs who have previously benefited from CARE&#x2019;s activities in Zoghara camp, CARE proposes to provide 310 dignified shelter units to support 310 HHs still living the tents in new and old Zoghara camps.

CARE&#x2019;s proposed dignified shelter design is based on the shelter cluster&#x2019;s Dignified Shelter and Safer Living Conditions Guidance as well as the Dignified Shelter Technical Annex. The proposed dignified shelter unit consists of two living rooms, one toilet, a bathing room, and a kitchen with 27.5m2 of space. CARE will be installing ground beams (30*25 cm) and a concrete slab to transfer loads and strengthen the unit&#x2019;s stability. The walls and roof of the living room are made of sandwich panels, 4cm in thickness, carried by a metal frame, and standing on the concrete blocks up to 80cm to ensure stability and insulation. The WASH facilities will be constructed of concrete blocks (15cm) and a reinforced concrete roof, 12 cm in thickness. The water tank will be provided for each unit. The internal doors and windows are made of PVC, while the external door is made of metal.

CARE will connect these new shelter units with the existing water and sewage networks at the site under complimentary WASH funding from German MOFA and BHA to ensure safe and dignified access to WASH services for all beneficiaries targeted under this project.

In addition, CARE proposes to rehabilitate a total of 150 shelter units in the old Zoghara camp adjacent to the new Zoghara camp. CARE will also address the need for improved site infrastructure conditions by graveling access roads and ensuring adequate drainage to ensure dignified living conditions are met at the site for 1,785 HHs (6,536 individuals including 1,623 men, 1,593 women, 1,789 boys and 1,531 girls). These activities will target areas of the site where site standards are inadequate, to ensure all IDPs living at the site have adequate site infrastructure conditions. These activities will address the specific needs of women, girls and PwD as well as the needs of the wider population at the site. 

CARE will engage in project planning and coordination with relevant clusters and actors to ensure adequate access to livelihoods, health, and education facilities and services throughout the site. Protection and safety principles will be applied by engaging beneficiaries and staff and conducting safety audits. CARE will actively engage IDPs within the target sites at each stage of decision-making to ensure the specific and diverse needs of these populations are addressed, especially women and PwD. CARE will also ensure camp committees and camp management are central in decision making processes. Proposed solutions will be based on stakeholder engagement. CARE will ensure strong complaint mechanisms and referral pathways are in place throughout the project cycle.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-SHL-188643-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">819233.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">675979.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22224">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">1495212.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
