<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/FS-ER/NGO/22213</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelop 2: Support livelihood opportunities by empowering women and men in the community to engage in income-generating activities. And improving people&apos;s access to services and markets in Idlib and Afrin areas.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to need assessment and market analysis, this project aims to provide integrated ER and FSL services on community-level. It aims to support income-generating activities through VT and small business grants. And improving access to markets to contribute to early recovery efforts.
The project will support 82,142 direct BNFs in 12 communities in Mhambel, Jis Shughur, Sharan, Jandairis subdistricts.

A) FSL activities:
1- Training 600 women on food processing (traditional and modern techniques). It will be through two consecutive training courses. Each course will target 300 women. Dividing the training into two groups is due to the team&apos;s ability to train and keep pace with two different seasons of the year. The training axes of the first group are different from the second, according to the food processing calendar in NWS.
Training mechanism: The training is 12 sessions, one day for each session (take up 4 to 5 hours). It will be in rented and equipped training centers. Training content is theoretical and practical explanation.
At the training end, 300 women will be eligible to receive grants. Then training the second group will start with other topics corresponding to the training timing. 
Two sessions out of 12 will be for training on topics related to people with special needs. A cornbread-making session for people with malabsorption, bran bread, and oat biscuits for those with diabetes. That called healthy kitchen.
Training goal: empower women through practicing professions adapted to women&apos;s requirements and capabilities. 
2- Distributing small business grants with value 350 $ to all 600 targeted women through E-vouchers modality. 
600 food processing tools-vouchers with value 150 $ per woman. And 600 raw materials-vouchers with value 200 $ per woman divided into 2 rounds/months. To be redeemed by vegetables, fruits, milk, or other food items. 
The grant value is based on NA findings and lessons learned. It enables the initiation of small business projects.
3- Establishing 5 workshops consist of interested women. IHR will train them on teamwork and marketing. Each workshop will receive the training tools to be assets of their sustainable projects.

A) ER activities:
1- Supporting 200 BNFs of start-up business through VT on most 12 professions needed by society, which were demonstrated by NA findings
200 BNFs will attend theoretical sessions for 20 hours during one week
Eligible trainees will attend practical sessions by presenting for the contracted service providers. Every trainee must attend daily (3 hours per day) for one month to practice the profession. 
The service provider will get on 100 $ for training 3 to 5 trainees in one month through two or 3 shifts.
Eligible BNFs will attend business development training for three days. They will learn to write the proposal
IHR and CRB will select and support the best 100 projects with a grant (1000 $) for two batches.
2- Supporting 100 BNFs of existing businesses through capacity building and soft skills training for developing their business.
IHR and CRB will select and support the best 50 projects with a grant (600$) for two batches.
2- Enabling 80,976 individuals&#x2019; access to services and markets through improvement in market infrastructure in four sub-districts. According to NA IHR proposed four rehabilitation projects with a total cost 136,110 $ to improve access for 80 % of total pop.   
Each project includes Rehab works related to the market situation and supporting 50 workers of IDPs and HC under the CFW activity. The project will ensure work opportunities for 50 workers for one month (26 days) against receiving 5 $ per workday
This project designed and adapted to accommodate women and PWDs to be directly targeted to promote their access to employment and entrepreneurship opportunities. More details in activities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-ERY-187558-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-FSC-187560-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="53" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="47" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">394744.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">455474.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22213">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">850219.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
