<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/WASH-CCM/NGO/22148</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance dignified living through life-saving integrated response of full WASH and CCCM services in the established dignified sites in Idleb and Aleppo, north-west Syria (NWS.) -Envelope 1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to continuing Maram&#x2019;s previous intervention in WASH and CCCM, and in line with the priorities identified in the 2021 Humanitarian Response Plan, the proposed project intends to enhance dignified living and address acute needs for 6135 HHs/ 30,389 people living in Idleb and Aleppo through integrated WASH and CCCM interventions.
In 2021 and in line with the vision of the Humanitarian Response Plan to provide safer and dignified shelter solutions, Maram was one of the first organizations that sought to improve and develop the shelter for the IDPs living in IDP Sites in NWS by establishing three planned camps using 2900 improved and dignified shelters (RHUs).
After establishing the three planned camps with dignified shelter and providing them with all the requirements for a decent life, Maram succeeded in providing an integrated WASH and CCCM response that will continue until 14 of June 2022. 
Therefore, through the proposed intervention, Maram Foundation aims to continue to protect vulnerable IDPs and provide them with life-saving and life-sustaining services with main-streamed protection and advocacy in the three planned camps under envelope1.
Providing WASH services is critical in mitigating outbreaks of water borne diseases, by availing safe drinking water, as well as enabling domestic activities like cooking and personal hygiene. There-fore, in pursuit of this, Maram has designed this project to support a total of 30,389 individuals, 6,135(HHS) living in three planned camps and Ehtiemlat village in Idlebamp Aleppo Governorate with basic WASH and CCCM services including establishing more sustainable mechanisms for water supplying, solid waste management, and enhancing the reality of hygiene and reducing water-related diseases through expansion and operation of sewage networks. 
As well as providing a full package of CCCM activities such as Strengthening camp management systems amp services, Coordination for multisectoral services, basic care and maintenance activities to infrastructure and facilities, information management amp capacity building.
The project will also enhance the community participation of IDPs by supporting the formation of gender-balanced IDPs committees that ensure equal participation, and that vulnerable groups including women and PLWD have a safe space for meaningful participation.
The targeted sites within the proposal are as follows:
Aleppo gt A&apos;zaz gt Suran gt Ehteimlat (Ehteimlat PCamp Ehteimlat village).
Idleb gt Idleb gt Maaret Tamsrin gt Kafr Jales (Kafr Jales PC)
Idleb gt Idleb gt Maaret Tamsrin gt Shekh Bahr (Sheisk Baher PC).
The planned intervention will mainstream protection principles especially (Do no harm) throughout the project cycle by considering the different needs of men, women, children, adolescents, adults, adults, and older adults. 
Implementation plan: 
- MF will hold coordination meetings with local authorities to explain MF&apos;s WASHampCCCM intervention, update needs, and IDPs numbers.
- Regarding the daily activities (water supply, regular maintenance&#x2026;etc) all PRs and tenders will be prepared after signing the agreement in order to start providing the services at the beginning of the project period.
- While for other PRs (Solar systems, concrete water tanks, Fire points establishments..etc) all tenders will be prepared after project starting according to MF policy.
- Furthermore, during the project life, MampE will be conducted at every stage of the project by collecting routine data and analysis on a continuous basis, in addition to evaluating the services pro-vided by MF to evaluate the service and find out how it met the needs of beneficiaries.

Consequently, the project will seek to enhancing dignified living through life-saving integrated response of full WASH and CCCM services in the established dignified sites taking into account the strategic cross-cutting elements throughout the project cycle including gender, protection, PSEA and AAP to ensure inclusive programing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-CCM-188025-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-WSH-188016-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">498765.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">493314.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22148">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">992079.68</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
