<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/22024</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 2: Improving access to livelihood opportunities through sustaining minimum food consumption needs by Baking and distributing free bread for IDPs in camps  and Cash-for-Work  as olive harvesting, and establishment of small food processing workshops</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Proposed project goes under Envelope 2 

The proposed project aims to increase the resilience of affected communities by improving access to livelihood opportunities and basic food security services in IDPs camps and IDPs high population communities in Idlib governorate for a duration of 9 months.  

SKT has developed this project to meet the recommended results and activities in the allocation paper and to scale-up efforts to sustain the most vulnerable IDPs&apos; minimum food consumption needs through Supply flour or bread directly to bakeries and providing free bread distribution in areas with limited access to subsidized bread in Harem and Slqin subdistricts as listed as prioritized locations. 

This project aims to provide FSL services recommended in the allocation paper 

1-  Food Security: Baking and distribution of free bread for IDPs in camps:
The proposed project will cover the needs of 3509 IDPs families (15971 beneficiaries) accommodating in 18 camps and random settlements in Harem and Salqin sub-districts ( locations and names of camps in the assessment report attached). This intervention is part of SKT central bread distribution program that is ongoing since 2015 and funded partially several times by SCHF. 
The gender and age distribution of the target beneficiaries is as follows 
Malegt18 : 3354
Fmalegt18 : 3687
Boys: 4376
Girls: 4554

The proposed project will contribute in the food security of the target IDPs.  This project will cover the procurement of flour, the baking costs for the bakery for the flour to be baked, nylon bags, transportation and distribution costs. Each ton of flour will provide 1277 bread bundles with  900gr for each criterion (900gr for each family with members of 4 and less and 1.8kg for each family with members of 5 and more daily). 54% of HH will get 1 bundle and 46% will get 2 bundles per day. children&apos;s will be considered. 
SKT will monitor transferring the bread from the bakery to the distribution points (6 distribution points). The distribution points will not be more than 7 km maximum and the distance between each distribution point and the targeted beneficiaries will not be more than 1 km maximum), the volunteer will monitor and supervise the distribution process. 
The proposed project is a continuation of last year&apos;s SKT project. SKT has access to IDPs&apos; information and needs. Thus, the proposed project will be a continuation of the cluster plan to support the food security of the most vulnerable groups in NWs. 
The needs assessment report showed that these camps have got only SKT bread distribution assistants during the last 2 years, and no other FSL activities were provided to these IDPs and camps.

2- Livelihoods: Cash-for-Work (CfW) to support value-chain-related activities such as olive harvesting
After coordination with the cluster to avoid duplication, SKT will support the olive harvesting C4W activities. 800 IDPs workers will work for 10 days (50 USD per worker) from both genders (Female IDPs HH are the main target beneficiaries) to increase the number of IDPs supported under this activity. the harvesting is done between Sep and December each year.
200 small and olive farmers who own 1-4 dunums planted ( female farmers are the main target BNFs) with olive trees at the fruiting stage. Each farmer will get support for 4 dunums with short-term employment opportunities. The daily workers will get harvesting kits and orientation sessions. The target areas are Harm and Salqin subdistricts.

3- Livelihoods:
Establishment of small food processing workshops producing dairy products and yogurt. SKT will select 90 IDPs to attend 10 days of training according to vulnerability criteria ( PLW and FHH) The training will be on producing dairy products using the available resources in the target area. at the end of the training, 45 trainees according to their final evaluation will be supported through tools and equipment with a cost of 290 USD in harim and salqin.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-FSC-188041-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">483167.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">316831.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22024">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-04">799998.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305691990">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-26">319999.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
