<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/NFI-WASH/NGO/22230</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelop 1: Provision of dignified shelter support and integrated WASH services leading to dignified and safer living conditions in north-west Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to provide Shelter support and integrated WASH services leading to dignified and safer living conditions under envelop1. The project will support 25493 IDPs living in 18 camps in Sharan, Jandairis, Ariha, Dana,Maaret Tamsrin, and Atareb Sub-districts through a set of comprehensive activities.The activities are designed based on the need assessment in each location based on community consultation and discussed with the individuals and key stockholders.
IHR adopted the integrated approach in project design. After a chain of coordination with NGOs active in the target location, we complemented the missing services in some locations and provided complete services in other sites. Details in NA and activities below 
The activities are as follows:
A) Shelter: 
1-Installation of better-dignified shelters served by WASH facilities and associated with the site&apos;s infrastructure.This activity will help 145 HHs,120 in Hirsh Kastak Jundo, and 25 in Islamuna 2 camps.This type of shelter will secure adequate space and more dignity and privacy.This activity will ensure midterm sustainability for protection from weather factors and floods
The design of the dignified shelter units and infrastructure were selected according to the SNFI guides 2022 and by consultation with WASH and CCCM clusters and with active NGOs in the same locations to ensure the project is integrated and IDPs resilience increased.
2-Graveling and establishing the drainage system on main and sub-roads of the inside camp&#x2019;s roads to facilitate the IDPs movement, especially during the winter season, and prevent flood effects. This activity will be implemented inside Hirsh Kastak Jundo, Horan, Al Qamue, Islamuna2, Alnahda, and AlShariaa camps.
3-Installation of solar lighting poles in 6 camps in Hirsh Kastak Jundo, Horan,Al Qamue, Islamuna2, Alnahda, and AlShariaa camps to enhance safety and improve the living conditions 
4-Tents leveling in Horan camps. to prevent moisture and medium flood during rainstorms entering the tent.
5-Rain drainage system and channels in Hirsh Kastak Jundo, Horan, Islamuna2, and AlShariaa camps to mitigate flooding and improve access to services
B) WASH: 
In line with dignified shelter and improving the dignified living conditions, the activities are 
1-Rehabilitation and Expansion of sewerage systems in Hirsh Kastak Jundo and Islamuna 2 camps where the new dignified shelters are provided.IHR will expand the sewage system as an integrated service of infrastructure improvement for implementing the145 dignified shelters in Camps.  
2-Rehab of SS in Al Mohamdiyah,and Deir Ballut camps
3-Distribution of 18 water storage tanks in 2 camps
4-Construction and Rehab of 11 latrines of two cells with high consideration of PWDs in 2 camps. Besides hiring 6 cleaning workers in 3 camps
5-Distribution of 75 garbage bins in 5 camps
6-Distribution of 2893 hygiene kits via CVA modality in 8 camps with delivering hygiene promotion to control water-borne diseases (WBDs)
7-Rehab of 4 water stations with small-scale network rehab and upgrade them with solar power, including operational support, chlorination of water for ten months, and the establishment of WASH tariff collection and cost recovery mechanism in Al Mohamdiyah, Deir Ballut, AlTaawun, and Abdul Rahman Alsumit water stations. Abdul Rahman Alsumit water station provides water to 10 camps in Dana and Alatareb which already have a water network. Still, the station needs operational costs and rehabilitation to serve the target camps with the required water
8-Operational Support with chlorination of Islamuna2 water station which serves 7001 beneficiaries in Islamuna2 and Alnahda Camps
9-Full package of Basic WASH services (Water trucking for 3 months,Desludging and solid waste removal for 10 months) in Al Qamue camps
All above services were designed and considered the actual  Women and PWD  in targeted camps in all phases and took into account the specific needs of each group.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-SHL-188162-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-WSH-187546-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="43" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="57" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">555809.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">641318.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22230">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-03">1197127.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
