<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/H/NGO/22212</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase access to life-saving and life-sustaining coordinated, equitable humanitarian health services for those most vulnerable and in need with an emphasis on those in areas with high severity of needs in NW of Syria - envelope1</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to continue and increase accessibility to essential life-saving health services to address the dire and increasing needs of health services for all age and sex groups boys, girls, women, and men, with attention to people with disabilities elderly, people with chronic diseases, including IDPs of remote camps that have difficulty accessing life-saving health services in NW Syria, through continuing the support of the already existing and functioning following components:
1-Harim General hospital (HeRAMS code G0703149), located in Harim subdistrict that is crowded with IDPs, which is now considered one of the most crucial facilities in NW Syria covering more than 71,424 individuals all of them are PiN
The hospital consists of 13 beds in hospitalization department(7 for men,6 for women) and 6 ICU beds and it will expand its capacity to include additional 4 beds for hospitalization department.
The main activities provided through this component will include:
 Integrated primary health care services as per the Essential Health Service Package through the outpatient unit. 
 Prevention and control of NCDs and communicable diseases
 Provision of essential medicines, medical supplies, and equipment, focusing on the essential medicine list of EHSP.
 Surgical, trauma, injury care, minor and major surgeries with attention to acute medical emergencies requiring immediate surgical intervention.
 Hospitalizing services. 
 Intensive health care services through supporting ICU. 
 Integrate WASH services, particularly medical waste management, save water provision, hand hygiene resources, etc.
 Ensure referral pathways for cases that need further management through coordination on a high level with the referral network.
 Operate the central oxygen concentrator to supply the health facilities within Harim and the surrounding area with oxygen cylinders (more than 15 HFs) in coordination with Health Directorate 

2- For more integration and complementarity in provided services, and to reach IDPs of remote camps and with limited mobility, SDI will continue running the already existing mobile clinic (HeRAMZ code:SDI Mobile clinic 3!) within 6 camps of Harim subdistrict which were served by dignified shelter services by Geras Al Nahda and Binaa organizations a few months ago and iHH nowadays( in one of them) ,after high coordination with them to intervene in those camps and provide health services there.
This mobile clinic will be linked to Harim general hospital and will conduct daily visits to targeted camps to provide: medical consultation, RH, child health, medicine and referral services. SDI had already coordinated with the central referral system to allocate one car in order to transfer the referred cases by this M.C team to Harim general hospital or other respective health facilities to receive the required services (kindly see the coordination emails in attachment).
3- The project aims to continue supporting Afrin blood bank and thalassemia center (HeRAMS Code B0203082) located in Afrin city. 
This is the only blood bank that covers Afrin district in Aleppo governorate, it provides monthly blood components for 600 patients including women, men, boys, and girls. Supported cases include major surgeries, acute hemolytic anemia, acute hemorrhages, thalassemia, etc., and it is the only facility providing thalassemia services in Afrin districts including providing chelating therapy and medications interventions. 
The total number of beneficiaries from this project will be 44500 people in need including 15900 men, 13600 women,7700 boys and 7300 girls) disaggregated as (27914 IDPs, 16506 HCs and 80 Returnees) including 1500 PWDs.
The project will also contribute to COVID-19 response in NW Syria, by providing other facilities with oxygen cylinders in addition to ensuring strict applying of triage protocol, providing extra PPE, and applying other of precautions measures</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-HEA-187875-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">437846.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">361283.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22212">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">799130.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
