<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/NFI-WASH/NGO/22246</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing Dignified Shelter Solutions in Prioritized IDP Camps in NW Syria through an Integrated Shelter and WASH Response (Envelope 1)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">White Hands (WH) proposes a 9-month action that uses a flexible integrated programming approach that includes a multi-sectoral response (SNFI amp WASH) focusing on enhancing shelter and living conditions through providing better-dignified shelter solutions in NW Syria.

The project formulation has been based on needs identified by SNFI and WASH clusters, supported by MSNA conducted by WH in April 2022, firsthand consultations with camps management, local authorities/stakeholders, and IDP representatives, including marginalized groups such as women, girls, and PWDs. It aims to provide inclusive, dignified shelters with integrated infrastructure improvements and a comprehensive package of WASH supplies and services for affected households in high-needs and underserved areas in NW Syria. 
This will ensure safe and dignified living conditions for 380 most vulnerable IDP households/2,184 people (457 women, 443 men, 637 girls, and 647 boys) currently living in 2 prioritized IDP sites/camps (fully tented with valid HLP) in the sub-district of Atareb (Aleppo Governorate), through a holistic approach and a coherent and coordinated response between the SNFI and the WASH clusters.

WH&#x2019;s project recognizes the different needs and vulnerabilities of boys, girls, men, and women of different ages and strives to address the specific needs of each group across the range of shelter and WASH interventions.

The project aims to achieve the following outcomes:
SNFI Component: Improve shelter and living conditions among conflict-affected HHs in 2 prioritized IDP camps (Tayba(Kafr Karmin) and Al Manelah camps) in the sub-district of Atareb to ensure enhanced access to safe, dignified, comprehensive, and gender-equitable shelter solutions through:
(1) Merge the two targeted IDP sites into one organized site (in the same location/community) since the two camps are located next to each other, overlapping and without borders between them. Both camp management and residents gave their consent to do so.
(2) provide an essential infrastructure rehabilitation that may include site upgrade, graveling of main and sub-roads and infrastructure improvements, rain drainage system amp channels, paving paths between tents, road amp access maintenance, and lighting on main roads and pathways as needed.
(3) Provision of better-dignified shelter solution by piloting an innovative shelter approach which comprises steel metal frame and sandwich panels (indoor living space 23.82 m&#xB2;) in the newly organized site to accommodate 380 HHs/2,184 individuals (457 women, 443 men, 637 girls, and 647 boys) with all accessible features for households with PWDs to ensure accessibility, privacy, and safety for all vulnerable groups. 

WASH Component: Provision of an integrated, comprehensive, and more sustainable WASH intervention package in the two targeted IDP camps (merged) in the sub-district of Atareb, Aleppo governorate, to support and be integrated with dignified shelter interventions through rehabilitation/expansion of water distribution networks and sewerage systems by connecting them to nearby existing water and sewerage main pipelines, distribution of water storage tanks, solid waste management, distribution of hygiene kits via CVA modality and hygiene promotion activities.

Both components will be guided by Action Plan for Dignified Shelter amp Living Conditions in NW Syria and Dignified Shelter Technical Annex published by the SNFI cluster in March and April 2022, respectively as well as TWiG on Flood Risk Reduction 2021 and ensure that HLP documentation is well carried out in parallel with field coordination with the relevant local councils.

In the context of this highly strategic intervention that has to be delivered within nine months, WH brings in the value addition of its local expertise in local-based and infrastructure-focused projects approach throughout NW Syria, which has been there since the conception of this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-SHL-187728-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-WSH-187915-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-01">1005494.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-01">494505.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22246">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-01">1499999.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305692009">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-26">899999.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
