<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-22/3559/SA1/ER/UN/22100</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 2 - Strengthening resilience and enhancing physical access from Bab Al-Hawa Border Crossing to Jandairis through road rehabilitation and the re-deployment of the Emergency Road Rehabilitation Rapid Response Team throughout Idleb Governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Road infrastructure in North-West Syria has been severely damaged after more than eleven years of conflict, lack of capacity for repair and maintenance, increased usage after IDP population influxes and harsh weather conditions including flooding. This physical access constraint has hampered the delivery of humanitarian assistance while also undermining economic performance, access to services such health and education as well as resilience. 
The project will respond to identified urgent needs through the key strategic rehabilitation of roads and drainage infrastructure through the following activities:
1. Rehabilitating 20.1 kilometers of road between the Bab Al-Hawa Border Crossing and Jandairis as well as 4.7 kilometers of secondary roads which enable access to IDP sites and villages. 
2. Creating short-term livelihood opportunities for IDPs and host community members to support in the rehabilitation of the targeted roads. 
3. Deployment of the Emergency Road Rehabilitation Rapid Response Team to provide emergency infrastructure restoration services to access roads to IDP sites In Idleb Governorate during winter. 
The ERL project has been developed in consultation with the ERL, Logistics, CCCM and SNFI Clusters as well as with senior UN leadership, OCHA and OCHA Access to ensure the most efficient and necessary works are achieved through this intervention. The targeted road between Bab Al-Hawa Border Crossing and Jandairis is a strategic road which serves approximately 300,000 IDPs and 90,000 host community members. This includes the Atmeh Camp Cluster which receives humanitarian assistance via this road. Improving physical access will not only ensure the delivery of humanitarian aid all-year round, but also build the resilience of communities by strengthening access to markets and economic performance and the ability for basic services to be delivered. First, the project will rehabilitate 20.1 km of road between the Bab Al-Hawa Border Crossing and Jandairis and 4.7 km of secondary roads which enable access to IDP sites and villages from the primary road. In addition, 11 drainage infrastructure will be rehabilitated to mitigate the risk of flooding and further improve the sustainability of the road. Second, a cash for work scheme will be implemented and will engage 250 people in the rehabilitation of the roads and drainage systems who will be drawn from the local communities. Third, based upon UNDP&#x2019;s successful implementation of the Rapid Response Mechanism in the 21/22 winter, the project will provide emergency road rehabilitation for approximately 32 kilometers of access roads to IDP sites to restore physical access to flood-affected and damaged roads during winter across Idleb Governorate. 
Overall, the project will directly benefit 744981 people (148996 HHs). UNDP brings value addition through expertise in infrastructure projects around the world and in NWS specifically. UNDP&#x2019;s early recovery team, who are highly experienced in infrastructure projects, will provide technical guidance and expertise to ensure the quality and appropriateness of infrastructure works and livelihoods activities. UNDP will work in partnership with BINAA, a Syrian NGO which has experience with proven track record in the rehabilitation and reparation of roads and drainage systems, as well as in the creation of livelihood opportunities. Overall, UNDP will be responsible for the management of the project and its oversight against programmatic and fiduciary risks through efficient contractual arrangements and administrative support from teams in Gaziantep, Damascus and its regional bureau. UNDP will utilize its strong financial and procurement capacity as well as internal control, as per the HACT Micro Assessment findings, to ensure the efficient and effective implementation of the project.  This will strengthen overall risk management and ensure timely implementation of the project along with the high quality of activities and deliverables.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR22-ERY-188357-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR22" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2022 - 2023</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">2427370.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">2002912.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-22100">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">4430283.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
