<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9447</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberian Agricultural Company</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name:    Liberia: LAC      Region:Sub-Saharan Africa   Sector:   Project No:009447   Projected Board Date:May 13, 1999   Company Name:Liberian Agricultural Company   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	LACs main shareholder is Compagnie Internationale de Cultures (Intercultures) a Luxembourg-registered affiliate of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Financi&#xE8;re des Caoutchoucs Luxembourg SOCFINAL S.A. (SOCFINAL), a Luxembourg holding company with agricultural, real estate, banking and financial interests.  Among SOCFINALs shareholders is the Bollor&#xE9; group which has large investments in Africa. Agricultural activities include direct holdings in oil palm and rubber in Indonesia, Cameroon, Nigeria, Ivory Coast, Liberia, coffee and roses in Kenya and forestry in Cameroon.  SOCFINAL also has large portfolio holdings in firms involved in rubber and oil palm in Malaysia and Cameroon.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The project will consist of a US$7.0 million rehabilitation program to restart the Companys operations. IFC has been requested to provide a US$3.5 million loan to LAC.    Location of project and Description of site    	LAC is located about 190 km east of Monrovia.    	The LACs estate covers an area of 120,000 ha, out of which 10,500 has been developed as a rubber plantation  The rest of the concession is comprised of 27,600 ha of secondary high forest, 58,200 of broken forest, 10,000 ha of pastures and fallow and about 13,700 ha of wet zones and rice fields.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project involves the rehabilitation of a rubber operation of the Liberian Agricultural Company (LAC), which ceased operations following the eruption of civil war in Liberia. The Sponsor just acquired 75% of the shares of the Company.  The Sponsor will restart the operations and rehabilitate the Company with an immediate US$7.0 million rehabilitation program involving the reconstruction of buildings, workers camps, reconstruction of the factory, and rehabilitation and rebuilding of bridges and roads. In addition the Company will expand the plantation areas by 2,500 ha of rubber.      Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental and social review procedure because specific impacts may result which can be avoided or mitigated by adhering to generally recognized performance standards, guidelines or design criteria. The following potential environmental, occupational health and safety issues were analyzed: site acquisition, land tenure, existing land uses, confirmation that operations will not affect significant areas of natural habitat, plantation management and integrated pest management systems, compliance with relevant national and World Bank Group environmental and social requirements, management of any hazardous materials, and occupational health and safety issues.    The LAC estate is a long established estate (1961). No new land acquisition will take place, there has been no settlement of the existing LAC plantation areas and there will be no physical resettlement or economic displacement. The project will rehabilitate 10,500 ha of existing rubber plantation and establish an additional 2,500 ha of rubber on land that has been previously cleared of forest by others and which now supports tertiary scrub re-growth. The project will not result in loss of tropical moist forest and the Sponsor is looking at ways in which he can protect remaining forest assets within the estate from illegal damage by third parties.     Only very limited use of agrochemicals is envisaged and use will conform to World Bank Group (WBG) requirements in terms of storage, use and disposal practices. The Sponsor will comply with WBG requirements in relation to air emissions, wastewater effluents and solid waste handling and disposal. There is currently no relevant environmental or health and legislation in Liberia.     The company will develop and implement a formal occupational health and safety plan which complies with WBG requirements and will provide or organize appropriate training for staff.    The  is  April 7, 1999 from the InfoShop.       Host country location of environmental documents    Liberia      Date SPI sent to InfoShop:April 6,1999   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact: Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberian Agricultural Company</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9447" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-11-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-01-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="LR-Liberia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.5000000000 -9.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AI - Natural Fibers (Cotton, Sisal, Jute, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $3.50 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-11-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-11-12">3500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-11-12">3500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberian Agricultural Company</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9447/liberian-agricultural-company">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
