<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="9" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/16807" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MdM-GR-15-16807</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greece: Refugee &amp; Migrant Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doctors of the World has deployed its services in a number of entry points in the Eastern Aegean sea, principally the island of Lesbos, which is our largest of our extensive programs on the Greek islands in the eastern Aegean sea.

Migrants arrive in many locations on Lesbos, but are registered and processed in Moria. Doctors of the World Greece is present at the First Reception Center in Moria, collaborating with the Greek First Reception Service. Its activities are funded by the European Commission and the External Borders Fund, but the funding will run out in October 2015. We coordinate closely with organizations like the International Rescue Committee and others who are establishing programs in the area.

Our intervention on Lesbos focuses on providing free primary health screenings services for all migrant arrivals, including psycho-social support. We also distribute free health and hygiene kits, clothing, and non-food items; provide translation; identify vulnerable groups (such as unaccompanied minors) and refer them to social welfare bodies; and support sanitary, safe living conditions inside processing areas and shelters.

As migrant arrivals have surged, the center in Moria has been expanded and an unofficial camp has been opened in Kara Tepe. We have therefore expanded our team and are intervening with mobile units staffed with volunteers in Kara Tepe, Mytilene, and elsewhere.

Finally, an important aspect of our work is nutritional support to elderly people in need, for whom severely reduced pensions have made the most basic necessities unaffordable. We have recently switched from a physical basket of food to a food voucher system, which is logistically simpler, meets beneficiary needs more closely, and is cheaper to manage. On a weekly basis beneficiaries can obtain a new food voucher, after submitting to the social service department receipts for the food they bought with the previous voucher.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greece has reached a previously unseen level of crisis, driven by two concurrent and growing issues. First, the economic downturn has left an unprecedented number of Greek citizens without the means to pay for rent, food and other basic necessities. Access to healthcare is among these, and Doctors of the World Greece has seen a huge rise in demand for our services, particularly among children and the elderly, as well as among the growing unemployed and homeless populations.

Second, migrant flows through Greece have more than doubled in 2015. Currently, up to 6000 migrants are entering daily. A significant proportion of these migrants are entering through just two islands: Lesbos and Kos, where surges of up to 10,000 per day are being reported by the authoritative source, the International Organization for Migration (IOM). These migrants are highly vulnerable, with medical and other needs that grow the longer they are en-route. The islands in particular are overwhelmed by the migrant arrivals and their infrastructures are stretched, with tensions rising and rioting in Lesbos in September.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-2426718" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doctors of the World-USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MdM-GR-15-16807" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doctors of the World-USA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tamera Gugelmeyer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communications Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>info@doctorsoftheworld.org</email>
   <website>http://doctorsoftheworld.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="18" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
