<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06594-03:PH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F4A Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the collaboration between the Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment Knowledge Hub and Oxfam Novib
Prepared by: Ruben De Winne (Learning, innovation &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; knowledge coordinator, F4A programme, Oxfam Novib) &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Marylew Echavez (Coordinator, Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment Knowledge Hub, Oxfam in the Philippines)
Date: 22 February 2022
Version: 3
Background
From 1 January 2021 until 31 December 2025, a consortium consisting of Huairou Commission, Oxfam Novib, SOMO, and Third World Network-Africa will implement the FAIR for ALL (&#x201C;F4A&#x201D;) programme. With funding from the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs and together with dozens of partner organizations, the consortium wants to make value chains and trade in 14 countries more inclusive and sustainable. Learning is a key component of the programme. Through effective learning, the programme stakeholders seek to improve ongoing programme strategies and maximize their impact. To that end, the consortium needs a deliberate space &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; infrastructure for learning, innovation &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; knowledge, available toall consortium members and their partner organizations, to enable continuous adaptive management so that the F4A programme is and remains relevant, efficient &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; effective.
Learning in the F4A programme happens both within the 17 countries, regional &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; global projects, and at the cross-country level. To harness cross-country learning, the FAIR for ALL country and regional teams decided to establish four Communities of Practice (&#x201C;COPs&#x201D;) that will each focus on one of the following four topics: capacity strengthening, civic space, (private sector) influencing, and women&#x2019;s economic empowerment.
The purpose of these Communities of Practice is to provide the staff of consortium members (both at the central and decentralized level) and of partner organizations with a safe environment for sharing, learning, collaborating, and strengthening capacities on capacity strengthening, civic space, (private sector) influencing, or women&#x2019;s economic empowerment. As such, this Community of Practice is part of the infrastructure for learning, innovation &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; knowledge available to all consortium members and their partner organizations.
Each Community of Practice will have a chairperson and an animator.
WEE Knowledge Hub background, purpose, and knowledge offers
Since its inception in 2013, the WEE Knowledge Hub (WEE KH) has mobilized and animated the Oxfam WEE network, created links for knowledge exchange, and made visible pre-existingknowledge across the confederation. These objectives have been reached by a shared service model focusing on communications accompaniment, knowledge management support, facilitating peer-to-peer learning exchanges unlocking strategic practitioner networking, and influencing opportunities.
The WEE KH has acted as a conduit to share and connect WEE practitioners across the confederation. Its legacies as a learning convenor across programmes and projects across Oxfam as a whole including its partners, through high impact learning forums, learning spaces, and brokering knowledge connection and shared expertise, have fulfilled the WEE KH purpose to strengthen Oxfam&#x2019;s quality work on WEE, learn from practice and influence social change.
This is the knowledge and learning offer of the WEE KH to the FAIR for ALL (&#x201C;F4A&#x201D;) programme.  WEE KH through its convenor and networker role, will support the WEE Community of Practice within the F4A programme to become effective WEE champions, innovators, and knowledge holders in promoting gender justice, racial justice, and transformation of economic systems.
Purpose of the collaboration between the WEE KH and Oxfam Novib
Oxfam&#x2019;s Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment Knowledge Hub, hosted by Oxfam in the Philippines, will manage the animator role of the F4A Community of Practice on women&#x2019;s economic empowerment. As such, the WEE KH will animate the Community of Practice by proactively encouraging and organizing the community members to connect and co-create knowledge from practice within the F4A program. WEE KH can also bring in its knowledge offer and thematic expertise from the wider WEE KH Network in Oxfam so that the F4A WEE Community of Practice will be able to connect to various WEE knowledge activities across the Oxfam Confederation and together, generate useful learning to improve ongoingWEE-related programme strategies and maximize its impact. To be able to do this effectively, the WEE KH will commission staff or consultant/s based on the identified needs of the F4A WEE COP workplan and supervise the execution of the animator role of the WEE KH to the F4A Programme.
Structural Approaches:
1. Learning Convenor Role &#x2013; the WEE KH as the animator through a dedicated staff/consultant will assist the chairperson in the preparation, delivery of knowledge activities such as meetings, webinars, learning events, and active participation of the WEE COP members in its learning activities.
a. WEE KH will manage and ensure up-to-date COP membership, profiling of database, and report to the FAIR for ALL Learning Coordinator the developments, needs, and any necessary informationrelated to the F4A programme.

2. Knowledge Management Role &#x2013; WEE KH will co-lead and provide advice on the development of learningproducts &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; methodologies and on the organization of learning events, to support the development of the F4A WEE COP as a learning network.

a. WEE KH through a dedicated staff/consultant will document the activities of the Community of Practice and their outcomes. With inputs from the Community of Practice, WEE KH will facilitate the production of knowledge products that will translate the learning from within the Community of Practice into something also useful for those outside the Community of Practice. Expected deliverables from the WEE KH
Overall timeframe for the collaboration between the WEE KH and Oxfam Novib
The WEE KH and Oxfam Novib intend to engage in a 4-year collaboration: from early 2022 until the end of the FAIR for ALL programme in December 2025. The WEE KH and Oxfam Novib will regularly, but at least once per year, evaluate the modalities of their collaboration.
Expected deliverables from WEE KH
- Active and up-to-date list of F4A WEE Community of Practice members or directory that includes learning needs, expertise,or specialization aside from the usual contact list.
- A final Terms of Reference for the Community of Practice on women&#x2019;s economicempowerment, finalized together with the Community members and the chairperson.
- The preparation &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; facilitation of as many meetings of the Community of Practice as Community members deem useful, but at least once per month as of Year 2, in a format co-decided upon with Community members and the chairperson. For Year 1, one meeting with the Chairperson in February 2022 and one meeting with the F4A WEE Community of Practice in March 2022.
- Succinct, to-the-point documentation of the activities of the Community of Practice and their main outcomes.
- Facilitate consultations on and delivery of the knowledge products the COP decides to produce and disseminate within and outside the F4A programme.  These knowledge products will require inputs and content from the members of the Community of Practice.
- Integration of knowledge produced in/by the Community of Practice into other relevant Oxfam knowledge fora.
- Facilitate reflection of the outcomes and reach of knowledge activities of the COP (at least annually).
Expected support by OxfamNovib
- Oxfam Novib will cover the costs that the WEE KH will incur for the animation of the Community of Practice &#xE0; 35,000 EUR/year.
- Oxfam Novib will provide all necessary information related to the FAIR for ALL programmes.
- Oxfam Novib will convene all animators of all Communities of Practice to discuss common challenges and good practices.
Specific timeline for end of Year 1 and Year 2</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-202918" role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB Philippines</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Great Britain#s Philippine office has been in existence since 1987. It has maintained a developmental program in the country that has gradually shifted from relief and basic services provision to a more rights-based developmental approach. Oxfam Great Britain has supported community-based coastal resources management since the early 1990s, as an approach towards an integration of coastal ecosystem rehabilitation, poverty alleviation, and political equity concerns for small-scale sectors.
Oxfam inthe Philippines works towards a future where Filipinos, especially women and other vulnerable sectors, are free from the injustices of poverty. During emergencies, we respond with life-saving aid while supporting people recover their livelihoods. Everyday, we drive change by working hand-in-hand with our partners in finding practical yet innovative ways to help families lift themselves out of poverty by influencing decisions that affect them.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-27">140800</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">35200</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-04-01">35200</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2024-04-01">35200</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2025-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2025-04-01">35200</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06594-03:PH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001871"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007131"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="FAIR: FVCaFS"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06594"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="FAIR4ALL learning and Capacity Dev."></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civ Space-Gov policies</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Governments are supportive to dialogue with civil society, and create and implement enabling civic space legislation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases governments are held accountable by other governments, donors or regional and global bodies on civil society engagement and civic space.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where disenabling legislation is abandoned</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-4" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where enabling legislation is designed and approved</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where enabling legislation is implemented</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where political will for dialogue is expresed by Government</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
