<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05244-19:NG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YIAGA Africa- Ready to Run</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yiaga Africa launched the Ready To Run campaign to support young women, and men with competence, capacity and character to run for elective office in the 2019 general elections and beyond. Ready To Run is the response to a need observed during the Not Too Young To Run campaign, to equip young people with the requisite capacity needed to run an issue based campaign, win elections and occupy elective office. Upon its launch, the Ready To Run campaign set out to achieve four (4) major objectives, to locate,inspire, support, and provide linkages to young people vying for elective office.

Ultimately, the Ready To Run campaign will seek to mobilize young people to engage the political process towards the 2023 elections with a view to increasing youth candidacy and youth representation in the decision-making process by 10%. The campaign will engage with different stakeholders, including political parties and the joint committee on electoral reforms in ensuring the emergence of young people as candidates in the 2023 general elections, while leveraging on our existing structures at the state level to galvanize support for young people running for elective office in their locality through media campaigns on radio.

Following the passage into law of the age reduction bill, popularly referred to as the #NotTooYoungToRun Act, which widened the space for young people to participate in the political process, and resulted in an increase in youth candidacy in the 2019 general elections, the low number of young people that contested and won their election still calls for concern. Data from the Independent National Electoral Commission (INEC) shows that young people make up more than half the number of registered voters, with 51.11% of registered voters being betweenthe ages of 18 -35. In addition, the recent #EndSARS protests against police brutality led by young people across the country indicates that there is a renewed willingness to participate in the political process. Thus, there is a need to leverage on these numerical strengths and yearnings in mobilizing young people to engage the political process towards the 2023 general elections. The solutions that are being proposed are aimed at engaging with political parties towards ensuring open, transparent and direct party primaries, reduction in campaign costs for young people and increased inclusion and representation as party candidates.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YIAGA AFRICA INTIATIVE</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yiaga Africa was launched as a student organization in 2007 at the University of Jos, Nigeria and has since established itself as aleading civil society organization in Africa. Since its inception, the organization has carved a niche for itself as one of Africa&#x2019;s frontline non-profit organization promoting participatory democracy, human rights and civic participation.

Yiaga Africa envisionsa democratic and developed Africa where citizens are actively engaged in the governance processes. Our goal is to build and supportsustainable democracy and development anchored on the principles of inclusion, accountability and justice through research, advocacy, and capacity development. This we aim to achieve guided by the values of integrity, transparency, accountability, inclusion, excellence, teamwork, and innovation.

The organization is headed by a governing board, composed of seasoned professionals drawn from the academia, inter-governmental organizations, international non-governmental organizations, civil society, and the diplomatic corps.The board is made up of eight (8) members and is headed by the board Chairman with the Executive Director acting as Secretary. The board ratifies decisions taken by the management team.
Yiaga Africa is divided into eight (8) departments namely, Programs, Finance,Administration and Human Resources, Information Technology, Internal Audit and Compliance, Knowledge Management and Learning, Procurement, and the Media department, with each department headed by a departmental head. The heads of department make up the managementteam, headed by the Executive Director. The management team oversees the daily operations of the organization.

Effecting change bysolving social problems through movement building and community organizing. Yiaga Africa prides itself as a community organizing and movement building organization. We have consistently shown that in designing programs to address social issues, we prioritize citizens participation and engagement in crafting sustainable solutions. For instance, in elections, where Yiaga Africa has risen to become a foremost election observation group in Nigeria, citizens participation is one of the four-pronged areas in which we approach election programming. Yiaga Africa promotes active and sustained citizens participation in the electoral process through campaigns, workshops, web-based tools, and traditional media. We also conduct periodic civic camps for first time voters in addition to democracy clubs established in high schoolsto mobilize and empower young people for civic leadership.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-17">24485</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">24485</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">YIAGA AFRICA INTIATIVE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">24485</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05244-19:NG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05244"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Influencing grants Nigeria"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
