<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05275-05:AF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From Black Box to Building Blocks</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and participatory budget processes are crucial for ensuring #good governance# in Afghanistan as
these ultimately determine the effectiveness of provincial departments# provision of services. Despite
substantial public financial management reforms, progress in Afghanistan remains elusive in terms of
inclusive, accountable and transparent budgeting, with the Open Budget Survey still indicating a score
below the global average.4 Budget oversight mechanisms remain weak as the government provides the
public with limited information # except for the Citizen#s Budget # and few opportunities for civil society to
engage in the budget processes,5 creating a disconnect between the government and citizens.6 As a
result, budget priorities often do not match needs at the local level. The recent approval and inception of
the provincial budgeting policy (PBP) indicates a more inclusive process, as it aims to de-concentrate the
budget process, allowing for bottom-up participation of provincial entities. According to the government#s
implementation plan, the policy is envisioned to be implemented across the 34 provinces after the threeyear
pilot phase that started in 2015 in four line ministries including the Ministry of Education (MoE) and
Ministry of Public Health (MoPH).
At this critical juncture for Afghanistan, civil society has a crucial role to play to ensure more inclusion and
participation of Afghan citizens in the budget process, currently limited to a civil society workshop held on
the first budget circular7 and a limited number of planned consultations with civil society.8 Oxfam#s
governance programming experience shows that constructive citizen-state partnerships can be
establishedaround common agendas at district and provincial level, and that this increases the
responsiveness of national authorities to policy propositions and recommendations. This Action therefore
aims to strengthen citizen-state engagement through facilitating civil society involvement in the budget
process, particularly by capitalizing on opportunities provided in the PBP and the forthcoming Sub-
National Governance Policy.
This Action has a thematic focus on essential services of health and education. These services constitute
one of the basic tenets of a rights based approach to #good governance# internationally and in
Afghanistan. Since the removal of the Taliban regime in 2001, health and education provision especially
for girls and women has seen significant progress. For example, maternal mortality decreased drastically
from 1,600 deaths per 100,000 births in 2001 to 400 in 2014, and around 3 million girls arenow enrolled
in school. Despite these improvements, there are still major challenges to overcome in order to make
education and healthcare accessible, affordable and of good quality for all Afghans, especially for women
and girls as school attendance and access to basic healthcare continue to show a gender gap. Because
of this inequality, the Action will specifically benefit girls and women by making systems responsive to
their needs and also by ensuring gender is integrated in the inception, implementation, monitoring and
evaluation phases of the Action.
This Action will build upon the Citizens First program, currently implemented by three of the five
applicants (Oxfam, APPRO and PTRO) in the same provinces as selected for this proposal: Herat,
Nangarhar, and Takhar. Citizens First has laid a solid foundation, establishing an operational structure for
increased CSO participation in citizen-state processes at multiple levels through District Advocacy
Committees (DACs), Provincial Advocacy Committees (PACs), and the National Advocacy Committee
(NAC).9 These committees built trust and mutual understanding between CSOs, Local Authorities (LAs)
and the ministries. They facilitate dialogue based on community priorities and provide an established twoway
feedback loop through which citizens priorities andneeds can be communicated to the three
governance levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society has long been a crucial-actor in addressing the full range of issues in the social, cultural, religious, humanitarianand political life of Afghanistan. Given that addressing social development issues will be an important factor in enablingAfghanistan to transform into a stable, modern and forward looking state, civil society, and particularly local non-governmental organizations or NGOs, have the potential to play a critical and complementary role in the delivery of the government#s national priority programmes, supporting improved governance, connecting the wider Afghan population to the state, and in advocating for the vulnerable and excluded.
Enabling civil society organisations (CSOs) in Afghanistan to realize their potential and playan active role in national development is a challenging task. Despite successful partnerships between the government and CSOs (such as, for example, the National Solidarity Programme and the Basic Package of Health Services), there is often a negative perception within the public sphere on the role and value of CSOs. This is a significant risk for CSOs, as it limits the policy space within which they operate and affects access to resources, especially financial resources. Systematic and focused efforts are required to enable NGOs to improve their credibility and effectiveness.
The #Afghanistan Institute for Civil Society# (AICS) is a concept that has been incubating for several years amongst Afghanistan#s civil society community, following the 2007 Enabling Environment conference convened by the Government ofthe Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the Aga Khan Development Network, in partnership with the World Bank, the United Nations Development Program and the Asia Development Bank.  One of the key recommendations from the conference was to establish independent certification bodies for civil society organizations that are recognized by Government, the private sector, donor agencies and civil society.  The AICS establishment programme was launched byAKF-A in January 2014 through a partnership between AKF and Counterpart International under a wider USAID funded Afghanistan Civic Engagement Programme (ACEP) with the long-term goal of enabling CSOs to realize their potential in support of the developmentof Afghanistan. Behind this initiative are key CSO networks, civil society professionals, and representatives from national and international CSOs with an interest in Afghanistan.
AICS#s Mandate
To support a credible and competent civil society sector in Afghanistan by linking CSOs, donors, government and capacity building services through culturally appropriate certification schemes.  The Institute will encourage the growth of a vibrant civil society, promoting pluralism and participatory, non-discriminatory development in Afghanistan.
AICS#s Objective
1. Raise credibility of the civil society sector bycertifying local organizations against locally defined and internationally recognized standards;
2. Systematize capacity building efforts of local organizations by coordinating initiatives against measurable performance indicators;
3. Strengthen the role of civilsociety in Afghanistan#s development through collective efforts of policy dialogue and active engagement with government, donors, the private sector and the broader civil society sector;
4. Provide a channel for resources for civil society by strengthening philanthropic and corporate social responsibility efforts.
Expected Impact
The AICS will be an independent, non-affiliated, Afghanmanaged and owned institution.  AICS certified CSOs will operate efficiently, transparently and effectively; will receive the support, resources and technical assistance to build their internal capacity, and will comply with culturally appropriate, locally determined and internationally recognized governance, management and operational standards. By improving the efficiency, transparency and effectiveness of CSOs and by engaging the government, local and international NGOs and the private sector, AICS aims to make a significant positive impact on development and reconstruction efforts in Afghanistan and to foster an environment for philanthropy to take root and grow</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-26">277850</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-26">277850</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-26">-87632</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">83113</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-01">87632</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-02-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">19474</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">-1971</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">74126</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">1971</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">83113</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">-74126</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-05-01">-87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Institute for Civil Soc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">74126</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-202918" ref="GB-CHC-202918">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">1971</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-202918" ref="GB-CHC-202918">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">83113</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">-74126</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-01">87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-05-01">-87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">-1971</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">87632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05275-05:AF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001250;1001302;1001318"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007201"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Afghanistan ASIA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05275"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="From Black Box to Building Blocks"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="304"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="152"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="200"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
