<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05232-10:LA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LDWDC-Promotion of Disability-LA_507702</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen Organization People with Disabilities (OPDs) and the Disability movement to effectively advocate for the inclusion of people with disabilities across all impairment groups at national level and in Attapeu Province, Sekong Province, Xiangkhouang Province and Vientiane capital.
The government of the Lao PDR has adhered to a number of international treaties: it has ratified the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (CRPD) in 2009 and acceded to the Convention on the Rights of theChild (CRC) in 1991.
Whilst the government of the Lao PDR ratified the CRDP in 2009 and issued the Decree on the Rights of People with Disabilities in 2014, neither carries the force of law and the Lao PDR is yet to become a fully inclusive society.
The2015 Population and Housing Census has largely underestimated the number of people with disabilities in the country. It has identified around 160,881 persons withdisabilities or 2.8% of the population in stark contrast with estimates provided by WHO intheir World Disability Report indicating that people with disabilities represent 15% of the world population.
There is very little information on people with disabilities from minority ethnic groups living in remote areas and given the level of poverty andlack of quality basic services these groups are faced with, people with disabilities are among the most deprived.
Since 2015, The National Committee for Disabled People and the Elderly (NCDE), under the MOLSW, is leading the development of two main documents: The National Policy for Persons with Disabilities andthe National Strategy and Action Plan for Persons with Disabilities. NCDE is working closely with line ministries, OPDs, INGOs and coordinate several consultation meetings. The 2 documents are finalized and have been submitted to the Ministry.
In parallel, NCDE drafted a Disability Law that was reviewed by the National Assembly in December 2018. However, the government of Laos has not yet enacted this law.
In spite of this legal and strategicframework promoting disability inclusion (the Decree on the rights of persons with disabilities, the Disability law, national policy, strategy and action plan), the reality of the legal context of disability in Lao PDR does not guarantee the rights to health, education, employment, leisure activities, communication and information as well as mobility, for persons with disabilities. These problems include:
&#x2022; The fact that the ratified Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (2009) is not implemented effectively. This limits the obligations of Lao PDR to uphold the rights of persons with disabilities.
&#x2022; The lack of recognition of the special needs of persons with disabilities and the general lack of knowledge of disability issues from political and administrative authorities.
&#x2022; The non-systematic application of the Lao legal framework that includes the Decree on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities, which sets out, &#x201C;protects and promotes the rights of people with disabilities, in areas that affect their everyday lives: access to healthcare, inclusive education, vocational training and employment and specify entitlements to lower or zero fees to use these services&#x201D; (2014).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao Disabled Women&apos;s Development Ce</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Lao Disabled Women&#x2019;s Development Centre (LDWDC) was established in 2001 as a non-profit organisation and is registered under the Ministry of Labour and Social Welfare. It is run by women with disabilities, primarily for women with disabilities and their families in Lao PDR.
The LDWDC developed their strategic plan 2018-2022, which is in the process of finalization.
Their vision is to havean inclusive society where people with disabilities are living independently and have equal rights and opportunity of access to healthcare, education, employment and services to enable them to achieve their full potential.
Their mission is to empower women with disabilities in Laos to be fully participating and contributing members of the community.
Their priorities are to develop the potential of women with disabilities, advocate on behalf of women with disabilities to raise community awareness, provide reliable, sustainable and culturally appropriate client services, and promote growth and sustainability of the organisation through effective resource management.
LDWDC provides vocational and life skills training to women with disabilities in the areas of sewing, weaving, recycled paper products, IT, English, social services and development and small business.
LDWDC provides training in their centre in Vientiane Capital and short courses in different provinces throughout Laos. The centre of LDWDC is a handicraft production unit that employs around 34 trained women with disabilities. LDWDC supports trained students to find decent work or/and start small businesses.
LDWDC expanded its activities to advocacy at national and local levels in relation to gender, disability inclusion, and policy dialogueand legislation development. In their advocacy, they have broadened their scope to include all women, girls, men and boys with disabilities.
Over the years, LDWDC staff received a series of capacity development training on relevant topics such as leadership, project management, small business management, health care and reproductive health.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-12" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-12" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-13" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-13" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-03">30838</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">30838</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao Disabled Women&apos;s Development Ce</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">30838</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05232-10:LA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05232"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Influencing grants Laos"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-13" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-02-12"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-02-12"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-13" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-02-12"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-02-12"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
