<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06861-03:VN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Workers and Trade Unions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Vietnam, textiles and footwear are the main export sectors, creating jobs for millions of workers and making an important contribution to the country&apos;s economic development. However, the Covid-19 pandemic has halted exports, disrupted global supply chains, andaffected businesses and  workers in these two sectors. According to the Ministry of Industry and Trade, the textile and garment industry is the industry that suffered the largest direct losses of the Covid 19 epidemic. The decrease in demand of the US and European markets greatly affects the total textile and garment export turnover of Vietnam (the US and European markets account for about 45% and 18% of textile exports, respectively). For the first time in 25 years, the export turnover of the whole textile and garment industry grew negatively, in 2020 only reached 29.8 billion USD compared to 32.8 billion USD in 2019 (down 9.2%).   However, by  2021,despite being heavily affected by the COVID-19 pandemic,  textile  and garment enterprises still maintained the growth momentum in 2021,   export turnover reached 39 billion USD, up 11.2% compared to 2020 and up 0.3% compared to  2019.  .  For the footwear industry,  the industrial production index  in 2021 increased by 5.2% compared to  the whole of 2020, but still lower than the increase of 9.9% in  2019.  Total  export  turnover in 2021 reached 20.78 billion USD (up 4.6% compared to   2020) .  Although there will be  export growth  in 2021  , textile  and footwear enterprises  are expected to face a series of challenges such as rising transportation costs  ; labor imbalances,  especially in  other countries.  Enterprises in the south still lack labor, while this area accounts for about 40% of the total export turnover of the whole textile and  garment  industry and over 70%  of  the export turnover of  thewhole leather and footwear industry.      These issues    directly  impact the  resilience  of   businesses and have a significant impact on employment.   The employment  of employees in the enterprises.
In addition, with industry   characteristics,    workers intextile and footwear  enterprises  with nearly 70% are female workers, low wages, long working hours, excessive overtime, high working intensity, ... Meanwhile, the Covid 19 epidemic poses new problems for workers in general and workers in the textile and leather industry in  particular such as: Unstable jobs, lost or reduced incomes; reduced labor conditions are only guaranteed to a minimumwhen enterprises cut costs when enterprises  are forced to  applying many measures to prevent covid 19; psychological and mental health problems caused by job loss and social distancing;  ...
From the above comments, the Institute  of Workers and Trade Unions (CNCD Institute) realized that this is a very important issue of research to assess specifically, comprehensively and deeply the working   conditions in textile and footwear enterprises in  the context of  the production  recovery  of the garment industry. and  footwear  in Vietnam, at  the same time proposing appropriate and feasible recommendations to ensure and improve labor conditions and promptly support workers and enterprises to overcome the difficult period left by  the  epidemic.  Unlike the      study &quot;The impact of  COVID-19  on workers in Vietnam&apos;s textile and footwear  industry,  workers  &apos; looks &#x2013;   current   policies for     trade unions  and the government&quot; implemented by Care  in collaboration  with CNV International  in 2020 focus on  such contents as:
  - Analyzingthe  impact  of COVID-19 on the lives  of  workers in the  textile and footwear industry in 3  main aspects:  economy, health- health, and  society  - gender;
   Identify    workers&apos;  needs  to  respond to COVID-19;
-   Petition proposals  can help   workers recover  and overcome  COVID-19 outbreaks.
The content of the study proposed by the Institute of Workers and Trade Unions  focuses on the main contents  such as:
- Status  and   changes in   working  conditions,   welfare   regimes and living  conditions of  employeesin may and leather   textile enterprises &#xE0;y in  the context of  enterprises are  in  the process of   restoring  production after the Covid 19  outbreak;
- The connection between salary and working conditions and the decision to return to work at the former company of the employee;
 - Proposing  specific  proposals to ensure and improve labor conditions in the conditions of gradually serving the supply chain of textile and footwear industry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Workers and Trade Uni</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Institute for Workers and Trade Unions is a research institution under the Vietnam General Confederation of Labour, with a legal entity, a separate seal and headquarters in Hanoi. The institute receives funding, other operation means and a bank account.

The Institute for Workers and Trade Unions have the following functions:

Organizing research on basic theoretical and practical issues concerning the working class and trade unions.
Based on the research results, providing scientific evidence to contribute to the policy-making process concerning the working class and trade unions in the new era.

Synthesizing scientific information that meets thetheoretical and practical research requirements of trade unions.

 The Institute for Workers and Trade Unions is a research institution under the Vietnam General Confederation of Labour, with a legal entity, a separate seal and headquarters in Hanoi. The institute receives funding, other operation means and a bank account.

The Institute for Workers and Trade Unions have the following functions:

Organizing research on basic theoretical and practical issues concerning the working class and trade unions.
Based on the research results, providing scientific evidence to contribute to the policy-making process concerning the working class and trade unions in the new era.

Synthesizing scientific information that meets the theoretical and practical research requirements of trade unions.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GERMANY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-29">21281</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">6385</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">14896</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Germany back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute for Workers and Trade Uni</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">14896</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GERMANY</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06861-03:VN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002511"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007256"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Vietnam (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06861"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Strengthening Workers&#x2019; Resilience for De"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fair food value-citizen voice</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active citizens, consumers or food producers in global value chains are mobilised in support of fair food systems and producers/workers&apos; rights</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9540-4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">people that exercise pressure on governmental actors, standard setting bodies, private sector and financial institutions, through public engagement, media, and alliance work</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9540-4" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
