<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06819-03:SO</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Women&#x2019;s role in peace-building</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Background:
Armed conflicts have a devastating impact on economic life, destroying infrastructure, markets, and livelihoods. Women&#x2019;s lives are drastically altered at this time as they are compelled to take on new tasks and responsibilities and family survival comes to depend heavily on women who are forced in such period of hardship to look for alternative sources of livelihood. Although women also take on roles previously held by men in the formal sector, they tend to maintain their livelihood and that of their families by working in the informal sector where their labour is neither legally recognized nor protected. In contrast with the pre-war period, a high number of woman-headed households become the primary source of family income and to a large certain extent, are atthe forefront of the country&#x2019;s or region&#x2019;s economic recovery in the post-conflict setting.
At the cessation of hostilities, women tend to be most neglected in formal economic reconstruction activities. This problem, which pervades transition economies as allowingemployers to discriminate in favor of men, reinforces gender disparities, violates women&#x2019;s rights and constricts women&#x2019;s contributions to economic growth. Working conditions of women frequently deteriorate and are characterized by low wages, little or no labour standards protection, poor working conditions, particularly with regard to women&apos;s occupational health and safety and a lack of job security and social security, in both the formal and informal sectors. Widows, women with disabilities, single women without family support and female -headed households as well as other groups such as rural women, refugee and internally displaced women, are especially susceptible to increased economic hardship.
This project willprevent such discriminations by providing more opportunities to women and female youth in El-Afwayn to positively take part the Post-conflict reconstruction in the district. It will support women&#x2019;s contributions in the informal and reproductive areas of the economy, where most economic activity occurs. Specific interventions will be undertaken to leverage opportunities for women&#x2019;s further economic empowerment and political participation and the promotion of gender equality as necessary pre-conditions fora real peace economy to flourish. Economic recovery and development is a key element in building sustainable peace and lack of economic possibilities and employment opportunities can undermine public support to post-conflict reconciliation and fuel political instability and insecurity. It is paramount that women&#x2019;s economic participation be an integral part of post-conflict recovery, thus providing an opportunity for women to engage more actively in a larger sustainable peace building context.
Approach Used to complement with other Oxfam interventions is El-Afweyn
A people-centered approach should deploy inmainstreaming community engagement of all planning in development and humanitarian programs  and local conflict resolutions to empower underrepresented groups such as women and youth. In that regards, Oxfam had tested triple nexus programing approach as part of transformative solution to the interconnected needs of the vulnerable and marginalized groups caused by the crises.  Therefore,  focusing on a particular area using area-based method in a cross-sectional coordination in other Oxfam humanitarian interventions implementing in El-Afweyn district, will result greater impact for sustainable development through eradication of the root causes of the conflict and finally bring resilient and inclusive society.
Current humanitarian and resilient interventions are; rehabilitation/construction of multi-use water structures, village saving loan associations (VSLAs), EWCs and contingency plans, agricultural input support, diversification of livelihoods, and restoring access to veterinary, agricultural, and advisory services, as well as supportingthe development of community adaptation action plans, are all existing interventions that address conflict triggers. Support women&apos;s producer associations by providing seed funds to help them leverage savings and gain access to loans also significantly tackles conflict but creates social capital within the society.
Therefore, the project is inline with the country strategy in relation to contributing inclusive governance systems and should address conflict crises and inequality to ensure effective participation of marginalized groups, particularly women and youth. Also strengthen the capacity of local community/actors and link to local government institutions through community dialogues to effectively influencing peace and security transformative processes.
Objective, Outcomes, Outputs and Activities:
Objective:  Strengthening local communities, particularly women and female youth and have increased their capacity to fully participate peace building processes to foster community cohesion and coexistence
Outcome 1. Enhanced role and participation of women in influencing conflict resolution and peace building processes to promote, sustain and consolidate peace.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NAGAAD Network</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nagaad is the women#s network in Somaliland, which ON has been supporting since its establishment in1997. Nagaad was formed by 32 women#s groups in Hargeisa. While it has raised its profile tremendously after 2000, with a range of advocacy and publicity actions in the media, notably around women#s political participation, it has always remained a  of 32 member organisations, many of them remain weak, except for a few larger ones (some of whom are also counterparts of Oxfam Novib). Nagaad built its own office and received support from a variety of donors. Over the last four years Nagaad has elaborated a restructuring plan and a new strategic plan that involves: (a) more focus on networking instead of direct implementation; (b) admission of 15 new members from the regions of Somaliland, and working relationships with regional women#s umbrellas and professional associations. The network now has a membership of 46organisations.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-31">53614</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">5361</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-01">26807</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NAGAAD Network</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-01">21446</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NAGAAD Network</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-01">26807</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-01">21446</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06819-03:SO">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007052"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Somalia HECA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06819"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Somali Women&#x2019;s role in peace-building"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to: # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to promote inclusive security and peace building.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to: # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to promote inclusive security and peace building.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to promote inclusive security and peace building.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to promote inclusive security and peace building.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="3160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
