<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06857-03:PS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building the Pales. Agr. insurnace - EU</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of piloting agricultural insurance products, ESDC will work on this key sub-component which is key to the potential commercialisation of, and introduction of the agricultural insurance system for both the insurance supplier (private insurance companies) and the insurance purchaser (SSPs), it is essential to introduce these products utilizing an incentivized  approach. Their work entails (i) introducing SSPs to the farm&#x2019;s best practices and risk cycle management, (ii) identification of and preparation of farms against climate change risks, (iii) familiarising SSPs to the concept and burden of insurance premium, (iv) introduce farmers to variouscredit receiving schemes within the Palestinian financial system, at the same time (v) familiarising the Palestinian government of the financial implications of agricultural insurance (financial capitalisation), including premium subsidies and its entailed capitalisation.

Thus, the below five inter-linked steps will be co-managed and implemented by ESDC. These steps are essential for the successful piloting of agricultural insurance products and raising awareness of the entire insurance system. It also ensures the gradual bearing of insurance premiums, preparedness requirements, and costs that are pre-requisites of insurance policy issuance as the case of any other insurance product. It worth mentioning that premium subsidy is a world-wide practice by holding governments, as it is related to state-levelled capacity against natural disasters and climate risks.

The five implementation steps under this activityare:
&#x2022; Develop booklets on 1) minimum acceptable agricultural specification 2) agricultural best practices and 3) farm risk management practices of certain agricultural establishments related to the launched/piloted products.
&#x2022; Conduct training and capacity sharing activities for SSPs/potential policyholders on the specifications, best practices, and farm risk management. The training will cover insurance practitioners&#x2019; staff to expand knowledge and enhance underwriting decision making. Furthermore, financial mainstreaming trainings and outreach activities are anticipated to introduce farmers to available financing mechanisms and schemes within the banking, MFIs and PACI systems. This will support farmers to think of and target financing of operational activities  as well as finance any farm enhancement requirements that may be requested for agricultural insurance eligibility.
&#x2022; Provide cost share (subsidise) of up to 35% of annual/cycle insurance premium in full cooperation with the insurance company/ies, in addition to the subsidy provided by the Palestinian Government. This activity is essential and is required to decrease risks (as a pilot/model &#x2013; to scale up investments).
&#x2022; Develop outreach materials and presentations for the piloted products.
&#x2022; Plan and implement targeted promotional and awareness-raising campaigns.

As explained  in section ii. Target groups, final beneficiaries, stakeholders, and co-applicants, the maximum of the 35% subsidy will not replace nor substitute the 20-30% government subsidy, but complements it to ensure affordability of the insurance products by combining the subsidy by both the government and the project during the pilot phase. Beyond this action, and based on PADRRIF&#x2019;s plans, the Palestinian government plans to capitalise for the full premium subsidy in the percentages to be enumerated as per the newly developed insurance system.

All above described trainings, extension services, and awareness raising activities are relating to Palestine&#x2019;s NDC implementation plan on climate-smart agriculture, specifically Output 2: Promote Conservationagricultural best practices and businesses, and Output 3: Scaling up sustainable community-managed irrigation schemes, resilient infrastructure and businesses to improve food and water security and resilience of vulnerable communities. More specifically, this action is aligned with Activity 3 of the NDC CSA on capacity building: (a) identifying appropriate technologies, tools and techniques of CSA, (b) assessing farmers&#x2019; indigenous and captured knowledge, (c) increasing capacity and technology transfer, and (d) training farmers on CSA technologies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESDC complies with Palestinian labour law; employees are covered with health insurance and the insurance to the offices; there is vehicle insurance and social insurance for guests ,The ESDC has a board of directors with a well-defined and written mandate. The board provides the organizations with oversight and accountability and does regular up-keep of business records. ESDC#s mission statement is also available. Finally, there are mechanisms and structures for ensuring participatory management by the organization&apos;s top management.

It is worth noting that ESDC was an ISO 9001 certified, which is a positive point for them in regards to governance structure.

They are well organized in term of their procedures and policies. Some procedures are in place but not systemized. They havea written complaint system, although it needs further work. It also needs to develop an operational manual. ESDC is governed by an elected, multidisciplinary Board of Directors (BoD). The BoD consists of 9 members, 6 men and 3 women. The term of the BoD is two years, after which elections are held and the General Assembly elects the new BoD.
ESDC is governed by the following core values: Equality, Democracy, Partnership, Cooperation, Transparency, Integrity, Social Justice, Civil Peace. ESDC staff consists of more than twenty full time employees specialized in capacity building of cooperatives and community based organizations (CBOs), agriculture, water and environment. The staff work from one of ESDC&apos;s three offices: Ramallah, Gaza and Tubas.

ESDC#s general assembly consists of 26 members from both genders, where members are from different areas and specializations in the field of development. They meet at least one time every year. The board of directors consists of 9members elected by the general assembly members every two years.ESDC staff consists of more than twenty full time employees specialized in capacity building of cooperatives and community#based organizations, agriculture, water and environment based on three offices in Ramallah, Gaza and Tubas.
 For the complaint system: the system primarily uses emails and letters, as well as oral complains. All methods of communication are put into the complaint system.
 Vision: A Palestinian cooperative society that is economically independent and socially just
Mission: Eventuating Integrated Development in Palestine through Economic &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Social Empowerment for the target groups
ESDC continues to align its organizational values withthe internationally-accepted co-operative principles. It also upholds the values of transparency, integrity and accountability, social justice, and peace. ESDC recognizes itself as a member of civil society in Palestine. Its stated strategic objective within the development programme:
1. To contribute in the national endeavours in improving the livelihood &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; food Security for the target groups.
2. To increase the capacities of  civil society organization, including cooperatives  in providing relevant services to their members &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; communities.
3. To reinforce the gender equitable &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; equity in ESDC&apos;s operations &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; activities.
4. To build the capacities of ESDC to be more efficient and effective in management &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; supervision.
Target Beneficiaries: CBOs , small scale farmers , vulnerable groups(youth, women) and vulnerable areas that are affected from displacement, the wall and settlers violence, communities who are vulnerable to food insecurity. ESDC#s geographical focus is in all of the West Bank and Gaza Strip with a main focus in rural areas and vulnerable communities (for Vulnerability definition ESDC uses definitions from national publications,UN OCHA, and other related organizations).
ESDC#s understanding of partnership: As a local NGO, they share a common objective with internationalNGOs and donors to meet and work with each other to achieve agreed objectives. The local partner brings technical expertise and relationships with local communities, where the international and donor partners contribute financially and in developing thecapacities of the local partner. They also the international skills and capabilities particularly in terms of advocacy and lobbying. Therefore, the agreed objectives are achieved through collective action from both partners , each of them participate within the scope of their capacity.
ESDC has a mechanism to identify beneficiaries in their work and are accountable to them through a well defined, organized system for beneficiary selection. ESDC ensures participation of all community members in the developmentof selectioncriteria and the selection process. ESDC presents the list of beneficiaries to the local community, receives feedback on it, and ifthere is a complaint, feedback, or a contradiction, they are open to discuss.They have a system for selectingtarget groups with communities and involving local communities in all project stages: announcing the project in communities, setting criteria with communities, involving communities in needs assessments, designing the interventions, promoting the project, selecting beneficiaries, involving local communities in the selection of beneficiaries, monitoring the progress of projects. ESDC also publishes projects details on their website.

ESDC is also accountable to its target group through a feedback system, in which complaints and any notes in regard to activities and other issues related to implementation and activities, can be sent and addressed.
ESDC also has forms to measure beneficiary satisfaction. However, this system should be more organized. ESDCrequires more capacity building in this area including mechanism to ensure regular reporting.

Level of accountability and transparency is good in general but needs a stronger documentation system that is integrated into their operational manual and M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E system.
ESDC works very closely with farmers and CBOs especially cooperatives, and support them in term of capacity building, marketing legislation issues, and with line ministries on the Cooperative Law.  Therefore, ESDC is strategically focusedonthe rights of farmers, policy and legislation that influences them and lobbying with other organization to improve farmers&apos; situation.

ESDC defines Vulnerability according to the country context, clusters&apos; definitions and UN agencies especially UNOCHA. They need to systemize their work according to this criteria, and not change on a project by project basis.

ESDC has its own gender strategy and give preference to female headed households as target groups, as wellas female producers and women#s cooperatives.

ESDC has both internal and external evaluations for its projects to measure impact and outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic and Social Development Cen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territories</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.6497 35.16207</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">209628</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">52407</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-11-01">52407</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-05-01">52407</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-11-01">52407</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06857-03:PS">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002522"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007018"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="OPT/I MENA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06857"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Building the Pales. Agr. insurnace - EU"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human economy-alliances</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People benefit from access to finance and improved livelihoods, through MFIs and local private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9760-4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">people benefitting from access to finance provided by micro-finance institutions in which Oxfam Novib has invested</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9760-4" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="735"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9760-5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">people benefitting from improved business practices of startups and impact-driven SMEs, such as smallholder suppliers, employees and customers, in particular women and youth</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9760-5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="735"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
