<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000141</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice; Nothing About Us, Without Us</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Voice is an innovative grant facility that supports the most marginalised and discriminated people in ten low- and lower-middle income countries in Africa and Asia. It aims to amplify and connect thus far unheard voices in efforts to leave no one behind.

Voice is an initiative of and financed by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands as part of their overall policy framework #Dialogue and Dissent# and is executed by a consortium between Oxfam Novib and Hivos.

Voice has two main components; a grant facility to provide financial support to groups and organisations totaling 35 million Euro for a period of 5 years (2016-2020). And a linking and learning programme that will nurture learning and innovation across countries and groups.

Through a decentralised management approach, Voice is coordinated by Oxfam country offices in Mali, Nigeria, Niger, Uganda, Laos and Cambodia. In Kenya and  Tanzania, Voice is coordinated by Hivos East Africa while in Indonesia and the Philippines, Hivos South East Asia takes responsibility for coordination and management. For more information please visit www.voice.global.

The long-term outcome of Voice is to strengthen the capacity for lobby and advocacy of CSOs and representatives of the most marginalised and discriminated people in order to empower these groups and to have their voices heard and respected, using innovative ideas in the field of capacity strengthening and in the field of lobby and advocacy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
