<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06575-12:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Superstar Impact SMEs Competition</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Superstar Impact SMEs Competition is an opportunity for SMEs involved in the SME development project implemented by Oxfam Uganda from the past and current cohorts to participate in scale-up support that is intended to highlight the impact the SMEs create in the community we serve.

After a rigorous competitive process, 3 SMEs who submit winning proposals will be selected by a team of juryand shall enter into a dedicated scale-up trajectory through grant and technical support. The grant shall be awarded to support implementation of the activities that the companies propose in their application. The technical support shall be provided by our local partner Open Capital Advisors.

2. Project Overview

General Objectives
The primary objective of the Superstar Impact SME competition is to accelerate societal (innovative) impact through SMEs and start-ups &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; job opportunities for youth.
This year, the project intends to pursue the following objectives
1) Accelerate environmental impact and create opportunities by supporting and promoting green business ideas.
2) Understand the needs of SMEs in creating green businesses and adapt our program accordingly.
3) Enable stakeholders to recognize the importance and potential of supporting and investing in &#x201C;Green Superstar SMEs&#x201D;

Expected deliverables
&#x2022; Deliverable 1: A competition is organized, 03 local companies are selected as winners
&#x2022; Deliverable 2: Technical support is providedto the 3 selected winners.
&#x2022; Deliverable 3:  A promotional documentary (video) and other related promotional materials are producedto help document and showcase the success story of one (1) winner to be agreed during the selection process.
&#x2022; Deliverable 4: A final report which contains details about the competition, implementation and project monitoring will be provided.

Selection Criteria and Implementation Approach
&#x2022; All SMEs that participated in the SME Development Project Uganda from its inception in June 2018 are invited to register for the competition. We shall also extend the invitation to the SMEs who participated earlier under the pilot with B-Space.
&#x2022; SMEs will join the competition using VC4A platform and shall use a team of &#x2018;jury&#x2019; to select the winning applications
&#x2022; Oxfam shall invite all participating SMEs to a Q&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;A webinar to address questions about circular business models, environmental impacts and how the competition will be run to enable the SMEs complete their applications. The participating SMEs shall also be engaged via WhatsApp /Facebook /E-mail to answer questions that may arise as they prepare their proposals.
&#x2022; After the applications arereceived, a panel or Jury will be constituted to review the applications and produce a short-list of 6 SMEs. The shortlisted SMEs will be invited to present to the Jury and 3 SMEs winners will be selected.
Three prizes shall be awarded as follows: First prize winner will be awarded 12,000 EUR, second prize winner will get 10,000 EUR and third prize will get 8,000 EUR &#x2013; (i.e. 30,000 EUR total prizes to winners).

&#x2022; After the selection, tailored consultancy support will be provided by Open Capital Advisors to help the 2 of the 3 selected winners to implement their plans. While the main focus this year is to accelerate environmental impact and create opportunities by supporting and promoting green business ideas, attention will also be paid to impact related topics such as decent jobs, women (gender justice), youth inclusion, etc.
&#x2022; The first prize winner will have a chance to participate in a global learning event.
&#x2022; All the winners will be introduced and promoted by Oxfam and its related partners through their communications channels and networks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OPEN CAPITAL ADVISORS</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We founded Open Capital Advisors (OCA) in 2010 to unlock growth and investment in East and Southern Africa.  The creation of OCA was driven by a core gap our founders observed between businesses and investors in the region.  We saw many small growing businesses (SGBs) with massive potential and opportunity for scale, but who struggled to find financing to support their growth.  At the same time, we encountered investors who had available capital, but were unable to find sufficient businesses they deemed #investment ready#.  The investors required a higher level of formalization and strategic planning than the businesses they currently encountered in the market.
To bridge this gap OCA provides high-quality, intensive support to help our clients adapt to rapidly changing and growingmarkets, including co-designing strategies, implementing best practices, and raising external funds to drive growth and impact. We take significant risk alongside our SGB clients, typically deferring a portion of fees onto a successful capital raise. This approach allows us to work with businesses that would otherwise be unable to afford support. We have developed innovative programs with impact investors, USAID, and others to defray risk and work with even earlier-stage companies.
We target SGB clients looking to raise between $500K - $5M USD. These SGBs are trying to solve the toughest problems in their local markets, including agriculture, renewable energy, financial inclusion, and more. We select SGBs where our work will help them transform markets, create new jobs, and innovate products and services.
Today, Open Capital Advisors has offices incorporated in Kenya and Uganda with our team of 42 full-time professionals spread across Nairobi and Kampala.
Our approach to integrating gender has evolved and expanded in focus over the maturation of the firm.  We view our gender agenda as having two prongs: internal and external.
Internally, we focus on hiring, training and retaining highly talented employees, especially women.  As laid out in greater detail in our organogram below, over half of our entire team is female, and 50% of our senior management team (including 1 of two founding partners) is female.
In 2015 we hired a dedicated head of Human Resources who has studiedgender equity in the workplace.  She has helped us formalize our practices on gender equity, including updating our HR procedures and introducing a gender policy.
Externally, we work with and support promising entrepreneurs, many of whom are female.  Historically, 30% of the founders we have worked with have been women and we continue to focus on increasing this ratio.  Further, we work with many pro-women businesses, that include empowering women # in their workforce or throughtheir products / services# as a core component of their business model.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-02">5000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">5000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds(project link)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">5000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06575-12:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06575"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Superstar Impact SMEs (2) Competition"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies: # cases private sector adopting/implementing improved policies on increasing transparency &amp; accountability, on integration of ESG &amp; Human Rights criteria in policy and practice and/or on promotion of financial inclusion of poor people</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases private sector adopting/implementing improved policies on increasing transparency &amp; accountability, on integration of ESG &amp; Human Rights criteria in policy and practice and/or on promotion of financial inclusion of poor people -DD2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-04" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies: # cases private sector adopting/implementing improved policies on increasing transparency &amp; accountability, on integration of ESG &amp; Human Rights criteria in policy and practice and/or on promotion of financial inclusion of poor people</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners in support of development/adoption of alternative policies/approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2410-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-04" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2410-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners to support monitoring of practices and implementation of policies by the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2410-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-04" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-04"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
