<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06895-05:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-506695</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Extractives Industrial sector investment in Cambodia have been growing rapidly. The Ministry of Mining and Energy (MME) opens more for local and oversea companies to invest in the mining sector. During the MME&#x2019;s annual meeting in February 2020, the MME updated that there are 17 mining exploitation licenses, 37 mineral exploration licenses, and 323 construction mineral licenses were issued.
The mining companies have been known and operating include Renaissance Mineral (Cambodia) Limited, Mesco Gold, Aluminum Development (Cambodia) Corp co., Ltd, Angkor Gold Corp, Golden Resources Development Co Ltd, Kun Yuan International (Cambodia) Co., Ltd and NITTESU MINING (CAMBODIA) Ltd. Based on information from the EIA reports and approved license, concession areas of these companies overlapped on Wildlife Sanctuaries, Community Protected Area (CPA), Prey Lang including community forestry and land areas of DPA&#x2019;s target communities. As example, the granted exploration concession areas to NITTESU MINING (CAMBODIA) Ltd from Japan, is 13,618.1 hectares and it has overlapped on Prey Lang Wildlife Sanctuary.
In June 2021, the Cambodia first off-shore oil project that was sounded promising few years ago turned to be stalled recently as Kris-Energy announced bankruptcy to continue to operate the project. Given geographic locations of the mineral, oil and gas deposits that predominantly exit in Mekong and Tonle Sa watersheds, explorations havebeen and are being conducted.
Given the importance of extractive resourcesand reduction of revenues from other sectors such as fishery, land and forest, Government seems to give more priority to explore and exploit extractive industries resources in the Mekong and Tonle Sap Watersheds. If exploitations occur in those watersheds without discrimination and proper regulations, it will cost severenvironmental and social consequences to the troubled water and lands in Tonle Sap and Mekong and the livelihoods of millions people.
In addition, the revenue collection and management in EI sector is another concerning issue, based on the revenue collection strategy 2019 -2023, as it is indicated that mining and energy revenue collection increased in an average 41.1% annually started from 2013 until 2018. Until 2019, Ministry of Mine and Energy (MME) collected 3.3 million US$ of mining development fund. This fund is set aside to be used to support local development of mining affected communities. The information about the fund has not been well disseminated to the public especially mining affected communities. The procedures of how community access to this fund has not been available yet.
The increasing investment of extractive industries sector in Cambodia has created a huge concern about social and environmental impacts of affected communities, especially Indigenous Peoples (IPs), including losing IPs cultures and mean of livelihoods, water and soil pollution, health impacts, conflicts over natural resources, and human rights violations. Therefore, Oxfam and its civil society partners and alliances are working to promote good governance and responsible investment, particularly among major extractive projects in the northeastern provinces of Cambodia.

Oxfam will further build strategic alliance and the established important coalitions on extractive industries including (1) the Extractive Industries Social and Environmental Impact Network; and (2) NGO Coalition on Extractive Industry Governance.
Oxfam and its allies will establish IPs rights and FPIC Think Tank to make the resources available for learning, advocacy and research related to social and environmental impacts of indigenous peoples from extractive industries project and other development projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994.  Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education forall, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies.  Oxfam established this country office to support local organizations and projects.  Through this local office Oxfam Novib directly contributes towards this project#s implementation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.5656 104.9909</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-06">3411</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-01">817</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">2594</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06895-05:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000122" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002542"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06895"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Strengthening EI Governance in Cambodia"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate justice activism-Strength CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs have strengthened capacity (and maintain and expand their civic space) to engage local, nationally and internationally in influencing on gendered climate justice, natural resources and/or land rights issues in an effective and inclusive way.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9920-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs who demonstrate strengthened capacity to engage in influencing</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9920-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-03-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal-Priv Sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased equality &amp; equity in formal rules and practices as laid down in constitutions, laws, and policies of Private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9110-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where private sector policies are increasingly promoting equality and equity</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9110-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-03-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9110-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where private sector practices are increasingly participatory and accountable</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9110-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-03-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-08-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
