<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06301-05:14</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chambua - Enhancing Inclusive Taxation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The &quot;Chambua - Enhancing Inclusive Taxation&quot; projects long-term vision is that marginalized citizens (particularly people with disabilities and young women) see an increased access to productive resources and open and inclusive spaces for political participation by enhancing citizen engagement in issues around taxation. The project hopes to see an increased (and more responsive) public expenditure to address the needs of those living at the margins of society, by promoting their sustained and active in decision-making processes by empowering communities to engage directly with the duty bearers, interrogating key public expenditure documents, and make recommendations to influence allocation and utilization of public funds to address their needs. The project objectives are:
# To strengthen inclusive tax collection, procedures and systems safeguarding the concerns of People living with Disabilities and Women facing exploitation, abuse and/violence in Nairobi and Kisumu Counties by April 2022.
# To increase allocation and utilization of publicfunds towards the priorities of PWDs and women facing exploitation, abuse and/violence in Nairobi and Kisumu Counties by April 2022.
# To enhance the participation and visibility of 1,189 PWDs and 2,000 women facingexploitation, abuse and/violence in decision making process at the National and Sub-national level by April 2022.
Meaningful change will be achieved if marginalized people is empowered to participate in the governance processes, increase the strength oftheir voice in the taxation dialogues, express their needs and push for inclusive taxation and public expenditure allocations so that no policy should be decided by any representative withouttheir full participation as they are the ones who are being affected. Only then shall government be responsive, prioritise inclusion and diversity in service delivery provision.

This project is implemented by a consortium led by the Kenya Paraplegic Organization, in collaboration with the National Taxpayers Association (NTA), and the Kenya Female Advisory Organization (KEFEADO).

# Kenyan Paraplegic Organization (KPO) which was registered under the NGO Coordination Act on 18th of March 2004 as a Non-Governmental Organisation (NGO) with the vision of an inclusive society where persons with Disability enjoy equal rights, lead dignified and sustainable lives and achieve their full potential. Kenyan Paraplegic Organization exists to inspire, empower and enhance quality of life of persons with Spinal Injury and related disabilities to be productive members of the society.
# NTA is a national, independent non-partisan organization which is focussed on promoting good governance in Kenya. NTA has been implementing programmes focused on enhancing public accountability through monitoring the quality of public service delivery and the management of devolved funds.
# KEFEADO is aNon-governmental organization who undertakes its work in Nyanza region. It exists to promote gender equity, equal opportunities andhuman rights for all.

The consortium will employ an intersectional and intergenerational approach to ensure that synergies built with their constituencies through the years can be pooled together to ensure that principles of cross movement building is built on. Theexperience shall be drawn from the three institutions work on advocacy on disability and inclusion; public expenditure tracking and intersectional and intergenerational feminist movement building at all levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KENYAN PARAPLEGIC ORGANIZATION</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Kenyan Paraplegic Organization (KPO) was registered 2004 as a non-governmental organisation with a vision of an inclusive society where all persons with disabilities enjoy equal rights, lead dignified and sustainable lives, and achieve their full potential.  KPO exists to inspire, empower and enhance quality of life of people with disabilities, particularly those with spinal injury (and related disabilities) to be productive members of the society.

KPO endeavours to achieve this through using participatory integratedapproaches that strengthen the capacity of community-based organisation structures to facilitate their participation in socio-economic and political processes. As an organisation, KPO has five strategic pillars:
- Governance and Accountability: to enable the participation of people with disabilities (PWDs), in civic education, lobby and advocacy, social audits, and use of media, to influence and enhance service delivery and accountability from duty bearers.
- Economic Empowerment: by promoting entrepreneurship and business development among PWDs, by enhancing access to micro-finance institutions and devolved funds for capacity building and credit facilities, value chain enhancement, entrepreneurship development, promotion of aggregation and collection centres, skills in resource mobilization.
- Psychosocial Support: through peer sessions, support with aiding devices, life skills development, social inclusion and integration, mentorship and exchange programmes, KPO contributes to reduce stigma against PWDs and increase their self-reliance.
- Rehabilitation; KPO is establishing a trauma and rehabilitation centre for care and support with long term personalized follow up for adherence, integration and social support.
- Organizational Development. KPO is a learning, self-reflecting Organization to continually enhance skills and knowledge in advocacy, resource mobilization, documentation, networking and socio-economic development strategies as well as continually improving on internalsystems and procedures.

KPO reaches PWDs in 9 Counties in Kenya: Nairobi, Kiambu, Laikipia, Kajiado, Nakuru, Baringo, Bomet, Bungoma and Busia. KPO has membership in various coalitions and Disability Persons Organisations (DPOs) that move forward the disability inclusion and diversity agenda.  KPO is uniquely placed as its constituent account for the highest number of persons with physical disability who again are the largest cohort in persons living with disability. KPO is also able to address cross-cutting challenges of all persons with disability while paying special attention to the uniqueness of its core constituent; this is also possible though effective linkages, networking and collaboration with other DPOs and partners.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East and Centra</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-29">58425</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">55504</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KENYAN PARAPLEGIC ORGANIZATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">2921</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KENYAN PARAPLEGIC ORGANIZATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-01">55504</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">2921</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06301-05:14">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001989"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06301"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="From Open to Inclusive Governance"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders develop and implement innovative strategies to reach, empower and strengthen the capacities of rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Communities of Practice supported by programme staff and Linking and Learning facilitating organisations to define a set of learning questions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># Communities of Practice with active participation of grantees emerging through Linking and Learning processes</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.c.i</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and type (article, training material, blog, podcast, video) of publications produced by Communities of Practice to develop, share and document knowledge</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.c.i" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.c.ii</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># learning meetings held by Communities of Practice to develop, share and document knowledge</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.c.ii" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders develop and implement innovative strategies to reach, empower and strengthen the capacities of rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># grantees, rightsholder groups and other key stakeholders reporting use of new insights and innovative approaches that they have acquired through Linking and Learning</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.1.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-28"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
