<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06810-03:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amplifying digital rights in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project objectives include:
1) To empower citizens with the skills, knowledge, and tools to self-advocate for their digital rights.
2) To increase the number of young women engaged meaningfully in the governance discourse in Uganda.
3) To reduce digital literacy inequality among groups commonly left out by mainstream media e.g. young women, youth and the women&apos;s movement.
4) To provide virtual safe spaces for valiant civic discussions that are accessible and affordable to citizens.

The project activities include:
1) Video promoting voices for digital rights. The project will embark on production of citizen led video to showcase digital rights challenges and&#x202F;priorities for the citizens as well as gaps in the legislation and laws that govern .&#x202F;The video will also document voices from some digital rights&#x202F;experts in the country.&#x202F; The video will be centered around common themes, including concerns about people&#x2019;s lack of understanding about&#x202F;their data use and&#x202F;how&#x202F;their&#x202F;data is used, and the challenges that activists and civil society organizations face in&#x202F;getting citizens&#x202F;to see these issue as a concern and the uphill task to get citizens to engage meaningfully on digital platforms.&#x202F; The project will widely disseminate the video through a wide range of social media networking sites which will provide powerful means of sharing, organizing, promotion and engagement. The video will have a ripple effect where citizens, with the capacity to undertake independent analysis of issues presented or highlighted in the video, form opinions and influence fellow citizens and duty bearers, and can lever&#xAC;age social media for policy engagement on digital rights and freedom.
2) Hosting young feminists on the women show. CCG will host a young women driven show to bring together young feminists from across the country, at  what we shalldub a virtual &#x2018;central&#x2019; talk. This will be on topic-specific discussions that reflect themes that will emerge from ongoing events across the country. This will be followed by a wider shared discussion on how these issues can be tackled, and made positive, by citizens.

These conversations will lead to four main themes in the digital rights debate:
i. Education &#x2013; digital in education and education about digital;
ii. Misinformation; the digital divide and the sexual strain on women;
iii. How to make digital rights a priority of the public sector; and how to make digital rights a priority of the private sector.
iv. The state of internet freedom and protection of young women&#x2019;s rights. This will focus on constitutional laws and the ever upcoming amendments by policy makers and how these affect participation and engagement of women in the governance discourse of the country.
As these conversations take place, many of the talking points will be influenced by feminists topical discussions around issues brought to the fore by COVID-19 and the subsequent lockdowns. In addition, this space shall serve to mentor them in Public speaking skills as well as advocacy through the media.
3) Amplifying young people&apos;s voices on the youth round table. The show will target young people in Uganda aiming to address issues related especially to accessing information through digital technology like never before, and using it to make them seen and their voices heard. This will open opportunities for greater citizen engagement countrywide and virtually. The project is mindful that there is growing recognition that in order to create an inclusive and responsive society in Uganda, citizens, and especially the youth, need to be at the centre of policy-makers&#x2019; considerations; not just as targets, but also as agents. This show will therefore aim to develop policies and design services that respond to individuals&#x2019; needs, and that are relevant to their circumstances.
4) Mobilizingcommunity leaders to promote digital rights on community show/ citizen journalism. In order to promote community ownership and sustained engagement, we shall mobilise community leaders on a weekly basis to highlight the importance of digital rights and freedom.
General advocacy for digital rights on citizens chat shows. For full realization of the potential of digital technologies to transform society and economies in Uganda especially during the pandemic and beyond, there is need for continued advocacy to uphold and protect freedom of expression, access to information, and equitable participation online. We shall therefore launch 7 advocacy campaignsand or drives to reaffirm the immense importance of digital technologies for government and citizen interactions, public services provision, employment, education and commerce, while the government was seen to use the pandemic as an excuse to impose further clampdowns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Constitutional Governance (CCG) is a regional organization based in Uganda and reaches out to the Eastern Countries of Kenya, Tanzania, Rwanda, Burundi and South Sudan with a cardinal goal of strengthening constitutional governance by bridgingthe gaps in governance and challenges in policy and regulatory framework.

CCG seeks to promote constitutional governance in the greater EastAfrican region in areas of regulatory policy making and governance concepts by directing attention towards democratic and constitutional governance and bypassing old dichotomies on the future of the nation state.
Under organizational development (OD) have been guided by commitment to building and strengthening CCG.

CCG has over the period of time invested in institutional strengthening through procurement of equipment and recruiting competitive human personnel. It has only managed to enroll for a few staff training programs to fill some capacity gaps. The organization also benefited from technical support fromsome donors on security surveillance system that were installed to increase safety of staff personnel.

On gender integration, CCG recognizes the role women play in development in terms of their contribution, the unpaid extra labour and has purposely developed a gender policy at administration level to guide recruitments of staff and at program level to ensure that participation of all project activities beneficiary composition is ata ratio of 50/50 for both women and men across spectrum.
2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?

3.INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
The Vision:
An empowered citizenry that can fully utilize their constitutional rights and obligations to participate in their governance as well as promote constitutional governance anddefend the constitution

Mission Statement: To promote constitutional governance through carrying out constitutional literacy campaigns and advocacy across East Africa

Mission: What is the current purpose of the organisation?

Promote and advance constitutional governance whose main challenge at the moment is shrinking civic space which stops free citizen#s participation in their governance.
Institutional objectives: What are the principal changes the organisation seeks to achieve over the long term?
1. Promoting research-based constitutionalism and constitutional governance
2. Promoting democratic culture through creating platforms for discourse, debate and activism
3. Promoting integrity of the democratic processes by advocating for effective policy, legal and institutional mechanisms
4. Strengthening civil society and other social institutions through social justice campaigns
5. Carrying out public interest litigation and legal representation of activists
6. Setting up an Institute for International Studies in East Africa

CCG works ina highly sensitive political environment with new operating legal regulations, The relevant social actors include; CSOs in human rights, governance sector, Universities, &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; other public institutions, the judiciary, private sector Faith Based organisations, Youth and Women leaders.

Most of these are stakeholders at planning and design of projects, and beneficiaries and activists, influence in policy making level.

CCG is unique in the current position as a promoter of constitutionalism and citizenparticipation and it#s the lead in spearheading the work on pushing back against civic space in Uganda.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Constitutional Governanc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM International Affiliates</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-24">6180</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-01">6180</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam International Secretariat</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Constitutional Governanc</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-01">6180</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM International Affiliates</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06810-03:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002458"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06810"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Amplifying digital rights in Uganda"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civ Space-Gov policies</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Governments are supportive to dialogue with civil society, and create and implement enabling civic space legislation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases governments are held accountable by other governments, donors or regional and global bodies on civil society engagement and civic space.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where disenabling legislation is abandoned</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-4" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where enabling legislation is designed and approved</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where enabling legislation is implemented</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9200-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where political will for dialogue is expresed by Government</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9200-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
