<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06873-03:PS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-Provide Safe MPCA to vulnerable HHs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam aims to provide MPCA to 600 HHs referred from protection community based organizations (CBOs) in partnership with TdH in Palestine. The Activities will include carrying out joint vulnerability and protection assessment, provide response plans and cash delivery over a period of 5 rounds. Oxfam will also carry out analysis of case studies implemented under Oxfam programmes to highlight importance of Humanitarian Development Nexus programming.
Based on the selection of the financial service provider,and after final cross-checking with cash partners, delivery of cash assistance will be provided to the selected 500 HHs through the provision of top upamounts on their accounts/wallets. Oxfam will be coordinating with the financial service provider and will carry out all related arrangements, verification, provision of finalized lists and following up on any issues related to receipt of payment by the assigned HH member.

Oxfam will carry out payment verification with a sample of beneficiaries as wellas verification provided by the financial service provider who will be requested to provide real time information on cash withdrawal and spending when relevant. (For example, at vendors). The five rounds of cash provision will be carried out within 5 to 6 months period, having between the payment and the other 3 to 4 weeks. Post distribution monitoring will be conducted after the second payment and an endline after the fifth (last) payment.

Additionally, Oxfam will conduct Cash Consultations on the capacity and willingness to integrate cash programming among humanitarian sectors in Gaza.

Oxfam proposes to engage humanitarian actors including Cluster Coordinators in assessing the opportunities of integrating cash and in turn identify key barriers thathinder such integration the process. By defining these opportunities and barriers it would help clarify to cash actors where there is a need to invest, in terms of funding, research, capacity building, and advocacy and policies and procedures developmentthat are needed by each of these sectors. The consultation process includes technical and policy discussions with cluster coordinators, sector members within each of the selected sectors, general characteristics of feasibility of cash integration and will set out recommendations for cash actors to take forward. The consultations will also include understanding how sectors (currently using cash and those which are not) can adapt and make use of new technologies used in cash transfers, such as the digital transfers. The discussions will also aim to create a more serious dialogue on whether MPCA could besufficient in address sectoral outcomes or moving towards sectoral cash is also a necessity in responding to some needs in specifictime frame along the humanitarian response time spans.

Oxfam will be contracting with a specialized consultant who will carry out the consultations and will prepare recommendations, key barriers and opportunities and present to cash partners. Oxfam will keep close consultation with ECHO to develop the scope of the ToR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib has been active in the Occupied Palestinian Territory/Israel (OPT/I) since 1982 and working with Palestinian refugees in Lebanon since the mid 1980s. It has built up a strong network of relationships with local NGOs and counts among its localcounterparts some of the largest and most professional NGOs in various sectors. It has accompanied these NGOs in their development from ad hoc volunteer groups to sizeable professional institutions with national outreach.  At the same time the conceptualisation of the programme has evolved from three country programs in the early 1990s to a program for Palestinians in the Middle East (PME) working withPalestinians in OPT, Israel and Lebanon.

The programme has changed over the years with the establishment of the Palestinian Authority (PA) in the mid-1990s from a focus on support and service provision at a grassroots level and grassroots mobilization, to working towards influencing the establishment of the PA, its lawmaking and supporting building a democratic state # this involved supporting efforts of Palestinian civil society to build the basis for a democratic Palestinian state with room for civil participation, ensuring inclusion of vulnerable groups, refugees and women, and shaping its laws and systems. Oxfam Novib has also supported partners that are working on the provision of humanitarian assistance, response preparedness and conflict transformation. We have also supported partners in the provision of health services, access to quality education and gender justice.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territories</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.5225 34.45359</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-24">10111</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">10111</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union EU ECHO</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06873-03:PS">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002524"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007018"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="OPT/I MENA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06873"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Address basic needs &amp; protection of HHs"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-06-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-06-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-06-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-06-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
