<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05695-05:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indigenous Women and mining impact- CIPO</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indigenous people are group of people living in the territory of the Kingdom of Cambodia, whose have particular ethnic, social culture economic unity and practice their traditional lifestyles according to custom. Their agriculture and plantation on the plots of land they have occupied are done according to collectively customary usage of the land. In Cambodia, there are diverse of indigenous people such as the Bunong, Kuoy, Tumpong, Chary, Kroeng, Brao, Kavat. Totally of 24 groups. The indigenous people practices different culture tradition custom belief and languages according to their particular group.

In Cambodia there are many organization and institutions that work on indigenous people in capacity building, various knowledge about the rights to freedom of expression, political rights, the rights access to social protection. Although many relevant organization and institutions paid attention on indigenouswomen but their problem have not been responded yet. Seeing this, minority women from different indigenous group have common idea to establish the indigenous women network to voice their issues and concems and, hold the government and private sector to account and protect. The benefit of their communities. On 02 September 2018 women&#x2019; group organized a consultation workshop on the establishment of the first women&#x2019;s network in Cambodia, coordinated by the Cambodia Indigenous People Alliance (CIPA), Cambodia Indigenous People Organization (CIPO) Highlander Association (HA). Following its inception, the women&#x2019;s group received supported from International Indigenous Women Forum (IIWF) through the Cambodia Indigenous People&#x2019; financial system to carry out its activity starting in April 2019. In 2020 the women&#x2019;s group have prepared its action plan according to the old plan from last year, discussed with the members who do not yet have the budget to support and implement out the activity. For the women&#x2019;s team, there are many issues and needs that must be push and addressed indigenous communities, such as land rights issues decimation issue, economic, education, mining issue andclimate change issue.

The project was developed by seeing the impact of mining investment in Mondulkiri and its potential impacts on community&#x2019;s livelihood, heath, and environment and to empower IP women to take control and protect their resources and, ensure social and, environmental safeguarding. In addition, the women would like to have frequent training or meeting with communities livingaround mining investment area to strengthen their capacity to recognize their rights to participate in the early stages of researches and environmental assessment. Community awareness on the impact prevention methods are important to seek intervention from the company and the ministry of themines and energy to take strict action against the activities of its workers who violate the national law. The strengthening IP women network in the mining-affected area of communities, forests communities, and indigenous collective communities is crucialto voice their concems and hold the government and company accountable.

Recently, the Cambodian government through the ministry of Mine and Energy has provided mining investment license to private companies to boost the Cambodian economy as a senior official of the Ministry of Mines and Energy has recently confirmed about the first discovery of an international-scale gold mine in Mondulkiri Province.
Speaking at a press conference on the morning of April 21, 2020, Mr. Yos Monirath, Director General of the General Department of Mines of the Ministry of Mines and Energy, stated: A gold mine is located in Okhvav, Kev Seima district, Mondulkiri province. In July 2018, the government decided to grant a mining license to an Australian company called Renaissance Minerals (Cambodia) for a 15-year exploration area of 11.5 square kilometers in O&apos;Khvav, Keo Seima district, Mondulkiri province. According to Emerald Resources, Western Australia has some of policies to help the community such as:
1. Establishingand contribute to a fund for community development for the benefit of the community in the project area.
2. Seek the support of major suppliers and contractor to also contribute to the fund
3. Fund governed by a committee of local senior stakeholder including company representative of communities and NGOs organization.
4. Applications from local community will be assessed in accordance with community needs.
5. School Nursery initiative as a way for students to raise funds for their school, to increase environmental awareness in young people andprovide trees for future rehabilitation activities.
6. An Industry Partner supporting the Lion Water Sanitation Initiative in Obenlieu Commune, installing latrines and water filters in homes.

Objectives (intermediate impact)
Strengthened the rights and collective voice of indigenous women to influence and prevent from the potential impact of mining investment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CIPO is a new established and registered organization (2014), is an IP-led organization that combines the best knowledge of IP and Cambodian society context with the ability to creatively respond to the needs, for supports, of the IPs in Cambodia,. The organization is execute and operating by different ethnic groups of young generation and under active support from eldest group who as advisory board. CIPO has it governance board consists of leaders from local and international organizations. CIPO established to build the capacity and empower the IPs to take lead and own the development processes of IP communities in Cambodia.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia Indigenous Peoples Organiz</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-23-7069110" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-17">2472</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-01">2472</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia Indigenous Peoples Organiz</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-01">2472</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-23-7069110" ref="US-EIN-23-7069110">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05695-05:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000122" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001592"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05695"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Extractive Industries Governance"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to: # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to fullfill their rights on freedom of association, freedom of expression and to participate in public affairs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2160-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men  living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to fullfill their rights on freedom of association, freedom of expression and to participate in public affairs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2160-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="60"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2160-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women  living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to fullfill their rights on freedom of association, freedom of expression and to participate in public affairs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2160-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="9"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="156"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2160</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to: # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to fullfill their rights on freedom of association, freedom of expression and to participate in public affairs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2160-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2160-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="60"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2160-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2160-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="9"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
