<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06068-13:17</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting West African Marches</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our world is in crisis. From extreme weather to terrible hunger, the climate crisis is fuelling an increase in inequality worldwide&#x2013; threatening us all.  We are at a tipping point to prevent an irreversible climate catastrophe which will cost the lives and livelihoods of millions of people if we sit by to watch the inaction of those who pollute most.
&#x2018;Climate change for us is real. It is already here. It is causing great hunger.&#x2019;
- Lucy Njeri, Kenia
There&#x2019;s nothing equal about this crisis. Not only are the richest countries and corporations responsible for the majority of all carbon emissions, but they are also the least impacted. It&#x2019;s the poorest onthe planet &#x2013; who did least to create the climate crisis - who are hit first and worst. Droughts, floods, wildfires and hunger are getting more extreme and are forcing women, racialized and otherwise oppressed peoples from their homes and into increasingly precarious livelihoods.
We need immediate, drastic action from our governments and corporations now, and not a second later.  The billionaire boom, carbon offsetting over emission cuts, our reliance on fossil fuels and the overconsumption by the 1% must end. We must build economies that care for people and the planet, over profit.
World Climate March
To coincide with the COP26 UN Climate Summit happening in Glasgow this year, Oxfam and partners are running a virtual action around climate justice.
We only have nine years left to prevent a catastrophic global temperature rise that will wreck even morelives around the world. We have a huge opportunity to do whatit takes &#x2013;  right now in 2021.
This November, in Glasgow, world changing decisions will be made that have a huge impact on all of us. The UK will be hosting the 26th UN Climate Change Conference (COP26) attended by world leaders and nearly 200 governments.
Due todiffering vaccine roll-outs and the current Covid-19 situation, it is unlikely that large numbers of people will be able to travel to Glasgow and participate in marches, and the COP26 coalition has already decided that instead of one large march there will be decentralised actions in order to maintain social distancing.
Audience insights commissioned in 2021 show that people are excited aboutthe changes COP could bring about, and eager to take part in actions that can be shared for a multipler effect. This online campaign action would aim to mobilise people around the world to take part in the World Climate March
People would be encouraged to participate by virtually joining the climate march by leaving their name and email address on a microsite. After that they will be asked tofilm their march, and to make it make it their own by use of costumes, placards, etc. People who joined will be contacted in the lead up to COP26 with decicated actions from Oxfam and partners. This project would be run by Oxfam but rolled out with partners globally to ensure a wide range of young people&#x2019;s voices are heard. The virtual march submissions would be displayed on a dedicated website, and during the COP26 meetings the virtual march will take to the streets of Glasgow using mobile billboards.

&#x2003;
Climate marches in 10+ West African countries
Young people around the world are rising up against climate change and demanding action to help protect the planet. In Africa, the effects of climate change are already being felt &#x2013; making the voices and protests of climate activists all the more important.
The goal of the African Activists for Climate Action programme is to amplify and unite the voicesin Africa demanding that women, youth and local and indigenous communities can defend and realise their human rights and live a decent and dignified live in a healthy and sustainable environment, within the context of the climate emergency. One of the specific objectives of the programme is to amplify the voices of people who are disproportionately affected by the changing climate, and that offer solutions for a more sustainable future, such as women, youth and local and indigenous communities.
The Oxfam West Africa Platform is collaborating with Jeunes Voluntaires pour l&#x2019;Environnement to support youth in organising climate marches in the run-up to COP26 in the following countries: Senegal, Niger, Ghana, Togo, Cameroon, Rwanda, Zimbabwe, Gambia, Ivory Coast, Benin and Central African Republic.
Oxfam will support Jeunes Voluntaires pour l&#x2019;Environnement to coordinate the climate marches in the above-mentioned countries, in collaboration with Oxfam.
As such, youth in a great number of countries can raisetheir voices, while at the same time creating content for the World Climate March website and the COP26 offline activities taking place in Glasgow.
Footage from the climate marches inWest Africa will be shown at digital billboards at the COP26.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Interm&#xF3;n is since 1997 a member of the international Oxfam confederation, sharing values and a strategic plan to achieve greater global impact. Interm&#xF3;n Oxfam fights, with and for disadvantaged populations and as part of a broad global movement, with the aim of eradicating injustice and poverty, and to ensure that all human beings can fully exercise their rights and enjoy a dignified life.
Mission, Vision and Values are the components of Oxfam Interm&#xF3;n identity and guide its steps as an organisation and the ideal with which Oxfam Interm&#xF3;n  wants to live in order to obtain a fairer world with greater solidarity.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PACJA- Panafrican Climate Justice</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Africa Reg</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to a sustainable livelihood</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-08">4000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">4000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Panafrican Climate Justice Alliance</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">4000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065-PACJA-AACJ2021OXF" ref="KE-NCB-OP218051200904966065">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PACJA- Panafrican Climate Justice</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06068-13:17">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001872"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007121"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="GREEN: CJA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06068"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="PVP Climate Justice AACJ"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts promoting climate change resilient  farming systems and/or  genetic diversity.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts promoting climate change resilient  farming systems and/or  genetic diversity -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1320</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts promoting climate change resilient  farming systems and/or  genetic diversity.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-10-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
