<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05259-13:14</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DataWise</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LGBTQI organisations in Kenya, Tanzania and Uganda have limited opportunity to speak. When they do, it&apos;s vital they have the tools and resources they need to communicate effectively.Data4Change (D4C), with input from Voice Global, will select eight LGBTQI organisations from our existing and trusted partners in target countries to participate in DataWise. Trusted partners from other countries may be included as agreed by D4C and Voice.DataWise empowers grassroots organisations working at the intersection of LGBTQI, women&#x2019;sand young people&#x2019;s rights to use data, design, and storytelling to build and strengthen community,inspire action, and hold power toaccount. After participating in DataWise, organisations will: collect and use data to inform and implement innovative advocacy strategies; transfer newly acquired data skills to their own communities using D4C toolkits andresources; and communicate insights from original data and research online and offline to hyper-local, regional, and global audiences. The eight selected organisations will be split into two cohorts of four. Each cohort will complete a full set of activities thatfall under three streams: &#x201C;collect&#x201D;, &#x201C;coach&#x201D;, and &#x201C;communicate&#x201D;.Collect Eight LGBTQI organisations collaborate with D4C data coaches to identify relevant existing data (&#x201C;datamaps&#x201D;) and missing data (&#x201C;data gaps&#x201D;). Coaches work with each organisation to co-create an innovative, ethical and secure data collection strategy that generates original data about LGBTQI rights. Outputs Eight documentation packs, each including a data capacity assessment, a data maps and gaps profile, and a three-month data collection plan Eight new datasets collected and up to 40relevant open data sources Coach Up to 16 LGBTQI leaders (two per organisation)participate in D4C&#x2019;s immersive and interactive three-month DataSkills Fellowship. They acquire a foundational understanding of the data workflow (collect, clean, understand,communicate) and apply these skills to create and publish a data project of theirown. They participate in virtual &#x201C;link and learn&#x201D;events to share knowledge with their cohorts and they lead in-person Data Skills Bootcamps to transfer knowledge to their communities. They confidently andactively use data insights to create and implementnew 12-month data advocacy strategies for their organisations and create up to two data-driven advocacy outputs each. Outputs 16 LGBTQI leaders participate in three-month fellowship 16 data-driven projects and training diaries Four&#x201C;link and learn&#x201D; events80 LGBTQI community members attend Data Skills Bootcamps Eight 12-month data advocacy strategies32 data-driven advocacy outputs Communicate LGBTQI organisations share data insights with diverse audiences from hyperlocal (e.g. their own communities, families) to global (e.g. diplomats, rapporteurs, funders). With D4C data, design and storytelling coaches, each organisation co-creates a series ofonline and offline communications as part of a data-driven&#x2018;dispatch&#x2019;, and contributes to amulti-stakeholder, cross-regional and cross-theme data-driven advocacy campaign that speaks to a global audience. They participate in virtual meetings with international stakeholders, presenting original data on LGBTQI rights and reporting on their countries&#x2019; human rights records. Outputs Eight data-driven &#x2018;dispatches&#x2019; Two data-driven advocacy campaigns Eight virtual meetings with international stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DATA4CHANGE</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Data4Change was established in 2014 by co-founders Stina Backer, a journalist who has worked for the BBC, The Independent and CNN, and Dr Bronwen Robertson, a researcher and Internet Freedom Fellow. Data4Change is an LGBT-led organisation and our co-founders are women. We support a global network of more than 70 civil society organisations (CSOs) and 200 creatives across 90 countries. We identify in-country and in-region talent to work as coaches on our projects, building their capacity through pairings with industry experts and mentoring from our core team. Initially incubated by Stina and Bronwen within the UK-based nonprofit Small Media Foundation,Data4Change was created to address a number of insights we learned during a large-scale needs assessmentof CSOs in the MENA region as well as of data visualisation and data storytelling professionals (data scientists, data journalists, information designers, graphic designers, data artists and technologists) globally. The needs assessment showed that data visualisation and data storytelling professionals had the appetite and capacity to work on data-driven projects for social good but didn&#x2019;t know where to start. They wereapprehensive to work on regions or topics they lacked contextual knowledge and experience in and they lacked connections to CSOs who collect data on those topics. The needs assessment found that CSOs working on human rights fell into two groups. The first group had some qualitative and quantitative data, but were not communicating it effectively. The second group had no data experience, but were hungry to work with data as they recognised its power and potential. Both groups lacked the skills, resources, and confidence touse data effectively in their advocacy strategies. To address thesefindings, Stina and Bronwen set up Data4Change, a creative, agile, and scalable solution. We designed a prototype for a data and design sprint format to match data and storytelling professionals with CSOs and tested the first iteration in London in 2014 over a three-day in-person event. We were hooked! Since then we have iterated upon and expanded our model to become a five-day, in-person sprint. We&#x2019;ve hosted eight in-person sprints so far (London 2014, Beirut 2015, Beirut 2016, Kampala 2017, Beirut 2018, Amman 2018, Nairobi 2019, and Tallinn 2019). In 2020 we couldn&#x2019;t host an in-person sprint due to Covid-19, so we&#x2019;ve spent the past 12 months adapting our model to an online format. We&#x2019;ve received great feedback and we&#x2019;re excited to apply this approach in DataWise. In 2018, with the blessing and support of Small Media, Data4Change was registered in the UK as a non-profit company. We have since received funding from CIPESA, Small Media, and Omidyar Foundation. Data4Change also provides consultancy services for purpose-driven organisations, and is currently working with Social Media Exchange, Columbia Global Freedom of Expression, and Arab Women Organization of Jordan.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East and Centra</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-13">52726</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">52726</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DATA4CHANGE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">52726</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05259-13:14">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05259"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Global Influencing grants"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-04-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-04-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
