<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06815-02:SO</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-Triple Nexus Programming</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Somalia has three main program pillars &#x2013; Just economy and economic development, Gender just and inclusive governance and conflict-sensitive humanitarian response, resilience to climate and fragility. Integrating these programs and realising the nexus means we will contribute to Oxfam&#x2019;s global ambitions of Just Economy, Gender Justice and Climate Justice. Oxfam Somalia has also recently developed its learning strategy that will feed into the Oxfam global learning framework. Nexus programming was identified as a key learning priority in which we try to learn from within and outside Oxfam. This grant would  kickstart this analysis and documentationof Oxfam Somalia&#x2019;s nexus work and provide clear insights on the success, challenges and learnings.
Thisgrant represents exciting seed funding which will help consolidate and strengthen
pathways towards a more coordinated and coherent nexus approach in Somalia e.g. using the research to write a Nexus strategy will ensure that Oxfam Somalia has a clear operationalisation road map  across all its programs.
&#x2022; This grant will enable further testing of triple nexus approach, with an emphasis on the peace pillar, in this case inthe Ceel Afweyn district. The project aims at tackling key drivers for community conflict that have the potential to derail peace in Somalia and undermine any development gains made by strengthening the establishment of community-level peace building institutionsat grassroot level.
&#x2022; This grant will finance research and documentationwhich captures Oxfam and partners&#x2019; experiences and the nexus good practices that are already taking place. The results of this research are envisaged to; inform the development of a country-wide triple nexus operational strategy, guiding partners&#x2019; and Oxfam&#x2019;s work in Somalia, produce material for donor lobbying and make good practice evidence andlearning available to  other countries, regions and affiliates to inform organizational thinking on how to deliver the ambitions laid out in the new 10 year strategic plan and RRR Horizon Plan.
The project complements existing humanitarian-development work with added focus on gaps identified in coverage of the peace pillar. Project outputs include:

&#x2022; Establish six community-based peace building institutions (committees) responsible for the promotion of peaceful coexistence
&#x2022; Research publication on feasible triple nexus programming that are relevant to different contexts/regions within Somalia
&#x2022; At least 2 case studies produced following implementation of peace-building initiatives that complement already existing humanitarian/resilience work in target villages</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2004 Oxfam Novib set up a Liaison Office in Nairobi, Kenya in order to support the Strengthening Somali Civil Society Program, at the request of the EU. This request was based on Oxfam Novib&apos;s work in Somalia to date, but intended to be more widely directed atthe entire civil society sector and the specific context in which it is operating in a post-conflict country. The program started with consulting local organisations in Somalia and Somaliland to get a complete picture of the sectors and regions where they are active, the challenges they face and the relationship between civil society, local political structures and the private sector. A program was then developed to strengthen the institutional development of Oxfam Novib&apos;s partners and those of other Oxfams, as well as a range of new NGOs.
In the first year local consultants were trained in Somalia. They were then seconded to civil society organisations to build their capacity in financial and organisational management. Furthermore, workshops were organised on specific themes suchas human rights and the role of civil society in the Somali context. The Liaison Office is now going to support the expansion of the program, focussing on strengthening both organisation and project management, while facilitating more training in the fields of civic education, governance, human rights and women&apos;s rights, HIV and AIDS and child protection.
Over the years, the Somalia Country Office has expanded its intervention on short term humanitarian response as well as development development interventions. In 2015/2016, a decision was reached to move the Country Programme operation, which was largely in Nairobi, from Nairobi to Hargeisa. The country office has a small office in Nairobi , Kenya and large operations office in Hargeisa, Somaliland.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-19">45909</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">29916</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-01">4001</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">11992</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06815-02:SO">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002464;1002580"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007052"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Somalia HECA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06815"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Triple Nexus Programming"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resillient comm-Strength CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Crisis-affected and at-risk communities (represented through CSOs, networks and movements) have increased skills and means to prepare, prevent, mitigate and respond to crises, and to influence decisions for improved preparedness and response to crises.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9320-3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs/NGO&apos;s and/or communities strenghtened with skills and means to have power to influence local and national decisions for imporved preparedness and response to crisis&apos;.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9320-3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9320-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs/NGO&apos;s and/or communities strenghtened with skills and means to prepare, prevent, mitigate and respond to crisises.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9320-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9320-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">local and (sub) national CSO&apos;s that voice needs and concerns of crisis affected communities.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9320-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
