<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06138-04:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMME FORTE UGANDA -FF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xfam Canada is the lead applicant and only signatory partner. IPPF, Guttmacher and Action Canada are non-signatory partners. We will work with the following local implementing partners: In Uganda - RHU; CEHURD; FEMME FORTE UGANDA; and Makerere UniversitySchool ofPublic Health. In Mozambique - AMODEFA; LAMBDA; and Associacao Mocambicana de Mulheres e Apoio a Rapariga. In Sudan - GRACe; and SFPA. Partnership agreements with detailed roles and responsibilities will be signed with each project partner at inception. Oxfam Canada will: be accountable for project funds and results; ensure project implementation according to local legislation; fulfil the GACContribution Agreement; provide Canada-based staff to support project management, capacity-strengtheningand financial monitoring and reporting; and coordinate with Action Canada on Canadian public engagement. The Oxfam Country Project Teams will coordinate with local partners, governments and stakeholders and will ensure management and monitoring of the project, as well as the promotion of best environmental practices. Local partners will be the main interlocutors with government, other CSOs, communities, and participantsand will deliver many of the key project activities. There will be: a) a Project Advisory Committee to provide general oversight and strategic direction to the project, composed of Oxfam, IPPF, Guttmacher, Action Canada, and GAC; b) 3 Project Coordination Committees (1 per country), led by Oxfam and with participation of local partners, and key stakeholders; and, c) a Program Management Team including Oxfam country-based project managers and officers, as well as representatives from IPPF and Guttmacher to assess project implementation, address operational issues and provide peer support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Femme Forte Uganda</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Situation:
We are at a turning point for women, where advances in women&#x2019;s rights are at threat from rising fundamentalisms, financial crises, political turmoil and backlash against feminism. Very important gains have been made in many frameworks, policies andlaws that protect the rights of women, yet, the power dynamics that drive inequality between women and men remain in force at all levels.

Who are we:
We are a movement building entity. We love women and believe in their advancement in the economic, social and political sphere.

We exist to strengthen pathways between young and older women who aspire to meaningfully contribute to the greater women&#x2019;s movement in Uganda.

Mobilizing and equipping young women to become better leaders who change the story.
We empower women inUganda for inclusive growth through providing skills training, mentoring, sisterhood support, spiritual and financial support.

OurStrategy

Our strategy is hinged on stories of phenomenal women both in the bible and around us that we would like to model. The idea is to change mindsets by helping women imagine a better version of themselves, create environments and opportunities where they can thrive in their unique qualities, teach them to be better at what they do in leading themselves and others and eventually celebrate their accomplishment, humanity and success.


Target Audience

Our primary audience is young women between 15-35 years of age. This notwithstanding, we will carry out specialized activitiesfor those over 35 to grow mentors in them.

We run tailor made programs in the form of equip circles (learning circles) for three audiences;

15- 19 years
20- 25 years
26-35 years

Our young woman is one that aspires to lead, one with potential to lead with inadequate support to her aspirations.

How we established our Priorities

As sisters, we have been part of the women and feminist movements. We have grown here and have experienced firsthand the joys and shortcomings therein. Our Priorities are therefore established by;

&#x2022;  Our experiences. The celebrations we wish to scale up as well as the challenges unattended to that we wish Femme Forte can fill        the gap on.
&#x2022;  The needs of women from various walks of life. We reached out towomen as young as 15 and as old as the heart can imagine and        asked what sort of female space they would be inspired to be part of. The responses we got together with our experiences formed        the foundations of what we will primarily work towards achieving
Our Vision

A balanced society that provides equal opportunity to men and women.

Our Mission
Foster effective resilience to Break barriers and reach new heights for women in Uganda.
Our Values
Our values are summarized as SAFE.
OurProgram Priorities

Our programs are hinged on three strategic anchors: Communication, Organizing and Leadership. We are rolling these out through Equip circles that are learning spaces for different issues women encounter.

Body Rights
&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Integrity

&#x2022; Sexual rights andhealth
&#x2022; Gender based violence
&#x2022; Body rights - celebrating sexuality, menstruation, yoga
Financial Literacy
&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; the Wealth Agenda

&#x2022; Economic Equality
Transformative Feminist Leadership

&#x2022; Femme Forte school of
Leadership and Workcamps
&#x2022; Femme Forte Writers&#x2019; Initiative-
The journals
&#x2022; The Equip Circles
&#x2022; The moving library


STAFFING  CHART
Catalyst
Program Officer
VIEW DETAILS
Chief Builder
Program Officer
VIEW DETAILS
Connector
M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E Officer
VIEW DETAILS
Dreams Fulfiller
Finance Manager
VIEW DETAILS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM CANADA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2028-04-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-12" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-26">13905</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">13905</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Canada back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Femme Forte Uganda</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">13905</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM CANADA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06138-04:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002351"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06138"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="GAC STAND UP SRHR &amp; GBV"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal-Strength CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs representing excluded and marginalised individuals have strengthened capacity and maintain and expand their civic space.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act and to maintain and expand civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-12" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2028-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act in favour of equality and equity</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-12" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2028-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
