<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06501-02:NG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Remediation in the Extratv. Ind.(CISLAC)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil Society Legislative Advocacy Centre (CISLAC) is a non-governmental, non-profit, advocacy, information sharing, research, and capacity building organisation. Its mission is to strengthen the link between civil society and the legislature through advocacy andcapacity building for civil society groups and policy makers on legislative processes and governance issues. CISLAC was integrated as a corporate body (CAC/IT/NO22738) with the Nigeria#s Corporate Affairs Commission (CAC) on the 28th December 2006. Prior to this incorporation, however, CISLAC had actively been engaged in legislative advocacy work since 2005. The organisation is also compliantwith the Anti-Money Laundering Act 2007. The Organisation reports to SCUML, any transaction that is above One thousand dollars, detailing the payee, purpose and the other KYC (Know Your Customer) requirements. This is done on a weekly or monthly basis depending on the volume of transactions and to ensure appropriate compliance with anti-money laundering laws. NPC Certified CISLAC is registered organisation under the National Planning Commission.
ECOSOC Status In recognition of its broad perspective the CISLAC was granted an ECOSOC status by the United
Nations in 2011 giving it the mandate and the instrumentality of the UN. EFCC Anti-Money Laundary Compliance
CISLAC is duly registered in accordance with the provisions of Section 5(1) (a) of the Money Laundering (Prohibition) Act, 2011 of the Economic and Financial Crime Commission (EFCC). CISLAC/TI Partnership CISLAC is the National Chapter of Transparency International (TI). Also, CISLAC is registered organisation under the National Planning Commission. As indicated above, the organisationemerged from the need to address the gaps in legislative advocacywork of civil society and government access to civil society groups. CISLAC#s engagement with Federal Ministries, National and State Assemblies, Local Government Administrations, private sector interests, and non-government organisations, has opened a window through which the public and policy officials can interact and collaborate.

Specifically on this project, With a population of over 200 million people and  an annual budget of 7-8 trillion with over 80%dependence on the extractive industry which is plagued with lack of transparency, accountability and has left the sector vulnerableto a lot of ill dealings and illicit financial transactions resulting in a huge loss of revenues for the Nigerian government. The persistent loss of extractive resources has left the country to this meager budget over time resulting in underdevelopment of infrastructure and basic social needs for the citizens. This lack of transparency, compounded with weak governance and rule of law allow oil and gas companies, as wellas other major players in the sector operate in an unaccountable manner, abuse human rights, partake in illicit financial flows and exploit the fragility phenomenon in many oil producing communities. This project focuses on raising awareness on the socialand economic costs, associated with the opacity in the Nigerian extractives sector while also advocating for improved governance in the sector to ensure that firms operate in human rights and conflict sensitive manner.

Mining in Nigeria startedover 2,400 years ago, but only became organized in 1903 following the commissioning of the minerals surveys of the Southern and Northern protectorates. Before the discovery of oil and gas in 1956, the Solid Minerals sector served as one of the major sources offoreign exchange earning alongside agriculture for which Nigeria is reputed to be greatly endowed with. Ever since, the governance of the Nigerian extractive industry has been opaque. The industry lacked transparency, accountability, competition and corporate governance. For instance, flow of information on company payments and government receipts, availability of data on investments flow, processes and opportunities remain the exclusive preserve of only a few.

There was general ignorance about the quantities of resources extracted and traded, as well as, the implications for revenues among citizens. The consequences to the economy are huge losses of revenues due to corruption, fraud and impunityin the administration of the sector. This contributed toNigeria being described as a country enmeshed in #poverty in the midst of plenty# (largely referred to in the Extractives Industry Transparency Initiative as Resource Curse).
The negative consequences on national development were evident in the areas ofcollapse of social infrastructure, poor access to health care, education, jobs, housing, transportation, security and basic amenities for the citizens. Nigeria#s mismanagement of her revenues from natural resources also led to series of communal conflicts, ethnic militia, insurgency and mass exodus of the citizens in search of better opportunities abroad.
In response to this challenge, the Nigerian government signed up to implement the Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative Initiative (EITI) in 2003 and establishedthe Nigeria EITI (NEITI) in 2004. In 2007, Nigerian government institutionalized the implementation of EITI in-country with legislation, the NEITI Act of 2007.
The decision of the Federal Government of Nigeria to sign up to implement the Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative (EITI) was to enthrone transparency and accountability in the governance of the sector. The expectation was that revenues from oil, gas, and mining should translate to improved quality of life for the citizens,through improved access to good roads, health care, education, housing, social security etc.
In pursuance of this principle, the NEITI, has in line with its mandate, appointed independent auditors to reconcile payments made by companies against governmentreceipts. Since implementation began, NEITI has conducted 9 cycles of industry audits inthe Oil &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Gas (1999-2004; 2005; 2006-2008; 2009-2011, 2012 and 2013, 2014, 2015, 2016) and 7 in the Solid Minerals sector (2007-2010; 2011, 2012 and 2013, 2014, 2015,2016). As expected, efforts are made to widely disseminate these reports, Oxfam and partners have played a leading role in simplifying and providing a CSO perspective of the Reports, analyzing them and disseminating as widely as possible, including atthesubnational levels.
The Audit reports over the years (1999 to 2016) threw up recurring findings. These include:huge revenue losses are resulting from lapses andunder assessments/underpayments; questionable interpretation of MoUs and legal agreementsin thecomputation of taxes and royalty; absence of metering facilities for measurement of crude; poor record keepingby relevant Institutions. A major gap in the NEITI process was the lack of implementation of recommendations from the audit reports.Thishas resulted in the recurrence of the same recommendations in about 14 years of implementation and slowed down reforms in the sector, making the much desired transparency and accountability in the sector and deprived citizens of the needed provisionof development; social services and enhanced welfare possible from the efficient utilization of resources form the sector.
Consequently, in 2015, Oxfam in collaboration with our partners Civil Society Legislative Advocacy Centre (CISLAC), the NEITI secretariat andmultiple stakeholders commenced a Campaign on Remediation. The aim was to pressure government to undertake remedial action by implementing therecommendations from all previous NEITI audit reports. The remedial issues were streamlined, reducedto campaignformat, a campaign strategy was developed and using a variety of tools, some activities were carried out, including a flagship radio programme, Media Interactions, social media messaging, direct engagement of major stakeholders. These resulted in eliciting promises form the then leading candidates in the elections and subsequent implementation of some remedial actions in the forms of reforms of the oil and gas sector. These include: the on-going restructuring of the national oil company, Nigeria NationalPetroleum Corporation (NNPC); the cancellations of the oil swap/off shore processing arrangement OPA, creation of the Treasury Single Account (TSA) replacement of oil subsidy with price modulation policy and a commitment to review of Nigeria#s JointVenture Agreements, existing Oil Contracts. Others include the implementation of an open, transparent and competitive process for the award of licenses and contracts in the sector, a commitment to pursuing Contract Transparency and Beneficial Ownership as a matterofpolicy by the NEITI, as well as, the commitment to the passage of the Petroleum Industry Bill.
The EITI process in Nigeria collects and publishes information about Nigeria#s extractiveindustry and disbursement of revenue. The annualOil andGas Audit,SolidMinerals Audit and Fiscal Allocation and Statutory Disbursement Audit provide data and information about the management and utilization of extractive revenue.

The audit makes various recommendation and identifies those responsible forimplementing remediation. To ensure that citizens benefits from the utilization of revenuederived from the sector, there has to be mechanism to engage various segment of the public to hold government accountable and engage them in informed debate. Empowering the citizenswith information from the audit will help them know how much government receives from the sector, how it is distributed and allocated; and empower them to demand better utilization for improved service delivery andsustainable development.

The EITI standards is a tool for continuous improvement of audit and monitoring the extractive sector, provision of data and information; and engagement of stakeholders.
Overall Objective.
In the light of the above and in consideration ofthe progress made sofar,the overall objective of the proposed intervention is to further strengthen the implementation of the NEITIby promoting remediation and incremental incorporation of new EITI Standards to drive the on-going reforms in the extractive industry in Nigeria.

Specific Objectives

The Specific objectives therefore include:
a) Strengthenthe capacity of the legislature to debate NEITI Reports in plenary and use the information and data for effective monitoring and oversight of the extractive industry in Nigeria.
b) Broaden citizens# participation in the implementation of NEITI and the OGP process.
c) Advocate for the expansion of the boundaries of EITI implementation to include the new standards on beneficial ownership and contract transparency.
d) Trackandmonitor sector reform performance and impacts on welfare of the citizens especially at community level.
e) Promote the implementation of theUnited Nations Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights through the implementation of the National ActionPlan of the same which currently seats with the National Human Rights Commission with support from Oxfam and partners.

Proposed Intervention
Series ofactivities have been proposed to be implemented by Oxfam, CISLAC and in collaboration withNEITIand other stakeholders, see below for the outlined activities;

1. Induction Program for relevant Committees of the NASS: This will be for ice-breaking, confidence building and orientation for the members. With the Turnover in the NASS after the 2019 elections and the composition of a new NSWG, thisprogram will provide a platform for continuous engagement in the next years. Issues relating to remediation, Petroleum Industry Bill (PIB), EITI standards and expected areas of collaboration wouldbe mutually agreed upon for subsequent follow up

2. Stakeholder Interface on Metering: As a remedial issue which has remained elusive with divergent opinion as to its workability and cost and considering its strategic place in the upstream, weproposesan interface sessionbringing together the relevant stakeholders on the issue. These include the Nigerian Academy of Science, Departent of Petroleum Resources DPR, OPTS, CSO, MEDIA, NEITI, Development Partners, Legislators and the office responsible for weights and measure. In addition, this interface provides a platform for robust discussions that can result in practical recommendations to the government

3. Workshop on OpenData and Advocacy: In broadening citizen#s participation in the NEITIprocess and to strengthen the capacities of both CSOs and the media in the use of open data for advocacy, a workshop is proposed. This will be in the form of a Train-the-trainer method so that trainees can conduct step-downs in their respective zones. Trainees will be carefully selected and made committed to low-coat step-downs in a creative way.

4. Sector Score Card: Weare proposing a periodic Public enlightenment event to present an impact assessment of the reforms on the lives of Nigerians as it relates to remediation.The absence of a monitoring and evaluation component of the reforms makes tracking and recording of the progress of change difficult. Considering that this administration has 3 years left, a quarterly session is proposed. The reforms will bemeasured around its reflection of NEITI#s remedial issues, the performance of Institutions, improvements in processes, the enactment and effectiveness of legislations, and policies such as the Treasury Single Account, Direct Purchase:Direct Sale, DomesticCrude Allocation, NNPCRestructuring, PIB, etc. The essence is not just to measure change or progress but demonstrate how this is impacting lives. Representative of the Relevant MDAs will be engaged and interactive sessions proposed tofollow. Alternatively, an independent personcan evaluate and present while the MDA responds and sheds light.

5. Policy Dialogue Series: To project EITI standards that depict international best practices and contribute to a fundamental change on how the sector is governed, a #Dialogue Series# isbeing proposed that will focus on 2 key remedial issues gaining international ascendancy and one with domestic peculiarity. Example is Contract Transparency, Beneficial Ownership and Metering. The Latter couldbuild on the interface session and the proposed research by the Nigerian Academy of Science with support from NEITI. This can be adjusted to address any issue that will emerge and require public discourse. The aim is to provide concrete recommendations on how Nigeria can incorporate these recommendations into her extractivegovernance framework.

6. Multi-Stakeholder consultation on Extractive Transparency of the Open Governance Partnership (OGP): This proposes to bring together stakeholders to appraise the OGP, learn lessons andfurther strategieson implementing the National Action Plan especially the Extractive Transparency component.

7. CSO/Non- State-Actors Consultation on the OGP: We propose to hold additional consultations among CSOs and other non-stateactors to deliberate on the OGP. Having understood the provisions in principle, a CSO position would be helpful as representatives of the citizens. Participants would be drawn largely from among groups from the multi-stakeholder consultations.The expected outcome of the meeting is to agree on the possibility of preparing a unanimously adopted memo to the federal executive council (FEC) to be used for advocacy to the presidency and the milestone and gaps of the process.

8. Advocacy meeting with National Assembly relevant Committees:We propose an advocacy meeting with the relevant NASS Committees to pressure them to intensify oversight on open contracting and information sharing in the sector. Especially by NNPC in terms financial disclosure and contract transparency.

9. CampaignMaterials: We propose the use of information education and communication IEC materialsas a medium for information dissemination, agenda setting and outreach to stakeholders and the general public. Outcomes of sessionsand monitoring processes would be documented and shared through this medium.

10. Dissemination of NEITI Audit Report 2016: We willcarry out a CSO-led dissemination of findings contained in the NEITI Audit Report. This will complement the NEITIdissemination process, as wellas, ensure that citizens are empowered to understand and further engage with the findings and especially highlight remedial issues that would emanate from it.

11. Radio program (Open Audit): We plan to sustain this program as a flagship for public engagement.It will contribute to the overall project as a media outreach component. It will be used for tracking remedial actions, and reform performance, the PIB Process and Updates and generate public debates on the impacts of these processes on citizens.There isneed toincreasethe airtime and re-design the programme to incorporate a Social Media component to drive the campaign and get citizens engaged.

12. Documentation: Proper documentation is needed to keep track ofthe publications and other information materialsassociated with the project. This will contribute to the existing literature and deepen knowledge and research in the sector, especially from a CSO perspective. This is because knowledge remains a major gap for citizens# engagement with extractive sector.

13.National colloquium on Business and Human Rights with the private sector and government with community members on the impact of business activities at community level towards promoting peaceful co-existence between companies and host communities.

Expected Outcomes
a) Sustained media engagements with the National Assembly on disclosing beneficial ownership, remediation issues, tax compliance, and illicit financial flows. This will reduce about N36.57 trillionnaira that leaks out of Nigeria which makesabout 30.5% of the total revenue lost from Africa
b) Empowered constituencies campaigning on beneficial ownership, tax compliance, remediation, and illicit financial flows.
c) Strengthened CSOs capacity to engage and pressure the National Assembly to publicly disclose commitment towards a robust understanding and public engagement on the OGP process.
d) Ensure people centered reforms by monitoring the performance and impacts of sector reforms on the welfare of citizens especially at community level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CISLAC</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Civil Society Legislative Advocacy Centre (CISLAC) was set up in 2005 to strengthen the link between civil society and the Nigerian legislature. It was officially registered in 2006. Its priority areas are anti-corruption, fiscal responsibility, public procurement, the Nigerian Extractives Industries Transparency Initiative (NEITI) Act and budget tracking. Its main intervention areas are lobby, advocacy, research and capacity building of civil society organisations, legislators and media. CISLAC has been very instrumental in passing the NEITI Act in 2007 and monitoring and assisting the Nigerian government in its implementation.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-22">111031</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-22">27802</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-22">10963</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">111031</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CISLAC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">1259</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-02-01">2115</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-01">3875</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">2531</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">2542</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">4425</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-01">1816</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-08-01">2748</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">2775</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">2483</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-01">1086</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">145</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">2488</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-01">753</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">1173</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-01">535</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">1972</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">4040</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">111031</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06501-02:NG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000168" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002215"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007155"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Nigeria (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06501"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Remediation in the Extractives Industry"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to expose and influence financial and fiscal policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to expose and influence financial and fiscal policies -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-08-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="29"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to expose and influence financial and fiscal policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-08-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="6"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
