<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06140-02:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-Coordination and Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Given the commitment of Oxfam US and the Oxfam Regional Platform in Asia to promote justice in extractive sectors in Asia; and following the Oxfam 2020 modality, this regional project is to demonstrate the funding commitment from OUS to the OI Regional Platform in Asia  with the support of ONL as an Executive Agency to help manage this project. This project main objective is to enable the Regional EI Program Coordinator to fulfil his roles to coordinate the implementation of country and regional partner grant proposals inorder to deliver program outcomes and impacts. It will also enable him to contribute to the design of the new OI Global EI Program Strategic Plan taking into account the program experiences, the Asia#s context and priorities as guided by One Oxfam Regional Strategy Framework for Asia.



This project will complement the country based and regional partner based projects by fostering regional networks, learning and exchanges within existing regional platforms related to indigenous people rights, gender, and revenue transparency that would improve capacity of staff Oxfam country offices and NGO partners in Cambodia, Vietnam, Myanmar, Timore Lester, Philippine and  Indonesia while country investment of the program remains with 2 countries including Cambodia and Vietnam.  In addition, this project will strengthen its alignment with the OI Regional Strategy Framework by taking into account the changing context, opportunities, and challenges where ownership and leadership of the program have been transferred to the OI Regional Platform. This project will enable the regional EI program coordinator to develop, manage and oversee EI related projects contracted by OUS with partners such as Oxfam in Cambodia; Oxfam in Vietnam; AIPP in Thailand;and NTFP-EP in the Philippines.


 In addition under this project, we take the following approaches to integrate gender into the project interventions where the regional EI program coordinator will have the roles to play:
-       Gender and power analysis: This project will enable the regional EI program coordinator to offer technical advices and support to country projects in Cambodia and Vietnam and our regional partners namely NTFP-EP and AIPP to socializeapproaches of gender impact assessments and to promote better understanding of gender and power analysis with their local partners and network members.
-       Collection and analysis of sex and age disaggregated data: This project will enable the regional EI coordinator to offer technical supports and oversights to plan for gender impact assessment pilot in Cambodia
-       Gender capacity needs: This project will enable Oxfam to be better informed by grant partners about gender capacity needs through the Regional Women in Action on Mining inAsia Skillshare workshops. Identifications of gender capacity will eventually be turned into a project proposal for Oxfam#s funding.

-       Oxfam funds a Women#s Rights Organization: This project enables the regional EI program coordinator to offer coordination and technical oversights to NTFP-EP and Dhaatri who have received funding support from Oxfam to develop capacity of Women Human Right Defenders through the regional network called Women in Action on Mining in Asia (WAMA).
-       Individual Women#s and men#s consciousness. This project enables the regional EI program coordinator to help develop knowledge, skills and interests of Oxfam Country staff, partners and Oxfam affiliates to undertake GIA, and to integrate gender into country project implementations.
-       Individual Women#s access to resources: This project will enable the regional EI program coordinator to offer technical support in planning and review to enhance women voice at local, country and regional levels; and to strengthenwomen roles in controlling and access natural resources.
-       Social and cultural norms and exclusionary practices: The project will enable the regional EI coordinator to facilitate discussions with AIPP, a regional partner, on how to develop closer linkage between gender and FPIC.

This project will enable the EI regional program coordinator to undertake his roles and annual performance objectives (2019-2020) as below:

- To strengthen the capacity of Oxfam staff and partners to understand abouttools, tactics, approaches, lessons learnedand experiences for planning to engage and advocacy with private sector;
- To enable regional partner(s) to develop and implement project proposals that will increase IPs and women voice at regional and international forum; and to promote the use of tools relatedto social responsibility (ethic, labor, FPIC, gender)  with selected mining companies in Asia;
- To explore funding raising opportunities  through the  development of project concept(s) to strengthenIP rights and gender in EI sector in the region;
- To provide oversights and technical supports to  Oxfam in Cambodia, Oxfam in Vietnam and regional partners (AIPP,NTFP-EP and other)  to ensure compliance, effectiveness and impacts of projects that willbe funded by OUS#s restricted and restricted funding (see table below);
- To work with Oxfam in Cambodia in particular, Gender Advisors of relevant affiliates and partners to plan and implement GIA pilot that results into Gender Impact Assessment Reportto be shared with other stakeholders;
- To develop project concepts to proposition howto engage with Chines mining companies and stakeholders in discussion with OUS, and OHK;
- To develop a Policy Brief and Influencing Strategy  on EI that is in line with Oxfam/ASEAN influencing strategies with the coordination by Oxfam ASEAN Advocacy Coordinator;
- To offer technical support to Oxfam Cambodia and Vietnam to develop and implement projects effectively;
- To contribute to the OIled regional platform#s discussion and meetings and structures (NRM Regional Program Cluster); and to foster linkages and contributions to other regional programs; country programs; and with OI Global EI Program in order to strengthen One-Oxfam Approach and Oxfam#s world-wide influencing agenda;
- To promote gender integration into grant project proposals and coordinate implementation of gender related project interventions with regional partners namely NTFP-EP and AIPPs; and
- To support communications, learning and exchanges through documentations of lessons learned and impact stories of program interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994.  Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education forall, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies.  Oxfam established this country office to support local organizations and projects.  Through this local office Oxfam Novib directly contributes towards this project#s implementation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-15" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-15" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="32110" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-13">7025</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-13">87096</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-13">9194</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-01">7025</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">57841</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">7093</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">8456</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-01">13706</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-06-01">5641</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-01">8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">3544</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06140-02:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001972"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06140"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Coordination for Mekong Regional EI Prog"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-03-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-03-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
