<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06353-04:TZ</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TZ AFO_Bahari HUB, Ukombozi wa Wanawake</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bahari HUB Yetu, Ukombozi wa Wanawake project aims to transform women&apos;s challenges through empowerment in their fisheries related activities to overcome the challenges based on technical, knowledge, gender, socio-cultural and religious barriers through establishment of Bahari Hub. We are developing Bahari hub to model local innovations for fisheries practices to generate revenue and close thedisparities faced by women. In this hub we will conduct ocean culture training to fisher women involving artists,record 1 documentary with 4 series videos in four coastal communities for breaking the silence on social cultural and religious barriers, organize forthe first ever fisher women and conduct an art campaign of painting 40 fishing boats with coastal Swahili sayings will be conductedaddressing the sociocultural, religious barrier and negative concepts of feminism to enhance participation and collaboration between men and women in fisheries

The grant applied to AFO will support the implementation of Bahari HUB Yetu, Ukombozi wa Wanawake project. This project through the hub will create artifacts from oceans&#x2019; unseen treasures that inspires and promote unification; The Innovation hub will create an arts for change campaign that will mark the 40 boats artistically by written phrases that encourages participation of women in fisheries activities, drawn paintings by well trained articulated artists from the established women fishers groups showcasing the unwanted social norms in fisheries that widen the gender gap, hinder freedom and participation of women in fisheries activities.

The activities that will be implemented in this project include a baseline and endline Survey will be conducted to identify the socio-cultural and religious barriers alongside feminism concepts and its impacts on fully participation of women in fisheries prior and after the project implementation in Kilwa, Mafia, Paje-Zanzibar and Msasani fishing community members, For Oceanculture training - 4 artists will be recruited to conduct two trainings of which at least 48 women (12 from each coastal community women group) will be trained on painting and making of hand made artifacts from ocean related materials and swimming skills. Video documentary- 1 documentary with 4 series videoswill be produced from the selected four coastal communities to break the silence on socio-cultural and religious barriers holding women back from fully participating in fishing activities. For fisher women festival- More than 400 participants (men and women) will be engaged during the Fisher Women Festival aiming at strengthening freedom of expression and visibility of the fisher women, the festival will run in the 4 selected coastal communities where recorded video documentarywill be screened publicly tostimulate conversations, followed by &#x201C;fish cook competition&#x201D; where the women will compete on how innovatively they can use own cultural recipes to make and garnish food/fish dishes (using ocean arts), and winners will be awarded; this will be a motivationfor these women to feel recognized and appreciated</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua Farm Organization Arts and Culture for Development (A</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua-farms organization is a non-governmental organization that is operating in Tanzania. It was founded in July 2017 by 13 young and vibrant scientists with the aim of replenishing livelihood of the coastal and lacustrine communities through the sustainable use of aquatic resources as far as culture, heritage as well as fisheries and aquaculture. Aqua-Farms works with women and youth as our key stakeholders of change in the community.
Aquatic Resources Education Program at Dar es Salaam, Tanzania in promoting the utilization of aquatic resources through carrying out of trainings to youth in secondary school on aquatic resources biological and economic potentiality Sept 2017 to May 2019

Quarry life Award Project Implementation Project funded by TwigaCement. (Integrated. Aquaculture Project), Project title; Community Based economization of rehabilitated fish ponds at Wazo Hill Quarry
Training on Feed formulation and nutrition As Aquaculture is growing fish feed is a growing challenge that has made many farmers to fail in there venture, by observing this potential AFO in collaboration with Green Aquaculture hosted a training May 2018 at American Corner- Tanzania National Library, where 30 fish farmers and 10 Newbies we trained on Fish feed and nutrition.

Trainings of integrated aquaculture Through the community based economization of Wazo hill Quarry, We have trained 400+ interested participants in different time through 2018, through this we have been able to train military officers, Industrial workers, women community groups around Tegeta- Kinondoni, and University Students
Demonstration farm at Wazo Hill Quarry A temporary demonstrational integrated fish farm was constructed with support from Tanzania Portland Cement Company TPCC, Where the ponds are stocked with tilapia and catfish, alongside associated with a poultry farm and horticulture garden planted with Amaranthas, Pumpkins and Chinese cabbages.

AFO- envisions to replenish aquatic resources with community-based conservation and sustainable aquaculture. In the context of  this project Hapo Zamani za Kale, the project will reach coastal communities including Zanzibar, Bagamoyo and Tanga where fishing is a prominent source of income.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-24">24634</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-09-01">12511</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-12-01">1232</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">6391</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua Farm Organization Arts and Culture for Development (A</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">4500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua Farm Organization Arts and Culture for Development (A</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">6391</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">4500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06353-04:TZ">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001988"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06353"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice2 Innovate and Learn Tanzania"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal-Strength CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs representing excluded and marginalised individuals have strengthened capacity and maintain and expand their civic space.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act and to maintain and expand civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act in favour of equality and equity</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
