<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06612-02:NL</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HO-Movements &amp; Alliances Funds The Hague</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flexible funding mechanisms
Introduction
Through the programme, the consortium and partners will devise agile and adaptive influencingstrategies to respond to unexpected changes, events and opportunities. Lessons learned show thatfinance and administrative procedures are often too inflexible to respond quickly to opportunities,especially with (in)formal groups, so the consortium will reserve funds for responding to eventsoutside of the planned programme scope. Three flexible funds will be available forcapacitydevelopment and influencing. These funds aim to enable partners to respond to uniquecircumstances when existing commitments are too limited to capitalize on them.
1) Alliance Fund
Given the uncertain contexts in which the programme operates, andthe unpredictability of change
processes, the Alliance Fund enables flexible responses to sudden opportunities for influence &#x2013;
when, with a quick injection of support, we can accelerate action and achieve a quick win or pave
the way for bigger gains inthe future. Activists and organizations canamplify their influence by working together. While FAIR for ALL brings organizations together in a worldwide influencing network, the Alliance Fund aims to further
stimulate and facilitate collaboration amongallies in networks broader than FAIR for ALL. It will
enable responses to chance circumstances and unique influencing opportunities with the possibility
for catalytic change if groups canwork together. For example, when former top international
football player George Weah was elected president in Liberia, civil society in the country worked
with international organizations and alliances such as the Land Rights Now Alliance to successfully
advocate for community land rights. The Alliance Fund will be an online and open fund, marketed through the consortium and partners&#x2019;networks. Applications will be assessed as they are submitted, according to standards of quality,
accountability, reporting and the potential for impact.
Almost EUR 2m will be available to support alliances. On average we will support about seven
alliances per year to substantially improve their ability to influence, for example by:
&#xF0B7; Coming together to jointly mobilize and organize their constituencies and audiences offline and
online;
&#xF0B7; Bring in women&#x2019;s movements and voices to allow for increased representation and ownership;
&#xF0B7;Strengthening the network and complementarity of roles by creating opportunities for new or
innovative approaches;
&#xF0B7; Linking national alliances to global networks and platforms to leverage external support for
their own asks and
&#xF0B7; Providing seed money to support the activation of (new) alliances on emerging issues.
2) Movement Building Fund
Social movements are increasingly a way for communitiesandcitizens to voice concerns abouttheir rights, welfare and wellbeing by engaging in collective action and public protest. In recentyears the reach of representative movements and their speed of development has increasedgreatly through the worldwide web and social media. Movements bring together a critical mass of
voices to achieve transformative systems change.The movements we aim to support are grassroots, independent and mostly not formally registeredas organizations. They typically have many &#x2018;leaders&#x2019;and are based on individual connections and
networks rather than a formal structure. This expresses itself in decentralized fundraising and spending for autonomously determined purposes. As such activities to be supported are often adhoc, short-termand based on voluntarism, andrequire relatively small amounts of money. They are undertaken by individuals rather than organizations with financial or administrative structures.
Flexibly supporting movements while ensuring financial accountability requires innovation in systems to comply with rules and regulations. Such movements do not usually look for &#x2018;calls for proposals&#x2019; &#x2013; instead they make activities happen by collecting online and offline donations. Funding such loosely coordinated, decentralizedactivities by people who independently drive their
own agenda requires a level of risk taking. We will implement our flexible administrative procedures for movements with the utmostcare. A Movement Building Fund of EUR 600,000 will be made available.
Given the local nature of movements and how they operate, funds will be transferred in ways that best suit each particular movement, such as mobile money, cash, wire transfer, Western Union or other types of cash transfer, or crowdfunding linked to mobilemoney.
The Movement Building Fund is innovative for the consortium, and we anticipate a phased
implementation. In Year 1 the framework and criteria will be defined, with an accountability
mechanism and clarity on acceptable financial risk. In Year 2 we anticipate testing the fund by
creating dedicated periods for evaluation of various funding mechanisms. From year 3 the fund will
be fully operational.
3) Rapid-Response Fund for Human Rights Defenders
Influencing, especially in a shrinking civic space, isrisky for activists. People who speak truth to
power expose themselves to intimidation, threats, legal actions and attacks that sadly sometimes
lead to loss of life. Those in power sometimes use crisis situations to further restrict civic space
and civil liberties, and limit space for dissent and opposition. Many restrictions imposed in
response to the Covid-19 pandemic will most likely not be lifted when the pandemic abides.
We will reserve around EUR 150,000 for protecting activists and organizations that speak out. This
flexible fund will be available to partners and activists in their networks to support them in the
broadest sense when they are under attack. This could range from physical protection to digital
security, travel expenses, legalfees and psycho-social support for their families. The fund will
enable immediate support, before other protective mechanismsfor human rights defenders &#x2013;
which require more time-consuming approval processes &#x2013; can kick into action.
When facing threats, immediate action is paramount. The fund can retrospectively cover
unplanned protection and security expenses after they have been incurred &#x2013; that is, requiring no
prior application process. The flexible fund is our commitment to stand with our partners and
activists in their networks. In our experience, such funds are not often called on, which is why the
size of the fund is limited &#x2013; it is primarily important that activists and organizations know they
have a safety mechanism to fall back onif needed.
Accountability will take into account that expenses will mainly be activity-based. As such, &#x2018;receipts when realistically available&#x2019; and records such as photos of outputs will be used for accountability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib was founded in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994.  Oxfam Novib is member of the Oxfam International confederation. Working together in the confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education for all, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies.  Oxfam Novib&apos;s main office is based in The Netherlands, it supports the work of a network of local offices, the implementation of global projects, fundraising, campaigning and advocacy.  Oxfam Novib&#x92;s the Hague office contributes towards this project&#x92;s implementation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-26">4800</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-01">4800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D Lobby&amp;Advocacy</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-01">4800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004319" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06612-02:NL">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001871"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007131"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="FAIR: FVCaFS"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06612"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Fair for All Movements&amp;Alliances Funds"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civ Space-Strenght CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society actors transformed and strengthened,</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO actors that build trust and work in inclusive way in coalitions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO that improved their acccess to flexible resources to actively address, reclaim and navigate civic space offline and online, involving and considering esp. marginalized groups</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs that strengthened the links with their constituencies due to changed ways of working</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved risk strategies and improves support when a civic space crisis occurs</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-4" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with increased women and youth in leadership positions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">informal movements/individuals with access to flexible resources to address, reclaim and navigate civic space offline and/or online</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
