<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06893-02:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-WASH Support to DRC Refugees</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will provide adequate and safe water supply, promote hygiene practices, provide appropriate sanitation facilities, reduce environmental health risks and ensure conditions that allow approximately 338,881  refugees and hosting populations in Kyaka II,Rwamwanja and Kyangwali to live with good health, dignity, comfort and safety.

Average water supply across the three settlements of Kyaka II, Rwamwanja and Kyangwali is currently at 13.1 l/p/d with Rwamwanja posting 14.6 l/p/d, followed by Kyaka II at 13.9 l/p/dand then Kyangwali at 10.9 l/p/d; with water trucking constituting 0.9% of the water supply in Kyaka II, 1% in Kyangwali and 0.1% in Rwamwanja respectively (UNHCR Gap Matrix, October 2021). One of the WASH sector key strategic priorities is to eliminate water trucking which is costly and unreliable. Upgrade and development of existing water sources by both operational and implementing partners will present additional challenges related to cost of operation and maintenance. On average, only 11.3% of piped water supplied isby solar energy,10.7% from grid power and 78% is by fuel driven pumping systems, making cost of water production very high. Low groundwater potential in Kyaka and Rwamwanja is a bottleneck to water provision. Currently, most of the water systems are being manageddirectly by UNHCR and/through partners. Efforts are underway to set up sustainable management models for operation and maintenance (O&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;M) with gradual transitioning to a utility approach, through integration with existing government systems. Catchment degradation remains a major bottleneck and a risk to sustainable groundwater recharge and supplies.  All interventions planned under this objective, target an increase in per capita access to water supply from 13.1 l/p/d to 17 l/p/d, which is close to the UNHCR water supply standard of 20 l/p/d.

Crude household Latrine coverage across the three settlements averages 65%, which is still far below theUNHCR standard of 85% and Ugandan National standard of 100%; with Kyaka II at 66%, Kyangwali at 59% and Rwamwanja at 79% (Settlement Sanitation Matrices, October 2021). Efforts will continue to scale up the dome-shaped slab production and increase latrine construction to achieve 75% latrine coverage, on average. Majority of the refugees who are women and children (over 80%) still face numerous barriers to access and inclusion in WASH programming. Latrine construction at household level cannot be effectively completed given the numerous child and women headed households and PSNs, needing direct assistance to construct latrines of acceptable structural strength.

At institutional level, latrine access levels are generally low. Faecal sludge management remains a critical gap with only one treatment facility in Kyaka II and none in Rwamwanja and Kyangwali refugee settlements and in all the settlement hosting districts. Costs of hiring cesspool emptiers continue to be exorbitant and unsustainable, as faecal sludge has to be extracted using gulpers on a small scale and major institutional desludging relay on transporting sludge across districts for disposal. Despite recognisable efforts by the operation, WASH NFI distribution, soap, water storage containers, and menstrual hygiene management (MHM) materials is still below recommended Sphere minimum standards owing to budgetary limitations. In most institutions, MHM spaces are either unavailable, lacking in hygiene supplies like soap and water, or not safe/private for girls to use.

Solid waste management especially in markets, trading centres and other public places, still remain a challenge with the need to strengthen and equip the solid waste management committees/voluntary groups for improved efficiency and effectiveness in execution of their roles. Community based structures such as VHTs need to be strengthened to step up the community mobilization interventions for improved sanitation and hygiene at household level. All interventions planned under this objective, target an increase in household latrine coverage from 65% to at least 80%.

Water supply approaches will look at onboarding community structures through the transition process by strengthening thewater supply and sanitation board (WSSB), water user committees, handpumps mechanics association. Our Sanitation and Hygiene Promotion will be approached through creating livelihood opportunities via sanitation marketing, barrier analysis and child centered hygiene promotion. Crosscutting issues such as natural resource use and water source conflicts, peaceful coexistence, inclusion and gender will be mainstreamed through the WASH interventions as well as ensuring there is responsible environment and natural resource management through Water Source Protection Plans and ongoing Monitoring. Learning will be undertaken through research, testing innovative approaches such as Lamella clarifier, low-cost faecal sludge treatment systems, Prepaid Water Dispensing, Vermi compositing to degrade solid waste). Linkages and working with local partners and community engagement will be critical in WASH service provision.

The program output looks at ensuring refugee and host settlements have access to adequate and safe water, adequate and appropriate sanitary facilities along with increased promotion of good hygiene practices thereby improving lives by limiting the spread of illness and disease.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994.  Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education forall, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies.  Oxfam established this country office to support local organizations and projects.  Through this local office Oxfam Novib directly contributes towards this project&#x92;s implementation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-22">358806</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">41596</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-01">-41596</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRA Programme Expenditures Country Offic</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-01">80037</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR - UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-03-01">74395</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR - UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-01">67171</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR - UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">137202</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR - UN ORGANISATIONS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-01-01">41596</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-02-01">-41596</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06893-02:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002538"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06893"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="WASH Support to DRC Refugees 2022"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="166720"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="177048"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="166720"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-01-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="177048"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
