<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06549-08:PS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jerusalem center for women  JCW</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results in environmental sustainability, inclusion and innovation

JCW, after implementing the bread recycling initiative in another region in the year of 2021, believes that this initiative has the potential to be duplicated in Jericho as there is a large numberof facilities who are willing to cooperate and provide our teams with all excess bread in the area. The project contributes to environmental sustainability and also can be considered a solution to decreasing the amounts of excess bread from restaurants, schools, households or even bread left on the streets which on its part contributes to minimizing the negative impact rotten bread may cause animals and using the excess bread to feed cattle by providing farmers with the recycled bread.

Also, JCW works on including women of diverse backgrounds and history in targeted communities in reasons and decisions to be taken regarding their communities. The proposed project works on introducing women to the proper method of recycling bread. It will increase the role of women in achieving and leading environmental projects and spread practices that lead to a sustainable community. It also reflects the impact of the project on the environment as follows: decreasing of excess bread left on dumpsters or at schools, households and restaurants. It contributes to the health of all citizens in the area and uses excess bread as food for cattle in parallel with minimizing the effect of rotted bread on other animals.


Results in environmental sustainability,inclusion and innovation

JCW, after implementing the bread recycling initiative in another region in the year of 2021, believes that this initiative has the potential to be duplicated in Jericho as there is a large number of facilities who are willingto cooperate and provide our teams with all excess bread in the area. Theproject contributes to environmental sustainability and also can be considered a solution to decreasing the amounts of excess breadfrom restaurants, schools, households or even bread left on the streets which on its part contributes to minimizing the negative impact rotten bread may cause animals and using the excess bread to feed cattle by providing farmers with the recycled bread.

Also, JCW works on including women of diversebackgrounds and history in targeted communities in reasons and decisions to be taken regardingtheir communities. The proposed project works on introducing women to the proper method of recycling bread. It will increase the role of women in achieving andleading environmental projects and spread practices that lead to a sustainable community. It also reflects the impact of the project on the environment as follows: decreasing of excess bread left on dumpsters or at schools, households and restaurants. Itcontributes to the health of all citizens in the area and uses excess bread as food for cattle in parallel with minimizing the effect of rotted bread on other animals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jerusalem center for women</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Jerusalem Center for Women is a non-governmental organization, founded in 1994 and located in East Jerusalem. The center aims to empower Palestinian women, as well as to enhance their capabilities for them to become active members and resilient agents of change within their own community. The JCW wishes to do so by spreading the culture of human rights, gender equality and acceptance of the other, this to ensure the full realization of Jerusalemite women&apos;s rights and enhance their participation and visibility in all aspects of the Palestinian society. The JCW also works on raising awareness at the local and international levels of the human rightsviolations committed by the Israeli occupation forces against all Palestinians. It aims to highlight theconsequences of the occupation&apos;s use of military force and security restrictions, main reasons for the lack of security and safety in Palestine, from which women are the first victims. Nevertheless, at the JCW we also believe in the importance of women&#x2019;sinvolvement in realizing a regional peace based on justice, and through the establishment of local and international networks as such, the JCW stresses the necessity of networking and strengthening partnerships with local, regional and international (private or public) institutions, in order to better implement pilot projects and achieve long-term sustainability in Palestine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM QUEBEC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territories</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-21">8324</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-01">4162</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">4162</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06549-08:PS">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002234"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007018"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="OPT/I MENA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06549"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Volunteer Cooperation Program 2020-2027:"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal-Strength CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs representing excluded and marginalised individuals have strengthened capacity and maintain and expand their civic space.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act and to maintain and expand civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-07-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act in favour of equality and equity</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-07-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
