<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06919-02:NE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-505233</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">tensions and conflicts through the social and economic reintegration of young girls and boys as well as women in conflict with the law, to build peace and promote social cohesion. The intensification of terrorist attacks in the regions of Diffa and Tillab&#xE9;ry has led to massive displacement of civilians from their homes. Economic activities (agriculture, transport and fishing) have been largely disrupted, weakening the economic situation of these regions. At the same time, the communities have endured a significant increase in the level of crime and banditry. The national authorities are preparing a plan to emerge from the crisis with the aim of anticipating the challenges of rebuilding the two regions after the conflict. They have made a constant appeal for the return of individuals enlisted in armed groups. In both Diffa and Tillab&#xE9;ry, acts of surrender have been recorded, particularly involving young minors and women who are often forcibly associated with terrorist activities or banditry, but who have renounced these illegal activities. These individuals, who are described as having been &quot;in conflict with the law,&quot; are expected to return to their communities and resume a normal life.However, two challenges have been identified: the care and reintegration of individuals in conflict with the law and the prevention of related social tensions.Indeed, an action focused on the reintegration of a category of the population may causefrustration and misunderstanding among the affected populations who may feel excluded and wronged. They will perceive the prospect of taking charge of this category of people as &quot;a premium for violence or transgression of the law&quot; when their basic needs are not all covered. They may express reservations, or even opposition, to a process of which they are ill-informed and of which they wish tobe a part. This can fester and lead to tension that can backfire on the beneficiaries of the reintegration activities and underminesocial cohesion and project implementation.  It is clear that the success of a reintegration process requires a strategy of community dialogue and reconciliation within the communities themselves. In addition to the above challenges, inter- and intra-community conflict over access to natural resources has increased since the crises broke out in the two regions: while the reception of refugeesand displaced persons by host populations was initially absorbed by traditional solidarity mechanisms, the economic weight of refugees and displaced persons is now generating strong social tensions, especially over access to natural resources.Thus, this action aims to establish structural elements within the framework of the response that the G5-Sahel sub-region, with the support of its partners, is developing and implementing in the face of the worsening instability factors that are particularly affecting the north of the Tillab&#xE9;ry region and the Diffa region as a result of the conflicts that are taking place in these border areas with Mali and Nigeria. This initiative alsorelies on the creation and strengthening of social dialogue between communities in an environment conducive to peace. It will link with interventions on the same theme conducted by Oxfam and its partners in these areas, in collaboration with other state and non-state actors.With the reintegration of vulnerable groups by providing 500 young and female heads of householdswith the means to ensure their livelihoods and to look forward to a more dignified future, the project will help revitalize the local economic fabric (Output 1) and avoid possible recuperation by armed groups. A consensual reintegration mechanism will create the conditions for success and help reduce conflict. In addition, the project will make efforts to help put an end to situations of obvious tension related to resource management (Outcome 2) between displaced populations and host communities and prevent the outbreak or resurgence of violent conflicts in an already fragile context. I. General ObjectiveTo contribute to the reintegrationof persons inconflict with the law and the reduction of conflict in the regions of Diffa and Tillab&#xE9;ry through dialogue.II. Specific Objectives : - Facilitate a consensual reintegration process for people in conflict with the law through dialogue - Reduce, through mediation, intra- and inter-community conflicts and tensions likely to fuel instability in the regions of Diffa and Tillab&#xE9;ryTranslated with www.DeepL.com/Translator (free version)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994. Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education for all, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies. Oxfam Novibs main office is based in The Netherlands, it supports the work of a network of local offices, the implementation of global projects, fund raising, campaigning and advocacy. The Hub Niamey Niger exists since 2006 as a humanitarian field office and since 2012 as the decentralized Country office for Oxfam Novib, dealing with all the development and humanitarian themes like Sustainable livelihoods, Right to Basic services, Humanitarian and resilience interventions, The right to be heard and the right to an Identity, including women&apos;s rights and sexual and reproductive health rights. The Country Office in Niger works with local partners to realize the vision of a Niger without poverty</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-06">2633</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">2633</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB funding with back donor</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06919-02:NE">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002566"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007154"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Niger (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06919"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Reducing conflict in Diffa and Tillabery"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5260-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to respond effectively to disasters</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="5260-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
