<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06138-03:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHURD- Stand Up for SRHR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The centre for health Human Rights and Development (CEHURD) is an indigenous non-profit Research and advocacy organisation which ispioneering the justisciability of the right to health in the East Africa Region. It is duly registered under the laws of Uganda. Founded in 2010 by three young professionals, it has travelled a journey that has allowed the organisation to continuously grow and ground itself as a key leader in the field of health and human rights in Uganda,

Oxfam Canada is the lead applicant and only signatory partner. IPPF, Guttmacher and Action Canada are non-signatory partners. We will work with the following local implementing partners: In Uganda - RHU; CEHURD; FEMME FORTE UGANDA; and Makerere University School of Public Health. In Mozambique - AMODEFA; LAMBDA; and Associacao Mocambicana de Mulheres e Apoio a Rapariga. In Sudan - GRACe; and SFPA. Partnership agreements with detailed roles and responsibilities will be signed with each project partner at inception. Oxfam Canada will: be accountable for project funds and results; ensure project implementation according to local legislation; fulfil the GAC Contribution Agreement; provide Canada-based staffto support project management, capacity-strengthening and financial monitoring and reporting; and coordinate with Action Canada on Canadian public engagement. The Oxfam Country Project Teams will coordinate with local partners, governments and stakeholders and will ensure management and monitoring of the project, as well as the promotionof best environmental practices. Local partners will be the main interlocutors with government, other CSOs, communities, and participants and will deliver many of the key project activities. There will be: a) a Project Advisory Committee to provide general oversight and strategic direction to the project, composed of Oxfam, IPPF, Guttmacher, Action Canada, and GAC; b) 3 Project Coordination Committees (1 per country), led by Oxfam and with participation of local partners, and key stakeholders; and, c) a Program Management Team including Oxfam country-based project managers and officers, as well as representatives from IPPF and Guttmacher to assess project implementation, address operational issues and provide peer support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for health Human Rights &amp; De</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Centre for Health Human Rights and Development (CEHURD) is an indigenous non-profit Research and advocacy organisation which ispioneering the justisciability of the right to health in the East Africa Region. It is duly registered under the laws of Uganda. Founded in 2010 by three young professionals, it has travelled a journey that has allowed the organisation to continuously grow and ground itself as a key leader in the field of health and human rights in Uganda. CEHURD focuses its efforts on critical issues of human rights and health systems in East Africa such as sexual and reproductive health rights, trade and health, and medical ethics whichaffect the vulnerable and less-advantaged populations such as women, children, orphans, sexual minorities, people living with HIV/AIDS, persons with disabilities, internally-displaced persons, refugee populations and victims of violence, torture, disasters and conflict.

CEHURD&apos;s influencing approach covers the following:
1. Social justice: Where Civil claims (including #small claims#) must be addressed.; 2. Empowerment:  of rights-holders to claim and protect their rights.; 3. Health rights: Work to advance health rightsfor vulnerable communities.; 4. Litigation: We use strategic litigation to address health system gaps.

CEHURD is guided by four (4) Strategic objectives that include;
1.To build local National and regional awareness and institutionalise and mainstream health andhuman rights.; 2. To promote equitable access to health services and goods.; 3. To address the underlying determinants to the rightto health.; 4. to maintain a strong vibrant and sustainable centre of Excellence on health and Human Rights in Uganda, Africa and Internationally.

CEHURD&apos;S ROLE ON FUNDING THE BLOOD CAMPAIGN:will be to coordinate  implementation of the blood campaign and will jointly work with other Finance for development partners namely; Oxfam in Uganda,SEATINI; CSBAG; AFIC; UWONET; FIA; PACU; FORMO; CEFORD; ARID.  The campaign will be implemented for a period of six (06) months and has been designed to be in tandem with the national budget planning process.

The project objectives for funding the blood campaign include:
1. To advocate for the prioritisation and increment of the domestic budget allocation to UBTS by 22% of their annual budget in the FY 2020/21 through rigorous engagement with the Ministry of Health, Parliament and Ministry of Finance, Planning and Economic Development.
2. To promote donor recruitment through raising public awareness onthe blood shortage in Uganda and conducting values clarification and attitude transformation trainings.

The Campaign Policy Asks include:
1. Increase domestic financing to UBTS#s by 22% of their annual budget in the FY 2020/2021.
2. Increase UBTS#s annual blood collection by 360,000 units in order to meet the transfusion needs for all patients in Uganda and to meet the increased demand for safe blood transfusion especially at health Centers IVs, which are located in rural areas where most of the population lives.
3. To improve blood transfusion infrastructure in the regional blood banks of Gulu, Arua, Fort-portal, Kitovu.
4. To transform blood collection centers of Hoima, Jinja, Kabaale, Rukungiri, Lira and Soroti into blood distribution centers to bring services nearer to the health care facilities.
5. To ensure every Ugandan gets safe blood free of charge whenever he or she needsit. 6. To address corruption and other governance challenges in accessing safe blood.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM CANADA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2028-04-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-12" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="5404" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-29">17154</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-01">17154</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Canada back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for health Human Rights &amp; De</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-01">17154</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM CANADA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06138-03:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002351"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06138"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="GAC STAND UP SRHR &amp; GBV"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal-Strength CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs representing excluded and marginalised individuals have strengthened capacity and maintain and expand their civic space.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act and to maintain and expand civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-12" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2028-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9120-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved organizational and technical capacity to act in favour of equality and equity</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9120-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-11-12" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2028-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
