<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05868-09:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STAD Saving Lives now &amp; future Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute in strengthening the civil society organizations and alliances to claim and exercise the right to quality education, constructively participate, engage and influence peace process and policies.
2.1.1. # of Public accountability forums organized between citizens and duty bearers with &#xBD; of action points addressed or followed by CSO#s with authorities
2.1.2. # of Community meetings, dialogues supported on governance and service delivery with 40% in attendance being females
2.1.3. Improved public perceptions regarding social cohesion, reconciliation, as well as delivery and citizen engagement with authorities because of active participation and spaces created to dialogue on pertinent issues, including those related to the peace process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-88136411" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUPPORT TRUST FOR AFRICA DEVELOPMEN</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support Trust for Africa Development (STAD) was founded in 2000 as Sudanese Orphans Support Trust (SOST). Its legally registered in2002 at Chamber of Commerce, The Hague, The Netherlands. The major founding goal was Education of Sudanese refugee orphans in Northern Uganda. In 2004, its activities included empowerment, capacity building, income generation peace building, health and environmental programs for youth, women and people with disabilities.

STAD currently operates in Uganda and South Sudan.In Uganda, STAD is officially registered as a civil society organization (CS0) on the 11/10/2019 with Koboko District Local Government with Reg. No 563/0147. It operates in Koboko district, Adjumani and Imvepi refugee settlements through partnership withWindle Trust International. While in South Sudan, it is officially registered in Torit Eastern Equatoria (State level) reg. no 066 &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Juba at the (national level) reg no 2901.  It is also registered in UN portal. At the moment, Koboko is the coordinationCentre for the Juba &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Torit offices

in Uganda STAD, works passionately to better the lives of the most vulnerable men, women, girls and boys suffering in the communities by providing basic assistance such as school fees, food assistance to students, scholastic materials for learners both
in refugee and outside refugee settlements.

STAD through its partners STAD supported Borole Primary School in Adjumani district with desks to aid learning in the school. Boroli Junior primary school is one of the 33primary schools in Adjumani Refugee settlements supported by Windle International Uganda. The school has a total of 1,415 learners comprising of 1290 refugees and 125 Ugandans) at the ratio of 712 (boys and 703 girls). It has 2 blocks of 6 classrooms with inadequate classrooms, desks &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; pit latrine stances forsuch a huge number of pupils. STAD supported Boroli Jr primary school with 90 desks (3-seater).
Construction of a 2 stance Ventilated Improved Pit (VIP) latrine for teachers is on hold due to COVID-19 lockdown.

Imvepi secondary school.  Imvepi SS is one of the community secondary schools established in Imvepi Refugee settlement to provide and support refugee education. It has an enrollment of 847 students in 2019 compromising of: 756 Refugees,and 91 Nationals (652 males and 195 females.) STAD has been supporting each year about 50 unaccompanied minor refugee students with parents and teacher&#x2019;s association (PTA) contributions, School uniforms, emergency sanitary materials and maize flour for porridge.

Institutional Purpose;
Vision: STAD envisions a future of sustainable peace anddevelopment for the people, especially the vulnerable groups in Uganda and extending into the region beyond.
Mission: STAD seeks tosupport the vulnerable groups(women, orphans, refugees, youth and the elderly) in Uganda in market-oriented skills for self-reliance, empowerment &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; capacity building for the furtherance of peace &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; conflict resolutions in the region.

STAD&apos;s core values include; Participation, Respect,Effectiveness and Efficiency, Transparency and accountability, Integrity, Equality, Dedication, Compassion and perseveres

Principle objective
The overall goal of STAD is to support education and training of orphans, refugees, andwomen and youth empowerment for self-reliance.

The specific objectives:
Support and promote basic primary, secondary education andvocational training in market-oriented skills for self-reliance.
&#x2022; Support and promote the implementation of UNSCR 1325: Women, Peace and security (WPS) and the SDGs
&#x2022; Support capacity building, empowerment programmes on human rights (in particular, women&#x2019;s and children&#x2019;s rights), conflict resolutions and peace building to promote peaceful coexistence.
&#x2022; Carry out awareness campaigns and training works in communities on Sexual Gender Based Violence (SGBV) prevention
&#x2022; Organise and promote activities, programs on peace building, conflict resolution
&#x2022; Promote economic activities for youth and women and enhance the sustainability to improvetheir living
&#x2022;Advocate for provision of water and promote hygiene &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; sanitation (WASH) in vulnerable communities to combat water born related diseases.
&#x2022; Awareness raising on health issues &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; HIV/AIDS prevention and counselling programmes for traumatized children andpeople in general
&#x2022; Advocate and lobby for Environmental protection
&#x2022; Networking and Partnership with NGOs which share similar objectives to further the course of vulnerable groups in Uganda and South Sudan respectively.


Strategic Positioning;
STAD works in partnership with civil Society and Community Based organisations, local community leaders/members, academic and religious institutions and non-governmental organisations (NG0s). Among them are the Local government (mention implementation of EU project) Muni University - STAD chair board members and technical advisor and dean of students, mentor and coach STAD staff and volunteers) Windle Trust (Imvepi Secondary and Boroli primary school (School materials), Youth and Women Community Development Organisation (partnering in organising events and hosting STAD office) Save the Children International (SCI) South Sudan etc.
unique about the position of the organisation (STAD)
&#xF0A7; STAD has full and part-time staff volunteer staff, both locally and internationally
&#xF0A7; Has experience in developmentand humanitarian response programs in the field of refugees, finance, SRHR, HIV/AIDS Awareness, Peacebuilding and Protection, Waterand Sanitation, Food Security and Livelihoods), Academia and Teaching, etc.
&#xF0A7; Has a data base of all current and potential staff and volunteers
&#xF0A7; Strong International, national and local networks and partnerships
&#xF0A7;  STAD is one of CSO selected for strategic and Humanitarian Partnerships with Save the Children International (SCI), South Sudan
&#xF0A7; It&#x2019;s a signitory to the UNSCR 1325
&#xF0A7; It&#x2019;s a member of the WO=MEN, the largest gender platform in Europe. Around 50 organisations and 125 professionals are linked to WO=MEN: development and peace organisations, women&apos;s and gender rights organisations, diaspora organisations, trade unions, police, journalists, knowledge institutes, academics, military personnel, entrepreneurs, students and opinion-makers. Together we work towards a just world in which gender equality andthe rights of women and girls are respected.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.41362 30.95998</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-20">9000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">9000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUPPORT TRUST FOR AFRICA DEVELOPMEN</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">9000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05868-09:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001728"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05868"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Saving lives now &amp;future thru education"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-07-15" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-07-15" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
