<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000166</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable increased of incomes for the poor</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Program ID PROG10143

For Oxfam in Nigeria, the Livelihoods programme is central to realizing our vision of a just Nigeria without poverty. It aims to improve agricultural livelihoods and income opportunities for 1,000,000 smallholder farmers (SHF), 60% of whom are women across Nigeria by March 2020.

Through a market-based intervention that brokers a public private partnership, the program will strive to increase productivity, improve food security and incomes for the targeted households, reduce gender gap and youth employment and reduce conflict around productive resources (land, water and grazing areas). The market-led livelihoods will promote value chain agriculture with specific focus on Sorghum, Maize, Fish,, Agro-forestry and Vegetables using Oxfam&apos;s systemic gendered market approach. This ties together climate change adaptation, value chain, rural enterprise development with policy framework and private sector investment.

The Private Sector engagement will bring together small-scale farmers and big companies to provide equitable and sustainable access to training, inputs and markets. The over-arching strategy is that the sustainable livelihoods program will have a differentiated approach, which will nicely combine resilient livelihoods with market led livelihood interventions to transition the chronically poor to the stage where they become economically active and capable to engage. The resilient livelihoods interventions will include social protection/safety nets -cash transfer and/or voucher program, considering a fluctuating market system and security situation, temporary employment in the form of food for work, VS&amp;L/Savings for Change, livestock management, backyard gardening, local food reserve, nutrition enhancement programming.

The program specifically addresses desertification and climate challenges in northern Nigeria. An additional 1 million trees will be planted in Katsina State and more 20,000 mud efficient clean cookstoves produced and disseminated by September 9, 2018, to reach an additional 100,000 direct beneficiaries</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
