<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06178-04:VN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Impact assessment in EI -CGFED</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Research Center for Gender, Family and Environment in Development (CGFED) was established in May 1993 under the Decree 35/HDBT on January 28th, 1992, and obtained the registration for scientific and technological activities No.05/Dk-KHCN on May 05th,1993 issued by the Hanoi Department of Sci-ence, Technology, and Environment (which by now named Department of Science and Technology).  CGFED is a non-governmental, non-profit organization in Vietnam focusing on research and policy advo-cacy aiming to promote individuals and communities to create the happiness based on Gender Equality.
In the last 20 years, CGFED has applied Human Rights framework, the International Covenant on the Elim-ination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) to develop research and interventions in gender equality, women&#x2019;s health, environment, education, sexual and reproductive health rights, climate change, violence against women.
Protecting women&#x2019;s economic rights and gender equality in manufacturing industry are the key strategy of CGFED in the period 2020-2025. Between 2012 and 2013, CGFED with the support of Oxfam Hong Kong implemented the first qualitative research to explore and build understanding about gender in the ex-tractive industry in Vietnam
Main objective:
This project aims to assess gender issues in mining in Vietnam and to propose approaches and recom-mendation on promoting gender equality and mitigating negative impacts in the mining sector.
Specific objectives:
- Assessing the status and potential risks for women and men living in communities affected by mining activities regarding environmental and social aspects
- Highlighting the concerns and views of women directly and indirectly affected by mining activities to protect their rights
-Analyzing the views and the way of working of local authorities and mining companies concerning their perception and the enforcement of policies on mining sector and women&apos;s rights
- Providing specific policy recommendations to policymakers and mining companies to address re-lated issues.
- Proposing an action plan for Oxfam in Vietnam on assisting local people and their participation in the legal framework development process, and dialogues among stakeholders inmining activities
Project site: Dai Tudistrict, Thai Nguyen province
Thai Nguyen is a rich province in mineral resources. Minerals with significant reserves for an industrial scale exploitation include coal, iron, wolfram, tin, cement limestone, and original ilmenite. In addition, paving stones and placer gold can be exploited at a small scale. 11 coal mining sites in this province en-compassfat coal (Lang Cam, Am Hon, Phan Me) reserving nearly 10 million tons, long flaming coal distrib-uted in Nui Hong with reserves of about 15 million tons, in the composition of coal contains germanium; Anthracite coal (Ba Son, Quan Trieu, Khanh Hoa) with more than70 million tons. Currently, all coal mining sites are being exploited.
Dai Tu is a mountainous district located in the northwest ofThai Nguyen province, with rich mineral re-sources distributed in most communes and towns. Many types of precious and rare mineralswith large reserves such as Tungsten, Coal, Titanium, Kaolin, Tin, Iron, Barite, clay ... concentrate mainly in 19 com-munes and towns including communes of An Khanh, Cu Van, Ha Thuong, Tan Thai, Luc Ba, Tan Linh, Phuc Linh, Ky Phu, Cat Ne, Khoi Ky, Phu Thinh, Phu Lac, Duc Luong, Phuc Luong, Phu Cuong, Minh Tien, Yen Lang, Na Mao, and Hung Son Town. In addition, this district has mining sitesof common construction ma-terials distributed in most communes and towns. The population is about 160,598 people (in 2012). The average population density is about 283 people / km&#xB2;. The main ethnic groups are Kinh, Tay, Nung, Dao, and San Diu.
Regarding the governance of mining activities, in Dai Tu district, there are 23 companies are licensed to explore and exploit minerals of 34 mining sites. Through inspection, 08 mining site are in operation, 07 sites are under construction, 10 sites are suspended due to the expiration of the license and companies are completing procedures for extension, 02 sites are undergoing site clearance, in 02 sites licensewere revoked , and 05 sites are for exploration. In the district, some enterprises employ highest proportion of female employees inthe mining industry that is seen as male-dominant labor sector.
5. Duration:
Project Duration: September 2020 - February 2021
6. Activities:
Main activities are implemented in this project:
i. Conducting base line survey aiming at gathering basic information about communities affected by mining activities in terms of social and environmental aspects.
ii. Training on Gender in Extractive Industry to multi-stakeholders
iii. Dialogue between affected groups in thecommunity and relevant stakeholders to discuss and analyze difficulties, opportunities, and challenges based on the collected information. An action plan to mitigate risks, overcome difficulties, and take advantage of available opportunities is alto-gether developed to ensure the requirements and interests of the affected group.

6.1 Baseline survey:
The baseline survey has an objective to collect demographic and economic data about the affected com-munities including income status and poverty level.Collected data is extracted by gender, ethnicity, age, and income. The data is analyzed by gender, division of labor, level of control and access to resources in order to examine the impact of mining activities on different groups of communities.
Detailactivities comprise of:
- Collect secondary data from annual reports of the Commune People&apos;s Committee, related de-partments, and local authorities
-  Develop a research framework and tools: detailed research outline and quantitative question-naire andin-depth interview (IDI) questions.
- Piloting the questionnaire and IDI questions to complete the framework(10 interviews using questionnaires and 2 IDIs with one man, one woman
- Field research:
o Quantitative information: 100 questionnaires for women,men, and leaders
o Qualitative information:
&#xF0A7; 20 in-depth interviews with: women, men, company leaders, community leaders, leaders of social organizations
&#xF0A7; 2 group discussions: with women and men communities.&#x1B0;
- Synthesize and analyze research data
- Write a research report.
6.2. Training on Gender in Extractive Industry to multi-stakeholders
A training course is organized to share and consult on preliminary findings of the baseline survey with communities&#x2019; members, mining companies, local authorities (30 people, 3 days):
- Content and materials: Providing information and raising awareness for participants on gender in the mining; Sharing and discussing findings from baseline survey and collecting additional infor-mation for the completion of the research.
- Participants: About 30 people are representatives of groups in the community including women, men, mining company leaders, community leaders, local authorities, representatives of mass or-ganizations.
6.3. Multi-stakeholders dialogue and action plan
Dialogue on research finding and together develop action plan: (30 people, 1 day)
- Discussing and analyzing difficulties, opportunities, and challenges faced by affected different groups of communities based the collected data.
- Participants: About 30 people: representatives of groups of communities including women, men; company leaders, local authorities, representatives of mass organizations.
- An action plan based on the discussion and outcomes of the multi-stakeholder Dialogue is devel-oped
7. Project deliverables:
- One training document for communities affected by mining on the impacts of mining on commu-nities in the perspective of gender equality and Vietnamese cultural characteristics.
- One gender impact assessment reportwithtypical stories that analyze the impacts of mining on different groups of communities and provide important principles and methods to ensure the meaningful participation of communities and protect rights of vulnerable group and affected groups.
- One action plan: based on the discussion and outcomes of the multi-stakeholder Dialogue</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background: Over the past five years, a range of agencies # mostly government bodies, the media and international development partners- have done numerous studies and interventions to enhance WPL, however, gaps still exist in tackling such an issue. Someof the examples include 1) limited understanding of what factors help challenge gender stereotypes to design effective interventions to tackle these issues, despite the fact that gender stereotypes have been identified as major barriers for the participation of WPL; 2) existing projects/interventions are not fully addressing gender stereotypes on women political leadership to shift the power imbalance;3) media content has been found to reinforce gender stereotypes rather than challenging them; 4) limitedco-operation or joint campaigns between the aforementioned stakeholders to shift public attitudes and perceptions on WPL; 5) insignificant role and limited participation of CSOs in promoting WPL.

The 2016 election is a critical momentum for strengthening multiple partnerships among government bodies, CSOs and media outlets aiming to change public perceptions and to influence policies on WPL.

This is a One Oxfam coordinated and joint effort to strengthen our influencing capacity in the area of genderequality and women empowerment. Through in depth research and collection of cases and stories, Oxfam will have strong evidences to build a significant advocacy and campaign programme over coming years. This project will further contribute to governance,economic leadership, and humanitarian programme. Oxfam will document the lessons learned and share broadly to provide better understanding of current WPL#s practices and gaps in the region.

Objectives: The project aims to promote involvement of governments, media, CSOs and public in addressing gender stereotypes on WPL, in order to contribute to the advancement of gender justice in Viet Nam.

Expected results:
- 300 female and male policy makers will have improved understanding of WPL and gender stereotypes relating to WPL.
- 100 journalists and 5 media agencies have active participation in challenging gender stereotypes on women political leaderships
- 20 CSOs/networks and mass organizations actively participate in promoting WPL to create socialmovements supporting to WPL.
- 1500 women and men commit to supporting WPL.

The budget (199,680 EUR) for the project has been committed from 9/2014 to 12/2015 by TFSN
Partners: NCFAW (National Committee for the Advancement of Women in Vietnam), CSAGA (Center for Studies and Applied Sciences in Gender - Family - Women and Adolescents) and CGFED (Research Centre for Gend+er, Family and Environment in Development)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research Centre for Gender, Family Environment in Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to an identity</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-14">11504</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-14">2589</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">5752</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research Centre for Gender, Family Environment in Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">8341</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research Centre for Gender, Family Environment in Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-01">5752</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">8341</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06178-04:VN">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001995"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007256"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Vietnam (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06178"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="EITI phase 2"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2110</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Private Sector: # of cases where Oxfam/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies by private sector on ensuring space for civil society, esp. to hold  private sector to account</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies by private sector on ensuring space for civil society, esp. to hold  private sector to account -DD3</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2110</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Private Sector: # of cases where Oxfam/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies by private sector on ensuring space for civil society, esp. to hold  private sector to account</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2110-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners in support of development/adoption of alternative policies/approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2110-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">document for advocacy on gender in EI</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2110-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners to support monitoring of practices and implementation of policies by the private sector</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2110-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Impact Assessment - Case study report</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased citizens voice:  # of people (M/F) take action  for better and increased aid and more civil society space  following Oxfam Novib/partners actions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men  take action  for better and increased aid and more civil society space  following Oxfam Novib/partners actions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2140-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women  take action  for better and increased aid and more civil society space  following Oxfam Novib/partners actions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2140-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased citizens voice:  # of people (M/F) take action  for better and increased aid and more civil society space  following Oxfam Novib/partners actions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140-D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">media citations of Oxfam and partners research or products</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2140-D" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men participating in public events / spaces organized by Oxfam Novib and partners</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2140-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">men shared their stories for case studies</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140-C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">public events/spaces organised by Oxfam Novib and partners in which citizens express their needs and aspirations to policy makers.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2140-C" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 social media campaign on gender in EI</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2140-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women participating in public events / spaces organized by Oxfam Novib and partners</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2140-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">women shared stories and experience for case studies</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4460</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to participate in politics exercising transformative leadership</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4460-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4460-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4460-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women directly supported by Oxfam Novib/partners to enhance their capabilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4460-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">4460</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Men able to:  # of people (M/F) living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to participate in politics exercising transformative leadership</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4460-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">men living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to exercise their SRHR.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4460-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4460-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">women living in poverty and injustice use their enhanced knowledge and skills to exercise their SRHR.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="4460-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-09-01" value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
