<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05224-18:ID</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ID_IPAS - DARE Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decriminalization of Abortion for Rape (DARE)

Under Indonesia&#x2019;s legal framework, survivors of sexual violence seeking sexual and reproductive health (SRH) care and the clinical service providers who manage their cases are both subject to criminal charges. This is alarmingly prevalent in cases of rape that lead to the termination of unintended pregnancies.

Indonesia&#x2019;s Government Regulation No 61/2014 on Reproductive Health (herein referred to as the Health Law) and Ministry of Health (MoH) Decree No3/2016 legalizes elective abortion services, training of abortion providers, and development of safe abortion protocols for cases of rape. However, findings from a recent policy study conducted by the Institute for Criminal Justice Reform (ICJR) and IPASIndonesia highlight serious gapsbetween the Health Law and the delivery of abortion services. Currently there is no guidance from the government on the implementation of this law, and in several instances, other government policies contradict the HealthLaw, leaving police and lawmakers without a clear understanding of abortion legality.

In 2020, the MOH began covertly drafting national guidelines on safe abortion that would lay out the path for operationalizing the Health Law. However, the MOH did not involve relevant stakeholders in the draft process,other than organizations of doctors and midwives and a limited number of local government officials. Civil Society Organizations (CSOs) were left out of the process, as was the National Police Force, even though the IPAS Indonesia/ICJR study found that the National Police Force is in favour of developing guidelines that can inform an integrated standard operating procedure (SOP) on sexual violence that the Force can adopt. A SOP on sexual violence at National Police Force would ensure timely access to comprehensive abortion care for rape survivors, as the Health Law allows termination of pregnancy only up to six weeks gestational age. Currently, Yayasan IPAS Indonesia works with the National Police Forceto support a provincial police hospital with developing clinical protocols andreferral mechanisms and providing comprehensive SRH care for survivors of sexual violence. A SOP on sexual violence at the nationallevel for the Police Force is necessary to complement the clinical protocols being developed at the hospital level, as there is currently no standard guidance for the Police Force in how they can address reported cases.

Under the proposed project, IPAS Indonesia, in partnership with ICJR, aims to create a supportive environment for the decriminalization of safe abortion for sexual violence survivors. We intend to achieve this by: 1) Creating public demand for the development and dissemination of national guidelines that underpin the Health Law by strengthening CSO alliances and movements beyond traditional sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) CSOs, and 2) Claiming civic space through support from partners in media and allies in Parliament and engaging in the process of developingandrefining a National Police Force SOP on sexual violence that will ensure timely access of comprehensive SRH care for sexual violence survivors, including the elective termination of unintended pregnancies. Our activities will include promoting commonmessaging for public awareness, conducting joint advocacy with CSO partners, and creating safety measures for protecting survivors of sexual violence and service providers through the establishment of legal support when needed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atau Yayasan IPAS Indonesia adalah sebuah organisasi nirbala berbadan hukum dengan kantor pusat di Jakarta dan terdaftar di Kementerian Hukum dan HAM Indonesia sejak Mei 2018. Yayasan IPAS Indonesia berkomitmen untuk bekerja sama erat dengan Pemerintah Indonesia untuk mendukung Pelaksanaan Program Nasional Kesehatan Ibu dan Anak, serta Program Nasional Kesehatan Usia Reproduksi yang berkontribusi mendukung penurunan Angka Kematian Ibu (AKI) dan peningkatan status kesehatan perempuan dan remaja perempuan secara umum. Yayasan IPAS Indonesia merupakan afiliasi dari jejaring Ipas di tingkat global dan Ipas sendiri adalah organisasi non-pemerintah yang berkantor pusat di North Carolina, Amerika Serikat.

Pada pelaksanaan kegiatan proyeknya, Yayasan IPAS Indonesia bekerja bersama Pemerintah Pusat dan Daerah serta organisasi masyarakat sipil, termasuk di dalamnya organisasi profesi terkait dan akademisi, melalui aktivitas-aktivitas terkait perencanaaan kehamilan, serta penanganan kehamilan tidak direncanakan dengan meningkatkan akses dan penggunaan layanan kesehatan reproduksi yang komprehensif berbasiskan aturan hukum dan kebijakan program di Indonesia.

Dalam pelaksanaan program, Yayasan IPAS Indonesia fokus pada 3 pilar utama, yakni: Pendidikan dan Promosi Kesehatan Masyarakat, lewat pendidikan dan promosi kesehatan di tingkat masyarakat terutama bagi perempuan dan remaja perempuan yang berbasiskan kekuatan dan kearifan lokal yang dimiliki oleh masing-masing daerah; Penguatan Sistem Kesehatan di tingkat nasional, Yayasan IPAS Indonesia bekerja sama erat dengan pemerintah pusat (Kementerian Kesehatan, BKKBN, Kementerian Pemberdayaan Perempuan dan Perlindungan Anak) untuk mendukung pengembangan norma, standar, pedoman dan kriteria (NSPK) pelayanan kesehatan di Puskesmas PONED dan atau Rumah Sakit untuk memberikan Asuhan Pasca Keguguran (APK) yang komprehensif melalui rangkaian pelatihan dan bimbingan pemberi layanan kesehatan, jejaring rujukan antar layanan dan masyarakat; serta Kajian-kajian dan Evaluasi yang bisa digunakan untuk program selanjutnya.

Saat ini Yayasan IPAS Indonesia juga sedang mengerjakan beberapa proyek yang menggunakan pendekatan dari 3 pilar tersebut, salah satunya yaitu proyek PEKERTi yang merupakan modeling/proyek rintisan untuk APK yang komprehensif lewat kerja sama dengan 3 Kabupaten/Kota; Kabupaten Ponorogo (JawaTimur), Kabupaten Klaten (Jawa Tengah), dan Kota Yogyakarta yang memiliki prioritas dalam meningkatkan kualitas layanan publik dengan melakukan inovasi-inovasi layananuntuk menjawab kebutuhan masyarakat setempat, terutama dalam menurunkan AKI.

Pengembangan proyek rintisan ini diharapkan dapat menginformasikan kepada pemangku kepentingan yang ada di tingkat lokal dan nasional, untuk mengembangkan lebih lanjut programAPK yang komprehensif sebagai bagian dari upaya penurunan morbiditas perempuan dan AKI di Indonesia.

Sejalan dengan pilar Kajian-kajian dan Evaluasi, Yayasan IPAS Indonesia juga bekerja sama dengan beberapa pihak lainnya untuk melakukan diseminasi hasil-hasil studi terkait isu kesehatan reproduksi perempuan. Seperti proyek DAISY misalnya, bekerja sama dengan Guttmacher Institute dan Fakultas Kesehatan Masyarakat Universitas Indonesia untuk melakukan diseminasi hasil studi estimasi angka kejadian aborsidi Jawa.

Sesuai dengan visi misi organisasi, Yayasan IPAS Indonesia ingin berkontribusi untuk menciptakan dunia di mana perempuan dan remaja perempuan memiliki status kesehatan reproduksi yang baik serta hak dan akses pada layanan kesehatan reproduksiyang komprehensif, sehingga tidak ada lagi kejadian keguguran, kesakitan perempuan, kematian ibu, kehamilan tidak direncanakan, aborsi yangtidak aman, dan masalah kesehatan reproduksi lainnya.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan IPAS Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-14">43351</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">43351</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan IPAS Indonesia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">43351</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05224-18:ID">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05224"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Influencing Grants Indonesia"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(Informal) groups and organisations have capacity to build alliances, coalitions and networks with a variety of stakeholders, to amplify rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># alliances, coalitions and networks indicating to initiate activities based on joint action plans</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.2.1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># and type (article, policy, blog, podcast, video) of publications by non-grantees/rightsholders supporting issues of grantees and/or rightsholder groups</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.2.2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(Informal) groups and organisations have capacity to build alliances, coalitions and networks with a variety of stakeholders, to amplify rightsholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># joint actions on influencing social actors developed by (informal) groups, organisations and networks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.2.a" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># joint actions on influencing social actors implemented by (informal) groups, organisations and networks</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="1.2.b" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
