<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05275-04:AF</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From Black Box to Building Blocks</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and participatory budget processes are crucial for ensuring #good governance# in Afghanistan as
these ultimately determine the effectiveness of provincial departments# provision of services. Despite
substantial public financial management reforms, progress in Afghanistan remains elusive in terms of
inclusive, accountable and transparent budgeting, with the Open Budget Survey still indicating a score
below the global average.4 Budget oversight mechanisms remain weak as the government provides the
public with limited information # except for the Citizen#s Budget # and few opportunities for civil society to
engage in the budget processes,5 creating a disconnect between the government and citizens.6 As a
result, budget priorities often do not match needs at the local level. The recent approval and inception of
the provincial budgeting policy (PBP) indicates a more inclusive process, as it aims to de-concentrate the
budget process, allowing for bottom-up participation of provincial entities. According to the government#s
implementation plan, the policy is envisioned to be implemented across the 34 provinces after the threeyear
pilot phase that started in 2015 in four line ministries including the Ministry of Education (MoE) and
Ministry of Public Health (MoPH).
At this critical juncture for Afghanistan, civil society has a crucial role to play to ensure more inclusion and
participation of Afghan citizens in the budget process, currently limited to a civil society workshop held on
the first budget circular7 and a limited number of planned consultations with civil society.8 Oxfam#s
governance programming experience shows that constructive citizen-state partnerships can be
establishedaround common agendas at district and provincial level, and that this increases the
responsiveness of national authorities to policy propositions and recommendations. This Action therefore
aims to strengthen citizen-state engagement through facilitating civil society involvement in the budget
process, particularly by capitalizing on opportunities provided in the PBP and the forthcoming Sub-
National Governance Policy.
This Action has a thematic focus on essential services of health and education. These services constitute
one of the basic tenets of a rights based approach to #good governance# internationally and in
Afghanistan. Since the removal of the Taliban regime in 2001, health and education provision especially
for girls and women has seen significant progress. For example, maternal mortality decreased drastically
from 1,600 deaths per 100,000 births in 2001 to 400 in 2014, and around 3 million girls arenow enrolled
in school. Despite these improvements, there are still major challenges to overcome in order to make
education and healthcare accessible, affordable and of good quality for all Afghans, especially for women
and girls as school attendance and access to basic healthcare continue to show a gender gap. Because
of this inequality, the Action will specifically benefit girls and women by making systems responsive to
their needs and also by ensuring gender is integrated in the inception, implementation, monitoring and
evaluation phases of the Action.
This Action will build upon the Citizens First program, currently implemented by three of the five
applicants (Oxfam, APPRO and PTRO) in the same provinces as selected for this proposal: Herat,
Nangarhar, and Takhar. Citizens First has laid a solid foundation, establishing an operational structure for
increased CSO participation in citizen-state processes at multiple levels through District Advocacy
Committees (DACs), Provincial Advocacy Committees (PACs), and the National Advocacy Committee
(NAC).9 These committees built trust and mutual understanding between CSOs, Local Authorities (LAs)
and the ministries. They facilitate dialogue based on community priorities and provide an established twoway
feedback loop through which citizens priorities andneeds can be communicated to the three
governance levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACSFo,

Afghan Civil Society Forum (ACSF) was established in February 2002 on the request of 76 participants of Afghan Civil Society Conference in Germany, 2001, as a partnership between Afghan civil society partners and Swiss Peace. In May 2002 ACSF opened its offices in Kabul. In 2010, ACSF changed its legal status to an NGO (since then called ACSFo).

The Bonn agreement induced the processtowards democratic ideals and participatory political structures of which the Loya Jirga (June 2002) and the constitution (January 2004) were the first big steps. ACSF promoted the development of civic education (culture of peace, democracy and justice) among theyoung and undefined civil society in Afghanistan with partner organisations across the entire country in the context of these important events.

ACSF&#x92;s mission is to strengthen civil society and its countervailing power in stabilising the country, so that citizens are aware and committed to participate in the development of a just and equitable society; disarmament and security being prerequisites for democratic development.

From 2002 to 2005 civic education became ACSFo&#x92;s main strategy to prevent human rights abuses andto promote a culture of peace, democracy and justice. ACSF works as a network organization and organized Nation-wide campaigns (with support of DFID, UNOPS/JEMBS and USAID). About 10-15% of the Afghan population was reached leading to 31% women participation in the presidential elections (2004) and 34% in the parliamentarian elections (2005). These projects educated over 11 million Afghans. Since 2002 ACSF also has been able to publish 68 editions of Jamea-e-Madani civil society magazine have been brought out.

F rom 2006-2009 ACSF carried out a country-wide civic education programme financed by Oxfam Novib, contributing to awareness creation on civilrights and democratic processes amongst young and not yet &apos;defined&apos; civil society.
ACSFo also added advocacy and research, peace-building/governance and institutional capacity building to its activities consisting of:

&#x95; Facilitation of National Consultations/Dialogue: collecting public opinion concerning the by the government claimed achievements on security, poverty reduction, health, education, transparency and fighting poppy cultivation.

&#x95; Institutional Capacity Building: ACSFo works with Counterpart Inter&#xAC;national (CPI) to implement the &#x93;Initiative to Promote Afghan Civil Society&#x94; (I-PACS) &#x96; a nationwide approach that supports the development ofa civil society friendly legal framework.

&#x95; Advocacy/Research: ACSFo has set-up advocacy committees on topics such as youth, womenand people with disabilities, environment and transparency and accountability. Concerns of the citizens are advocated at national level and the organisation of National youth conferences (2002, 2004 and 2005).

ACSFo has implemented a research project &#x84;How Peopledefine Violence and Justice&#x93;, examining the people&#x92;s understanding of violence in the past five decades. Results were used to strengthenpeace initiatives via local and people-driven justice and reconciliation processes.

&#x95; Peace-building/Governance: ACSFo is member of the Afghan Civil Society Organisations Network for Peace (ACSONP). Peace-building training manuals have been produced aNational Peace Day was celebrated throughout the country in 2007.

In 2009, ACSFo piloted a Community Policing project in 31 districts of five Northern provinces, bridging gaps between the governmental/law enforcement institutions and the civil society, reducing local conflicts and improving capacities and accountability of the Afghan National Police.

&#x95; Networking/Coordination: ACSFo has expanded its civil society network across Afghanistan, comprising 320 partner organisations and 130 members othermembers.

In recent strategic repositioning discussions it was concluded that ACSFo should continue emphasising rural areas and as organisation try to form an important &#x91;internode&#x92;/cross-point for synergic sharing and strengthening of qualities of individual members (horizontal linkages) and for analysing and forwarding of information originated at central government level and organisations active in the context of local government institutions and structures (vertical linkages). In the current development of the government decentralisation and devolution of government towards provinces, districts and further downwards to grass-root levels civic education, awareness creation in combination with mobilisation and are very important co-processes for empowering communities and strengthening of the democratic basis in Afghanistan, wherein ACSFo plans to play a catalysing role.

ACSFo  is one of the few NGOs that really have added value to civil society development in Afghanistan. Projects of most NGOs areactually to a large extent service deliveries and relief activities, which often use traditional social and political power structures to reach the communities and therewith confirm and consolidate thesepower relations. Critical analysis if activities are reaching the most vulnerable people are lacking in many organisations and perhaps some activities are even counterproductive. Oxfam Novib has endeavoured to strengthen NGOs capacities and to develop insights. ACSFo has been an important player in this CS strengthening process and is in the current local governance programme showing it can also bring the countervailing power function of CSOs in practice.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EC_DEVCO" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-15">152092</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-15">152092</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-07-15">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">53379</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-02-01">15337</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-02-01">29084</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-01">15337</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-01">29084</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-02-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">19743</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">47574</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam GB own funds OGB</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">53379</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">-47574</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">44421</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">44421</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib public funds</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Civil Society Forum</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">47574</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-202918" ref="GB-CHC-202918">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-01">53379</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-08-01">-47574</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-01">44421</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">44421</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05275-04:AF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001250;1001302;1001318"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007201"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Afghanistan ASIA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05275"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="From Black Box to Building Blocks"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="54"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="152"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="54"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
