<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05225-11:ID</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ID-RMI Kampung Katong</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The title of this project is &#x2018;Kampung Katong&#x2019; which in Nusa Tenggara Timur (NTT) Province dialect means Our Hamlet. Kampung Katong also an acronym for Kami Pung Manekat, Papada, Kampo Tanga which means Our Spirit for Collective Work (Manekat, Papada, andKampong Tanga are local terms from Mollo, Labuan Bajo, and Larantuka representing &#x201C;collective work of a community&#x201D;). This project idea was born from the reflection between RMI and Lakoat Kujawas on the collaboration in Being and Becoming Indigenous (BBI)in 2020-2021. In the BBI project, financial resources were disbursed to Lakoat Kujawas to support the implementation at the community level. This approach then ended up in several informal (i.e.: outside of the project work plan) capacity building providedby RMI for Lakoat Kujawas in terms of project administration and management, which was positively reflected by both parties. Lakoat Kujawas sees the additionaladministration and management capacity as a meaningful resource in improving their initiativesin working with the indigenous youth and children. RMI, affirming with Lakoat Kujawas, sees that this approach is needed not only by Lakoat Kujawas, but by other local initiatives and that the collaboration model that strengthens local communities&#x2019; access to productive resources can be formalized as a specific project in the future. By mentioning productive resources, we refer to funding, capacity building, and linking and learning opportunities that will capacitate indigenous peoples and ethnic minorities(IPEM), especially their young women and men, in governing their land and strengthening ownership toward their local culture. Taking into account the gender balance of rightsholder groupwho participate, it is also decided that 50% of participants inthe community organising and partners&#x2019; local initiatives are women.

This project is also designed in response to global trends and its unintended consequences when many financial resources are mobilized directly to communities that are often not preparedeither socially or organizationally. RMI involvement with other grant schemesshows that the managerial capacity of many other involved community organizations was the main barrier in grant implementation. Donor&#x2019; expectation on project management and reporting, especially in terms of administrative works, is beyond community capacity. Although series of initial training on several themes such as project management, financial reporting, and M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;E were conducted pre-implementation, the one-off approach proven tobe ineffective in the face of other organizational issues such as leadership and organizational management and HR turnover. Our extensive experience working with Kasepuhan IPs communities in Lebak Regency also shows how prone the communities are to elitecapture which often results in horizontal conflict and failure of community organization when certain funds are directed to the community without proper assistance. This is why community preparedness is of importance today. Thus, after several initial discussions, identifying potential collaborators, and one consultation process with other potential collaborators, RMI, Lakoat Kujawas, SimpaSio Institute, and Kolektif Videoge agreed to propose this proposal as a consortium with RMI as thelead/hostorganization.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rimbawan Muda Indonesia (RMI) was established in 1992, dedicating its work with youth and later on worked with indigenous peoples# communities mainly in form of community organising and advocacy. RMI has given emphasis to empower rural youth, including those who are member of indigenous communities, to be the agents of change regarding their communities&apos; situations, including their young-peer&apos;s situations. Ever since, RMI has carried out various projects and activities that empower them and provide spacefor them to be part of their communities&apos; development.
Various studies have been produced to mainstream the discussions of rural youth, including indigenous youth. Due to its focus on rural-indigenous youth, RMI was appointed in 2018 by the NGOs/CSOs coalition in national level to write the part on &apos;indigenous youth&apos; in a policy paper for Indonesia&apos;s Bill on Indigenous Peoples.

RMI has also developed wide range of campaign activities, including to connect the rural and urban youth to build solidarityin supporting rural development. Youth platforms namely Relawan for Life, Suara Muda Nusantara and Teens Go Green are amongst the strategy that RMI develops to empower youth # both rural and urban # to promote indigenous youth participation in Kasepuhan Indigenous Peoples Community&apos;s Forum that has always exclude women and youth voice. Furthermore in 2017, RMI was appointed as the coordinator of a regional youth and land platform within Asia, under the International Land Coalition-Asia.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan Rimbawan Muda Indonesia Bog</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-12">59077</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">59077</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yayasan Rimbawan Muda Indonesia Bog</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-01">59077</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05225-11:ID">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05225"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Innovate Learn grants Indonesia"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-09-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-09-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
