<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05244-17:NG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE- Project Accessible Aviation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project Accessible mass public transit CARE &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; Access For All ... Call to Action is an initiative of Center for Ability Rehabilitation and Empowerment (CARE) founded by Dr. Chike Okogwu in line with one of the Centre&#x2019;s mantra that &#x2018;Experiences in LifeShould Refine and Not Define One...Rise Above That Challenge&#x2019;. It is aimed at removing all barriers to accessible air transportation for persons with disabilities in Nigeria. It was borne out of the daily frustrations passengers with disabilities continueto face in airports and local airlines companies in Nigeria, bearing in mind, most importantly, that we need to have the compassion and caring for helping to protect vulnerable people as Ellen Sauerbrey says and &apos;If we truly believe in the value of life,we should care about all of the weakest and most vulnerable members of society&apos; - Joni Eareckson. Tada).

Nigeria currently has several Airports, railway services, and millions of buses  but most of them are inaccessible .They are plagued by inaccessible infrastructure rendering them literally useless to persons with disabilities. This Project is intended to amongst other things, ensure solutions &#x2013; in the transportsector.  There must exist modern assistive devices to eliminate any form of accessibility barriers around the airports, bus stops, and railway stations
In addition, there must be a &#x2018;CARE and Access For All Counters&apos; supported by the National Commission of Personswith Disabilities (NCPWD) and National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) to provide services to all PWDs defined as, sick, pregnant women, elderly, albino and any vulnerable person. The desk will register, assist and record all PWD passenger and ensure their best treatment all through the journey. The records received will help the NCPWD in her issuance of Disabilities Certificate program in line with the Nigerian Disabilities Prohibition Act (2019).
Also, all the PWDs assistants at the desks must wear Personal Protection Equipment (PPE) in conformity with COVID-19 Protocols for protection of PWD passenger, airport assistants them, all the other passengers and crew on the transit.

Project Accessible Transport through the Voice I-rant grant seek to amongst other things;
1. Commit keystakeholders in the Nigerian transportation sector to implement accessible transport systems.
2. Train transport operators on the rights of persons with disabilities
3. Procure and deploy assistive devices at transit terminals
4. Create jobs for the operators of the assistive devices and ancillaryservices at the airports. We estimate that at-least 1000 new jobs will be created.

Decisions flow from the Board of Trustees to the management team and then to the staff, project decisions flow from the management, to the team lead and eventually to thestaff. The BOT meet annually twice in a year to plan and review activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRE FOR REHABILITATION &amp; EMPOWER</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Center for Ability Rehabilitation and Empowerment in Nigeria (CARENigeria) was founded in 2014 by Dr. Chike Okogwu, a spinal cord victor from a freak car crash in on December 15 2006 that left him paraplegic from waist down. The key aim of CARENigeria is to highlight values out of disability, these values are products of CORE (Courage, Opportunities, Responsibilities and Empowerment, which are the basics required for achieving excellence in any person with disabilities, CARE Nigeria is at the forefront of the disability advocacy in Nigeria, with her rehabilitation and empowerment programs.

The main goal of Center for Ability Rehabilitation and Empowerment is to ensure that Persons with disabilities face no barriers in accessing services and facilities anywhere in the country.

CARE has carried out several interventions including provisions of  scholarships, humanitarian relief (during COVID 19 lockdown), advocacy on accessible air travel etc. They believe strongly in accessible air travel campaign because key stakeholders like airlines companies, government officials and agencies have begun to see the need for such campaign.

The  current Project is an initiative of Center for Ability Rehabilitation and Empowerment (CARE) founded by Dr. Chike Okogwu in line with one of the Centre&#x2019;s mantra that&#x2018;Experiences in Life Should Refine and Not Define One...Rise Above That Challenge&#x2019;. It is aimed at removing all barriers to accessible air transportation for persons with disabilities in Nigeria. It was borne out of the daily frustrations passengers with disabilities continue to face in airports and local airlines companies in Nigeria. They believe that there must exist modern assistive devices to eliminate any form of accessibility barriers around the airports, bus stops, and railway stations.

The project will be led byDr. Chike Okogwu- a disruptive innovator and first class media and management development consultant. He is the former Nigerian Coordinator  (Abuja) of the CNN Multichoice African Journalist of the Year awards alongside providing both commercial and editorial contents for CNN, BBC and Aljazeera news channels. As a paraplegic with a spinal cord injury sustained in a car accident, he is an advocate of inclusion and accessible social infrastructure. He has overtime advocated for accessible air travel for passengers with disabilities.  Chike has committed to being a Champion of Change with education from the Academy of Business Management Switzerland (DBA), York St. John University, Yorkshire, UK (MA in Leading Innovation and Change), Triple Alumnus of the prestigious Harvard Kennedy Sch of Govt., Cambridge, USA in Leadership in the 21st Century; Chaos, Conflicts and Courage Program (2010) and Expanding Impact Program (2011), Leadership, Organizing and Action (2012); He works on Leadership Trainings around the world with emphasis on producing change agents in Africa with his faculty members in Harvard KSG, The Thinking Heads Global Group, Australia and The Innovative IdeasDevelopment Services Ltd as CEO. He has held top leadership positions in the Nigerian Presidency and is a top adviser to state governments, blue chip firms, CSOs and Start ups.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="16" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-20">21758</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">21758</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D VOICE</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CENTRE FOR REHABILITATION &amp; EMPOWER</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-09-01">21758</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-27910" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05244-17:NG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000141" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1000923"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007881"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05244"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Voice Influencing grants Nigeria"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to protect and widen civil society space -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2120</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs:  # of CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts  to protect and widen civil society space..</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial, knowledge, skills, networks, training, etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-08-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
