<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06895-02:KH</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DPA- EI Social Environmental Impact</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DPA-EISEI continues to maintain good relationship with and engages closely with the MME and MoE, and facilitate and participate in public consultation on the draft laws/policies, sub-decree and guidelines. Engaging strongly with policy dialogues and national and sub-national multi-stakeholder dialogue platform contribute to increase the capacity DPA staff and EISEI network members and contribute to attain the outlined outcomes and outputs. Additionally, DPA-EISEI has been reviewing EIA reports and attending the inter-ministerial meetings to give comment and inputs on EIA reports as the part of NGOs participation for effective and better EIA as well asEnvironmental Management Plan (EMP).
DPA works closely with other NGOs, those two government&#x2019;s ministryand private sector in ensuring the function of Extractive Industry Governance Forum (EIGF) and strengthening EISEI network at local and national level for influencing works to address emerging development issues related to gender and mining impact issues,and legal framework improvement. DPA-EISEI expands an engagement of the community representatives and community mining focal persons (CMFPs), so that they would be able to present their concerns and dialogue directly with the representatives of government&#x2019;s Ministry and private sector, and asked for intervention and solution.  DPA-Extractive Industry Social and Environmental Impact (EISEI) is continuing to work with communities to improve their rights respected and received equitable benefits from extractive industry sector that enhance their livelihood conditions. The DPA-EISEI provides support services in terms of capacity building, facilitating building and strengthening network at local and national levels and facilitating multi-stakeholder dialoguesto address emerging development issues related to gender and mining impact issues.

Overall objective of this project is to mitigate the social and environmental impacts of mining on local people, include indigenous people communities, particular womenin the DPA&#x2019;s target areas.

The specific objective is to build and strengthenEISEI network and proactively collaborate with (EIGF) CSO alliance in supporting multi-stakeholder engagement and policy dialogues at national levels in order to enhance social and environmental performance and improve development and enforcement of legal framework in EI Sector.

DPA EISEI secretariat will work in Ratanakiri, Mondulkiri, Stung Treng, and Preah Vihea.

The expected outcomes and outputs of the project are:
Outcome #1:  Resource dependent communities especially women and indigenous communities are empowered to claim their rights to access to natural resources and advocate to strengthen social and environmental accountability.
&#x2022; Output 1.1: Improved knowledges, skills, capacity and networks of CSOs, IPs, Youths and Women Human Rights and Environmental Defenders for negotiations and advocacies for protection of natural resources.
&#x2022; Output 1.2: Increased participation and voices CSOs, IPs, Youths and Women Human Rights and Environmental Defenders in dialogues and or platforms to strengthen social and environmental accountability.
&#x2022; Output 1.3: Water resource dependent and mining affected communities are better organized to implement actions to protect and preserve their resources.
Outcome #2: Resource dependent communities especially women and indigenous community access to natural resource management justice, with national and international recourse and redress.
&#x2022; Output 2.1: Oxfam and partners activelyengaged to influence gender sensitivity in drafting processes of Mediation Law
&#x2022; Output 2.2: CSOs created and utilized platforms to support alternative dispute resolution mechanisms in NRM

Outcome #3: Cambodian government and private sectors improvedand enforced policies and regulations incorporating internationally recognized standards: CRS, Business and Human Rights Principles
&#x2022; Output 3. 1:  Increased CSOs&apos; participations in monitoring and reporting process of Intended Nationally Determined Contribution (INDC) and NRM related laws and policies.
&#x2022; Output 3.2:  CSOs and affected communities are aware of negative impacts from existing NRM policies and legal frameworks and are able to engage and influence policy changes to protect natural resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and Partnership in Acti</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and Partnership in Action (DPA) is a non-political, non-religious, non- partisan, non-profit making Cambodian non-governmental organization devoted to furthering community development, partnership work with Cambodian NGOs and lobbying and advocacy. DPA is the successor of CIDSE Cambodia which was established in 1979 as part of the larger CIDSE CLV programme created by a consortiumof International NGOs from Europe, Canada, Australia and New Zealand. With a mission spanning more than 25 years,the milestones andachievements of CIDSE Cambodia are significant, not least of which is moving from meeting basic daily needs of beneficiaries to focusing on strategic long-term aims of building capacity and empowering partner organizations to assist in changing their target communities lives. CIDSE Cambodia began funding CNGOS in 1993 and formally established the Partnership Programme in 1994. Due to the evolving social climate and the strong capacity and commitment of its local staff, CIDSE Cambodia decided to localize and in 1996 began a transition process which enabled the organization to emerge as DPA in January 2006. DPA assumed responsibility for all work of CIDSE Cambodia from 1 January 2006, with an emphasis on community organizing (CO) and rights-based (RB) strategies.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.5656 104.9909</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-15">18151</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">17868</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and Partnership in Acti</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">284</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam America own funds OUS</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">17868</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM USA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06895-02:KH">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000122" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002542"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007251"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Cambodia (ASIA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06895"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Strengthening EI Governance in Cambodia"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate justice activism- PS policies</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Companies (local, national and international) avoid doing harm and/or adopt credible policies and practices that advance (gendered) climate justice and promote and protect rights relevant to land and natural resources.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9910-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases of policy changes made by companies (in part) as a result of influencing activities supported</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9910-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9910-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases of practice changes made by companies (in part) as a result of influencing activities supported</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9910-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal-Priv Sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased equality &amp; equity in formal rules and practices as laid down in constitutions, laws, and policies of Private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9110-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where private sector policies are increasingly promoting equality and equity</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9110-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9110-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where private sector practices are increasingly participatory and accountable</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9110-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
