<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05868-13:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SSURA Saving lives now &amp; future Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute in strengthening the civil society organizations and alliances to claim and exercise the right to quality education, constructively participate, engage and influence peace process and policies.
2.1.1. # of Public accountability forums organized between citizens and duty bearers with &#xBD; of action points addressed or followed by CSO#s with authorities
2.1.2. # of Community meetings, dialogues supported on governance and service delivery with 40% in attendance being females
2.1.3. Improved public perceptions regarding social cohesion, reconciliation, as well as delivery and citizen engagement with authorities because of active participation and spaces created to dialogue on pertinent issues, including those related to the peace process</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-88136411" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SSURA stands for South Sudanese Refugees Association founded in Koboko &#x2013; Uganda in 2016 mindful of the need for the South Sudanese refugees in Uganda getting united, promote reconciliation and peaceful co-existence among the South Sudanese Refugees in Uganda across all tribes and the host communities of Uganda, creation and promotion of economic activities for self-reliance, advocacy and awareness on legal protection issue for the refugees in the camps, self-integrated urban refugees within the Urban communities of Uganda.

As an eyewitness to the heart-breaking situations in South Sudan, we (South Sudanese refugees in Koboko) are driven by our visionto establish a durable and sustainable progressive platform through trauma healing, peace building andpromotion of social-cultural and socio-economic diversity. Our programmes focus is on trauma healing, peace building and reconciliation, assistance to orphans and vulnerable children and elders, delivery of health and sanitation awareness at community level, skills development, and small &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; large-scale agricultural development and economic empowerment.

Since establishment, SSURA opened doors and provided conducive environment of interaction to its members through activities such as VSLAs, family visitsand traditional dances which builds on social bond among the refugees and host community.

SSURA have also acquired the following in its principal changes;
&#xF0FC; Legal status, acquired certificate of registration from Koboko Municipality.
&#xF0FC; Volunteers SSURA have retained committed volunteers/staffs and Divisions executives who carry on with its services to the refugees and host community.
&#xF0FC; Physical presence, acquired land for the office and the trauma healing centre from Koboko Municipality on right ofuse Land MOU between SSURA and Koboko Municipal Council.
&#xF0FC; Uniting the South Sudanese and the Congolese refugees&#x2019; communities in Koboko

2. ACHIEVEMENTS
What have been the principal results in the past three years that contribute to significant, structural, sustained and positive improvement in the lives of men, women, girls and boys suffering from poverty, injustice, insecurity and exclusion?

Psychosocial support aimed to improve the psychosocial well-being of refugees and host communities to promote community co-existence through addressing individual experience and creation of positiveattitudes in the community at household level.

Leadership &#x2013; in order to build a bridge between tribal leaders&#x2019; groups within the refugees&#x2019; community, to develop strong leadership structures empowered to promote peace.  SSURA in 2018 created two peace programmes,the peace cells and the tribal leaders&#x2019; reconciliation forum both in Koboko and Arua. The peace cell was at a Division level aimed at solving DomesticandGender Based Violence within the community. The tribal leaders&#x2019; reconciliation forum discussions were based onsecurity and general issues which are experienced to have been the main causes of conflict between tribes in South Sudan and in thecamps.

Itis evidenced in the daily life of SSURA&#x2019;s members and Refugees communities in Koboko and Arua that the Psychosocial programme and the creation of peace cells and tribal leaders&#x2019; forum have enabled the refugees&#x2019; communities in Koboko and Arua to freely interact across all tribes at all age groups and gender.

SSURA has been supporting affected South Sudanese with devastating situations on trauma, medical referrals from the camp to Koboko, Arua and Kampala. Deceased refugees in Koboko and Arua with no relatives and means of corps, transportation and burial arrangements. Those in police custody and facilitation of new arrivals to OPM through OPM&#x2019;s office for registration. Reconciliation and mitigation of conflicts. SSURA is currently active in mobilizationand dissemination of information to the refugees&#x2019; community.

SSURA have settled 17 domestic violence cases and those families are living happily withtestimonies of SSURA&#x2019;s positive strategy to bring peace into families within the refugees&#x2019; households

As it is at the centre of SSURA&#x2019;s heart to scale up its emergency interventions with minimal resources, SSURA mobilised vulnerable refugees and host community Women and Youth in Koboko into 28 VSLAs groups in which 27 (Twenty-seven) are Women groupsand 1 (one) Youth group. 18 of the    groups are very active and have successfully loaned money to their group members who paid back with a 5% interest.

3.    INSTITUTIONAL PURPOSE
Vision:
To establish a durable and sustainable progressive platform through peace building and promotion of social-cultural and socio-economic diversity

Mission:
Strive to empower refugees&#x2019; capacities through awareness creation, dialogues, trainings &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; advocacy on peaceful co-existence, human rights, environmental protection, sustainable livelihoods, gender and social welfare, promote smooth transition and settlement of refugees in urban areas, refugees&#x2019; settlement camps and the host communities.

Core values:
All members of SSURA shall individually and collectivelyuphold to the common vision, mission and objective through
&#xF0FC; Cohesion; is the action or fact of forming a well-integrated and united community.

&#xF0FC; Inclusiveness; the practice or policy of including people who might otherwise be excluded or marginalized, such as those who have physical or mental disabilities and members of minority groups.

&#xF0FC; Participation;  the process during which individuals, groups and organizations are consulted about or have the opportunity to become actively involved in a projector program of activity.

&#xF0FC; Transparency; is operating in such a way that it is easy for others to see what actions are performed. Transparency implies openness, communication, and accountability.

&#xF0FC; Integrity; the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles.

&#xF0FC; Commitment; the state or quality of being dedicated to a cause, activity

&#xF0FC; Accountability; the fact or condition of being accountable; responsibility.


Principle objectives
&#xF0FC; To promote reconciliation and peace building activities among the refugees.
&#xF0FC; To create and promote economic activities for self-reliance.
&#xF0FC; To strengthen capacity building programs for effective participation in the refugees&#x2019; camps.
&#xF0FC; To advocate and create awareness on legal protectionissue forthe refugees in the camps, self-integrated individuals, and urban refugees within the communities in Uganda.
&#xF0FC; To lobby and advocate for internal and external support for the association.
Field(s) of activity: What are the principal thematic and geographic areas in which the organisation works?  Who are the social actors that benefit from the work?
Thematic areas of our work: Describe what you do in each (as relevant)
&#x2022; Water Sanitation and Hygiene &#x2013; Community sanitation on solid waste management at Household level and Public places, safe water handling and use of water and awareness on safe excreta disposal including children feaces at Household level and hygiene promotional messages on critical hand washing, family compound cleanness werepassed through community meetings and house hold visits aimed at raising awareness about improved hygiene practices.

&#x2022;  Livelihoods &#x2013; VSLAs, Women groups &#x201C;Chain Link for Growth&#x201D; and Agriculture activities (Kitchen Gardens) most especially during dry season.Womenare trained to treat waste water with ashes and reuse it for moistening their vegetable gardens. Use of Organic manure for vegetables production.

&#x2022; Health &#x2013; Psychosocial support, at our trauma centre, SSURA is providing Psychosocial support counselling to affected individuals and groups of Women, Men and Youth.

&#x2022; Protection, Peace building, Social Cohesion &#x2013; Legal issues, SSURA have been following up refugees in Koboko prison and Arua Prison and presents such cases to OPM (RDO) office for such victims to be presented in court than keeping them in cell more than it is meant to be. Family tracing, SSURA have handled three cases of unaccompanied minors and reunited them with their families. SGBV, SSURA handled 3 cases of resources denial (Food ration)in which the husbands want half of the received food ration sold for their personal financial needs. SSURA intervened and helped understand the importance of the food for the family and reconciled those families who are living happily now.

&#x2022; Environment and Energy &#x2013; SSURA carried out two keep Koboko clean and green campaign in which SSURA planted 37 trees around the Koboko main Hospitals and other parts of the town as directed by the Town Mayor.

&#x2022; Education &#x2013; SSURA connected 20 refugeesYouth for course in Motor Vehicle engineering through KKT Company in Koboko and 3 Ladies for entrepreneur course through Baptist church in Jinja.


&#x2022; Others - specify
 Areas of operation:
&#xF0FC; Koboko
&#xF0FC; Arua
&#xF0FC; Bidibidi
4. STRATEGIC POSITIONING
Analysethe environment in which the organisation works? Who are the other relevant social actors, including government and business, and what roles do they play? In this context, what is unique about the position of the organisation?
SSURA work in conducive environmentaswell it has unique designed program with community high demanded for, the trauma healing, women and youth economic empowerment, kitchen gardening and youth social activities.

SSURA works in collaboration with other social actors namely: ACAV, CERID&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; CECI.Finance institution like such Centenary Bank and Koboko United Sacco, and the local government of Koboko Municipal Council and Koboko District Authority

ACAV take solid responsibility of empowering SSURA with technical guardians and working together on developing projects for community response, as well it includes space for store of SSURA&#x2019;s stocks.

 CERID, CECI and CORA, those are partnerswhom SSURA planned its activities together to avoid duplication of activities and share other relevant information that benefits the social living of both refugees and the host community

Finance institution such as Centenary bank is the institution where SSURA is banking in while Koboko SACCO help in building up VSLA/YSLA on finance management.

KobokoMunicipal Council has been working together with SSURA as well Koboko municipal gave SSURA piece of land for hosting the Trauma healing other activities which SSURA is rendering to both the host and the refugees community.

 Koboko district authority has been positive coordination since from the influx of the refugees and has been help for linkages with other districts where refugees face challenges and deserve some help, and it hadbeen helping the refugees community on awareness on thelaws governing the country and its interventions during the COVID 19 challenges the self-settled refugees are facing.

The uniqueness of SSURA is on its community approaches, innovations and intervention, SSURA with the trauma healing centre which is the only institution responding to both the refugees and the host communities in Koboko including some trauma cases and domestic violence which were referred from the camp. SSURA has well designed peace building strategies which enhance community involvement and participation where necessary.



5. FUNCTIONAL ORGANISATIONAL CHART include below your organisational chart)
How are authority and responsibilities structured? For each operational unit, indicate the job titles, number ofpeople in each position, andif they are men or women.





























 ORGANS OF SSURA
SSURA has the following organs:
&#xF0D8; The general assembly (GA) is the supreme authority of the Association/Agency answers, to her questions and inquiries.
The generalassembly of consist of 36 members (22 females and 14 males)
FUNCTIONS AND DUTIES OF THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY (GA)
The functions of the general assembly are stipulated below:
&#xF0FC; It comprises of registered members who regularly conform to pay their monthly subscription after fulfilling all conditions and eligibilities.
&#xF0FC; It&#x2019;s the supreme authority of association/Agency.
&#xF0FC; It has the right to demand for the amendment of the constitution either by adding or eliminating some clauses within the constitution.
&#xF0FC; It is entitled with the power to discuss and approve polices, plans and the staffs operational manual of the association/Agency in accordance with its objectives.
&#xF0FC; It has the power to suspend membership of a member or dismisses him/her.
&#xF0FC; Monitors and reviews the implementation plan of discussed reports to the association/Agency.

Position  Sex
Chairperson  M
V/chairperson  F
Secretary  M
Vice Secretary  F
Treasurer  F
Member 19 F
Member 12 M

&#xF0D8; The board of directors(BOD) isthe sub-supreme organ of the Association/Agency and has 11 members where 7 are males and 4 are females
BOD shall perform the following roles:
&#xF0A7; The BOD consist of eleven (11) members drawn from competent and different skills within the generalassembly
&#xF0A7; TheBOD is the sub-supreme organ of the association/Agency.
&#xF0A7; This board is to report to the general assembly.
&#xF0A7; Provide leadership with policy and guardians.
&#xF0A7; Ensure that, SSURA&#x2019;s polices, plans and programs aslaid down by the general assembly are executed through the managerial body and ensure that these policies are adhered to.
&#xF0A7; Approves, monitor the budget presented by SSURA&#x2019;s (EC) managerial body.
&#xF0A7; Reports SSURA&#x2019;S activities to the general assembly for endorsement.
&#xF0A7; Appoint auditors andapprove audited reports of the association/Agency.
&#xF0A7; Appoint sub-committees and other special adhoc committees when need arise.
&#xF0A7; Recommend termination and promotion of any Executive Committee member for job well done of staff of the association.
&#xF0A7; Draw up together with the Executive Director of the association/Agency agenda for general assembly meetings including dates, time and venues.
&#xF0A7; Deal with all disciplinary matters and actions to SSURA executive.
&#xF0A7; Calls for extra ordinary meetings if recommended by 50+1 of its members.
&#xF0A7; The board members will contribute 50,000shs every month for running the administration cost.
&#xF0A7; Lobby and advocate for funding.
&#xF0A7; To give, professional advice to SSURA general assembly or managerial body on matters relating to programs and provide linkages among SSURA structures.
&#xF0A7; Resolve issues declared contentious by the chairperson.
&#xF0A7; Attend annual general meetings.

Position  # members  Sex Destination
Chairperson  01  M  Koboko
V/chairperson  01  FArua
Secretary  01  MKoboko
Treasurer 01  F  Arua
Member 02  F  Arua
Member  01 M  Arua
Member  04  M  Koboko

&#xF0D8; The technical Advisors (TA) The primary purpose of the Committee is to assist the Board in fulfilling its oversight responsibilities on specific technical matters which are beyond the scope or expertise of non-technical Board members.
The technical committee has 5 members, 3 females and 2 men

Functions of the technical advisor:
&#x2022; Understand the nature and scope of work assigned by the boardof directors.
&#x2022; Learn committee objectives and goals.
&#x2022; Attend and actively participate in all scheduled committee meetings and conference calls.
&#x2022; Offer unbiased recommendations and work for the good of the organization and membership.
&#x2022;Respond to communicationsfrom chair and staff liaison in a timely manner.
&#x2022; Provideinput to IA staff and committee leadership upon request.
&#x2022; Recuse them when their company&#x2019;s mission is in direct conflict with the focus of the committee.
&#x2022; Review supplied materials for discussion (if any) prior to meetings or conference calls.
&#x2022; Seek guidance and direction from committee chair.
&#x2022; Report to committee chair.
&#x2022; Responsible for expenses to attend meetings.
Position  # members  Sex  Destination
Chairperson  01  F  Koboko
v/chairperson  01  M  Arua
Secretary  01 M   Koboko
Treasurer  01  F  Arua
Member  01  F Koboko

&#xF0D8; The executive committee (EC) is the implementing and managing organ of the association/agency.
THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE (EC)

The executive committee shall comprise of members according the project and perform the following:
  Is the implementing organ of the association/Agency
  It produces all the narrative reports of the association/Agency on its success of the projects.
  Is responsible forall the assets and all the liabilities of the association/Agency.
  Is responsible for any association assessment or survey for the identification of a project within the operational area.
  It is responsible for all the accountabilities, internal and external audit of all the finances of the association/Agency.
  It is responsible for daily implementation of activities of the association/Agency.

Position  # staffs (volunteers) Sex  Destinations
Executive director  01  M  Koboko
Program manager  01  MKoboko
Program assistant  01  F  Koboko
Trauma healing coordinator  01  M  Koboko
Livelihood coordinator  01  M  Koboko
Program Unit manager01  M  Arua
Program Unit manager 01  M  Yumbe
Program Unit manager 01  M  Adjumani
Finance assistant  01F  Koboko
Finance assistant 01  F  Arua
Finance assistant  01  F  Yumbe
Human resource  01  F  Koboko
Information officer  01  F  Arua
Procurement  01  M  Koboko
Trauma Healing officer  01  F  Arua
Agric Assistant  01  F  Koboko



6. CURRENTBALANCE SHEET/FINANCIAL POSITION
Oxfam Novib requires information about what the organisation owns, debts that you must pay and your net financial worth. Therefore, we ask for a balance sheet (available in Microsoft Excel) foryour entire organisation asit stands at the end of your two most recent fiscal years.


Approved by (head of the organisation)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudanese Refugees Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.41362 30.95998</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-07">9000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">9000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudanese Refugees Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">9000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05868-13:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001728"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05868"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Saving lives now &amp;future thru education"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-07-15" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-07-15" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
