<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-000167</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transforming  attitudes about women&apos;s rights</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM program ID PROG10144

Gender Justice is an outcome and a process that places Oxfam in Nigeria#s work for gender equality in the context of a rights-based approach. The programme has both stand-alone components and is also mainstreamed across programmes: These include the following components:

Women#s Participation and Transformative Leadership (WPTL);
Violence Against Women and Girls (VAWG);
Women#s Economic Empowerment (WEE) and
Gender Mainstreaming

Our Women#s Participation and Transformative Leadership(WPTL) ensures that women participate in and gain equally and meaningfully from all development and humanitarian programs. WPTL aims to strengthen women#s individual and collective power to end poverty and challenge inequalities. Based on our understanding of the diverse barriers, including social restrictions that limit women#s participation and leadership, our approach to this is through the VSLA systems that creates safe spaces for women to save, organise and influence their households and the society.

Our Preventing Violence Against Women and Girls (VAWG) aims atending violence against women and girls requires changes in laws and policies as well as in individual and collective beliefs, attitudes and behaviours on women#s rolesandrights.We will seek to build collective power and create strategic community of champions (men and women) who would promote zero tolerance and non-acceptance of violence against women in our ENOUGH Campaign. The national approach is targeted at advocating for the domestication of theVAPP Act 2015 in the States of the Federation; while advocating for the passage of the GEOB Bill.

Our Women#s Economic Empowerment (WEE)seeks to implement targeted programmes that increase women&apos;s access to resources to build sustainable livelihoods. It also seeks to build the capacity of women small-holder farmers to change negative cultural beliefs, influence policy formulation and encourage other women.

Our Gender Mainstreaming will be adopted throughout the whole Gender justice program. What itmeans is that major gender considerations and related actions will be integrated. A focus will be given to methodologies such as RCA, GALS to challenge unequal power relations, unpaid care analysis that prevent women from participating in social and economic activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl/Mission-and-vision">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
