<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06606-05:NG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BudgIT-F4ALL Extractives &amp; Fiscal Just</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BudgIT, is a civic tech organisation founded in 2011 to raise the standards of transparency and accountability in public finance. Since inception, the organisation has applied technology to meld citizen engagement and institutional improvement, with the aim of enabling societal change.

BudgIT employs a wide range of creative tools and the social media to simplify the budget and public expenditure for citizens, consequently raising standards of transparency and accountability in Government. BudgIT partners with civil
society organizations, public institutions and the media, mainly in the areas of fiscal analysis, civic technology and data presentation.

Our unique approach includes deploying data mining skill sets to creatively represent informationusing infographics and empower citizens to use the information to articulate their demands for service delivery. Furthering its advocacy to reach the hearts of the people in the grassroots is TRACKA - a project tracking tool that allows citizens monitor developmental projects in their communities. Created in 2014, this web and mobile platform is currently operational in 22 States (one field officer in each State), and bridges the communication gap between elected representatives and their people, thus ensuring the completion of projects at grassroots level. Through a series of workshops, regular publication of infographics and social media engagement, TRACKA has kept State and Local Governments on their toes in the past year, fast tracking service delivery, and aims to expand its thematic and geographical scope in the nearest future.

For three years, BudgIT has also led advocacy campaigns to achieve Nigeria#s membership on the global Open Partnership initiative. In 2016,Governance Nigeria formally joined the Open Government Partnership by sending a letter of intent to the OGP Global Secretariat. BudgIT was actively involved in the development of Nigeria#s first National Action Plan which is a strategy document with actionable commitments that Nigeria (civil society, government and private sector) will work on within a period of two (2) years. BudgIT is currently the secretariat of the Open Alliance - a coalition of over 100 civil society organisation working on the OGP in Nigeria. The Open Alliance hasbeen the forerunner of OGP in Nigeria from the days of advocacy for membership.

In partnership with the Nigeria Extractive Industries Initiative (NEITI) and Natural Resource Governance Institute (NRGI), BudgIT recorded remarkable success in bringing attention to the extractives industry, particularly with the #FixOurOil campaign. The activity has further opened up the workings of the oil and gas sector, simultaneously unmasking various economic opportunities that lie in the solid minerals sector.
The Power of Voices Partnership (PvP) is an influencing programme with the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs. The programme  FAIR for ALL led by Oxfam Novib is five year long initiative implemented jointly with consortium members Huairou Commission, SOMO and Third World Network-Africa (TWN-Africa) aimed at supporting and collaborating with people&#x2019;s rightful demands towards companies, governments and multilateral organizations for economic, social and environmental justice, promoting global trade and value-chains that are fair for all. The main focus of the FAIR for ALL programme proposal is to support and strengthen CSOs to play their diverse roles; as educators, mobilizers, creators and watchdogs to make trade and value chains FAIR for ALL.

In Nigeria, FAIR for ALL programme aims at strengthening capacity and raising awareness about the socio-economic costs associated with the Nigerian extractives sector, while advocating for improved governance to ensure that firms in the sector operate in a mannerthat respects human rights and is conflict sensitive. In addition, the programme will influence policy debates and initiatives to ensure sustained and prudent management of tax revenue and other revenues from the extractive sector, and promote accountability in delivering publicservices.

The Nigeria FAIR for ALL programme will be implemented by Oxfam in Nigeria and partners, aiming to: 1) Mobilize citizensand strengthen capacities of local organizations to increase the level of accountability of public actors; 2) Monitor state budgetsand build strong alliances (in particular with women&#x2019;s organizations) towards a well-regulated extractive sector, ensuring better management of natural resources, and more transparent public-private deals; and ensure 3) Fair and inclusive trade and fiscal systems, with proper taxation of extractive industries and investment of revenues through pro-poor spending in basic services. These objectives will be achieved by increased knowledge on public finance management, including overall fiscal knowledge and literacy on publicbudgets and government expenses, and increasing capacity to foster citizens&#x2019;participation in budget processes. To achieve main objectives of the programme in Nigeria, Oxfam will collaborate with BudgIT</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BUDGIT FOUNDATION FOR PROMOT. OF IN</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BudgIT Information Technology Network (BudgIT), established in 2011, initially conceptualized and developed in Nigeria#s foremost technology hub, Co-Creation Hub, has a core goal of making the Nigerian budget simpler and accessible for the average citizen. The availability of budgets in non-readable pdf formats on the government website provided an initial opportunity for BudgIT to stretch forward its innovative idea, by simplifying the budgets using infographics and interactive applications. BudgIT, with over 3 million web views and 112,000 unique users (mostly digitally literate users) believes that active participation in government finance is a key to a functional society. Citizens need to know how government revenues are expended in the delivery of public infrastructure, meeting debt obligations or funding the recurrent component of the budget. And they need to know this in a clear, timely and transparentmanner.

BudgIT (yourbudgit.com) operates based on the principles of open data which stimulates transparency, accountability and better outcomes in the private and public sectors. Open access to data has proven capable of illuminating issues and expanding the inclusion of citizens in informed debates. However, wrong handling of data in open formats can throw facts in a context which wrongly informs or communicates nothing. BudgIT#s goal of innovation is about making public data a social object, and building an extensive network of active citizens that demand institutional change. Currently BudgIThas offices in Lagos, has 16 staff members and 6 volunteers.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">63137</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">62332</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">43632</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-08-01">18700</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">63137</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Dutch SP D&amp;D Lobby&amp;Advocacy</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BUDGIT FOUNDATION FOR PROMOT. OF IN</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">63137</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004319" ref="XM-DAC-7">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs NL</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06606-05:NG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000181" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001871"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007155"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Nigeria (SAWA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06606"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="FAIR4ALL Extractives &amp; Fiscal Justice NG"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2300</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Governments &amp; global actors: # cases where Oxfam/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies holding (sub)national governments or global actors to account for inequality &amp; pover</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">cases where Oxfam/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies holding (sub)national governments or global actors to account for inequality &amp; poverty -DD2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of events held during the reportig period.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2300</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved policies Governments &amp; global actors: # cases where Oxfam/partners influencing has contributed to adopting and/or implementing improved gender sensitive policies holding (sub)national governments or global actors to account for inequality &amp; pover</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2300-A</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners in support of development/adoption of alternative policies/approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2300-A" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of media products produced: video, research, blogposts, infographics, communication materials.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2300-B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">pieces of evidence (documents, studies, videos, testimonies etc.) produced by Oxfam Novib and partners to support monitoring of practices and implementation of policies by governments and global actors</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2300-B" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">All news articles</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-02"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
