<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-05868-12:UG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UCLF Saving Lives now &amp; future Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute in strengthening the civil society organizations and alliances to claim and exercise the right to quality education, constructively participate, engage and influence peace process and policies.
2.1.1. # of Public accountability forums organized between citizens and duty bearers with &#xBD; of action points addressed or followed by CSO#s with authorities
2.1.2. # of Community meetings, dialogues supported on governance and service delivery with 40% in attendance being females
2.1.3. Improved public perceptions regarding social cohesion, reconciliation, as well as delivery and citizen engagement with authorities because of active participation and spaces created to dialogue on pertinent issues, including those related to the peace process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-88136411" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="24">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Christian Lawyers Fraternity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Christian Lawyers&#x2019; Fraternity is an association of Christian legal professionals which was started in 1987 as a fellowship of Christian law students and was registered as NGO in 2005, and has since grown to about 500 members who are working in allfacets ofthe Justice, Law and Order Sector.  Our vision is a world where justice and human dignity is a reality for all and our mission is to share our faith in Christ Jesus, promote access to justice and the respect for human dignity, through speaking up, fellowship, mentorship and defending the rights of the vulnerable.

UCLF runs established Legal Aid Clinics and offices spread across the Northern,Western and Central regions of Uganda with a presence in Kampala, Kayunga, Kasese, Gulu, Masaka, Buikwe and Moyo Districts.

UCLF uses a rights-based approach in order to address the underlying causes of injustices, including patriarchy, poverty and social exclusion. We have an established track record in the delivery of civil legal aid, criminal defence, paralegal advisory services, community legal education and policy advocacy.

UCLF is committed to significant change in the lives of women, girls, boys, and men and recognizes the distinction between genders of all ages in the areas of operation. UCLF strives to mainstream gender equality throughout all programs and across all departments to ensure that the different needs of women, girls, boys, and men are met. The organization takes a pro-active approach to promote gender equality as an essential step in the protection of women, girls&#x2019;, boys&#x2019; and men&#x2019;s basic human rights. UCLF&apos;s gender policy incorporates approaches to mainstream gender equality through all programs to ensure the needs of male and female beneficiaries are met. The direct result ofthese activities is that community members, particularly women, have increased ability to identify, assess and address root causes of conflicts, and gender-based violence in their communities while the longer-term impact is to contribute to the promotionof gender equality and empowerment of women and girls. UCLF ensures that not only will there be equitable participation of both men and women, but that both can be equitably involved in design, monitoring and evaluation.

Women make up the biggest number of the Staff and the Board of UCLF. UCLF&#x2019;s current Board is comprises of 5 women against 2 men. The staff are 13 women against 10 men.

UCLF has undergone all stages of Organisational development as explained bellow
In the recent three years UCLF implemented the Paralegal Advisory Services, free legal representation, Alternative Dispute Resolution, Environmental Justice program, community legal rights awareness and offering psycho social counselling programs, where there were 22,210 direct beneficiaries and 720,000 indirect beneficiaries in 2017//2018, and 17,384 direct beneficiaries and 2,062,000 indirect beneficiaries in 2019/2020. Most of the beneficiaries were women and children or juveniles.

Institutional Purpose
Vision: A world where justice and human dignity is reality for all.

Mission: We are an association of Christian legal professionals sharing our faith in Christ, promoting access to justice and respect for human dignity through speaking up, fellowship, mentorship and defending the rights if the vulnerable.

Core values
We are committed to upholding the Christian faith and its principles of:  christian ethics and integrity, justice, equity, compassion, peaceful resolution of conflicts, good governance, fellowship, professionalism, volunteerism, diversity and respect of different cultures.

Principle objectives
&#x2022; To inform and educate people (especially those who have no access to legal information), about the law and their rights.
&#x2022; To advocate for, represent and advice, those who have no voice and unfairly disadvantaged.
&#x2022; To advocate for the enhancement and implementation of fair laws and policies which are in harmony with Christian principles.
&#x2022; To encourage member participation in ethical legal practices and communityinvolvement by providing probono opportunities.

Strategic Positioning;
UCLF has an established secretariat and regional offices that offer conducive facilities to staff inthe performance of their Work.

UCLF is the only organization in Uganda thatbrings together lawyers and judicial officers, most of whom hold key positions of leadership that will be capitalized on in implementing this project.

UCLF has active formal partnershipswith key Justice Law and Order Sectors (JLOS Uganda), the District Local Governments (DLGs), the Ministry of Gender, Labor and Social Development, a long spanning working relationship with the Uganda Prisons Services, the Office of the Prime Minister, the Uganda Police Force, the Ministry of Gender, Labour and Social Development, and the Judiciary.

In respect to this project, the above institutions will be contacted where there is need for resource persons to train from the said institutions, the Police will also be relevant in partnering with UCLF in community policing within refugee camps and host communities. UCLF will also engage the Office of the Prime Minister during sensitizations in the gaps and they be consulted where any relevant information is required within the camps.

Additionally, it is accredited by the Uganda Law Council as a legal aid service provider in Uganda.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.31569 32.57811</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to life and security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="1" vocabulary="2"></tag>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-26">9000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">9000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS) back donor</narrative>
   </description>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Christian Lawyers Fraternity</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-01">9000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">incoming transaction</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-88136411" ref="DK-CVR-88136411">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Denmark (IBIS)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-05868-12:UG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000101" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1001728"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007104"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Uganda (HECA)"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-05868"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Saving lives now &amp;future thru education"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict -DD5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-07-15" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3220</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened CSOs: # CSOs increasingly participate in or initiate influencing and advocacy efforts to contribute to conflict transformation/address root causes of conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">organisations supported with means (financial,  knowledge, skills, networks, training etc.) to strengthen capacity in specific areas -DD6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-07-15" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="11">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Achieved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
