<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27108436-A-06963-03:MZ</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CO-506575</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is being implemented in a context where the education sector in Mozambique presents numerous challenges. On the one hand, the quality of teaching is very low, characterized mainly by the inability of boys and girls in primary education to know how to read and write and on the other hand, by the fact that access to the right to education for all is far from being a reality. The lack of access to primary education affects mostly young girls, particularly those who come from rural areas. Social norms and negativegender stereotypes are one of the main factors for poor access to education for young girls. The Education for Active Citizenship implemented since 2018, an initiative that aims to mobilize communities, through school councils to challenge harmful social norms for the full development of girls in order to ensure access and retention of girls in Primary Schools. The project benefited more than11,000 school council members and resulted in significant changes in the functioning of schoolsand, above all, in the reduction of school drop-out rates for girls, thus offering opportunities for girls to dream of a promising future. The project ended its implementation at the end of 2019 and in order to ensure the consolidation of good practices in working with school council to improve access and retention in primary Schools to serve as evidence for advocacy, Oxfam Mozambique and Oxfam Hong Kong agreed to design an initiative, lasting one year, with the aim of contributing to girls and boys having access to an inclusive and quality education, based on the previous experience of working with school councils. The project will focus on the collection, documentation of evidence at the local level that will later be systematized and documented to serve as a basis for influencing education authorities at the localand national level, an will be implemented in Zamb&#xE9;zia proncice in 3 selected Distric of Nicoadala, Maganja da Costa and MIlange, and will cover directly proximately 800 school Council Members. The quality education Moz 2 project aims to improve skills and competences of students in the first cycle of primary school.
Outcome 1: Improving the pedagogical performance of students through retention and completion of student in the first and second cycle of primary education and the active participation of SC in school management and pedagogy of the school.
Outcome 2: Improved school management capacity, quality service delivery in schools, through improved school environment and accountabilityby education service providers. To achieve this goal, we shall combine three key priority areas of actions: dismantling the barriers to access to education including sanitation facilities such as latrines and toilets for students and improving the reading and writing students competences; strengthening the capacity of participation of School Council; and improving and strengthening and school managers governance. Oxfam will play a crucial role of identifying opportunities for sharing experience, lobbies and advocacy, as well as  establishing strategic links between the Implementing partner with the different stakeholders, as well as providing technical and strategic support to the implementing partner so that the objectives of the initiative are achieved. apart from that, Oxfam will strengthen capacity of partners and stakeholders with engagement tools (CPC) to The projectproposes to use the dialogue and civic engagement tool named Community Score Card (CPC). CPC is community-based monitoring tool, usedtoreinforce accountability and the responsibility of service providers and social and public accountability. Through the inclusionin this process of dialogue meeting between service providers and the community, this tool allows immediate feedback. And theCPC process also serves to train citizens and the groups involved, in addition to producing consistent information on the quality of public services provided.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM HONGKONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib is one of the 17 national affiliates of the Oxfam International Confederation. It started life in 1956 as the Netherlands Organisation for International Assistance (Novib), and joined forces with Oxfam in 1994.  Working together in confederation, the Oxfam affiliates can speak with one clear and compelling voice on issues of global concern: climate change, health and education forall, agriculture, trade, and conflicts and emergencies.  Oxfam established this country office to support local organizations and projects.  Through this local office Oxfam Novib directly contributes towards this project&#x92;s implementation.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">end-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">start-planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@oxfamnovib.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.oxfamnovib.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PO box 30919, 2500 GX The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <point srsName="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-18.665 35.52956</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="http://www.oxfamnovib.nl">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The right to social and political participation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">9250</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-05-01">6047</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Hong Kong own funds OHK</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-01">3203</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Hong Kong own funds OHK</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://atlas.oxfamnovib.nl/#/project/A-06963-03:MZ">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atlas project browser</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27108436-000161" type="1"></related-activity>
  <legacy-data name="grant-reference" value="1002609"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="oxfamnovib-view-type" value="EXT"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre" value="0000007302"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="profit-centre-name" value="CO: Mozambique SAWA"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project" value="A-06963"></legacy-data>
  <legacy-data name="project-name" value="Quality Education Project Moz II"></legacy-data>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civ Space-Strenght CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society actors transformed and strengthened,</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-6</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO actors that build trust and work in inclusive way in coalitions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-6" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO that improved their acccess to flexible resources to actively address, reclaim and navigate civic space offline and online, involving and considering esp. marginalized groups</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-2" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs that strengthened the links with their constituencies due to changed ways of working</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-1" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with improved risk strategies and improves support when a civic space crisis occurs</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-4" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-5</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs with increased women and youth in leadership positions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-5" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">9220-3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">informal movements/individuals with access to flexible resources to address, reclaim and navigate civic space offline and/or online</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="9220-3" indicator-uri="https://oxfam.box.com/s/2l7ktb7otlfcoflkmqp9gp4eg68oexgn" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2022-04-01" value="0" year="2022"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
