<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BAN224</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raising awareness and advocacy to tackle violence against women</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a small solidarity grant to support Naripokkho and help to strengthen CAFOD&apos;s gender justice work in Bangladesh. Narripokkho are a member based women&apos;s activist organisation committed to the advancement of women&apos;s rights and entitlements, while building resistance against violence, discrimination and injustice.   This funding will support Naripokkho&apos;s activism around the issue of violence against women in Bangladesh, and will aim to raise the issues faced by survivors of sexual abuse and rape, including the issue of honour, family and societal exclusion and treatment of survivors. 
The grant will support work on a project called the Forgotten Women of 1971 which is supporting survivors of rape and sexual assault during Bangladesh liberation war. Many of these women were rejected by their family and community, and are living in extreme poverty. Naripokkoho and likeminded organisations have worked tirelessly to advocate for the Government of Bangladesh (GoB) to recognise these survivors as &apos;freedom fighters&apos; a term used in Bangladesh to recognise a persons sacrifice to Bangladesh during the 1971 war. As a result of this work by Naripokkho, the GoB has recognised these women as freedom fighters, giving them access to government welfare support allowance. This grant will help to fund a documentary which will raise awareness on the extremely challenging and poor conditions the women live in and be used to advocate for the way survivors of rape and sexual abuse are seen and treated in Bangladesh society. It will be an important advocacy tool to challenge issues of honour and treatment of women more widely in Bangladeshi society. 
Th</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BAN224" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BAN224" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Naripokkho</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BAN224" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">14993</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54785">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-03">14993</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
