<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-BAN234</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Doritry (Mother Earth-A Project on Eco-enterprise development and marketing (vermi compost)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh is a densely populated and agricultural country. About 70% of the total population live in rural areas and is dependent on agriculture. However, 80 percent of this farming population is small farmers with less than one acre of land. The widespread use of pesticides and fertilizers are contributing to degraded soil of the arable lands.
The proposed working area is 42 villages from 14 wards of 2 unions in Agailjahara sub-district under Barishal, in Bangladesh. The working area has high vulnerability to impact of environment degradation.
The problems identified will be addressed through the use of vermi-compost, an excellent soil conditioner, enhancer and bioactive fertilizer for the vegetables and crops in the immediate community as a whole. Vermi-composting turns &#x201C;waste&#x201D; organic materials, such as the huge domestic debris, food residuals and other bio-degradable materials, into a valuable product (vermi-compost) that enhances soil by increasing its porosity, water-holding capacity, texture and reduces erosion. Vermi-compost also helps vegetable plants and other crops grow bigger, increase crop yield, and decreases plant diseases and pest attacks.
Hence there is huge potential to develop and sustain the agro ecology practices and natural resources systems including livelihood enhancement of climate vulnerable communities through producing and using vermi compost and reducing utilization of agro chemical fertilizer and pesticides. This supports pro-poor and pro-environmental development in line with attaining the SDGs and Bangladesh Biodiversity Act, 2017; Safe Food Policy in Bangladesh 2016, Agriculture policy in Bangladesh 2018 of Bangladesh Government. In view of that the project is intended to support sustainable development of vulnerable community by using natural resources and promotion of organic agriculture in the face of climate change impacts</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="BAN234" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Bangladesh Central Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="BAN234" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="BAN234" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">33097</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55839">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-10">26824</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="55900">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-15">6273</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
