<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-160254</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the development of selected agro-food value chains</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ministry of Industry in its letter dated 31.10.2016 to the UNIDO regional representative gave its support for the implementation of the project. The Italian Agency for Development Cooperation confirmed its availability to finance the project.  Since 2011, UNIDO has been supporting the agro-industrial sector through the CELEP project by helping local micro and small industries to cope with the crisis and training unemployed affected communities on market oriented professional skills in technical sectors. Through the three phases of CELEP 68 SMEs and 20 agricultural cooperatives were directly supported with specialized equipment, civil works and technical assistance.  Building on this UNIDO#s expertise, the project will mainly consist on providing direct technical assistance to selected agro-processing micro, small- and medium-enterprises (M&lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt;SMEs), beekeepers and agricultural cooperatives, specifically in the dairy and apiculture sectors. At this end, the project will build upon the Creative Lebanon initiative that, established within the framework of UNIDO projects, is currently proving market access support to project beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITALY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-160254" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="LB" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beirut</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.88894 35.49442</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="LB" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.854721 35.862285</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
