<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200268</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adoption of Smart Urban Technologies in Tehran</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project contributes to enhancing the knowledge and capacities of the network of organizations and actors participating in the planning and delivery of smart, sustainable and low carbon infrastructure at the urban scale through an integrated technical assistance program of support in areas of policy advice, planning, knowledge sharing and technology demonstration. The project makes specific contribution to UNIDO result area 1: Polices and Strategies for ISID and Result Area 2: Conducive Industrial Ecosystems. The project benchmark Tehran as a smart city and assist in evaluating the Smart Tehran Program (STP). The project will give the city exposure to international city rankings, and options for smart applications in planning and infrastructure. The project will provide technical assistance to development of the second phase of the STP as well as air pollution reduction strategies. The preparatory assistance will be used to elaborate the specific theory of change and a more detailed program of work for delivering knowledge and capacities in the three focal areas of leadership, levers of change and action plans. UNIDO offers its expertise in technical cooperation, capacity building and knowledge management for tailor-made solutions as well as access to financial mechanisms to support the transition to sustain</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regular Programme Of Technical Cooperati</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-200268" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iran (Islamic Republic of)</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.427908 53.688046</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="IR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tehran</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.69439 51.42151</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
