<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-140405</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Mozambique&apos;s SMEs in Investment Promotion</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project responds to the requests received by UNIDO ITPO Italy from the Government of Mozambique, through CPI # the Centre for Promotion of Investments, to support Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs), as the development of strong and competitive SMEs has a strategic role in the process of sustainable growth in Mozambique. The objective of the project is to support the Mozambican Government to increase local and National production and improve the competitiveness of Mozambique SMEs thought technology transfers and investment promotion. UNIDO ITPO Italy will promote investment opportunities, innovation and techniques, as well as efficient technologies to improve SMEs competitiveness and increase production in the Beira, Nacala and Zamb&#xE9;zia Economic corridors. It will also act as an honest broker in the identification &lt;(&gt;&amp;&lt;)&gt; formulation of Investment Projects for Mozambican SMEs and to promote them within the UNIDO ITPO Italy network and in the International business community. Following project activities, assisted SMEs will be strengthened and geared to local, National and International markets. In addition, as a consequence of technology transfers occurred in the project framework, raw materials will be converted into marketable products and manufacturing inputs. The project will contribute to the Millenni</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITALY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-140405" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="MZ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maputo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-25.96553 32.58322</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="MZ" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-18.665695 35.529562</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
