<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-130164</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41123" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparation of Feasibility Study &amp; Business Plan for Piloting Integrated Agro-Food Parks (IAFP) in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia has high potential for agricultural-led economic growth. However, its Agro-Industrial development is still in its infancy. At the production level, output is hindered by low-input, low value-added, limited marketing infrastructure and subsistence-oriented practices. At the processing level, most food processors operate well below capacity # many operate at less than 60 percent # and their products often to have difficulties complying with international quality standards.  In response to the current situation, the Government of Ethiopia requested UNIDO to assist in the development of its Agro-Industrial sector. UNIDO agreed to develop a business plan for an Integrated Agro-Food Park (IAFP).  An Integrated Agro-Food Park (IAFP) is a cluster of independent firms grouped together to share infrastructure, (i.e., roads, power, communication, etc.) and to exploit the opportunities for joint buying, selling, training, extension services and other synergies which can arise from shared efforts.  The concentration of activities and services in one area is expected to facilitate economies of scale for the transformation of agricultural products for export or further commercialization. IAFPs will lead to increased competitiveness of the agri-food sector, while including smallholders farmers and processing businesse</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ITALY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-41123-PROJECT-130164" ref="XM-DAC-41123" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Industrial Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ET" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addis Aba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.02497 38.74689</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ET" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.145 40.489673</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
