<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41215393-CO4006</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018 CO4006 Peace Circus</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Peace Circus focuses on the deconstruction of a culture of violence in one of Colombia&#xB4;s most violent departments. While fostering the construction of relations build on respect, democracy, tolerance and non-violence, in an environment where children will feel protected, can dream and play again, and start thinking about a future outside the conflict.War Child&#xB4;s Peace Circus will be a major boost to territorial peace. Ten villages of Putumayo will participate in the transformation of their schools and communities. An eye catching Peace Circus tent will travel consecutively for 3 years from village to village, unfolding innovative peace education practices. Children and teachers will embrace peace through creativity, visual arts, acrobat performances, theater, music, dance, and more. Within three years 2,400 children and 100 teachers will actively participate in the Peace Circus, generating positive transformations in their schools and villages.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To create change one has to be creative, innovative and think outside the box. Or, in this case, inside the tent. Welcome to The Peace Circus - a peacebuilding collaboration between H&amp;M Foundation and War Child. The Peace Circus focuses on the deconstruction of a culture of violence in one of Colombia&#xB4;s most violent departments. While fostering the construction of relations build on respect, democracy, tolerance and non-violence, in an environment where children will feel protected, can dream and play again, and start thinking about a future outside the conflict. War Child&#xB4;s Peace Circus will be a major boost to territorial peace. Ten villages of Putumayo will participate in the transformation of their schools and communities. An eye catching Peace Circus tent will travel consecutively for 3 years from village to village, unfolding innovative peace education practices. Children and teachers will embrace peace through creativity, visual arts, acrobat performances, theater, music, dance, and more. Within three years 2,400 children and 100 teachers will actively participate in the Peace Circus, generating positive transformations in their schools and villages. The participation of girls will be encouraged. Children will have strengthened their life skills and artistic competences opting for peaceful coexistence. The teachers will be trained in peace education and equipped with creative tools adapted to the local context. The Peace Circus will, from the outset, be a project oriented toward the sustainability and transfer of skills to the communities. War Child will engage in advocacy on the importance of guaranteeing systems of governance that provide quality education and protection in vulnerable rural schools at the national and local level</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-CO4006" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-CO4006" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-BLV-802479-5828" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Partnerships and Grants</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>+31 (20) 422 7777</telephone>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmholtzstraat 61G, 1098 LE , Amsterdam, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Putumayo</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2018  HMF01 CO4006 E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">72933</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure linked to code HMF01. Reporting period: 2018 Calendar Year. Updated: 2019/11/04</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-CO4006" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2019  HMF01 CO4006 E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">101778</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure linked to code HMF01. Reporting period: 2019 Calendar Year. Updated: 2019/11/04</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-CO4006" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41215393-HMF01" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
