<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41215393-LK4004</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018 LK4004 WC023 Strengthen Mental Health Systems | Relating Rights and Expanding Opportunities of Children and Youth in Post Conflict Settings</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Though ten years have gone through since the conflict is over in Sri Lanka, the review and analysis of youth empowerment, child rights and violations, primary duty bearers and their roles and responsibilities, capacity and abilities to implement obligations as well as the relationship between right holders and duty bearers, should be considered against a solid understanding of the country&#x2019;s inherited and fast changing context to better respond to the needs of children and youth particularly in the North, especially with the reference to mental health and welfare. The prevailing political context following decades of armed conflict, Tsunami has revealed changes in government followed by several changes across ministerial portfolios, changes in existing systems, structures, committees including the creation of new departments, ministries consuming excessive time and resources. This has been further hindrances the lives of the children. All this has added to the confusion for those involved in work on youth empowerment, child welfare and monitoring including government officials themselves and the public health sectors. Unaddressed psychological issues further block youth and children to enjoy their educational rights, healthy environment, and to take part in the decision making process. By considering all these aspects, WCH developed this proposed plan. The activities contributing to project objective designed to mobilize the community (led by youth and children) into taking actions to create a system established for MHPSS. In this sense, WCH will offer capacity to a wide range of stakeholders in promoting MHPSS, CBCP, activities listed below. These actions will build demand for greater promotion and protection of rights from the grassroots level. Firstly, the proposed intervention plan will minimize negative consequences on the lives of the children and youth; further project indicators will be developed with certain developmental indicators to measure the changes in the lives of the children and youth in working locations. The specific issues which will be addressed through activities are listed below; 1. Improved psychosocial functioning (as practically defined locally by MHPSS team in the North) of target groups affected by conflict-related violence; through this, the achievements will be improved MHPSS will be in place at local level which provides reliable services leads to durable solutions. 2. Estimated that, at least 500 children who have been identified with CR violations or related issues will be directly reached through PSS services and more than 85% of those children have been proven with positive changes through a follow-up mechanism.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Probation and Child Care Services, Mental Health Unit, Department of Public Health Services, Provincial Level, Association for Health and Counselling (AHC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Institute for Social Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Partnerships and Grants</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>+31 (20) 422 7777</telephone>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmholtzstraat 61G, 1098 LE , Amsterdam, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kilinochchi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.234596 80.235352</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mullaithevu</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.166000 80.475999</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="15144" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2018  WC023 LK4004 E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">5836</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure linked to code WC023. Reporting period: 2018 Calendar Year. Updated: 2019/11/04</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-LK4004" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2019  WC023 LK4004 E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">12622</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure linked to code WC023. Reporting period: 2019 Calendar Year. Updated: 2019/11/04</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-LK4004" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2019 LK4004 ESCO02 OC">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-01">18695</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outgoing Commitment.Financial Code: ESCO02. Reporting period: Whole project duration. Message updated: 2019/11/04.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-LK4004" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Self Reliant Community Awakening Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2019 LK4004 ESCO02 D">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">7630</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transfer to partner. Reporting Period: 2019 Calendar Year. Updated 2019-11-08</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-LK4004" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Self Reliant Community Awakening Organization (ESCO)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41215393-WC023" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
