<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41215393-PJ3492</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016 PJ3492 PJ3506 PJ3535 Accelerated Education Working Group (AEWG)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Background Globally, Accelerated Education (AE) programmes are employed with more and more frequency to address the overwhelming numbers of out of school children and youth. However, while there is widespread agreement on the need for such programming among agencies and governments, there is insufficient validated documentation that provides guidance, standards and indicators for efficient programme planning, implementation and monitoring. In practice, AE takes different forms in different countries, and even within countries. Moreover, there is little significant documentation on the impact of such programming, including how far we are contributing to learning achievement and how successful we are at facilitating pathways between accelerated programming and formal and non-formal education. To address some of these specific challenges related to AE, starting with the lack of guidance and standards, a small number of education partners working in the area of AE formed the Accelerated Education Working Group (AEWG). The AEWG is currently led by UNHCR with representation from UNICEF, USAID, NRC, Plan, IRC, Save the Children, INEE, ECCN and War Child Holland. Based on the aim for a more standardised approach to AE the AEWG has begun to develop guidance materials based on international standards and sound practice for AE. We have recently completed a pocket guide which is part of the AEWG&#x2019;s efforts to produce guidance to develop a more harmonized standardized approach to AE. Purpose and Scope of Assignment The purpose of this assignment is to field test the recently developed AEWG Pocket Guide on Accelerated Education. The pocket guide is now ready for an in depth multi-country field test to obtain feedback and conduct a thorough analysis on how the Pocket Guide can be used in various contexts. Dimensions such as language and usability will also be tested, as well as the content of the pocket guide. The field testing will be managed by War Child Holland as part of the AEWG, in collaboration with technical inputs from other AEWG partners such as UNHCR and UNICEF. The appointment of the field research assistant will be made in line with War Child Holland human resource policy. Objective: To develop clear recommendations, based on field testing using the agreed AEWG tools and protocol for improvement of the AE Pocket Guide. Tasks: a. To be fully conversant with the agreed tools and protocol for field testing b. Develop a draft plan for data collection and agree it with AEWG c. Lead the field testing of the AEWG AE Pocket Guide in 3 locations (TBD) d. Communicate with organisations in the determined locations to organise travel plans and logistics e. Determine roles and responsibilities as well as capacity needs for field collaborators/ support required in each location f. Travel to a minimum of three locations (TBD) to field test the pocket guide g. Write a final report with analysis of data and clear recommendations for the AE Pocket Guide</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Connect@Now Program)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF (funding)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PJ3492" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland (implementing)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PJ3492" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland (leading)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
