<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41215393-LB4017</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 LB4017 Supporting vulnerable girls and boys to access and remain in education in Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2013, War Child Holland (hereifter War Child) and UNICEF have worked together, with different partnership agreements, to identify, refer and integrate out-of-school children into the formal education system, as well as to provide non-formal education altertives. Over this time span, War Child has steered its programmes to meet the needs on the ground and to reflect the priorities outlined in RACE, the tiol education strategy developed by the Ministry of Education and Higher Education (MEHE) with the support of the UN and the intertiol community aiming to enroll and retain all children in the formal education system. The purpose of this partnership is to provide Community-Based Early Childhood Education (CB-ECE) activities targeting 2,550 (slots) for children aged 3-5 years without access to Kindergarten (108 sessions per cycle over 3 cycles). WCH will also provide Adapted BLN (A-BLN) activities targeting 1,150 children aged 10-14 years. A-BLN is the same curriculum as BLN but it is adapted in a way that the most vulnerable groups (children with disabilities, working children, risk of early marriage, etc.) are able to attend the whole programme since the time is adapted to their circumstances. The child will attend sessions 2 days a week, 3 hours per day. War Child will also Conduct community outreach for most vulnerable groups, including children with disabilities, children in worst form of child labour, stateless children, etc. and will include a whole outreach component to the PD. War Child will use the unified ECE package that has been developed by CERD and a range of tiol partners with the support of UNICEF. The interventions will take place in 4 main governorates (Tripoli, Akkar, Beirut/Mount Lebanon, Bekaa/Baalbak Hermel) and will include healthy light meals/scks for the children, minimum transportation when required, learning materials and other support services as well as engagement with parents and community actors. Inclusion: WCH will ensure that at least 3% of the target includes children with disabilities (motor, hearing; seeing; speech, intellectual, learning disability; in all governorates). WCH will ensure that the caseload is diverse, includes challenging cases, and does not only include mild cases. Most vulnerable groups are also included in the ABLN programme? children with disabilities 5%, risk of early marriage or married 2%, working children 70%, stateless 5% and the percentage may change depending on the area. The following support will be provided to support their inclusion through: (i) Provision of Inclusion Officer/Special Educator, (ii) Provision of specialized services like speech therapy, psychomotor therapy, mobility coaching, etc. (iii) Referral to Humanity &amp; Inclusion (Handicap Intertiol) for special needs supplies, (iv) Capacity Building and Mentoring (trainings provided by UNICEF to be cascaded by partner to their outreach workers, teachers and relevant staff. The partner will ensure the following activities; through inclusion officer or other relevant staff (i) Guide the outreach workers /social workers/educators to identify and work with children with disabilities, families and communities (ii) Provide training, mentoring and methodological support and guidance to regular teachers on including children with disabilities in learning (iii) Conduct special education needs assessment process of the learners or if necessary refers to formal assessment, organizes the provision of specialized services or special needs supplies referral (iv) Monitors the progress of the learners with special education needs and discusses with teachers and parents; collects data and maintains records of progress and development, provide data for AI and CLM reporting (v) Makes a recommendation on the pathway for the child after completion of the given course of study, and follows up (vi) Liaise with Movement Social Inclusion workers for follow-up in case of problems in enrolling in school (vii) Participates in child protection and education sector meetings. (viii) Participates in trainings organized by UNICEF (ix) Document their experience and provide success and challenging stories</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AL Ribat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ajyal Al Arab</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Wai wal Mwasat (ACA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azaheer</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Common Effort Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Openness development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanmya wal Salam</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="1" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="1" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting War Child</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnerships, Programmes and Grants Department</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>+31 (0)20-422-7777</telephone>
   <email>info@warchild.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.warchild.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmholtzstraat 61-G; 1098 LE Amsterdam; The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2019  UNA29 LB4017 E">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">402938</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure linked to code UNA29. Reporting period: 2019 Calendar Year. Updated: 2019/11/04</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-LB4017" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41215393-UNA29" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
