<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 PS4018 * Palestinian Women and Girls Lead and Engage on Women Peace and Security in occupied Palestinian Territory (oPt)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict shapes the context in oPt: The context in which the programme operates is highly politicized and conflictual - an environment where multiple actors attempt to impose their agenda and conflict dynamics shape and influence every aspect of life. The continued Israeli occupation of oPt has led to the fragmentation of Gaza, the West Bank and East Jerusalem since 1967 which has resulted in the different realities - involving different actors and diverse political and socio-economic factors - that women and girls face today.
At the end of April 2021, violence escalated in the oPt particularly in East Jerusalem as Israeli forces restricted Palestinian access to the Al-Aqsa mosque1 during the month of Ramadan. On 7 May - the last Friday of Ramadan - Israeli military forces raided the Al-Aqsa mosque and assaulted worshippers, sparking anger and outrage in the Palestinian population. Between (10-21) May, hostilities ensued between Israeli forces and Palestinian armed groups in the Gaza Strip leaving 256 Palestinians, including 66 children, dead; and at least 72,000 Palestinians displaced2, while demonstrations throughout the West Bank against the Gaza strikes were met with excessive force by Israeli forces.
According to the UN, a total of 31 Palestinians, including 5 children, in the West Bank were killed in the
first 20 days of May.3 Eleven of these fatalities took place on one single day (14th of May), marking the highest recorded number of West Bank fatalities since the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) began tracking this figure in 20054. More than 7,000 Palestinians sustained injuries at the hands of Israeli forces, according to UN estimates.5
As an attempt to understand the new emerging needs and effectively respond to the deterioration of stability and escalation of violence, in July 2021 War child Holland (WCH) conducted two rapid need assessments; one in Gaza Strip and one in the West Bank. The findings of the assessments have demonstrated that among the highest protection risks in the oPt were physical and mental health needs due to spikes in political violence and pandemic-related stressors.6
Furthermore, Israeli settler attacks against Palestinians doubled, from an average rate of 36 in January - April, to 72 in May, according to the UN7, causing a spike in physical injuries and property damage while simultaneously undercutting the feeling of safety and security among the Palestinians in general, and among women and girls in particular. Israeli forces also targeted Palestinian properties, demolishing, confiscating, evicting or sealing off access to 34 structures during 20 separate incidents in April and May, based on OCHA data8. In a January 2021 statement, Michael Lynk, the UN Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in the Palestinian Territory, said that 877 people, mostly women and children, were at risk of forced evictions and homelessness because of eviction applications filed by settler groups9. Shelter insecurity and the loss of homes, whether through court-ordered evictions or demolitions, can all affect the protection of women and girls.
WCH need assessment results in the West Bank have strongly demonstrated that respondents&#x2019; of the survey that targeted 12 vulnerable communities with direct contact with settlers, saw their living environments as dangerous, with three out of four respondents (approximately 75%) saying that they feel unsafe and unprotected in their current place of residence. Significantly, the main reason that families said they felt unsafe were the physical attacks by Israeli forces or settlers (nearly 40 percent of respondents). A little less than a quarter of respondents cited issues related to Israel&#x2019;s ongoing occupation of the West Bank, and associated presence, activities and procedures, while about 20 percent cited political upheaval and insecurity. Women and girls were particularly more affected with these realities as 78% of women expressed changes in their moods and behaviors following the escalation in the second quarter of 202110.
Another challenge that might add to the advancement of the women peace and security agenda in Palestine is the postponing of the general elections. on September 6, the Palestinian Cabinet issued a decision to postpone the legislative council election and that to only hold elections on the local government level on two phases. The first phase covers 387 local councils classified as (C) in the West Bank and Gaza Strip and the second phase was determined to be held on 22 March, 2022 for local councils classified as (A) and (B)11. This decision was met with criticism by the public and civil society organizations as it withholds democracy and obstruct the Palestinian people from choosing their representatives and democratically elected leaders. Moreover, holding the local government elections on two phases might diminish accountability and allows space for results to be manipulated12.
COVID 19 situation in 2021: The spread of COVID-19 in oPt since March 2020 has drastically increased vulnerabilities and depleted the coping mechanisms of Palestinian people across the crowded enclaves. Not just the virus itself, but the restrictive measures put in place to contain the spread have had dire repercussions for the whole of society. Healthcare, undermined and weakened by decades of Israeli military occupation and limited resources directed by the PA, has been placed under additional strain. Economic hardship, already widespread after decades of occupation and repeated violations of international law, is at risk of deepening further due to lockdown and border closures. Marginalized groups and isolated households are particularly vulnerable, including women and workers in the informal sector who have lost their daily wage due to the lockdown and restrictive measures.13 COVID-19 has not only led to heightened protection risks in oPt, it has also put pressure on strained safety nets within families and communities, and posed a number of new Mental Health and Psychosocial Support (MHPSS) risks. In a rapid needs assessment conducted by War Child in September 2020, 97% of respondents reported that the COVID-19 pandemic and associated measures have had a negative effect on family life, access to services and work, and general wellbeing/stress levels. An alarming 79% reported changes in their relationships with family since the onset of the crisis, with the majority reporting the use of physical and emotional violence against their children due to excessive stress and feelings of frustration as a result of their inability to provide for the basic needs of their loved ones.14
Prior to the April-May political escalations in the oPt, the West Bank and Gaza Strip were also battling a third wave of high COVID-19 cases amidst a sluggish vaccine rollout. As of October 2021, WHO reported that there were 452,272 confirmed cases of COVID-19 across the occupied Palestinian territory (oPt)15. While Israel has led globally the highest per capita vaccination rates, Palestinians have struggled to access vaccines. The Palestinian government only started the distribution of the vaccines on a mass level on April 2021. As of October 30, only approximately 25 percent of the Palestinians were fully vaccinated16.
According to World Bank (2021), the Palestinian economy was badly hit as a result of the pandemic, ultimately contracting by a total of 11.5 percent. The West Bank closed the year 2020 with 15 percent unemployment - lower than the national average of 23.4 percent unemployment across oPt17, while in Gaza the unemployment level went up to 48%.18 Economic strain is a known &#x2018;push factor&#x2019; for family tensions and therefore raises the risk of domestic violence. In May 2020, a UN Women survey concluded that the Palestinian rate of domestic violence escalated following the outbreak of the COVID -19 pandemic, as lockdowns forced survivors of violence to shelter-in-place with their abusers19.

---

1 Al-Aqsa Mosque, located in the Old City of Jerusalem, is considered the third holiest sites for Muslims around the world.
2 UN: There is &apos;no safe place in Gaza, 72,000 people displaced - The Jerusalem Post (jpost.com)
3 &#x201C;West Bank: Escalation of Violence,&#x201D; OCHA (May 2021), https://www.ochaopt.org/sites/default/files/west_bank_snapshot_2021_4june.pdf
4 &#x201C;Escalation of Hostilities and Unrest in the oPt,&#x201D; OCHA (May 2021), https://reliefweb.int/sites/reliefweb.int/files/
resources/flash_appeal_27_05_2021.pdf
5 &#x201C;West Bank: Escalation of Violence,&#x201D; OCHA (May 2021), https://www.ochaopt.org/sites/default/files/west_bank_
snapshot_2021_4june.pdf
6 War Child Rapid need assessment (July 2021), West Bank.
7 Ibid
8 Data extracted from the OCHA Demolition System online tool on June 20, 2021
9 Ibid
10 10 War Child Rapid need assessment (July 2021), West Bank.
11 https://www.elections.ps/Default.aspx
12 MIFTAH - Emergency session for representatives of institutions, factions and parties to discuss Cabinet decision on local elections
13 WCLAC COVID-19 and Women&#x2019;s rights in Palestine, Gender Assessment Report, May 2020
14 War Child, Rapid Needs Assessment on Covid-19 impact, September 2020.
15 https://covid19.who.int/?adgroupsurvey={adgroupsurvey}&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMI7dSk3ffs8wIVGap3Ch0s7QRjEAAYASABEgIKvPD_BwE
16 https://ourworldindata.org/covid-vaccinations?country=PSE
17 Palestinian Territories&#x2019; Economic Update,&#x201D; World Bank (April 2021) Palestinian Territories&#x2019; Economic Update,&#x201D; World Bank (April 2021), https://thedocs.worldbank.org/en/doc/20006620c264fb78d6fe7a6fcd325ba4-0280012021/original/13-mpo-sm21-palestinian-territories-pse-kcm2.pdf
18 https://www.pcbs.gov.ps/post.aspx?lang=en&amp;ItemID=3987
19 &#x201C;Rapid Assessment on COVID-19 and Domestic and Family Violence Services Across Palestine,&#x201D; UN Women (May 2020)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MIFTAH</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27108436-A-06684-02:PS" ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27108436-A-06684-03:PS" ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27108436-A-06684-04:PS" ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27108436-A-06684-05:PS" ref="NL-KVK-27108436" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004356" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs (funding)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Centre for Legal Aid and Counseling (WCLAC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnerships, Programmes and Grants Department</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>0031204227777</telephone>
   <email>ppg@warchild.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-29">980236</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">980236</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004356" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">980236</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004356" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">130820</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MIFTAH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">130820</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MIFTAH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">326519</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">326519</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-27108436" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam Novib</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">238136</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Centre for Legal Aid and Counseling (WCLAC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">238136</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41215393-PS4018" ref="NL-KVK-41215393" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child Holland</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Centre for Legal Aid and Counseling (WCLAC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">281202</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annual-narrative-plan-2022---Palestinian-Women-and-Girls-Lead-and-Engage-20220429030405.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual narrative plan 2022 - Palestinian Women and Girls Lead and Engage</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Baseline-Report-Final---Palestinian-Women-and-Girls-Lead-20220429030434.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline Report Final - Palestinian Women and Girls Lead</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-A---Risk-Analysis-Matrix---Palestinian-Women-and-Girls-lead-and-engage-20220429030446.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex A - Risk Analysis Matrix - Palestinian Women and Girls lead and engage</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.MS-EXCEL" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-B---MEAL-plan-ITT-and-IATI-Reporting-20220429030454.xlsx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex B - MEAL plan ITT and IATI Reporting</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-C---Compiled-achievement-to-MFA-Basket-indicators-20220429030448.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex C - Compiled achievement to MFA Basket indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-D---Enhanced-ToC-20220429030447.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex D - Enhanced ToC</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annex-E---detailed-report-on-the-international-advocacy-efforts-20220429030402.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annex E - detailed report on the international advocacy efforts</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Annual-narrative-report-2022---Palestinian-Women-and-Girls-Lead-and-Engage-20220429030431.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual narrative report 2022 - Palestinian Women and Girls Lead and Engage</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp;  Output 1.3: Awareness of community members and CSOs on harmful patriarchal and societal norms against women and children is enhanced &amp; Output 3.3: CSOs, women and youth activists are supported to document gendered impact of violations of IHL and IHRL</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG049ny" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of individuals (female) with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG049ny" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals and service providers are still in need of an in-depth understanding of gender equality, equity, women&apos;s rights and the relevant existing laws and policies concerning these concepts. In year 1, it was evident through partners&#x2019; engagement with the stakeholders of the SGBV referral system that young people and service providers in particular are not aware of the core and essence of family protection law and it applications.  
Almost three out of ten individuals (33.4%) are aware of the harmful impacts of patriarchal and societal norms against women and girls. The value is relevantly close between males and females</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="120">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Non Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="74">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Non Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These numbers reflect female individuals who participated in the capacity building trainings organized by the consortium (namely WCLAC). The trainings were conducted on three levels: 1) trainings of service providers who are members of the protection networks. 2) training of the members of the youth CBO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp;  Output 1.3: Awareness of community members and CSOs on harmful patriarchal and societal norms against women and children is enhanced &amp; Output 3.3: CSOs, women and youth activists are supported to document gendered impact of violations of IHL and IHRL</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG049y" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of individuals (female) with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG049y" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals and service providers are still in need of an in-depth understanding of gender equality, equity, women&apos;s rights and the relevant existing laws and policies concerning these concepts. In year 1, it was evident through partners&#x2019; engagement with the stakeholders of the SGBV referral system that young people and service providers in particular are not aware of the core and essence of family protection law and it applications.  
Almost three out of ten individuals (33.4%) are aware of the harmful impacts of patriarchal and societal norms against women and girls. The value is relevantly close between males and females</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="32">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These numbers reflect female individuals who participated in the capacity building trainings organized by the consortium (namely WCLAC). The trainings were conducted on three levels: 1) trainings of service providers who are members of the protection networks. 2) training of the members of the youth CBO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp;  Output 1.3: Awareness of community members and CSOs on harmful patriarchal and societal norms against women and children is enhanced &amp; Output 3.3: CSOs, women and youth activists are supported to document gendered impact of violations of IHL and IHRL</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG050ny" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of individuals (male) with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG050ny" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals and service providers are still in need of an in-depth understanding of gender equality, equity, women&apos;s rights and the relevant existing laws and policies concerning these concepts. In year 1, it was evident through partners&#x2019; engagement with the stakeholders of the SGBV referral system that young people and service providers in particular are not aware of the core and essence of family protection law and it applications.  
Almost three out of ten individuals (33.4%) are aware of the harmful impacts of patriarchal and societal norms against women and girls. The value is relevantly close between males and females</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Non Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="18">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Non Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These numbers reflect male individuals who participated in the capacity building trainings organized by the consortium (namely WCLAC). The trainings were conducted on three levels: 1) trainings of service providers who are members of the protection networks. 2) training of the members of the youth CBO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp;  Output 1.3: Awareness of community members and CSOs on harmful patriarchal and societal norms against women and children is enhanced &amp; Output 3.3: CSOs, women and youth activists are supported to document gendered impact of violations of IHL and IHRL</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG050y" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of individuals (male) with strengthened capacity (knowledge and skills) to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG050y" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individuals and service providers are still in need of an in-depth understanding of gender equality, equity, women&apos;s rights and the relevant existing laws and policies concerning these concepts. In year 1, it was evident through partners&#x2019; engagement with the stakeholders of the SGBV referral system that young people and service providers in particular are not aware of the core and essence of family protection law and it applications.  
Almost three out of ten individuals (33.4%) are aware of the harmful impacts of patriarchal and societal norms against women and girls. The value is relevantly close between males and females</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="11">
      <dimension name="Age" value="Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">These numbers reflect male individuals who participated in the capacity building trainings organized by the consortium (namely WCLAC). The trainings were conducted on three levels: 1) trainings of service providers who are members of the protection networks. 2) training of the members of the youth CBO</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp; Output 3.2.: National Coalition UNSCR 1325 is supported to develop and implement the Advocacy strategy</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG045" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women led CSOs with strengthened capacity to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.1</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG045" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian grassroot organizations lack a gendered sensitive dimension within their scope of work. Many organizations are still failing to mainstream or even to recognize gender across their programs and interventions. There is also a need for strengthened cooperation and coordination among partners in terms of advancing gender equality and rights. This need is even more prevalent in youth led organizations.
The national coalition consists of a group of CSOs, working together towards advancing the 1325 NAP. Historically, The national 1325 coalition has tremendously beneficiated from the strategic partnership and support of the WPS consortium members. They contributed towards developing the advocacy strategies and plans of the coalitions. The coalition highly depends of the contributions of WPS consortium partners for its development.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="38"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building on its ongoing partnership with the Palestinian women&apos;s coalition for the Implementation of UNSCR 1325, consortium through MIFTAH contributed to the development of a specialized manual on UN mechanisms (Contractual and Non-Contractual) related to UNSCR 1325 and subsequent resolutions, in addition to CEDAW convention and its General Recommendations (30, 32) to support the 20 feminist CSO members of Palestinian Women Coalition (PWC) in their advocacy work. The manual sets out international tools and platforms for better influencing and directing the advocacy efforts at the international level for the realization of peace and security for Palestinian women in an independent sovereign state of Palestine. The manual also supports advocacy efforts towards holding perpetrators accountable for the extended violence and military attacks and war crimes against Palestinians by the Israeli occupation. 
The manual supports the coalition members in utilizing the UN mechanisms through written information/ statements, attending sessions, providing oral statements &#x2026;etc., and more importantly, it will enable the coalition members in following a clear agenda and dates for key events and sessions that will serve their advocacy efforts at international platforms. Furthermore, the manual will facilitate the PWC work in addressing the Secretary-General, the Security Council, the General Assembly, the Economic and Social Council, CSW, the Human Rights Council. Member CSOs will be further trained on how to make best use of the manual.
Additionally,  Consortium through WCLAC partnered with two feminist CBOs in Hebron and Jericho to strengthen their capacities to provide protection services to rural women in Area C and other marginalized areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp; Output 3.2.: National Coalition UNSCR 1325 is supported to develop and implement the Advocacy strategy</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG047" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs (not youth or women led) with strengthened capacity to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.1</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG047" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian grassroot organizations lack a gendered sensitive dimension within their scope of work. Many organizations are still failing to mainstream or even to recognize gender across their programs and interventions. There is also a need for strengthened cooperation and coordination among partners in terms of advancing gender equality and rights. This need is even more prevalent in youth led organizations.
The national coalition consists of a group of CSOs, working together towards advancing the 1325 NAP. Historically, The national 1325 coalition has tremendously beneficiated from the strategic partnership and support of the WPS consortium members. They contributed towards developing the advocacy strategies and plans of the coalitions. The coalition highly depends of the contributions of WPS consortium partners for its development.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consortium (through WCLAC) strengthened the capacity of three Protection Networks (Hebron, Jericho and Qalqilya) through supporting them in developing protection plan for the year 2021. Ten coaching and supervision sessions were held</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1.2: CBOs, community actors and government service providers have the knowledge, skills, capacity to promote and respond to the needs of women and girl survivors of SGBV. &amp; Output 3.2.: National Coalition UNSCR 1325 is supported to develop and implement the Advocacy strategy</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG046" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth led CSOs with strengthened capacity to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 5.2.1</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG046" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian grassroot organizations lack a gendered sensitive dimension within their scope of work. Many organizations are still failing to mainstream or even to recognize gender across their programs and interventions. There is also a need for strengthened cooperation and coordination among partners in terms of advancing gender equality and rights. This need is even more prevalent in youth led organizations.
The national coalition consists of a group of CSOs, working together towards advancing the 1325 NAP. Historically, The national 1325 coalition has tremendously beneficiated from the strategic partnership and support of the WPS consortium members. They contributed towards developing the advocacy strategies and plans of the coalitions. The coalition highly depends of the contributions of WPS consortium partners for its development.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCLAC partnered with Youth led organization (Nibras) in Bethlehem building their capacities on themes related to gender justice. Besides the extensive training, WCLAC hired an expert to work closely with Nibras on developing organization&#x2019;s strategy and annual plan while ensuring gender mainstreaming. The expert held three intensive meetings with the staff of Nibras with an aim to collect information and analyse the existing situation and develop a strategic plan document that reflects the youth organization&#x2019;s interventions with special focus on gender issues.
Following the capacity building package, the youth CBO agreed to conduct the following:
-	a specialized training on gender-based violence, women&#x2019;s rights and protection mechanisms for 10 members of its board of directors, staff and volunteers.
-	To develop an action plan that focuses on promoting women&#x2019;s rights and enhancing CBO&apos;s role on genduer justice in the community.
-	To create a women&#x2019;s protection committee consisting of 10 members from the association (5 males and 5 females)
-	To hold annual meetings to monitor the work and identify challenges
-	To hold awareness workshops on gender-based violence for men in the community</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERMEDIATE OUTCOME 2: Increased and meaningful participation of women and girls, women rights organizations and networks, in local, national, regional and international decision-making spaces and processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="WRG039" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO demands and positions on promote women&#x2019;s meaningful and equal participation and leadership in conflict prevention and peace- and state-building and protecting women&#x2019;s and girls&#x2019; rights in crisis and (post-)conflict situations, through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or movement building</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 4.2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG039" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">While many CSOs have exerted efforts in creating a space to highlight CSOs demands and discussions on women&apos;s meaningful participation, it is evident through the baseline study (2021) that only a limited number of these efforts were successful. Women&apos; participation in public jobs in the civil sector was 44.4% in 2018, while women who occupied a &#x201C;general manager&#x201D; post and higher was only 13.1% .Figure 20 shows women representation in the various areas of the public positions, . In general, women participation is very limited, and in best cases&#xA0; didn&#x2019;t exceed 21%, which is alarming and requires intervention. Women highest participation is in student councils while they have zero representation in unions, and pale representation in political parties. In the past three years, the Palestinian Authority (PA) has been exerting pressure to limit and restrict the work and influence of CSOs in the oPt through introducing policies and procedures that limit and restrain the free space for CBOs to fully expressing their positions and demands. This reflects a need to intervene at such levels to raise awareness of such bodies, and push them to adopt more open and encouraging policies that is more supportive and inclusive for women</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <dimension name="Type: women-led, youth-led or other and formal/informal" value="Formal"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <dimension name="Type: women-led, youth-led or other and formal/informal" value="Formal"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consortium partner MIFTAH held two policy sessions: 1) an emergency session for several CSOs and representatives of national parties and factions to discuss local elections following the September 6 Cabinet decision which calls for holding local council elections in two stages. As a result, Civil society institutions presented a number of their demands in a policy paper which included their rejection of the Cabinet&#x2019;s decision. The policy session concluded with an agreement to continue coordination with the political parties and to continue pressuring the government to issue a decision to hold one-time local council elections in accordance with the democratic values of transparency and human rights. They also called for avoiding the political challenges that hinder elections in the Gaza Strip or prevent CSOs from assuming their oversight role on monitoring elections. 2) Another policy session was held in Gaza Strip during October 2021 to continue the advocacy efforts for holding the local elections during the first quarter of 2022 nationally on one ballot day including Gaza Strip and West Bank. The meeting opened the door for a national dialogue to include the demanded amendments that guarantee increased participation and representation of women and youth and enhanced pluralism and inclusion of all in the electoral process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO demands and positions on promote women&#x2019;s meaningful and equal participation and leadership in conflict prevention and peace- and state-building and protecting women&#x2019;s and girls&#x2019; rights in crisis and (post-)conflict situations, through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or movement building</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator 4.2</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="WRG039" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">While many CSOs have exerted efforts in creating a space to highlight CSOs demands and discussions on women&apos;s meaningful participation, it is evident through the baseline study (2021) that only a limited number of these efforts were successful. Women&apos; participation in public jobs in the civil sector was 44.4% in 2018, while women who occupied a &#x201C;general manager&#x201D; post and higher was only 13.1% .Figure 20 shows women representation in the various areas of the public positions, . In general, women participation is very limited, and in best cases&#xA0; didn&#x2019;t exceed 21%, which is alarming and requires intervention. Women highest participation is in student councils while they have zero representation in unions, and pale representation in political parties. In the past three years, the Palestinian Authority (PA) has been exerting pressure to limit and restrict the work and influence of CSOs in the oPt through introducing policies and procedures that limit and restrain the free space for CBOs to fully expressing their positions and demands. This reflects a need to intervene at such levels to raise awareness of such bodies, and push them to adopt more open and encouraging policies that is more supportive and inclusive for women</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <dimension name="Type: women-led, youth-led or other and formal/informal" value="Informal"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <dimension name="Type: women-led, youth-led or other and formal/informal" value="Informal"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consortium partner MIFTAH held two policy sessions: 1) an emergency session for several CSOs and representatives of national parties and factions to discuss local elections following the September 6 Cabinet decision which calls for holding local council elections in two stages. As a result, Civil society institutions presented a number of their demands in a policy paper which included their rejection of the Cabinet&#x2019;s decision. The policy session concluded with an agreement to continue coordination with the political parties and to continue pressuring the government to issue a decision to hold one-time local council elections in accordance with the democratic values of transparency and human rights. They also called for avoiding the political challenges that hinder elections in the Gaza Strip or prevent CSOs from assuming their oversight role on monitoring elections. 2) Another policy session was held in Gaza Strip during October 2021 to continue the advocacy efforts for holding the local elections during the first quarter of 2022 nationally on one ballot day including Gaza Strip and West Bank. The meeting opened the door for a national dialogue to include the demanded amendments that guarantee increased participation and representation of women and youth and enhanced pluralism and inclusion of all in the electoral process.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women led CSOs included in SPs programmes</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="SCS061" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women led CSOs included in SPs programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator #6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SCS061" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="22"></target>
     <actual value="22">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building on its ongoing partnership with the Palestinian women&apos;s coalition for the Implementation of UNSCR 1325, consortium through MIFTAH contributed to the development of a specialized manual on UN mechanisms (Contractual and Non-Contractual) related to UNSCR 1325 and subsequent resolutions, in addition to CEDAW convention and its General Recommendations (30, 32) to support the 20 feminist CSO members of Palestinian Women Coalition (PWC) in their advocacy work. The manual sets out international tools and platforms for better influencing and directing the advocacy efforts at the international level for the realization of peace and security for Palestinian women in an independent sovereign state of Palestine. The manual also supports advocacy efforts towards holding perpetrators accountable for the extended violence and military attacks and war crimes against Palestinians by the Israeli occupation. 
The manual supports the coalition members in utilizing the UN mechanisms through written information/ statements, attending sessions, providing oral statements &#x2026;etc., and more importantly, it will enable the coalition members in following a clear agenda and dates for key events and sessions that will serve their advocacy efforts at international platforms. Furthermore, the manual will facilitate the PWC work in addressing the Secretary-General, the Security Council, the General Assembly, the Economic and Social Council, CSW, the Human Rights Council. Member CSOs will be further trained on how to make best use of the manual.
Additionally,  Consortium through WCLAC partnered with two feminist CBOs in Hebron and Jericho to strengthen their capacities to provide protection services to rural women in Area C and other marginalized areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs (not youth or women led) included in SPs programmes</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="SCS063" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs (not youth or women led) included in SPs programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator #6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SCS063" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consortium (through WCLAC) strengthened the capacity of three Protection Networks (Hebron, Jericho and Qalqilya) through supporting them in developing protection plan for the year 2021. Ten coaching and supervision sessions were held</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth led CSOs included in SPs programmes</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="SCS062" vocabulary="99 - REPORTING ORGANISATION" vocabulary-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist"></reference>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth led CSOs included in SPs programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA Basket indicator #6</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="SCS062" indicator-uri="https://www.helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/indicator-codelist" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-01-01" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">WCLAC partnered with Youth led organization (Nibras) in Bethlehem building their capacities on themes related to gender justice. Besides the extensive training, WCLAC hired an expert to work closely with Nibras on developing organization&#x2019;s strategy and annual plan while ensuring gender mainstreaming. The expert held three intensive meetings with the staff of Nibras with an aim to collect information and analyse the existing situation and develop a strategic plan document that reflects the youth organization&#x2019;s interventions with special focus on gender issues.
Following the capacity building package, the youth CBO agreed to conduct the following:
-	a specialized training on gender-based violence, women&#x2019;s rights and protection mechanisms for 10 members of its board of directors, staff and volunteers.
-	To develop an action plan that focuses on promoting women&#x2019;s rights and enhancing CBO&apos;s role on genduer justice in the community.
-	To create a women&#x2019;s protection committee consisting of 10 members from the association (5 males and 5 females)
-	To hold annual meetings to monitor the work and identify challenges
-	To hold awareness workshops on gender-based violence for men in the community</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
