<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-NL-KVK-41145371-XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002806</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41145371" secondary-reporter="0" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maastricht School of Management</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TVET poultry and dairy MSM-AERES-IPB</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The educational institutes selected by this project are Indonesian educational institutes that provide TVET in the agriculture and food sector, more specifically the poultry and dairy subsectors: six SMK&#x2019;s with LSP centers for certification of its learners. All six are located in West Java, the region in which there is a concentration of poultry industry, and relatively close by SV-IPB. This will facilitate interaction and is cost-effective. Various studies, also the one referred to above, have shown that the SMK curricula do not match the labour market and President Jokowi has emphasised in 2017 to make the curricula demand driven, in the case of this project, agribusiness driven. Furthermore, the four Master trainers have an agricultural production background and come from the Polytechnics that provide diploma in agriculture. Many of certified SMK graduates continue their studies in Polytechnics, hence enrolling those four Polytechnics in the project will strengthen the agricultural TVET column in Indonesia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project approach: In this project the poultry and dairy vocational programs in SMK&#x2019;s will become gender sensitive, agribusiness driven and certified on the basis of the three CO&#x2019;s: Close COnsultation on educational needs and certification from the side of the authorities, CO-education from the part of the companies, CO-entrepreneurship by the educators. This entails authorities, companies and educators working together in curricula formulation, certification, implementation and evaluation. In order to achieve this, the proposed project approach has the following eight main characteristics: &#x2022; Focus on a specific agricultural sub-sector (animal production) &#x2022; Triple Helix &#x2022; Building on existing pool of well-trained Polytechnic teachers that will train teachers &#x2022; Introduction of innovative, e-learning &#x2022; Strengthening management and leadership &#x2022; Involvement of six SMK LSP centres for learners and the national LSP training centre for teachers &#x2022; Co-education facilitation &#x2022; Rollout to a larger group of SMK&#x2019;s.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The vocational education on agrifood in Indonesia (TVET) is in need of re-adjustment, as borne out by the relative lack of interest by prospective students and the low numbers of diploma holders reaching the labour market in contrast with good opportunities of work in the sector. This position is worsened by the rising unemployment figures in this age group. The national government, up to the highest level, has decided to urge change in the educational system. In order to increase student numbers, agricultural education programs need to become more attractive and fit the labour market. Although the current SMK&#x2019;s have accredited programs, a good percentage of the curriculum is spent on general courses, which limits time for true agricultural/food programs. The SMK teaching factories for student&#x2019;s practical education often lack basic equipment. Furthermore, TVET education turns to classical teaching, based on general certification. Despite the fact that SMK&#x2019;s sign MoUs with industry, these companies are not involved in formulating curricula standards and learning outcomes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002806" ref="XI-IATI-NL-KVK-41145371" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maastricht School of Management</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002806" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-04" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Due to the COVID pandemic, budget neutral extensions have been requested. New planned end date will be July 4th 2022</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-04" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The original planned end date was set for 2021-07-04. Due to the Covid pandemic budget neutral extensions have been requested.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31181" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The enhancement of the technical vocational education and training in this project is oriented towards the agricultural and food sector. The educational programs of both TVET and polytechnics will be revised using a triple helix approach in which private sector, government and educational institutes work together. The revised programs will become more practical to adhere to labour market needs for graduates.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education system (TVET/HE) is of good quality, relevant and accessible (SDG 4); the project aids in the enhancement of the educational programs in the agricultural and food sector. Currently, there are high unemployment reciords for young graduates as their skills and knowledge do not overlap with the labour market needs. The revised educational programs will be based on a triple helix model to overcome the unemployment issue.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to SDG: 2. Food securituy and improved nutrition. The popularity of employment in the agricultural sector is decreasing among young Indonesians, putting the food security and nutrition at jeapordy.</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-05">184589</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">184589</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">92295</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">184590</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">first installment of the total price at the start of the contract in 2019 (40% of total project budget)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs" type="10"></provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/MSM---201800266-20200220120223.049---Report-1---Annex-3---value-chain-analysis-poultry-sector.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value chain analysis poultry sector - desk study</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A preliminary Value chain analysis of the poultry sector (desk study) has been developed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/sas-21-steering-committee-april-2021">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Insightful SAS21 project steering committee meeting</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On April 7, the SAS 21 steering committee gathered to discuss the progress in the dairy and poultry pilot studies running in Indonesia. Participants included representatives from industry leaders, the Ministries of Education and Agriculture, and IPB University, Maastricht School of Management, and Aeres University of Applied Sciences.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-04-09"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/triple-helix-strengthened-in-indonesia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triple helix strengthened in Indonesia 05-02-2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On Wednesday February 5, key stakeholders relevant for the Indonesian agricultural vocational education met in Bogor for a Triple Helix Establishment consultative meeting of the SAS21 project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-05"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/sas21-closed-poultry-house-training">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Closed poultry house training in SAS21 project in Indonesia</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The SAS21 Closed Poultry House Training Project activity in collaboration with the IPB Vocational School, the Maastricht School of Management (the Netherlands) and AERES University of Applied Sciences (the Netherlands) was officially opened online on Tuesday January 18. The training will last until January 31, 2022 and is carried out in a hybrid manner (synchronous and asynchronous).</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-01-18"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/project-on-agricultural-tvet-in-indonesia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kick-off project on agricultural TVET in Indonesia</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &#x2018;Improving demand-driven vocational training &amp; education in poultry and dairy in Indonesia&#x2019;, also named SAS21: SMK Ayam dan Sapi 2019-2021 had its formal kick-off and first training workshop in Bogor, Indonesia, from 8 until 10 October</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-23"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/MSM---201800266-20200220110224.049---Report-1---Annex-2---value-chain-analysis-dairy-sector.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">dairy sector value chain analysis - desk study</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">a preliminary value chain analysis of the dairy sector (desk study) has been developed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/triple-helix-strengthened-in-indonesia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triple helix strengthened in Indonesia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-05"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/sas21-summer-school">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAS21: Vocational School Summer Course Adapts Competency Based Curriculum Method</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-12-07"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.msm.nl/news-events-and-blogs/news/sas21-indonesia-half-year-update">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAS21-indonesia-half-year-update</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Appendix-6---MSM-AERES-20200220070200.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project proposal MSM-AERES - The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of The Netherlands</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This document includes the project proposal for technical vocational education and training: for the agriculture and food sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-10"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/MSM---201800266-20200220110204.049---Report-1---MSM-AERES-IPB---Feb-2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">semi-annual report 1 MSM-AERES</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first semi-annual report for the dutch ministry of foreign affairs on the project development and planned activities</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/SAS21---Report-2-Ministry-of-Foreign-Affairs---MSM-AERES-IPB-20200713030707.FIN.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">semi-annual report 2 MSM-AERES</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-07-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/SAS21---Report-3-Ministry-of-Foreign-Affairs---MSM-AERES-IPB-20210209110245.FIN.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">semi-annual report 3 MSM-AERES-IPB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-02-05"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/SAS21---Report-4-Ministry-of-Foreign-Affairs---MSM-AERES-IPB-20210927040933.V4.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">semi-annual report 4 MSM - AERES</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/SAS21---Report-5-Ministry-of-Foreign-Affairs---MSM-AERES-IPB-20220413110424.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">semi-annual report 5 MSM-AERES</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-01-22"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.2 On the Job Training programs are problem/project based for experiential learning</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core to the project is the improvement and/or introduction of On the Job Training. Facilitated by the Triple Helix platform, the project will closely link to key companies in the poultry and dairy sector. The project will set-up mechanisms for working with companies in the role of co-educators and developers, assessing the training needs of companies through close consultation and advice. Concretely, the current internship program will be reviewed and improved.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of (knowledge) institutions supported directly</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of relevant publications</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1 Platform established</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For establishing the platform, the two project partners together with the local implementing partner SV-IPB will work closely together, in which MSM will take the lead throughout while facilitating cooperation and dialogue between and among representatives of education, government, industries, and community. The Triple Helix advisory platform plays an important role in connecting agribusiness, SMK&#x2019;s, polytechnics and certification authorities (BNSP and LSP certification center). The platform is very important in facilitating the certification processes. The authorities (ministries) and the qualification board (BNSP) in the platform need to facilitate the processes of change in curricula, certification and teacher training. At project start, duties, responsibilities, composition, meeting procedures, and financial matters will be formulated and formalized. A small budget will be made available for facilitating the meetings. The Board of the forum will be responsible for the Project Steering. A gender-balanced composition of the platform is aimed at.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of MoUs or other types of collaboration agreements signed</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">a selection of government, private sector and educational institues are invited to participate in the triple helix platform.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.4 Innovative, internet-based approaches developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated in the curriculum development process is the introduction of appropriate approaches through internet technology. Use of blended learning and apps and vlogs will increase the reach to students and companies in more remote areas, will facilitate the communication between the teacher and a student on placement, will facilitate peer learning via the set-up of a learning network, and enables continuous involvement of Dutch experts (through internet). The project can benefit of previous work of Aeres. Aeres has already developed e-learning modules on poultry production (vocational and applied level) that have been tested in Indonesia. The subjects are relevant to the current project. Current E-modules on call are 1. Introduction poultry 2. Poultry nutrition 3. Poultry health 4. Hygiene 5. Welfare and behaviour 6. Productions systems 7. Business economy 8. Entrepreneurship 9. Poultry and society. In the project, an App will be developed and tested that will enable teachers and learners to transmit advice and study materials while learners are out on internship. Standard elements of the curriculum will be available as of the development phase as MOOCs on a YouTube or similar channel.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of relevant innovations in revised/newly developed curricula for degree, non-degree and short courses</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.5 Certification of new education programs</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Once the curricula are reformulated they need to be certified. Therefore, the project involves as of the start BNSP and LSP Pertanian Nasional (National agricultural Certification Centre) in Malang (East Java). This Professional Certification Agency is a certification body licensed by BNSP, which provides certification services for &#x2013; among others - the dairy and poultry workforce (http://lsppertanas.or.id/). The teachers of the six SMK&#x2019;s will be trained and certified in this national agricultural LSP center. It is the intention that the authorities (crucial ministries), accreditation board and certification centers sign an agreement to support the certification process. In addition, each of the six SMK&#x2019;s included in this project have obtained a license from BNSP to conduct competency/profession tests, issue competency certificates in accordance with BNSP guidelines, revoke or cancel certificates of competences, and give sanctions to assessors and set and abolish Competency Test Sites (TUK) that violate the rules. These competency profiles will be reformulated and become agribusiness driven, following the whole value chain. The certification process will be facilitated by the local implementing partner SV-IPB, because they know best the details of the Indonesian regulations and procedures. Given the relative short project period of two years, the project partners cannot garantee that the fornmal certification will be completed before project end.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of accredited curricula (national/international)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 Integrated multidisciplinary, gender-sensitive and application-based curricula developed on diary and on poultry with agribusiness value chain approach</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The curriculum development process will be with a core group of 36 teachers at 10 ATVETs, including four well-trained Polytechnic teachers. The involvement of the Polytechnic teachers enables to review and improve all vocational education levels, from certificate up to Diploma. In this way, the project can address labour market needs on several levels, from basic worker up to advanced, highly skilled worker. Starting point will be formulating student and graduates profiles. The teachers will convene in SV-IPB and define together with all concerned and coached by the Dutch and Indonesian experts the priorities for the new curriculum. A separate working group in poultry and in dairy will be formed. Subsequently, the teachers will test the new curricula on actual company owners, not in a learning factory, but in the workplace of these entrepreneurs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the knowledge institution</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of curricula for degree, non-degree and short courses revised/newly developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of students reached with new curricula of supported institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 Project results sustained and disseminated</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has a well-defined rollout strategy. First, the 36 Master trainers teachers will all train five other teachers, leaving a result of 180 teachers. This will result in 216 TVET teachers trained by the project. It is expected that &#x2013; beyond project period &#x2013; they will each train another five teacher, resulting in 900 teachers trained. Second, the Triple Helix platform will be asked to nominate another 25 SMK&#x2019;s of which teachers and leadership can get a brief training on the lessons learned and new curricula developed. This will result in reaching out to another 100 teachers, hence a total of 316 TEVET teachers reached during the project period. Third, at project end, a one day dissemination workshop will be organized in Bogor focusing on the key stakeholders responsible for agricultural vocational education in Indonesia. Concerning sustainability (see also Part I), the project partners want to stress the ambition that the Triple Helix platform will be sustained beyond project period. It can be transformed into an ATVET Advisory Council, monitoring and managing the implementation of the roadmaps in the poultry and dairy subsectors, guiding the certification process (if not yet finalized), facilitating continuous information sharing and learning, providing internship places, and managing the co-education facilitation fund.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of (knowledge) institutions supported directly</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of beneficiaries in the society reached with knowledge, skills and techniques</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2160"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3 Capacities of SMK teachers and - leaders strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout the project period, a core group of 36 teachers will be trained, capacitated to become Master trainers. Capacity of male and female teachers will be strengthened on module formulation, problem/project-based learning, OJT facilitation, blended learning and teaching methods. There will be a strong focus on soft skill development, such as communication and presentation skills, team work, supervision, and entrepreneurial skills for self-employment. Besides the teachers, leadership of each of the (10) institutions involved will be trained on (participatory) leadership, industry relations, soft skills, and fundraising. Training sessions will be held at SV-IPB in Bogor as well as at the national certification centre in Malang, the latter responsible for certification of the teachers.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of staff have gained qualitative and relevant knowledge and skills to develop and offer the revised/developed study programmes (teacher/administrative, male/female, PhD/MSc/short training)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="216"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2 Triple Helix roadmaps for poultry and dairy subsectors developed and agreed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Together with the key stakeholders, Aeres (supported by SV-IPB) will undertake a gap analysis. First information source are existing labour market needs studies and policy documents, both from Indonesian authorities as well as the Netherlands Embassy and Dutch expert organisations. In addition, current data are gathered through the membership of the platform. This should result in agreed roadmaps for improved dairy and poultry vocational education programmes that will guide the project operations and desired outcomes. Gender will be an explicit aspect of the gap analysis as well as the roadmaps. Sex-segregated data will be presented as much as possible, including differences in career opportunities, and suggestions for gender-specific approaches.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of organisations revised/developed and implemented a strategic plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.3 triple helix pilot project assigned and implemented</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of organisations revised/developed and implemented a strategic plan (for project co-education facilitation fund)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-01-01" value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-07-04"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
