<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="82" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/4140" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MCC-ET-13-4140</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Menz Mama and Mehal Meda Harmful Traditional Practice Reduction</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harmful Traditional Practice (HTP) Reduction committees are being facilitated in Kebeles of Menz Mama district and discussion sessions for participants on local strategies are taking place. Discussion sessions are also being created for court representatives, religious leaders, community police, HTPR committee representatives and women representatives. More informal community conversations are taking place for local psychosocial support for families affected by HTP. Four youth sport clubs are being established that will attain new sports wear and volleyballs. Sports games are being initiated for the discussion of HTP and the roles of youth. Dramas are also being produced and staged in market places to address HTP and reduction practices. There is training for facilitators on trauma healing and reconciliation of offenders and victims&apos; families.  A revenge victims support group is meeting monthly. In-school girls&apos; clubs are being established to support them with life skill training and sport materials for discussion on HTP. Mehal Meda prisoners are also gaining physical, psychosocial, and economic support through committees that discuss reconciliation and ending hostility. Counseling sessions are available for victims by facilitators and trained religious leaders. The prison is being supported with sewing machines and woodwork materials to learn new trades and provide economic support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Teachers, Students, Prisoners, SHG members, sport club members, OVC, Female circumcisers. Witch doctors, community representatives</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is working to address the issue of Harmful Traditional Practices in Mehal Meda towns&apos; four Kebeles, the Prison and Menz Mama Districts of North Shewa Zone. Reducing harmful practices such as revenge killing are contributing to creating a better living culture in the community and improved social and economic condition of the needy communities of the project area. The project is currently employing strategies such as trainings, community conversation, and networking to reach its goal of reducing Harmful Traditional Practices. These practices are having serious affects on the well-being and livelihood of the people, particularly that of women and children. The project is also working towards increasing the capacities of local institutions (Kebele women representatives, community police, religious leaders, Kebele HTP committee and Kebele government representatives) in order to contribute to improved socioeconomic conditions of the target districts by March 2016.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-23-6002702" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mennonite Central Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meserete Kristos Church Relief and Development Association (MKC-RDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MCC-ET-13-4140" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="5239131" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-23-6002702">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mennonite Central Committee</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mennonite Central Committee</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alain Epp Weaver</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director, Strategic Planning and Learning</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>aew@mcc.org</email>
   <website>http://www.mcc.org</website>
   <website>http://www.mcc.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-04-01">120000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-23-6002702">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mennonite Central Committee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.mcc.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55009"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
