<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8977</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Campina 000</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name:    Russian Federation - Campina Yogurt      Region:Europe II   Sector:   Project No:008977   Projected Board Date:May 28, 1999   Company Name:Campina OOO   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The Sponsor, Campina Melkunie, is an international co-operative which specializes in development, production, sale and distribution of dairy products for the consumer market and high-grade ingredients for the food and pharmaceutical industries.  Campina is one of the largest dairy cooperatives in Europe, with sales of US$ 4.5 billion in 1997, and has a strong market share in The Netherlands, Germany and Belgium.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The Project Cost is estimated at US$ 30.5 million of which IFC will provide a US$ 10 million loan.    Location of project and Description of site    	The project is located on a 15-hectare site in Stupino raion, about 150 kilometres south of Moscow.  Stupino is the largest agricultural district in the Moscow region.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	Campina OOO is a 100 per cent owned subsidiary of Campina Melkunie.  Campina OOO will produce and market yogurt in the Russian Federation and expects to capitalize on the considerable growth potential for dairy products in Russia.    	The project will help rejuvenate the Russian dairy industry by improving animal husbandry, employing the latest technology and raising quality to international standards.  The Company will obtain its fresh milk supply from local farmers; hence the country&apos;&apos;s agricultural sector will benefit from the development of the dairy farming industry.  To ensure adequate supply of high quality fresh milk the Company will provide technical support to farms and improve milk collection.     	The project will leverage on IFCs experience in land privatization and farm re-organization to secure long-term supply arrangements with local dairy farms.  IFC&apos;&apos;s participation provides comfort to Campina in its first investment in Russia.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure. Key issues, which were examined during review of this project, included air and water emissions, solid waste disposal, hazardous materials handling, use of CFCs, plant hygiene, fire protection and worker health and safety.  Air emissions arise from boilers as well as dust odor from processing activities will be monitored regularly by the Company to ensure compliance with World Bank guidelines for emissions.  Dust levels will be controlled by ventilation and fabric filters.  Solid waste will include polystyrene, card and paper and will either be re-used or disposed of in licensed landfills.  All chemicals will be securely stored and access will be restricted to staff with requisite training.  A fire control system will be installed.  Standard protection measures and personal protection equipment will be employed to ensure worker health and safety.  The proposed project will meet World Bank group environmental and health and safety policies and guidelines and host country requirements    The  is  from the InfoShop.       Host country location of environmental documents    Stupino, Russia      Date SPI sent to InfoShop: April 28,1999   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kampina, OOO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8977" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-09-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-08-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RU" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Russian Federation</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="RU-Russian Federation">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>60.0000000000 100.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AF - Dairy Products</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-09-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-22">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-22">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kampina, OOO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8977/campina-000">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
