<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8805</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DReVo Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Russian Federation-DReVo              Region    Europe        Sector       Project No008805   Projected Board DateApril 9, 1998   Company NameDReVo   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The main Sponsor is Louis Dreyfus N&#xE9;goce S.A., a French major grain and oilseed trading company which is part of the Louis Dreyfus Group, an agribusiness specialist with investments and operations in oilseed crushing, storage facilities, and orange juice worldwide. Trading activities from Louis Dreyfus Group amount annually to FRF100  billion (US$17 billion).  Louis Dreyfus Group has also activities in shipping, energy sector, finance and commercial real estate    Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	The Project Company would have a US$3.0 million equity including the IFC investment of US$0.9 million representing 30% of the Companys shares, which would be purchased from the Sponsor.    Location of Project and Description of Site    	The Project is located in the Voronezh region.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project   (include IFCs Role and Development Impact)    	DReVo would be involved in cash crop production through contractual arrangements with local farms with a surface totaling 20,000 ha the first year and up to 100,000 ha following the third year. DReVo will leverage on its equity base to provide the necessary working capital, seeds, fertilizers, technical assistance as well as equipment through leasing arrangements to the contracted farms in exchange of a share of the production.  DReVo will also organize the trading of the production for the domestic and the export markets.  IFCs participation in the capital of the Company will increase the investors and DReVo trade partners comfort level to participate in one of the first integrated scheme in Russia that integrates suppliers of seeds and fertilizers, trading experts, suppliers of modern machinery and expertise in modern agriculture practice.  DReVo is a pilot project that would try to break the vicious circle of farms facing a lack of rural finance, deteriorating terms of trade and low productivity, through an association of all agribusiness interests: farms, input supply companies, trading companies and financial institutions.  Each of them will assume a share of the project risks (country, production, market) as well as a share of the benefits. These benefits will derive from improvements in the overall productivity of farming, and improvements in the terms of trade faced by the farms    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is an environmental review Category B project.  Environmental, occupational health and safety issues include: land cultivation techniques, use of pesticides and chemical fertilizers; pesticide/fertilizer handling, storage and disposal of containers and outdated materials and employee health and safety.  Land cultivation techniques are to be improved from the present.  A limited range of agro-chemicals is to be used, none of them is on the IBRD restricted list.  Operator training will be given in the use of spraying equipment and chemicals.  All supplies of chemicals will be safely stored in lockups both as a health and safety measure as well as minimizing shrinkage loss.    The  is  from the Public Information Center.       Host country location of environmental documents    Voronezh, Russian Federation      Date SPI sent to InfoShop February 19, 1998   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAO DreVo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8805" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-07-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-12-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RU" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Russian Federation</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="RU-Russian Federation">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>60.0000000000 100.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Grains and Beans</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.90 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-07-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-07-23">900000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-07-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-07-23">900000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAO DreVo</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8805/drevo-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
