<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26629</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">URSA Synd. Loan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The extensive regional branch network, and presence of SME and mortgage finance among the Banks priority business lines make the Bank an important strategic partner of IFC.  By providing support to URSA Bank, IFC continues supporting its strategic development objectives in Russia  in particular, increasing access to finance for SMEs, and bringing innovative and sustainable banking products and high-quality banking services into the regions of Russia.    The project will help the Bank to introduce new products and services with high development impact such as energy efficiency (EE) finance.  The Banks extensive branch network in Siberia and the Urals and its SME client base make it a very good candidate for energy efficiency lending.  The Financial Markets EE strategy in Central and Eastern Europe includes leveraging IFCs existing financial institutions client base and integrating EE into SME, housing and consumer finance offerings; developing innovative financial structures and new products; and building a robust advisory services program to support capacity building at client level.  By working closely with URSA Bank in this project, IFC would play a critical catalytic role in mobilizing the EE-focused funding for the SME sector in Russian regions via a demonstration effect, which is in line with its Financial Markets and EE strategies.  Encouraging URSA Bank to develop EE-focused lending business will therefore further enhance the development impact of the project.    In addition to provision of financing IFC plans, as a related, but separate project, to provide advisory services to URSA Bank and its clients on technical, financial and legal aspects of EE finance, as well as to provide EE-relevant training to URSA Banks loan officers, assistance in EE product development, and assistance in EE projects pipeline development.  Support provided to URSA Bank, the largest regional Russian bank operating in the Urals, Siberia and the Russian Far Eas, will have a significant positive impact on the Russian regional banking system in general.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">URSA Bank (URSA Bank or the Bank) was formed in December 2006 as a result of the merger of two regional banks: Sibacadembank, headquartered in Novosibirsk, and Uralvneshtorgbank, headquartered in Yekaterinburg.  Now it is one of the largest regional banks in Russia.  Its total assets as of June 30, 2007 were $5.5 billion and total equity $1 billion.   The Bank is a universal bank, offering a wide range of services to its retail and corporate clients.  Although its original strategy was to focus on SMEs, since 2004 the Bank has actively developed retail lending and more recently it also expanded residential mortgage lending.    The Bank is rated by international rating agencies, with Fitch rating of B (Positive) and Moodys rating of Baa3 (Stable).  Standard &amp; Poors put the Bank on the 4th place in its ranking of the most transparent banks in Russia in 2007 (among 30 largest banks included by S&amp;P in its Transparency and Disclosure Survey of Russian Banks 2007).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">URSA Finans, OOO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26629" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-02-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-03-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John McNaughton, Managing Director URSA Bank Moscow, Bryanskaya Street, 5 Russian Federation  Telephone: +7-495-935-7264 Fax: +7-495-935-7261</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RU" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Russian Federation</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="RU-Russian Federation">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Headquartered in Novosibirsk, as of November 1, 2007 the Bank has 20 regional branches, 244 outlets, 3 foreign representative offices and 8,940 employees in approximately 120 cities and towns of the Ural and Siberian Federal Districts of Russia.  Proceeds from both A and B loans will be on-lent throughout the entire Banks branch network.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>60.0000000000 100.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5221" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Commercial Banking - General</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $50.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-02-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-02-21">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-02-21">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">URSA Finans, OOO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26629/ursa-synd-loan">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
