<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="SEK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.diakonia.se" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:cso="https://csoadmin.sida.se/iati" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-ON-802017-3517-PS-4184</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-ON-802017-3517" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PHRI - Promoting &amp; Protecting the Right to Health for Residents in occupied Palestinian territory (oPt) 1 Sept. 2016-31 Dec. 2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective: Democracy is strengthened as the right to health for Palestinian residents of the occupied Palestinian territory (oPt) and Palestinian prisoners incarcerated in Israeli prisons is fully realized. To achieve this, Israel has been made accountable for human rights violations, and has lived up to its responsibility for health in the OPT including the underlying determinants of health such as access to water and nutrition
&amp;nbsp;
Specific Objectives:
1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Torture, ill-treatment and systematic violations of the right to health of Palestinian civilians in the oPt and Palestinians incarcerated in Israeli prisons and detention centres are combatted and prevented.
2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Israeli authorities&amp;rsquo; accountability and compliance with IHL, domestic law, and medical ethical regulations are increased to ensure the right to health of Palestinians in the oPt, thus promoting a democratic culture
3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The ethical and human rights commitment of Israeli health professionals as well as the general Israeli public is strengthened
As partners over so many years, PHRI and Diakonia have developed a thorough understanding of each other and share a number of strategic goals and advocacy messages, promoting the civil society&apos;s right to dialogue with national authorities and the need to challenge duty bearers to fulfil their human rights commitments which ultimately would contribute to a democratic culture. PHRI&amp;rsquo;s work has been successful where the original plans were well delivered and the results have been positively sensed among relevant stakeholders. Building on this, it is recommended to continue the partnership with PHRI (project fund) and support their new application for the new strategy period 2016-2020. This will allow PHRI to react quickly in a dynamic environment, buoyed by Diakonia support. This project seeks to promote, protect, and defend the right to health of Palestinian civilians of the oPt and Palestinian prisoners incarcerated in Israeli prisons and detention centres, and to advocate on the national and international levels for the recognition of Israeli responsibility for health in the Occupied Palestinian Territory thorugh adopting multi-strategy approach to achieving this objectives:
1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Combat and prevent torture and ill-treatment of Palestinian civilians in the oPT and Palestinian prisoners incarcerated in Israeli prisons and detention centres.
2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Increase pressure on the Israeli government to comply with IHL, human rights, domestic law, and medical ethical regulations to ensure the right to health of Palestinians in the oPT
3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Strengthen the ethical and human rights commitment of Israeli health professionals and the Israeli public towards Palestinians.
&amp;nbsp;
Utilising key strategic tools identified by PHRI, including casework and data collection, legal action, training of medical professionals, public outreach and international advocacy work, PHRI seeks to provide both direct medical services to support to cases in desperate need, whilst simultaneously bringing national and international leverage to bear on changing key policies and mechanisms that violate basic human rights in the oPt.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project mainly contributes to results within Democratic culture. Results will be reported later in the Global Civsam grant period 2016-2020</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Physicians for Human Rights Israel</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <website>http://www.diakonia.se</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2019-01-01">610690</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2019-12-31">0</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-802017-3517" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Physicians for Human Rights Israel</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-country code="PS"></recipient-country>
   <recipient-region vocabulary="2"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2019-01-01">610690</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802017-3517" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2019-12-31">0</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802017-3517" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project mainly contributes to results within Democratic culture. Results will be reported later in the Global Civsam grant period 2016-2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator title</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <cso:Strategyid>1</cso:Strategyid>
  <cso:Typeoffundingid>0</cso:Typeoffundingid>
  <cso:contributionstatusid>Active</cso:contributionstatusid>
  <cso:sidadepartmentid>1</cso:sidadepartmentid>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
