<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27367015-NL-CGIAR-PPP</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27367015" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WOTRO Science for Global Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Private Partnership and Research Uptake expert</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands government has a specific interest in furthering Public Private Partnerships (PPP) involving CGIAR. The aim is to (1) enrich research programs with the expertise of the private sector and vice versa, (2) become more demand and market responsive, and (3) improve the enabling environment for scaling and impact. &#x2018;Private&#x2019; in this context includes both global and local (SME) Business and Civil Society which is often referred to as the &#x2018;Growth-Diamond&#x2019; approach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PPP expert is expected to be a senior with an academic background (MSc/Ma/PhD) and at least 10 years of working experience in agriculture, food and nutrition, development economics, development studies or related fields, and employed by a Dutch university or (applied) research or development organization1. The candidate should have experience with initiating and implementing Public Private Partnerships or, from a consultative position, be able to advice on PPP development and operations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this position is to support the overall The Netherlands-CGIAR partnership to jointly enhance International Agricultural Research (IAR) with a view to contributing to achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs); to optimize the effectiveness of Dutch IAR knowledge, innovation and research capacities by enhancing leverage and strengthening linkages to the CGIAR System in combination with linkages to the private sector (NB both for-profit and not-for-profit); to answer to CGIAR&#x2019;s interest in mobilizing partners for the best science and along the research impact pathways towards development outcomes by providing opportunities to engage private partners for advanced research, reach, and impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27367015" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WOTRO - Food &amp; Business Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For specific questions about the subsidy for PPP candidates please contact Dr Monika Brasser, Academic Secretary of the NL-CGIAR research programme</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NWO-WOTRO</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Petra Griffioen MSc</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policy officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+31703440976</telephone>
   <email>nl-cgiar@nwo.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.nwo.nl/en/research-and-results/programmes/nl-cgiar/instruments/ppp</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
