<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-1260478-silsab</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-1260478" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SILSAB</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FARM AID</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OUR BROAD SURVEY Food is one of the basic need in the survival of human being due to the need to support (farm aid) projects in other to increase food production so as to combat potentials shortage. WE PLAN TO ALLEVIATE POVERTY THROUGH FARM AID PROJECTS Our projects includes the followings NGO industries 1. Setting and construction of mini NPK fertilizer manufacturing plant 2. Setting of cash crop farm land 20 hector 3. Setting food crops farm land 20 hector 4. Setting of poultry farm land 5 hector Our request is raw materials, equipment&#x2019;s and money. These will enable our Organization to create thousands of employments opportunities in the country. This will enable us to increase the capacity for agronomical expansion as much as possible, this will prepare the youth for future and economic recovery. And it will help us to achieve our activities of Human development through income funds e.g. Rehabilitation of Health centers such as Hospitals, care of the sick especially those who cannot afford to pay their bills, care of Handicap centers to prevent them from street begging. Taking care of the orphanage house, school charge fees, charity feeding, drilling of water boreholes in rural areas and schools. Thanks. Musa Sabo PRESIDENT</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SILSAB" ref="NG-CAC-NG-1260478" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SILSAB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="FARM AID" percentage="100" vocabulary="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FARM AID</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-05-05"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-05-18">750000000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
