<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41146461-4000004400</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41146461" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deltares</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JCAR - Egypt &amp; The Netherlands: Joint Cooperation in Applied Research Programme - Water</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The JCAR programme takes place within the context of the Egypt-Dutch water sector cooperation and enforces both the Egyptian and Dutch policy objectives. 
OBJECTIVE 1: JCAR supports the Ministry of Water Resources and Irrigation to prepare a clear path and agenda for Egypt to deal with current and emerging water management (and security) issues in order to prepare for future water challenges. OBJECTIVE 2: JCAR supports the integrated planning, development, and management of the water resources in Egypt, which is mandated to the newly established ministerial committee; and improves environmental assessment and strategy development in the water sector. OBJECTIVE 3: JCAR will also support Egypt in meeting the SDGs;
OBJECTIVE 4: JCAR aims to reach a well-developed capacity in MWRI, NWRC, Agriculture Research Centre (ARC) of the Ministry of Agriculture and Land Reclamation (MALR), and other relevant agencies. OBJECTIVE 5: JCAR aims to create partnerships between Egyptian and Dutch institutes to address the knowledge questions that stem from the NWRP 2037. This is meant to enhance the state-of-the-art and the knowledge base of the Egyptian agencies involved in order to strengthen the capacity in Egypt to plan, develop and manage its water resources now and in the future.
DELIVERABLES: during project duration the organisations involved will work on a validated/calibrated fit-for-purpose modelling train, a physical model and (pilot) projects. Also workshops and trainings will be organised. For communication purposes a JCAR website will be built to disseminate the findings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long-term Programme for Joint Cooperation in Applied Research (JCAR) between Egypt and the Netherlands on water related topics was brought forward during the scoping mission of the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs, as a direct request from the Ministry of Water Resources and Irrigation to Deltares, as a result of the continued dialogue between both organisations. The water sector in Egypt is facing large challenges and requires the mobilization of all resources and the management of these resources in an integrated manner. The programme addresses the identified needs caused by these challenges.  Egypt is among the countries that try to develop its economy at a fast pace. Infrastructural investments are needed to support the economic growth and to increase the well-being of the population. A study on Water Security and Sustainable Growth by OECD/GWP shows that good water management is a major precondition for economic growth. Water management in Egypt has reached a state where the quantity of water available is imposing limits on its national economic development. Being the most downstream country in the Nile Basin, and depending almost totally on the Nile River originating outside its borders, Egypt is one of the world&apos;s driest countries with a total renewable water resources dependency ratio of 97% according to FAO. The gap between the needs and availability of water is filled by drainage and wastewater reuse helping the Nile system in Egypt to reach an overall efficiency of about 79%. This, in addition to Egypt&apos;s water resources vulnerability to climate change, especially the impact of sea level rise on the coastal zone of the Nile Delta, is affecting not only water resources, but agriculture, tourism and human settlements as well. 
The Government of Egypt, through the National Water Resources Plan (NWRP 2037) has developed a future vision for the year 2037 based on the concept of Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM). As such it promotes the coordinated development and management of water, land and related resources. It covers water quantity, surface water and groundwater and all uses of water. In order to cope with these future water challenges and meet the set NWRP 2037 objectives, the Government of Egypt in 2020 formed a permanent Ministerial Committee responsible for the integrated management of Egypt&apos;s water. In close collaboration with the Ministry of Water Resources and Irrigation, the following needs have been identified:
1) Need for capacity building of the professionals involved in the implementation of the NWRP;
2) Need to develop technical solutions and tools as well as closing knowledge gaps in the identified priority areas of the NWRP by means of applied research activities;
3) Need for technical support for the Technical Secretariat of the Permanent Ministerial Committee on a multitude of topics by means of dedicated activities;
4) Need to strengthen the dialogue between the relevant agencies, stakeholders, donors and funding agencies, by means of a.o. evidence based policy briefs and creating a science-policy interface;
5) Need to improve environmental assessment system performance in the water sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Water Research Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41185216" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Commission for Environmental Assessment</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soil, Water and Environmental Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41146461" role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Deltares</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-09098104" role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wageningen University &amp; Research - Stichting Wageningen Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-04-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-04-20">6000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Grant decision on JCAR Water- Egypt and The Netherlands (activity no. 40000004400)">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-11-27">6000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004400" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-41146461" type="80"></receiver-org>
   <finance-type code="111"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Egypt-JCAR---Inception-report-approved-PUBLIC-VERSION-part-2-20220711120729.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JCAR Inception Report, part 2: chapter 6 Logical Framework and Risk Management, annexes</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JCAR Inception Report, part 2: chapter 6 Logical Framework and Risk Management, annexes</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-30"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Egypt-JCAR---Inception-report-approved-PUBLIC-VERSION-part-1-20220711120729.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JCAR Inception report, part 1: chapters 1 till 5</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JCAR Inception report, part 1: chapters 1 till 5</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-30"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Cooperation-Agreement-JCAR-incl-Annex-1-3-20220711110743.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperation Agreement for Joint Cooperation in Applied Research on Water Egypt - The Netherlands</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cooperation Agreement for Joint Cooperation in Applied Research on Water Egypt - The Netherlands, signed by the National Water Research Centre; The Soils, Water and Environment Research Institute; Wagening Environmental Research; the Netherlands Commission for Environmental Assessment and Stichting Deltares, during the first half of 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A04"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-07-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
