<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /WASH/INGO/22030</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH assistance to drought and displacement affected communities in Galgaduud</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will seek to provide assistance to 18,000 drought-affected persons (50% Female) that are currently facing acute water shortage, lack sanitation facilities, hygiene items and hygiene information in various rural and IDP settlements of Abudwak district. Proposed interventions include the following

 Provision of water supply through water trucking using vouchers. In total, 500 HHs (3,000 individuals) will be assisted. The beneficiaries will be provided water at the rate of 10 liters per day for 1 month.
 Provision of 5 No. water bladders in water trucking targeted settlements to store water. 
 Construction of 3 water points in 3 IDPs settlements along with extension of water distribution pipeline and networks. Each water kiosk will benefit 250 individuals. Thus, in total 750 individuals will be assisted.
 Distribution of 12,000 No. Aqua tab Sachets. Each sachet contain 100 Aqua tabs.
 Establishment and Training of Water Management Committees (WMCs)
 2 training will be given to Community Hygiene Promoters (CHPs)
 Awareness Creation on hygiene promotions and Public health campaigns 
 Provision of 1200 No. family hygiene kits reaching 1200 HHs (7,200 Beneficiaries)
 Distribution of 250 Menstrual Hygiene Management (MHM) kits) 
 Distribution of 100 No. sanitation kits to drought displaced communities 
 Rehabilitation of 3 No. boreholes with water infrastructure including solarization. Each borehole will benefit 1,000 HHs. Thus, 18,000 individuals (50% females) will benefit from this.
 Construction of 200 Family shared latrines. Each latrine will serve 3 households reaching 1,200 beneficiaries) 

Beneficiary selection will be consultative and transparent, drawing community leaders and representatives of marginalized, minority clans, new IDPs, the disabled and women, to ensure inclusiveness. A selection criteria will be agreed on to ensure proper understanding of how and why specific beneficiaries are selected. To ensure &#x2018;DO NO HARM&#x2019; principle, NRC will target 20% of the beneficiaries from poor host communities. NRC prioritizes value for money as minimum operational benchmark for the delivery of humanitarian assistance, and through this approach tries to reach the maximum beneficiaries possible with objective programming and quality services. Hygiene kits and water trucking will be provided through vouchers as markets within the target locations are functional. Construction works will be contracted to local companies through open and transparent competitive bidding. 

An all-inclusive approach will be applied in monitoring the project thus giving room to all relevant stakeholders to play a role. Project will be monitored by NRC staff together with the community members, Ministry of Water and local authorities. PDMs will be undertaken 6 weeks after distribution of hygiene kits using a structured household questionnaire. For MHM kits, data will be collected through Focus Group Discussions comprising women and girls aged 12 to 49 years. By implementing this project, NRC will contribute to the WASH Cluster strategic objectives by delivering life-saving WASH assistance to reduce acute needs amongst the most vulnerable people. Through this project, NRC will reach a total of 18,000 individuals &#x2013; 50% females, which are borehole rehabilitation beneficiaries and being considered as primary beneficiaries, without double counting.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Barnabas Asora</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 617219993</telephone>
   <email>barnabas.asora@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nadeem Ilyas</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH/Shelter Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 61 7022151</telephone>
   <email>nadeem.ilyas@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-21"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-02">550000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-22030">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-02">550000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
