<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/WASH/NGO/21533</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of  lifesaving Water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) assistance to the most vulnerable drought-affected/displaced populations in Qandala and Bosasso of the Bari region, Somalia&apos;s Puntland state</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the OCHA drought situation report, as of November 23, 2021, approximately 2.6 million people &#x2013; 22 percent of the population &#x2013; were affected by drought in 66 of 74 districts across the country, and drought had displaced nearly 113,000 people. WASH Cluster, corresponded that more than 6.4 million Somalis are affected by poor and deteriorating WASH conditions, necessitating severe and extreme humanitarian WASH assistance, which has been exacerbated by Somalia&apos;s recurring drought. WASH is one of the two main drivers of humanitarian needs in Somalia, highlighting the importance of WASH in determining the severity of humanitarian needs for both IDPs and non-IDPs.
In Somalia, WASH is one of the two key drivers of humanitarian needs, emphasizing WASH&apos;s growing importance in determining the severity of humanitarian needs for both IDPs and non-IDPs. The overall risk of water-borne infections has increased due to a lack of safe and drinkable water, as well as insufficient hygiene and sanitation facilities, with an increase in suspected cases of Acute Watery Diarrhoea/Cholera and measles.
PMWDO proposes a proposal to deliver life-saving and basic WASH services to 26948 (6200 men, 8000 women, 4750 boys, and 7998 girls)  drought-affected/displaced communities in Bossaso and Qandala districts: Through the rehabilitation and/or extension of existing water infrastructures, the construction of new water infrastructures equipped with appropriate storage systems, tanks, and distribution networks, the establishment of gender-balanced water management committees to ensure service continuity, appropriate operation, and maintenance, and the strengthening of women&apos;s leadership and participation in WASH projects through capacity building of new and existing water infrastructures
PMWDO created an intervention to support the 2022 Somalia Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) and efforts to address the needs of the most vulnerable displaced communities affected, by drought, with a focus on the Bosasso and Qandala districts in the Bari region.
PMWDO&apos;s proposed WASH activities will focus on both short-term and long-term interventions in providing safe water and good sanitation and hygiene practices, including:- 
	Rehabilitating two (2) nonfunctioning boreholes equipped with the hybrid system Namely (GUMCO Borehole and BEELWACTO in the districts of Bosasso and Qandala, respectively, in the Bari region and
	Providing emergency water tracking through vouchers to drought-affected households living in 5 rural villages. Each household will be given the number of persons/HH x 7.5lt/person/day for 60 days. 
	In order to ensure the long-term viability of the repaired water infrastructures,21 WASH committees, and well operators will be trained in operation and maintenance equipped with OampM tools, as well as disaster risk reduction a total of 21 WASH committees will be trained, with one WASH committee per facility PMWDO will target the most vulnerable populations by providing equitable access to boys, girls, men, and women. PMWDO will construct 283 gender-separated floodproof latrines with handwashing and locked doors for privatization purposes. WASH committee members will also have to be sensitized, and community education/efforts on hygiene practices will be widely used in Somalia to promote increased hygiene promotion and key messages.
	 Distribute 2500 hygiene kits, including 1500 MHM for females, to families at risk of AWD or cholera. Each Hygiene Promotion Kit comes with a 20L bottle, 3 pieces of soap (800gr), 3 aqua tabs (3-month supply), and 3 sanitary clothes. PMWDO will ensure that the planned WASH project is fully compliant with the Bari region&apos;s WASH cluster strategy..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdulkadir Abdullahi Warsame</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907795290</telephone>
   <email>asandhere@pmwdo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Maymum  Farah Samatar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>252907795960</telephone>
   <email>pmwd2000@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9663">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bari</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.64800000 50.23200000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-26"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">899988.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21533">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">899988.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305568372">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-16">539993.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puntland Minority Women Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
