<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /Shelter/NGO/21970</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of NFIs kits  to drought affected and displaced communities in Galgaduud region ( Cabudwaq, Dhusamreeb and Cadado districts).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is aligned with the allocation strategy as it is contributing to the scale up of drought responsive interventions. It aims at improving the living conditions of the drought displaced populations living in the IDP sites  in Cabudwaq, Dhusamareeb and  Cadado districts of Galmudug region. According to the PRMN report more than 300,000 people have been affected by the worsening drought in Somalia&#x2019;s Galgaduud region.  Federal Government declared a state of emergency, as thousands leave their homes in search of food, water and pasture. In addition to the worsening drought, Guriel, a town of some 100,000 inhabitants in central Galgaduud, has seen an intensification of conflict. At the end of October, heavy fighting broke out between Somali National Army and Ahlu Sunnah Wal Jama&#x2019;a group, killing dozens and forcing some 100,000 people to flee to the neighboring villages. SSWC further collected and ascertained these data through observations and phone call interviews of key community informants. The analysis of the data revealed that 5000 newly displaced households in the three districts are in need of non-food items without which they are exposed to protection risks. SSWC will distribute NFIs through vouchers to newly displaced IDPs in the targeted districts. SSWC conducted market assessment through mobile phone interviews targeting key businesspeople and community leaders the targeted districts. The outcome of the activity influenced the distribution modalities selected. The project will target 10 IDP sites in Cabudwaq, 7 in Dhusamareeb and 6 in Caddado.

SSWC will distribute 4,500 NFI kits (Plastic sheet, Blanket, Sleeping mat, Kitchen sets, Mosquito net, solar lamp, Jerry Cans) through vouchers to the 4500 newly displaced households in the IDP sites. The NFI kits will improve the living conditions of 27,000 individuals (6750 men, 9450 women, 4050 boys and 6750 girls). The beneficiaries will redeem their vouchers at vendor shops that will be contracted. The project staff will ensure strict adherence to COVID-19 guidelines during distributions. This will improve the living conditions of the targeted persons by providing the displaced with basic household items to support their living. 
SSWC will conduct awareness on safe programming to the selected vendors and the project, this will ensure the beneficiaries will not be exploited during targeting and distribution. There will be strict measures in place during beneficiary selection exercise.
Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) will be conducted after every distribution. Three post distribution monitoring exercises will be conducted for all the phases of distributions in all the districts. The monitoring exercises will provide beneficiary feedback on the effectiveness of the distribution. 20% of the beneficiaries will take part of the exercise to ensure proper representation and that exact feelings are recorded about the processes and quality of distribution. The PDM will also help to know the beneficiary satisfaction of the items distributed, identify the needs and feelings of the community better and inform on the effectiveness of the activities and achievements of targets while providing guidance towards success.
SSWC will use hotline numbers for CFRM. The anticipated data to be collected include among others both compliments and complaints: the quality of NFIs, beneficiary selection processes, shortness of items distributed, delays and other feedback. SSWC&#x2019;s staff will analyze the collected data and respond accordingly. This will ensure that community participation and AAP is at the centre of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Somali Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Somali Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmed Abdinasir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616954039</telephone>
   <email>ahmednasir@sswc-som.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirizak Rashid</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ME Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0617720727</telephone>
   <email>rashid@sswc-som.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-02">600000.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21970">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-02">600000.36</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Somali Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305629386">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">480000.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save Somali Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
