<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/H-GBV/NGO/21433</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of an integrated package of Emergency Primary Health Care services and GBV prevention response and mitigation mechanism through quality Primary health care services and strengthening of access to protection services for Drought affected population in Iskushuban District, Bari region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to HNO 2022, overall health needs are likely to remain insufficiently addressed. Health services have eroded to bare minimum levels in many locations as health partners face severe funding gaps. Health service delivery in Somalia remains dependent on humanitarian partners who finance and deliver a large proportion of health care to the population. In the absence of sufficient funding there is a danger of erosion of minimum standards of care of primary health care services. The overall humanitarian outlook in Iskushuban District is alarming in which HNO estimated that people in need (PIN) is 48,264 persons. Among this, 24,050 people are expected to be in (IPC3amp4) at the end of April 2022. As FSNU reported, total acute malnutrition burden in Iskushuban shows 3.1 % of Children had severe acute malnutrition and 19.1% had moderate acute malnutrition.
The proposed project is an 8 month Life-saving project that seeks to improve equitable access to quality emergency and essential lifesaving health services for the crisis affected population and provide vulnerable women and girls including GBV survivors and persons living with disabilities access quality, safe, timely and confidential GBV services in Iskushuban District, particularly 2 health centers (Iskushuban Health Center and Xiriiro Health Center) and 1 Mobile clinic Targeting (Timirshe Village, Camaan Village, Dawacaley Village, Dharoor Village, yadan-yoobil Village, Xubabeys Village, Jeedaal Village and Buulo IDP camp)
	Provision of life-saving primary health care services through 2 fixed (Xiriiro Health center and Iskushuban Health center) and 1 mobile (Timirshe Village, Camaan Village, Dawacaley Village, Dharoor Village, yadan-yoobil Village, Xubabeys Village, Jeedaal Village and Buulo IDP camp) outreach that will provide services including essential clinical care, communicable disease treatment, TB screening and treatment, emergency and trauma care targeting 4,940 (220 men, 2040 women, 1020 boys and 1660 girls) Vulnerable people including People with disability
	Provision of sexual and reproductive health services including SGBV (500 Women and Girls)
	Establish referral pathways for GBV, mental health and PSS services.
	Provide essential medications and supplies for 2 fixed (Xiriiyo Health center and Iskushuban Health center) and 1 mobile outreach that will provide essential ad life-saving service

	Community engagement and Outreach targeting hard to reach areas of Iskushuban District targeting 10,250 (300 Men, 4700 women, 1250 boys and 4000 girls)
	Mental health/psychosocial (consultation) services (420 Women and Girls)
	Immunization services in hard-to-reach areas in Iskushuban for 3200 (2,000 girls and 1,200 boys) and tetanus toxoid to 1000 women of child-bearing age 
The project is combined with GBV component which seeks to provide vulnerable women and girls including GBV survivors and persons living with disabilities access quality, safe, timely and confidential GBV services through: 
	Support the provision of CMR and specialized case management using health facilities and GBV one stop centres - (200 Women and Girls)
	Support direct cash and voucher assistance for vulnerable women and girls to mitigate GBV including pregnant and lactating women and Women with disability- (3 months for 155 women)
	Support the procurement and distribution of dignity kits to 420 vulnerable women and girls
	Support health actors in key health facilities to access for IPV and conduct safe and confidential referrals for services
	Provide 700 vulnerable women and girls with Menstrual hygiene kits</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirahman Mohamed Dahir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906527238</telephone>
   <email>adahir@tadamun.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Abdullahi Diriye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906796444</telephone>
   <email>ali.abdullahi@tadamun.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Abdullahi Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907798815</telephone>
   <email>ibrahim@tadamun.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9663">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bari</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.64800000 50.23200000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="66.67" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="33.33" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-07">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21433">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-07">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305519679">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-18">120000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
