<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/Nut-H/NGO/21502</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated emergency lifesaving health and nutrition project aimed at reducing mobility and related mortality to vulnerable rural communities in Kismayo district, Lower Juba region Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kismayo district is under crisis emergency phase due to the ongoing effects of drought. A recent nutrition assessment by FSNAU reported a critical GAM rate of 15-29% among under-five boys and girls and a high morbidity rate of 12.5 per cent and 25.5 per cent among rural communities. The majority of rural communities have limited access to health and nutrition facilities due to distance to the nearest health facilities, affordability and/or lack of facilities. SOLO aims to improve coverage and the nutrition and health status of boys, girls, women and men by running an integrated health and nutrition program in 1 static primary health care ( PHC) in Wirkoy village and 4 health and nutrition outreach mobile sites across the 12 rural villages, mobile team 1 Abdi- Dhore, Fuuma, Dalsan, mobile team 2 Singaleer, Goobweyn, Osboda, mobile team 3 Qamqam Bulaburtiro, Luuglaaw and mobile team 4 Sunguni, Yontoy  Instabul. The program&apos;s overall objective is to improve the health and nutritional status of children under the age of five, pregnant and lactating mothers, and the whole community through a comprehensive, integrated health and nutrition program.
Through this integrated approach, the program will focus on community mobilization and sensitization to enable active participation of the targeted community in the intended project activities leading to community management that will contribute to sustainable development. The project expected result under the nutrition program will be achieved through treatment and prevention services that entail early detection of malnutrition through active case finding by routine screening of 3259 girls and 3131 boys, and 2875 pregnant and lactating mothers for severe and moderate acute malnutrition. Based on the nutritional and clinical needs, 1316 boys and 1370 girls, 2492 pregnant and lactating mothers will be treated through the outpatient therapeutic program (OTP) and targeted supplementary feeding program (TSFP). In addition, routine provision of Vitamin A supplementation will reduce and prevent deficiency, reaching 3131 boys and 3259 girls and providing micronutrient supplementation to 1420 girls and 1142 boys aged 6-23 months. Under the health program, SOLO will provide essential primary health care services by improving maternal and child health care through antenatal care (ANC) and postnatal care (PNC), reaching 2492 women. Provision of maternity services targeting 336 through skill birth delivery and provision of 1500 women with child spacing services. Immunization services will also be provided, targeting 912 boys and 949 girls under five. Treatment of common illnesses and prevention, mental health care, emergency care, and sexual gender-based violence (SGBV) care targeting 3699 men, 4002 women,1685 boys and 1768 girls through outpatient department (OPD)services will also be provided. In addition, SOLO will conduct specific training to enhance and foster skills and capacity this will play a significant role in promoting empowerment and strengthening local skills and knowledge in treating and preventing illness and malnutrition. 
Lastly, a referral system will be established and strengthened within the primary health care centre and the 4 outreach services, including referral to the Kismayo general hospital for severe cases to enable continuum care. Coordination will be paramount SOLO will actively engage with communities, state and national coordination forums, including relevant clusters and other partners operating in the same area in nutrition, health, WASH, food security, and livelihood enhancing linkage and collaboration. The recommended interventions comply with HRP 2022&apos;s 1st standard allocation approach and the Health Cluster SO2, SO3 and Nutrition Cluster SO 2 and S0 3 under HRP 2022. The proposed project will provide lifesaving, comprehensive emergency health and nutrition services to ensure underserved rural communities have equal access to humanitarian response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Lifeline Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Lifeline Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-04-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eric Chibole</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254724956994</telephone>
   <email>finance@somalilifeline.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hussein Kulmiye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ED</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722263346</telephone>
   <email>k.hussein@somalilifeline.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joel Asiago</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722893751</telephone>
   <email>program.advisor@somalilifeline.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="46" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="54" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-28">448217.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-28">167447.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21502">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-28">615665.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Lifeline Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305572869">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-18">369399.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Lifeline Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
