<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/H-GBV/NGO/21440</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated provision of emergency lifesaving primary health care services and strengthening direct access to GBV services through principled referrals, risk prevention for internally displaced people (IDPs) and other persons affected by droughts within Afmadow district of Lower Juba Region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project targets the underserved population in Afmadow district affected by droughts. The recent health assessment undertaken in January 2022 (UNOCHA 2021) highlighted the plight faced by the community living in Afmadow residents. BADEF Organization will therefore provide emergency free ambulance services, maternal, newborn and child health, mobile outreach and MHPSS services to the affected populace among them the IDPs, Host communities in Afmadow preferably in the following locations Afmadow Camps: Farajano IDP, Awaqbanboow IDP, Camp Bilisa , Dhobley camps: Arbow, Moulid Laqay, Danwadag IDP camps
 The project seeks to improve referral services targeting an estimated 15,249 beneficiaries through the following interventions 
1) Provision of free ambulance services to reduce maternal deaths and child mortality and morbidity. In doing so, BADEF will avail 2 ambulances attached to selected mobile health facilities in Afmadow district 
2) Provision of 2 Mobile clinics for outpatient services targeting 15,249 people of 2590 men, 5289 women, 3540boys and 4,833 girls 
3) Immunization programs/VPD (BCG, penta, IPV and Measles) to 979 women of child bearing age, 1250 Boys and 1390 girls under 5 years 
5) Scale-up early warning and response (EWAR) and case management of epidemic prone diseases through surveillance and data use. The project will build and support the national HMIS and reporting of notifiable diseases of national concern for appropriate action. This will involve building the capacity of the health care service providers to getting adequate knowledge on EWAR.
6) Integration of Mental Health/Psycho-social Support (MHPSS) services, community engagement, and health education to community members to enhance identification and referral of persons of concern in need of MHPSS while also conducting a focused MHPSS intervention through trained social workers. Conduct psycho-education sessions for persons in need, including raising awareness on key protection risks faced by PSNs i.e. discrimination, stigma. The MHSS team will consist of, midwife and PSS counsellor.
The proposed project is designed to provide immediate lifesaving services and risk mitigation to 2,590 GBV survivors and vulnerable women and girls in the IDP population through the following interventions:
1)	 Case management and psychosocial support for 600 GBV survivors (380 women, 10 men, 10 Boys and 200 girls) provided by 4 GBV case workers in line with the guiding principles of GBV
2)	In collaboration with GBV and Health sub cluster, organize CMRS training to 16 nurses/midwives (14 Women, 2 Men) working in GBV health centers. This will be in close coordination with UNFPA trained facilitator in line with UNFPA curriculum.  
3)	BADEF will provide dignity amp menstrual kits to 1290 vulnerable individuals (1007 Women, 283 girls) including survivors, or at-risk girls and women based on survivor centered approach to cover their holistic needs and in line with the Somalia GBV AoR standards.
4)	In order to address immediate GBV concerns of women and girls, BADEF will provide Cash Voucher Assistance to 86 GBV survivors (60 Women, 26 Girls) based on case-by-case approach aimed at preventing, reducing exposure to specific protection risks rights-violations.
5)	BADEF will mobilize 20 PSS counselors (10 Men, 10 Women) for 4 days to deliver one on one and group psychosocial support and counseling for traumatized women and girls in the IDP camps. The counselors together with community mobilizers will sensitize the community and provide basic psychological support to the GBV survivors, early or forced marriage and vulnerable girls
6)	The case workers will provide transport cost for 280 GBV survivors (220 Women, 60 Girls) to access CMR services within health facilities in-line with WHO CMR guidelines and adherence to ethical standards to improve referral mechanisms for survivors and encourage the survivors report on time for timely response within the protocols</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bashir Hagio</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0615888383</telephone>
   <email>Bashirxaajow@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saadia Abdullahi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254790274427</telephone>
   <email>Info@badef.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-07">449111.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-07">50811.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21440">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-07">499922.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305605968">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">199969.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
