<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/WASH-Nut/NGO/21508</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency lifesaving WASH and NUTRITION support for the most vulnerable population affected by natural disasters (drought) and the impact of COVID-19 Pandemic.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The drought had a devastating impact on the lives and livelihood of an estimated 6.4 million persons in Somalia. Through this integrated approach, beneficiaries will benefit from Nutrition and WASH interventions where WASH and Nutrition facilities supported will offer services free of charge and facilitate access to all members of the community who seek services regardless of sex, age, race, disability, and sexual orientation. Services will be provided with a strong commitment to ethics on non-discrimination, do no harm, and access for all solely on the basis of need. A recent assessment conducted by SFH on the existing water supplies including existing boreholes and shallow wells in Lower Juba and particularly Afmadow and Dobley shows, 3 boreholes require urgent and significant rehabilitation due to the overuse and lack of sustainable power supply. In this proposed intervention SFH will select 1 borehole in Afmadow and establish it into a complete system. This will entail the installation of a solar system &#x201C;11Kwt submersible pump, 64 solar panels&#x201D;. Construction of 40M3 elevated concrete water tank, pipeline distribution network, and construction of 3 water kiosks with 6 facets and benefit 250 persons per tab. Distribution pipelines will be connected to the water tank which will supply water to the tap stands through gravity flow. Each pipeline distribution network will cover approximately 1.5KM in length and will benefit approximately 1,500 beneficiaries, thus reaching 4500 beneficiaries (Boys, girls, men, and women-including persons living with disability) for 1.5KM pipeline distribution systems. The construction process will include Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR) including raised plinths to withstand the structure against flash floods or any other natural disasters. The distance of fetching water will be reduced and water access especially for women will be prioritized through participation on the sites for the pipeline systems, Women will be consulted within the decision process to identify the locations of the water points to ensure safety and reduce chances of protection risks such as GBV.
Water quality testing will be conducted on the existing shallow wells and the borehole. Automatic chlorine dozing pumps will be provided to disinfect water and decrease the chances of water-borne diseases. Water quality tests will also ensure that water is free from fecal coliforms and is fit for human consumption. Community Hygiene Promoters will train the Water management committees on how to maintain the automatic chlorine dosing pumps. This will enrich the community&#x2019;s knowledge on water hygiene and will significantly reduce the cases of AWD outbreaks in areas of intervention.
SFH will construct 200 Communal Latrines (30 special +170 normal) with lockable doors and handwashing stations to eliminate open defecation. Hygiene promotion activities will be conducted through the community hygiene promoters who will be trained and also double to conduct hygiene kits distribution.
SFH will Strengthen the Community component of IMAM and community care practices in Afmadow districts through regular community education screening of children under five including referrals and follow-up treatment of under-nutrition (OTP amp SC), promotion of appropriate IYCF practices and dissemination of key health and hygiene messages. Community mobilization will enhance access to and coverage of nutrition services, contributing to reducing mortality by early detection of acute malnutrition. Key strategies include capacity-building of Community health workers and regular education sessions to equip the target communities with key skills and knowledge on the prevention and promotion of child and maternal health and nutrition practices. This intervention will directly target 1400 gender-disaggregated beneficiaries (Boys and girls) under the age of 6-59 months and 1000 Women of Child-Bearing Age including persons living with a disability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solutions for Humanity International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solutions for Humanity International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Bashir Abdi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0616087718</telephone>
   <email>Mohamed.Bashir@sfhsomalia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdi Hassan Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance and Administration Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0612365158</telephone>
   <email>ahassan.ahmed@sfhsomalia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="31" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="69" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">489207.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">160688.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21508">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">649895.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solutions for Humanity International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305570992">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-17">259958.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solutions for Humanity International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
