<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /FSC/INGO/21993</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Food and Livelihood support to support drought-affected groups in Laas Caanood District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ActionAid International is proposing an integrated lifesaving project to communities affected by the protracted drought. The proposed intervention is guided by the findings of Somali Food Security Outlook (February to September 2022) and a needs assessment conducted by ActionAid in Dec 2021, which identified food, water, and protection as priority needs in the target IDP camps. The proposed action will also address the negative coping mechanisms that displaced populations have adopted as a result of the current measures&apos; inadequacy of food, water, and lack of protection mechanism.
The overall objective of the action is to provide emergency lifesaving support to the drought affected populations in Sool region. The proposed action will target with the urban IDPs that are in IPC 3 amp 4 to reduce food consumption gap and pastoral communities living in villages who are struggling for the negative effects of the drought on their livestock. The project is specifically contributing to SHF focus &#x201C;to improve immediate needs to food through unconditional transfers (food assistance and cash)&#x201D;. In addition, the project is congruent with the food security cluster strategic objective &#x201C;Improve households&#x2019; immediate access to food through provision of conditional and unconditional assistance depending on the severity of food insecurity phases, vulnerability and seasonality of the livelihoods&#x201D;. 
Output 1:  7,014 vulnerable people living Adhicadeeye, Farxaskule and Wadajir IDP camps and households with malnourished under five children (SAM and MAM) receive unconditional (multipurpose) cash transfer for three months. Under this output, ActionAid will 1) Community Mobilization Meetings - the action will conduct three community mobilization meetings at Adhicadeeye, Wadajir and Farxaskule IDPs camps at Lasacanood district, around 1169 people from the community will be attending the meeting. The meeting will be attending by the community committee, residents of the IDP camp, representatives from district government and ActionAid project team, 2) Unconditional Cash transfers to improve access to food (1169 people x 3 round Months x 90 USD per month) through (ZAAD SERVICE) Based on the population per IDP camp, the action will target Adhicadeeye (391 HHs), Farxasule (389 HH) and Wadajir (389 HH ) to address households&#x2019; immediate access to food and other household priority needs through provision of unconditional cash transfer. 1 Post Distribution Survey After the Distribution of Cash in 3 Rounds/Months
Output 2: 300 pastoral household living in Canjiid and Tuulosamakaab villages received fodder and water for livestock, and cash plus for 3 rounds.  The project will undertake the following to realise this output 1) community mobilization meetings which will be taking place at the community meeting halls, with representative of different population groups like males, females, young, elderly two meetings, one for each village, will be held over a day. 500 people will attend the community meetings in each village, and these will be from members from the residents of the village, government officials and members from ActionAid officials, 2) Distribution of Water for Livestock, the action will distribute water for 300 pastoral households living in Canjiid (150 HH) and Tuulosamakaab (150 HH), 3) Distribution of Animal Fodder, the fodder distribution activity will 300 pastoral households living in Canjiid (150 HH) and Tuulosamokaab (150 HH) will be provided fodder for three round/months. Each household will receive 21 bags of wheat brain of which each is 25kgs to feed their livestock for three round/months, this means each household will be receiving 7 bags of wheat brain (25kgs each) in each round and 4) Provision of cash + emergency livelihoods, targeting 300 pastoral households living in Canjiid (150 HH) and Tuulosamokaab (150 HH) and will be provided cash ($90) per month for three round/months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid Somaliland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid Somaliland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deeq Ismail</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance and Administration Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634418182</telephone>
   <email>Deeq.Ismail@actionaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Suleiman Tarabi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEAL Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634021995</telephone>
   <email>Mohamed.Suleiman@actionaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Masimba Nyamanhindi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252637242538/+263772239234</telephone>
   <email>masimba.Nyamanhindi@actionaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">600000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21993">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">600000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Aid Somaliland</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
