<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /Shelter/NGO/22037</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency NFIs to the newly displaced people affected by droughts in Kahda  Hoosh  IDP Camps, Banadir Region, Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter Project will provide Emergency NFIs  through in kind distribution to 4500HH (27000 Persons (7500 men 7500 Women 6000 Boys and 6000 girls) the newly displaced to Kahda district Hoosh 5 IDPs camps namely Banaanay Center, Bishaaro Center,Bakat, ,Kismayo and Rahmatu rabi  IDP Camps, According to Shelter Monthly information product on March 2022, 115,314 people of drought-affected families arrived at Kaxda IDPs sites, lacking all basic services fronted by shelter/NFIs.  According to OCHA drought droiught (March-April 2022), at least 146,000 new IDPs have been displaced to Mogadishu in 2022, including 137,000 due to drought. The IDPs are mainly from Bay, Bakool, and Middle Shabelle, The IDPs HH comprising of female-headed households, children, elderly and disabled members, they can&#x2019;t return due to they have lost what ever they had and can&#x2019;t afford returning cost, each beneficiary will be getting NFI kit comprising 1 Plastic Sheet, 3Blanket, 2 Sleeping mat, 1Kitchen Set, 1 Mosquito nets, 2 Jeri cans and 1 Solar Lamps. To avoid creating tension among the beneficiaries the registration process will be accompanied with AYUUB criteria selection and selection committee including local authorities and community leaders ,The project will prioritize in protection mainstreaming component through ensuring the protection, safety and dignity of all beneficiaries by proper selection of neutral distribution point under shade and safe entry and exit routes during the distribution process. AYUUB will ensure and prevent discrimination or exclusion of marginalized groups. The project will compromise the following activities:-
1. Beneficiaries registration: AYUUB will hold consultations with community members to jointly determine the targeting criteria, AYUUB will prioritize the Most vulnerable people in the Targeted area to ensure that are assisted based on their needs , the beneficiary identification and criteria Selection are included beneficiaries with Specific needs, Marginalized communities, Female headed house hold ,families with orphans, disability people and Very Vulnerable people, We Consider Protection and COVID19 awareness in our Shelter activities including Social distance, Wearing Mask ,during beneficiary identification we select through the criteria aforementioned.
2. NFIs Through In Kind distribution: AYUUB will distribute NFIs through in Kind distribution to 4500 households (27000 Persons (7500 men 7500 Women 6000 Boys and 6000 girls) due to the unavailability of the NFI kits in the local markets and surroundings in the target area, Cash is Impossible alternatively, AYUUB will precure basic Non Food Items and Shelter Kit through Tender process in Bakara and Suuq Ba&#x2019;ad Market.The age and gender disaggregation is based on the demographic profile in Somalia and prioritization of women and girls who are the most affected by displacements. The actual gender and age breakdown will be reported once beneficiary registration is completed. AYUUB will procure the standard NFI kit content approved by the cluster
3. During the NFI distribution will be followed with a follow up monitoring, AYUUB will publicly mobilize to the Targeted community through microphones and meetings and placing the AYUUB Complaint and Feedback Mechanisms Hotline number / Free charge (2288) in the public gather areas for feedback and Suggestions.AYUUB will Closely coordinate with community members, Local Authority, partners in the ground and donors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Hassan Shariif</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615598290</telephone>
   <email>ayuubngo@ayuubngo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOHAMED YUSUF MOHAMED</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive directo</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615815907</telephone>
   <email>ayuubngo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-10">599977.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-22037">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-10">599977.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
