<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/CCCM/INGO/21465</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrating CCCM response by strengthening safe access to multi sectorial services including emergency responses at site level in Dhobley and Afmadow IDP Camps</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this project is intended to integrate CCCM response by strengthening safe access to multi sectorial services including emergency responses at site level through improved site management and site-level coordination targeting 14 verified IDP Camps (4 in Dhobley and 10 in Afmadow). The response will be executed by two organizations. Whereas Iimaan Relief and Development Organization (IRDO) will focus on Camp Coordination and Camp Management and on the other hand Juba Foundation will focus on Shelter and Protection (HLP). A total of 4 verified IDP camps namely (Camp Qorax, Arbow, Moulid Laqay and Dawadaag) will be managed by IRDO in Dhobley District hosting 2,680 households with 16,538 individuals who are the occupants of this sites according to the available and verified data from a CCCM Cluster data base. Additionally, IRDO will also manage 10 verified IDP Camps in Afmadow (Cameroon, Comp Yaaq, Comp Kaxda Nabada, Awaqbanboow, Waamo, Camp Buale, Farjano, Hodan, Fanole and lastly Camp Billisaa) hosting 1,826 households with 10,903 individuals. The integrated response will focus on providing Camp Coordination and Management activities as managed by IRDO whereas Juba Foundation will focus on providing services related to shelter, NFI and Protection (HLP).

The management of CCCM initiative is anticipated to improve the living conditions and general security of IDP population in the camps, as well as provide fair access to services and assistance for all those in need. Through this, the initiative is anticipated to strengthen safe access to multi sectorial services at site level through improved site management and coordination. The CCCM interventions is also anticipated to improve living conditions of displaced people through site development, care and maintenance and decongestion initiatives. Last but not least, strengthening of community self-management and access to information for displaced populations in which IRDO is expected to lead in the information decimation across different platforms. Men, women, boys and girls are all expected to benefit from the integrated intervention through various activities. Among the integrated CCCM activities that will be implemented by IRDO across all the 14 verified and targeted camps include monthly service mapping and site monitoring. Site verification which will be done on bi annually basis targeting all other camps, Safety Audit which is also an annual activity, Mapping of the existing structures at the camp level and carry out capacity building of 112 CMCs (8 members from each camp) by offering CMC training package on CCCM principles. Similarly, IRDO will also undertake a site decongestion planning/consultative/workshop with various stakeholders to agree on best practices to be adopted in ensuring that site decongestion activities are well executed as led by the community. Juba Foundation a co -implementing partner on Shelter, NFI and HLP is expected to work closely with IRDO on this activity item. A tool kit will be procured and tools distributed to 14 camps and CFM established.

As a result 79 beneficiaries are expected to benefit from Cash for Work activities which is anticipated to improve their cash flow and therefore enhance food security at a household level among the IDP populations as well as nutritional value. The Cash for Work beneficiaries are expected to work for 3 days a week equivalent to 12 days a month and each day earn of work $5 dollars translating to $60 dollars on monthly basis for 9 months. Furthermore, IRDO will purpose to provide weekly new arrival tracking of drought affected new arrivals which will be done on weekly basis by the implementing and updated Thursdays of every week. The immediate needs of the drought affected populations will therefore be shared with the co implementing partner (Juba Foundation) and CCCM Cluster for circulation and prompt immediate response from other clusters. IRDO will also establish Complaint Feedback Mechanism</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iimaan Relief and Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iimaan Relief and Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jack Francis</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254724496760</telephone>
   <email>financeirdo@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hussein Mohamed Hussein</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615568420</telephone>
   <email>iimaan.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Romano Iluku</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254727077521</telephone>
   <email>irdo.program@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">199930.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21465">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">199930.68</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iimaan Relief and Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
