<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /Prot/NGO/21981</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Protection Monitoring  Support for Acute at-risk populations in Lascanood and Buhoodle Districts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is in line with the 2nd SHF 2022 Reserve Allocation round as indicated in the Draft SHF Reserve: Allocation Famine Prevention (April/May 2022) strategy and seeks to address the General Protection concerns in Las Canood and Buhoodle in Somaliland occasioned by the extreme drought conditions that have affected thousands of people leading them into forced displacement from their homes in search of water, food, and pasture. 

SOYDAVO anticipates undertaking drought vulnerability protection monitoring using Key Informant Interviews (KIIs) and Focus Group Discussions (FGDs) in Buhoodle and Las Canood to identify individuals who are experiencing rights violations, the trends and patterns of these violations in order to provide evidence-based reports to inform response based on existing vulnerabilities and violations. The project will also seek to implement individual protection packages that address the effects of shocks and disasters on vulnerable populations and create referral pathways in Las Canood and Buhoodle that ensure that the victims of violations are supported with the provision of and access to community-based prevention and response and general protection services targeting PwDs, elderly, minority clans, extremely vulnerable IDPs, refugees, and migrants. 

The project seeks the advocacy for proper protection frameworks by relevant line ministries and implementing agencies in Las Canood and Buhoodle to address gaps identified through protection monitoring.  SOYDAVO will produce monthly reports on the status of the drought and protection vulnerability to inform response mechanisms by relevant actors and also identify and respond appropriately to at-risk vulnerable individuals and families in the project location.  There is the provision of dignity materials (adult diapers, sheets and mattresses among other items) to drought-affected people in Buhoodle and Las Canood, to help restore a sense of dignity.  SOYDAVO will provide unconditional cash assistance to victims of violations as a result of the drought in Buhoodle and Las Canood. The project seeks to provide mobility aids to PwDs, and the elderly and may include support for individuals who have other impairments affecting their access to assistance (e.g., glasses for those with severe visual impairments that have lost them during displacement).  The Project seeks to develop referral pathways, feedback, and complaint mechanisms for hard-to-reach populations (interior) and link them with existing referral pathways, feedback, and complaint mechanism to make them stronger and more responsive to addressing the at-risk populations. SOYDAVO will leverage its existing collaboration and partnership networks to work with CCM, SPMS, and PRMN to augment and enhance the project&apos;s effectiveness, particularly with the protection cluster. 

The planned project activities and  target beneficiaries are as follows:
-	Cash Assistance to 805 People
-	Dignity Materials to 1,400 People
-	Mobility Aids to 200 People

The village committee, district authorities, and project staff will identify the vulnerable people in the communities based on these criteria:
Cash assistance 
- Must be a victim of protection violations and can&#x2019;t afford to pay for the treatments. 
Dignity Material and Mobility Aids
- PwDs
 - Elderly
- Minority clans
- Extremely vulnerable IDPs
- Refugees
- Migrants

The locations were selected based on drought-vulnerability monthly assessments conducted by district authorities in Buhoodle and Las Canood that identified them with more at-risk populations. The project is 6 months and primarily targets vulnerable and drought-affected populations often excluded and marginalized (persons with disabilities, minority clan populations, elderly, extremely vulnerable IDPs, refugees, and migrants. The project targets 2,380 people, Las Canood &#x2013; 480, Las Canood/Hawlwadaag 215, Las Canood Wadajir-190 Adhicadeeye-310 and Buhodel-440, Cudanlay-210, Gocondhaa</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somaliland Youth Development and Voluntary Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somaliland Youth Development and Voluntary Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Husein Aideed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chairperson</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634300009</telephone>
   <email>chairperson@soydavo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdisalan Awke</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 63 4437610</telephone>
   <email>director@soydavo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amal Abdiqadir Sead</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634111175</telephone>
   <email>finance@soydavo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9676">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Togdheer</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.40000000 45.43300000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">249458.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21981">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">249458.28</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somaliland Youth Development and Voluntary Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
