<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /H/NGO/22015</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving primary health care services to drought affected vulnerable host and IDP communities rural villages of Jowhar District, Middle Shabelle Region - Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision planned intervention is designed to deliver primary health care services to crises affected women, boys, girls, vulnerable IDPs, people with disabilities and host communities affected by the impact of drought in Jowhar District, Middle Shabelle Region. The proposed project will run for 6 months and will support 21,000 individuals. The direct beneficiaries of the project are 1200 pregnant and lactating women, 4200(2142 girls and 2058 boys) under five children and16800 (8232 males and 8568 females). Through this initiative, Aid Vision will operationalize one Cholera Treatment Centre(Horseed  CTC) in Jowhar town, three health facilities  that include ( Geedo Berkan Health center, Marerey health center and Yabal2/Kongo  center) and one mobile team that will cover  5 villages (Gaafaay,Bula Bishara,Kalundi,Magadley and Linta) in the hard to reach area that have little or no access of health care  services. The proposed project will provide life-saving primary health care services that include but not limited to free Antenatal and Postnatal care services, provision of AWD/cholera treatment, free skilled deliveries, free consultation and treatment of both under and over fives for common illnesses, immunization services both at the community and facility level. In addition, GBV intervention will be mainstreamed with the proposed health facilities to provide clinical management of rape and refer cases to safe house centers. Aid Vision will map partners providing specialized protection services and existing referral pathways. The project has also component of community health workers who will do active case finding, defaulter tracing, health/hygiene promotion messages  to the target groups at the community level. PPEs will be provided to the frontline health care workers to limit human to human transmission of covid19 virus. 
For purpose of the sustainability of the project, Aid Vision will employ community based participatory approach through strengthen community capacity, by capacity building own staff, local Authority staff, MoH staff and CHWs. The proposed project will be complimented by Aid Vision integrated  health and Nutrition project in Jowhar supported by SHF. Aid Vision will coordinate with WASH partner -SCC in Jowhar district  and closely work with other agencies (including but not limited to IMC, Terre Solidali and SOS)  in the region to better coordinate humanitarian interventions and avoid duplication.
The project is also designed to be gender sensitive as specific needs of men and women will be catered for. For instance, toilet facilities will be segregated for men and women, equally the project will directly target special groups including persons with disability, pregnant and lactating women, children under-fives who are affected by the impact of drought  in Jowhar Districts of Middle Shabelle Region.
The proposed project design is anchored on Somalia Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP2022) by reducing loss of lives for 5 million of the most severely vulnerable people, including 1 million children under 5, decreasing the prevalence of hunger, acute malnutrition, public health threats, and outbreaks, and abuse, violence and exposure to explosive ordinances by the end of 2022</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Raghe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">President/CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615555249</telephone>
   <email>info@aidvision.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idris Harrun Yussuf</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252610769460</telephone>
   <email>shanganihc@aidvision.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-08">268105.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-22015">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-08">268105.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305631996">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-16">107242.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Vision</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
