<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /GBV-CP/NGO/21973</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Protection Environment for Drought-affected IDPs through GBV Prevention  Response  Mitigation of Child Protection risks in Baydhabo District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project design aims to provide immediate lifesaving services and mitigate famine risk to GBV survivors, vulnerable women, girls and boys in the IDP population (from Madhayto, Xanano 3, Tabaarak, Sarmanweyn, Jiidow Bakool DP camps in Baydhabo Horseed section among other areas in the wider Baidoa district that are in need of GBV services ) through:
1) Case management and psychosocial support for 300 GBV survivors (220 women, 10 men, 10 boys and 60 girls) provided by 4 GBV caseworkers in line with the guiding principles.
2) READO will provide dignity amp menstrual kits to 848 vulnerable individuals (648 Women, 200 girls) including survivors, or at-risk girls and women based on the survivor-centred approach to cover their holistic needs and in line with Somalia GBV AoR standards.
3) To address immediate GBV concerns of women and girls, READO will provide Cash Voucher Assistance to 100 GBV survivors (80 Women, 20 Girls) based on a case-by-case approach aimed at preventing and reducing exposure risks.
4) To support the case management process and the most vulnerable individuals, READO will procure emergency support i.e. Non-foods items including Plastic sheets, Torch, Flask/Plastic thermos, Jerry can (20 litres) Mattresses, Bedsheets, Sleeping Mats and distribute to 400 beneficiaries(300 women, 50 men, 50 boys and 100 girls)  including GBV survivors, Men, Boys, female-headed households, and other women at risk of GBV due to poor lighting systems that expose them to sexual violence at night.
5) The caseworkers will provide transport costs for 280 GBV survivors (220 Women, 60 Girls) to access CMR services within health facilities in-line with WHO CMR guidelines and adherence to ethical standards to improve referral mechanisms for survivors and encourage the survivors to report on time for a timely response within the protocols.
READO will collaborate with the local authorities to identify and target the beneficiaries with a focus on those affected by drought to cushion them from the further effect of famine, related to GBV and protection risks. Cash voucher assistance aims to ensure the mitigation of associated risks, including risks of Gender-based Violence (GBV) in order to meet the specific needs and ensure the safety, dignity, and inclusion of diverse groups at risk of famine. 

On child protection, the response focuses on children&apos;s needs by addressing multiple protection risks for up to 200 girls and 200 boys through a comprehensive set of activities (in coordinated CP AoR SoPs) in a gender-sensitive approach for supporting children at risk including unaccompanied or separated children and adolescents through case management services that meet their unique needs, as well as mitigation and preparedness measures for speedy family tracing and reunification. Psycho-social support will also directly focus on 50 men / 100 women caring for separated children. READO will work with volunteers to prevent and mitigate risks to children by building their capacity on the rights approach. As part of case management, READO will provide PFA during identification. Reunification aims to also cushion UASC from famine, and READO will also work with caregivers on positive parenting as well as provide PSS to vulnerable caregivers affected by drought, conflict as well as COVID-19. Additionally, the project will engage with the community on awareness and mobilization of prevention messages against sexual violence, and harmful practices.
READO, comprehensive case management will include linkage to other services in line with the best interest assessment of each individual child, where services are not available, READO will provide transportation cost of $20 per child to support the reunification and/or access to services (such as health care, education) for 400 (50% girls, 50% boys) while accompanied with a caseworker</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muktar Mohamed Adan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615559433</telephone>
   <email>admin.finance@readosom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdullahi Abdirahaman Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>252615104060/</telephone>
   <email>info@readosom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-08">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21973">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-08">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Education and Agriculture Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
