<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/RA2 /FSC/NGO/22005</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Food Security Response to drought affected communities in Odweyne District in the Togdheer region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is that the food security situation of  1390 vulnerable households (8340 individuals) in mostly rural communities in Odweyne district of Somaliland is stabilized and communities are more resilient towards adverse climatic conditions.

To achieve the overall objective, the project offers a) unconditional cash (Cash +), provision of supplementary animal feeds and provision of water for livestock through rehabilitation of strategic water sources. The project directly targets an estimated 8340 individuals (mostly rural communities) particularly IDP communities, Host communities, households with malnourished children under-five child (SAM amp MAM)based on admission records and households with PWDs in Hara Sheikh, Gawama, Daba gorayale, Gatitaley, Haji Salax and Haydanle villages in Odweyne District, Togdheer region. The entire project duration is 6 months while the timeframe for UCT and Cash + to be disbursed will be 3 months to stabilize food security levels, One time distribution of supplementary animal feed and water trucking for 25 days. The major activities for UC and Cash+  will start with sharing selection criteria in a transparent manner with village leaders and communities.

Specifically, 850 households (HHs) will receive Unconditional Cash Transfers while 450 households will receive Unconditional Cash transfers (Cash +). The cash transfers empower people with choice to address their essential and individual food needs, while also helping to boost local markets. The cash values to be transferred on a monthly basis are provided by the Cash Working Group (CWG) Somalia based on the minimum expenditure basket (MEB) as per region across Somalia. The latest food cash transfer values for families in Togdheer is USD 85 (June &#x2013; August 2022). A local telephone company (Telesom) with extensive experience of conducting cash transfer to beneficiaries in remote areas will be commissioned to conduct monthly cash transfers to beneficiaries&#x2019; mobile phones. The beneficiaries who may not know how to use the services will be trained on how to use it. Candlelight will also procure supplementary animal feed which will be distributed to the same 540 households (Those receiving Cash+) with each household receiving at least 80 kgs. 

Also, water for livestock is one of the key issues that was noted in the Humanitarian Needs Overview (2022) in order to provide water to livestock and prevent drought-related fatalities the project will support water trucking in all the target villages, targeting the 540 households who are receiving Cash+ and Animal feed. Each of the 7 target villages have been allocated 1 truck of 45 barrels each day for a period of 25 days continuously. It&apos;s estimated that the 7 trucks of water of water per day can serve approximately 540 households (3240 individuals) in all villages with each household receiving approximately 117 liters. A strong community-self-monitoring mechanism will be established with the community committees to ensure the objectives for water trucking are achieved by the targeted recipients.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Candlelight for Environment Education and Health</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Candlelight for Environment Education and Health</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirizaq Bashir Libah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ececutive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634427848</telephone>
   <email>abdirizaqlibah@candlelightsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elijah Mulumba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 63 4416009</telephone>
   <email>m.elijah@candlelightsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samiira Jama Elmi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 63 4428308</telephone>
   <email>samiraelmi@candlelightsom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9676">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Togdheer</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.40000000 45.43300000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-21"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">498172.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-22005">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-27">498172.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Candlelight for Environment Education and Health</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
