<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/Nut-WASH/INGO/21513</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Lifesaving  WASH and Nutrition Assistance for drought-affected populations in Dhobley in Afmadow district, Lower Juba region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alight proposes to implement an integrated WASH program to address critically poor nutrition outcomes in vulnerable populations through targeting severely and moderately acutely malnourished children under five years old (U5) and pregnant and lactating women (PLW), and drought-affected communities including IDPs in need of access to water and sanitation services
Alight will contribute to improved nutrition outcomes of vulnerable households in Afmadow district targeting Dhobley and its neighboring villages through life-saving nutrition services and provisions and restoration of essential WASH services&#x2013; all complemented by, nutrition, and hygiene education aimed at behaviour change. 
Nutrition:
Curative and preventive nutrition interventions will be provided through 3 fixed Health facilities (Tula-barwaqo, Deg-elema, Dhobley SC) and 10 mobile/outreach sites (hard to reach villages around Dhobley area). Screening for acute malnutrition will take place for all under-fives and pregnant and lactating women (PLW) at the community level as well as during outpatient consultations, with treatment administered through outpatient therapeutic programmes (OTP), targeted supplementary feeding programmes (TSFP) and, in the most severe cases to stabilization centre (SC) in Dhobley. Infant and young child feeding (IYCF) messages will be delivered through group and one-to-one sessions.
 At the end of the project, Nutrition will reach directly a total of 2,120 (1039 boys and 11081girls) with Severe acute malnutrition, 5,796 (2840 boys and 2956 girls) and 1149 PLW with moderate acute malnutrition. In addition, a total of 6940 PLW will be reached with key IYCF messages in the targeted area. Provision of Micronutrient support for 6509 (3204 boys and 3335 girls) children 6-59 months and 2942 PLW with Vitamin A and multiple micronutrients (MMN). Staff capacity development through Training of 26 staff (11 male and 15 female) on integrated management of acute malnutrition (IMAM), infant and young child feeding (IYCF) guidelines to improve quality of nutrition services.  

WASH: 
WASH support will be provided at the health facility and community levels, restoring basic and essential water and sanitation services through water system rehabilitation, incorporating the use of solar pumps. At health facilities/Nutrition facilities, this will include rehabilitation of drinking water supply systems and sanitation systems (including toilets, handwashing, and waste management). In communities, this will include the provision of emergency water trucking services, rehabilitation of community water points, drilling of a new borehole for a drought-affected community, installation of solar systems, water chlorination and water quality monitoring, Hygiene promotion through community hygiene volunteers will encompass all WASH interventions. Furthermore, given the program&#x2019;s targeting of the most vulnerable households, hygiene kits, and dignity kits will be provided to vulnerable households with children or PLW enrolled in the outpatient therapeutic programs (OTPs) or supplemental feeding program (SFP). 
Overall, Alight intends to reach approximately  29989 people ( 5998 men, 8997 women, 6569 girls, and 8425 boys) who will benefit from the WASH and nutrition components.
 ALIGHT&#x2019;s integrated approach combining the WASH intervention with nutrition components ensures greater impact in the area of operation. Adequate WASH improves the overall public health indicators, including the lower incidence of communicable diseases, reduced mother and child morbidity, and stronger effects of nutrition interventions as a result of prevention of loss of valuable nutrients from diarrheal diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdinur Abdi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy CD</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252617326185</telephone>
   <email>Abdinura@wearealight.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adan Adar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254704595491</telephone>
   <email>adana@wearealight.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adan Haluba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615035177</telephone>
   <email>adanh@wearealight.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khadar Mohamud</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634480542</telephone>
   <email>khadarm@wearealight.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-14">599442.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-14">150375.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21513">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-14">749818.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
