<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/WASH/NGO/21532</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide lifesaving WASH services to the most vulnerable drought-affected/displaced communities including IDPs to prevent loss of lives and drought-induced displacement in lower juba region, kismayo IDPs and rural locations.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDP communities in Kismayo face cyclical scarcity to safe and sufficient water due to the current drought and protracted vulnerabilities. Vulnerable communities rely on unsafe water for drinking and domestic use, leading to increased health risks and poor living standards. Kismayo town is now attracting a huge displaced population who are forced to move to urban centres in search of livelihood opportunities, however, these populations join overcrowded IDP settlements where available WASH infrastructure is overstretched. Findings from a recent Tasco assessment confirmed 100% of the displaced communities in Kismayo IDPs (New) don&#x2019;t have access to Latrines which has contributed to open defecation menace that will cause cholera outbreak if not mitigated early. Similarly, the newly displaced IDPs and rural villages don&#x2019;t have access to clean and safe water.

Water and food prices have continued to rise sharply. In Jubaland State/Kismayo, prices of water have increased by 20 per cent in some rural locations with a 20-litter barrel costing $0.7 to $1, before and during the drought, respectively. Severe water shortages and inadequate access to sanitation and hygiene facilities have heightened the risk of disease outbreaks. Cases of Acute Watery Diarrhea/Cholera, as well as measles outbreaks, are spiking in multiple droughts affected locations including the Lower Jubba region.

TASCO will respond to these compounded risks by implementing complimentary WASH Activities that include Provision of temporary access to safe water through water trucking through vouchers to drought-affected rural communities for a maximum of 60 days, rehabilitation of five shallow wells in Kismayo IDPs, construction of flood-resistant latrines with handwashing facilities 
including 15% people with disabilities in Kismayo district, similarly the projects  will also target 2815HHs for hygiene kits(16890 individuals) of Newly Drought displaced IDPs in Kismayo.

The water trucking will target 2400hh with largely underserved and high-WASH risk IDP settlements in Galbet IDP and rural villages including leheley, leekoley, jiif wayne, Biyagaduud,xaajiweyne, istanbul and Barkada Shariifada. To ensure the sustainability of this action,TASCO will do a set of complimentary activities including water tracking, rehabilitation of 5 strategic shallow wells,water management committees training,Hygiene Promotion and will closely collaborate with the Local Authorities, line Ministries and Partners operating in the same geographical areas to reduce chances of overlapping. Moreover, TASCO will construct 201 flood-resistant and gender-sensitive latrines with 15% for people with disability to ensure year-round use as well as the distribution of Hygiene kits to 2815 hh. The full suite of activities aims to meet the acute needs of the vulnerable IDP communities.

The project is designed to ensure equitable access to WASH services by older people and those with disabilities, the safety of children and dignity and privacy for women and girls.The provision of immediate life-saving and sustainable solutions will contribute greatly to the reduction of morbidity/mortality and an improved sense of dignity, comfort, and security. Coordination with WASH clusters at national and state levels will be maintained, in addition to ongoing coordination with general key actors in Lower Juba, Kismayo in particular. Gender issues will be addressed through collecting gender and age-disaggregated data, which will be analyzed to identify gaps, implement disability-inclusive and gender-sensitive interventions, and ensure people with disabilities and women&apos;s participation and empowerment. Protection of beneficiaries will be ensured during access and utilization of services to minimize future risk</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farah Shukri Osman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252616459244</telephone>
   <email>farah.osman@taakulo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">449180.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">50819.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21532">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305566311">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-13">400000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
