<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/FSC/NGO/21437</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of lifesaving and emergency livelihoods support to the most vulnerable agro-pastoral affected by drought in Rural Bardhere districts of Gedo region, Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADA is planning to support the most vulnerable agro-pastoral communities in Bardhere district, Gedo region of Somalia, through supporting 820 agro-pastoral households with quality fodder feeds and unconditional cash transfers. Support in conditional cash transfers to 180 agro-pastorals, pastorals and IDPs households through rehabilitation of four water catchments, and support 450 households with water trucking activities.  The project will primarily target agro-pastoralist, IDPs, pastoral drop outs and rural poor living in and around the IDP camps and in rural villages. A total of 1,450 households will be supported for the 6-months project in ten villages in rural Bardhere district, Gedo region of Somalia. 

The project objective is to Improve and sustain life-saving food security and livelihood to 1,450 vulnerable agro-pastoral households consisting of  (2,088 men, 4,620 women, 522 boys and 1470 girls) affected by drought and protracted humanitarian crisis in Bardhere district of Gedo region in Somalia. The project will target the following villages Buloamin, Hureyna, Buulo Jadiid, Shimbiroole, Tawakal, Sarinleey, Buulo Baanyo, Buulo Garas, Bakal, Jafey in Bardhere district, Gedo region.
The strategic objective of this project: 
1. To improve access to food for people facing severe acute food insecurity
2. To protect livelihoods and related food and income sources for farmers, pastoralists, agro pastoralists and rural IDP.

ADA will ensure that the project is implemented through engagement with all relevant stakeholders, ADA has planned activities such as beneficiary selection, vulnerable Households with preference women headed Households will be selected and enrolled for the fodder feeds, water catchment, water trucking, conditional ampunconditional cash transfers. At least 70% would be women and 15% disabled persons. Procurement and distribution of quality fodder feeds to 820 households. Each livestock keeper will receive 30Kgs of fodders feed with total value of $255 per HH.

Fodder beneficiary households will be identified based on their vulnerability, such as low livestock holdings, low fodder availability, demonstrable positive coping behavior, and the presence of vulnerable people in their households. Quality fodder feeds will be sourced through local vendors for timely implementation of activities, since time is a critical matter as livestock will require urgent interventions.  ADA will ensure to carry out procurement and registration process by April 2022.The distribution will occur around May-June 2022. The farmers will ensure to feed the Sudan to their livestock&#x2019;s. The Sudan grass is exceptionally safe and good for the livestock, thus by increasing livestock feedings, the availability of milk will be improved and hence the ease of access to food for the households, this will directly contribute to an improvement in the food consumption score. A total of 820 households will benefit from unconditional cash transfers for three (3) months (April, May and June 2022), each will receive $210.

ADA will support in rehabilitating four water catchment sites. Each village about 45 households will be registered (total of 180 households) and will be engaged on labour activities for 3- months working, where each household would desilt about 70cubic metre of soil for three months. As such the participants will be paid $3 per metre-cubic, at the end of the activity each labourer is expected to complete 70cubic metres for the three (3) months, thus each household will collect $210 for the three months period. In addtion water trucking activities will support 450 households, where each day about 4 trucks, each holding capacity of 10,000Litres will be utilised for livestock consumption.

Lastly, ADA will conduct PDM survey to assess the effectiveness of the distribution process, to verify the number of beneficiaries who received their entitlements through the support of ADA&apos;s MEAL unit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr.Noor Ahmed Abdi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 724 612324</telephone>
   <email>Noor.abdi@ada.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Ali Mohamed Durow</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722458120</telephone>
   <email>activedev1_gedo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr.Adan Ukash Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615765791</telephone>
   <email>adan.okash@adasom.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9666">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gedo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.80200000 41.68800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-11">500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21437">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-11">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305570995">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-17">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active in Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
