<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-22/3485/SA1/Ed-CP/NGO/21420</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Integrated package of Emergency Education and Child Protection services for drought affected children including children with disability in Nugal (Burtinle) and Bari (Iskushuban,Qandala) Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Drought has deepened in Somalia and could push the country to the verge of a catastrophe in the coming months. Due to the deteriorating situation, the number of people affected has increased by nearly 35 per cent in just one month, from 3.2 million to about 4.3 million people. Of these, about 271,000 people have been displaced from their homes in search of food, water and pasture, according to data from partners. (OCHA Jan 2022). Children who drop out of school during a crisis are highly unlikely to return and are at increased risk of joining groups of out-of-school children and adolescents, placing them at risk of harmful practices, especially child marriage and possible child labour. lessons learnt from the 2011 famine show that many of the deaths of children caused by the drought could have been prevented if children had access to life-saving services at schools.
In the proposed project TASS aims to provide age-appropriate, disability-sensitive Quality education that will ensure drought affected children and youth have access to safe and protective learning environments and also provide them with quality CP services that will be focused on prevention, mitigation and response. TASS will prioritize hard-to-reach areas and will aim to provide these services in Burtinle, Qandala and Iskushuban Districts. The project will target 5,700 (3042 boys and 2658 girls) drought-affected children including children with disability living in hard-to-reach areas in 17 drought-affected schools (8 in iskushuban, 4 In qandala and 5 in Burtinle) with life-saving component such: 
	school-based feeding- 3,668 (1931 boys and 1737 girls) beneficiaries, 
	Provision of sanitary kits (1,250 girls), 
	Teacher incentives (51 teachers), 
	Strengthening Community Education Committees ability to manage water and school feeding programmes and Child protection at school Level- 85 (51 male, 34 female)
	Psycho-social Support- in all the 17 target schools for all the children through recreation activies that is disability friendly
	Distribution of school learning materials to target 5,700 (3042 boys and 2658 girls) drought-affected children including children with disability living in hard-to-reach areas.
       TASS will conduct Referral mapping that will strengthen referral systems from schools to child protection services 
	Appoint and train Child Protection focal points at school (1 male/1female) per school with additional PSS First Aid training and knowledge of referral pathways to specific child protection services
The project is combined with child protection component which includes strengthening existing child protection community-based mechanisms to create an overall enabling safe protective environment for children through 
	Provision of complete FTR Services to UASC- 100 (60 Boys and 40 Girls)
	Provision of Child Protection Case Management (200 beneficiaries), 
	Psychosocial support services provision to emergency-affected children and adolescents, caregivers (1020 care givers)
	TASS will conduct community awareness on protection risks potentially caused by the drought, induced harmful coping practices such as child marriages, family separation, unsafe migration, hazardous child work, as well as messages on the importance of good hygiene and nutrition and breastfeeding- 2700 (900 Men, 900 women, 450 boys and 450 girls)
	TASS will conduct one Child Safety walks audit  through identifying the safety risk for children and population in the targeted locations and strengthen the CP referral pathways to ensure integrated interventions are safe, accessible, inclusive and protective for all children.  
	Strengthening of community-based Child-friendly spaces to ensure the safety and wellbeing of children at school and community level and provision of Structured psychosocial support and recreational activities to school-going children and children in the IDPs camps and their caregivers particularly children with Disability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirahman Mohamed Dahir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906527238</telephone>
   <email>adahir@tadamun.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ali Abdullahi Diriye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252906796444</telephone>
   <email>ali.abdullahi@tadamun.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ibrahim Abdullahi Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907798815</telephone>
   <email>ibrahim@tadamun.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9663">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bari</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.64800000 50.23200000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9673">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nugaal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.20900000 48.84600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">599587.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">150412.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-21420">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-12">750000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tadamun Social Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
