<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-18/DDA-3474/PAK 18/Shelter/NFI/NGO/7783</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter Cash assistance to the vulnerable families at the areas of Return of Kuram Agency with special focus on women  child headed Families</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is based on the needs identified by the FATA vulnerability assessment findings. Based on the Vulnerability assessment report, Shelter cash assistance to 320 families of Ali sher zai, Zaimusht and Khoidad khel of Kurram Agency will be based on their vulnerability.  
In March 2015, the Pakistan army declared the area clear from the militants and the TDPs started return to their hometown to face the harsh reality of their destroyed houses and infrastructure.  The public infrastructure of schools, health units, roads and bridges etc. were destroyed during the military operation and continuous fighting. UNHCR was the first humanitarian organization that stepped to provide emergency assistance to the families (tents and NFIs) to cater their immediate shelter needs. FRD was part of the interventions as partner in Kurram agency to facilitate the families. Although the interventions provided immediate relief, but there is a need for permanent solutions to the shelter needs. There had already been some interventions in the agency under the PHPF but the need are high and there had been new returns since the last interventions, therefore is a need to provide assistance to the families of Ali sher zai, Zaimusht and Khoidad khel tribes. The area have seen severe devastation and are relatively new in term of returns. The families need permanent shelter which can help them escape the harsh weather conditions of the area and provide them security and protection with women and children and the elderly who are extremely vulnerable in such conditions. The project will complement the govt. efforts to resettle the families&#x2019; at their areas of origin through providing a long term permanent solution to their shelter needs. 
The project will target 320 of the most vulnerable families of kuram Agency at their areas of return with the provision of cash assistance for rehabilitation of their houses in accordance with their indigenous construction practices, with incorporation of the possible DRR measures and Guidance by the FRD technical staff.FRD has already been part of shelter assistance at Kurram agency and completed a project for the assistance of 310 families under the PHPF in 2016. FRD is still is on ground as part of the WFP interventions in the area. The proposed interventions will be the part of phase two interventions as per the shelter cluster strategy to enable the families to have suitable shelter solutions to their needs and in line with the PHPF allocation strategy for shelter sector. Due to high needs the project will target only the most vulnerable families which will primarily include the unregistered families and other vulnerable families with special priority to the women and child headed families. Over all the intervention will assist 320 most vulnerable families with priority to the women, child headed and the elderly headed families with no other support from any other source. 
Each beneficiary family will be provided with cash assistance of Dollars 600/- in three tranches. Each beneficiary family will utilize the assistance money for construction and FRD technical team will provide technical guidance and layouts to the beneficiary. Since preference in the identification is given to the female and the elderly therefore the field teams of FRD will also facilitate the arrangement of the skilled and unskilled labor from within the community with the facilitation of the community organizations formed as part of the community mobilization activities of the project.in case of extremely vulnerable family i.e. women headed household or elderly with no one for the construction work required for the construction, additional 100 dollars will be provided to 5o most vulnerable families as identified by the community organizations formed for project implementation facilitation as part of the project.  
After the completion of the shelter each beneficiary will be provided 100 Dollars cash for the solar panel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Rural Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Rural Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Azmat Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00923457776661</telephone>
   <email>azmat@frd.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fahim - Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00923459777783</telephone>
   <email>fahim@frd.org.pk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-02">299954.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1106882807">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-30">2451.18</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Rural Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-7783">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-02">299954.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Rural Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303439391">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-11">239963.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Rural Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303677758">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-23">59990.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Rural Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
