<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK-18/DDA-3474/PAK 18/H/NGO/7832</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Revitalization of Integrated Primary Health care services to reduce morbidity and mortality among the  returnees areas of Tehsil Makeen and laddah of South Waziristan Agency &#x2013; FATA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Waziristan is the largest Agency of FATA which has suffered at the hands of extremist elements and a subsequent military operation during the recent years. This has led to disruption of normal life and displacement of large segment of the local population from their homes. Women Empowerment Organization proposed project will be implemented in South Wazirtsan Agency. WEO designed this project in such a way that, Women, Men, Children, Adolescent and Youth including vulnerable groups have improved access to quality and equitable health services in 2 targeted Tehsils(Laddah and Makin) of South Wazirstan Agency. 

Under this grant WEO will make functional the following four (4) non-functional Health facilities.
1.CD Murubi, Tehsil Laddah,
2.CHC Tangi Budinzai, Tehsil Laddah
3.CD Makeen Tehsil Makeen
4.CD Chlarai Tehsil Makeen

WEO will Construct four(4)Prefabricated Health Facilities in 2 tehsils of South Wazirstan Agency as per need identified in FATA vulnerability Assessment in August/September 2017. WEO will ensure through Pakistan Humanitarian Pooled fund that four (4) non-functional government health facilities in the return areas of South Wazirstan Agency will be made operational to the fullest through provision of Prefabricated Health facilities.Initially WEO will establish four(4) Mobile Health Units to provide Integrated primary health care and psycho social support services. WEO plans to construct Prefabricated Health facilities within 4 months and then WEO health teams will be deployed from mobile health units to newly constructed Pre-Fabricated structures. 

WEO will provide Primary Health care services to 33450 patients during the project life, out of which 6810 will be male, 9600 female, 8400 Boys ad 8640 girls&#x2019; .WEO will deploy 4 health teams in targeted 4 government health facilities for 6 days a week for 7 months. WEO will provide first level of treatment to patients men, women and children for general diseases like Diarrheaamp Dysentery, Gastro Interties, URI, LRI, Otitis Meadia (Ear Plus), Enteric Fever, Scabies, Dental carries, UTI, Worm infection, Dermatitis amp Oral Trush etc. The patients will be examined and pharmacy staff will provide medicines to the patients as prescribed by the doctor. One health team will comprise upon: 1 Male/Female Medical Officer 1 Male medical Technician 1 Lady health worker and 1 Social Organizers and 1 psychologist on rotation basis.


WEO will ensure to provide Integrated Primary Health care services to returnee women in targeted 4 Health facilities of South Wazirstan agency.4800 returnee women and children will be provided with Mother and child health care, IYCF, Family planning and counseling. Recognizing, stabilizing and referring obstetric, neonatal and other emergencies to the higher level and follow-up of the referred cases will be done. Counseling on family planning and will be provided etc. 

WEO will distribute 600 Safe Baby Kits and 600 Safe Clean Delivery kits among the vulnerable women. Clean Delivery kits will be provided to pregnant women in 3rd trimester. Maternal and Child Nutrition promotion and education will be done through counseling: including growth monitoring, exclusive breastfeeding, timely and appropriate introduction of complementary feeding, nutrition during pregnancies, management of Iron deficiency anemia and Vitamin A deficiencies, diagnosis and referral of moderate and severe acute malnutrition to appropriate centers. Assessment and management of common childhood illnesses like diarrheal diseases and ARI. Training mothers to prepare homemade ORS and use of ORS. Referral mechanism will be established and strengthened with the nearby tertiary hospitals through the health field staff  of the 4 health facilities. Beside this Medicines, medical equipment&#x2019;s and furniture will be provided to 4 health facilities. WEO will provide psycho social support to 640 patients and furthermore 72 health and hygiene sessions will be conducted</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Empowerment Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Empowerment Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-11" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jan Nisar Ahmad</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager-WEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+92 341 32 55 750</telephone>
   <email>jannisar4u@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meena Baber</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Executive Officer-WEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+92 345 530 1938</telephone>
   <email>wmn.empowerment@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="PK4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fata</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.18320000 70.41980000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-13">355333.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-13">144612.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="PAK60-7832">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-13">499945.73</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Empowerment Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303459295">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-25">299967.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Empowerment Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303779752">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-15">199978.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Empowerment Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-PAK60-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
