<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-organisations version="2.02">
 <iati-organisation default-currency="USD" iati-organisations:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-organisations="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-organisations">
  <organisation-identifier>XM-DAC-1409</organisation-identifier>
  <name>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Integrated Framework</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EIF is the only multi-donor global Aid for Trade fund exclusively for the LDCs. It brings together LDC governments, donors and other development partners and helps them align their efforts toward a single, mutually desirable goal: harnessing trade for LDC growth. The EIF works on the trade-related challenges of the world&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x2122;s poorest countries, assisting them at every stage of their journey to leverage trade for growth and poverty reduction.</narrative>
  </name>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-1409" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Integrated Framework</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.enhancedif.org/">
   <recipient-country code="CH">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Enhanced Integrated Framework (EIF) brings together partners and resources to support the Least Developed Countries (LDCs) in using trade for poverty reduction, inclusive growth and sustainable development. The EIF is a global partnership between the LDCs, Donors and International Agencies, underpinned by a multi-donor trust fund, which provides financial and technical support to build trade capacity in 47 LDCs and 4 graduated countries. The EIF is the only global Aid for Trade (AfT) programme exclusively designed for the LDCs and therefore is uniquely placed to assist the countries to develop sustainable trade strategies. Through a multilateral approach, the EIF ensures a coordinated, transparent and efficient delivery of AfT. The EIF is recognized under Goal 8a of the Sustainable Development Goals.</narrative>
   </recipient-country>
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EIF website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B16"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-04-18"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-organisation>
</iati-organisations>
