<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11965A0101-MKD-15131</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intelligence Sector Reform and Oversight (DCAF)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Intelligence Sector Reform and Oversight (DCAF)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den politiska krisen i Makedonien som kulminerade i den s&#xE5; kallade avlyssningsskandalen 2015 avsl&#xF6;jade genomgripande kr&#xE4;nkningar av grundl&#xE4;ggande r&#xE4;ttigheter, respektl&#xF6;shet inf&#xF6;r yrkesetik, l&#xE5;ngtg&#xE5;ende maktmissbruk och bristande kunskap om k&#xE4;nsligheten i underr&#xE4;ttelsehantering. I en rapport av seniora r&#xE4;ttsexperter best&#xE4;lld av EU Kommissionen uppmanades till br&#xE5;dskande reform av underr&#xE4;ttelsetj&#xE4;nsten och dess tillsyn. Vikten av denna reform bekr&#xE4;ftades av den makedonska regeringen och ingick &#xE4;ven i den nya regeringens f&#xF6;rsta reformprogram. 

Sida bidrar med 4,5 Mkr till ett samfinansierat initiativ som hanteras av DCAF (the Geneva Centre for the Democratic Control of the Armed Forces) och som handlar om reform av underr&#xE4;ttelsetj&#xE4;nsten och dess tillsyn. Programmet inneh&#xE5;ller flera delar, som interna skydds&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder och kontrollmekanismer, st&#xE4;rkande av parlamentarisk och oberoende tillsyn, f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade r&#xE4;ttsliga standards liksom kapacitet f&#xF6;r godk&#xE4;nnande och granskning av metoder f&#xF6;r s&#xE4;rskild underr&#xE4;ttelseinh&#xE4;mtning. Programmet inneh&#xE5;ller ocks&#xE5; en slags mekanism f&#xF6;r ad hoc-r&#xE5;dgivning och expertis kring dessa omr&#xE5;den. 

Programmet syftar till att effektivt och h&#xE5;llbart bidra till en f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad demokratisk styrning och tillsyn av under&#xE4;ttelsetj&#xE4;nsten vilket bidrar till &#xF6;kad stabilitet, respekt f&#xF6;r r&#xE4;ttsstatens principer och d&#xE4;rmed f&#xF6;rutses den leda till en st&#xF6;rre tilltro till staten hos landets inv&#xE5;nare.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The political crisis in Macedonia culminated in the so-called wire tapping scandal in 2015, revealing major invasion of fundamental rights, direspect for professional ethics, far reaching abuse of powers and lack of knowledge of the sensitivity of intelligence handling. In a report by senior rule of law experts, comissioned by the EU, urgent reform of the intelligence service and its oversight was called for, which was also confirmed by the Macedonian Government in their reform program. 

Sida will contribute with 4,5 MSEK to a multidonor initative, managed by the Geneva Centre for the Democratic Control of the Armed Forces (DCAF), on intelligence sector reform and oversight. The program contains several parts, such as internal safeguards and control mechanisms, parliamentary and independent oversight, judicial and prosecutorial standards and capacity for authorisation and review of special investigative measure. It also includes a rapid response mechanism for ad hoc advice and expertise related to these areas.

The programme seeks to make an effective and sustainable contribution towards improved democratic governance of the intelligence sector thus contributing to enhanced stability, rule of law and security for the state and the citizens. Thereby an increased trust in the state administration among inhabitants in Macedonia is foreseen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The three clusters of the program with their intended outputs and outcomes will together contribute to improved democratic governance (effectiveness and accountability) of the intelligence sector, which will contribute to enhanced stability, rule of law and security for the state and the citizens. This will contribute to citizen&apos;s improved trust in the state.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47106" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DCAF/Geneva Centre for Security Sector Governance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47106" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DCAF/Geneva Centre for Security Sector Governance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Macedonia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15131" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice, law and order policy, planning and administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">158631.119195423</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">146584.5793022574</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">158631.119195423</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">146584.5793022574</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-01">500552.333609</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">172604.2529687932</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">158631.119195423</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-28">81435.877390143</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">65148.7019121144</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Mid Term Review of the programme points-out to the almost unanimous agreement among stakeholders interviewed that DCAF&#x2019;s expertise and track-record of SSR/G programming, research and advisory activities has contributed to the overall quality of the programme and enhanced engagement by the beneficiaries from the government, civil society, across the political spectrum, as well as donor partners.
DCAF&#x2019;s access to experts and knowledge in the broader region has made it well-placed to deliver the Programme. It&#xA0;has&#xA0;successfully used its extensive network of external and domestic experts. Several domestic experts were brought in the specific work on intelligence reforms, human rights, and use of special investigative measures, providing local contextual input into the publications produced and other outputs, especially in Cluster III (Judiciary).
In the country DCAF is perceived as neutral partner and this has boosted confidence in its role among all partners, which is especially valuable in order to achieve political consensus on the key reforms and project activities supported.
Activities in Cluster I - Intelligence Sector Reform have been limited, due to the nature of the relationship with the relevant institutions. As it is described in the signed Memorandum of Understanding with the Ministry of Interior, DCAF is not directly involved in operational intelligence reform and it can only get involved upon request by the Ministry of Interior. Therefore, planned outputs in this cluster are limited with no set date prior to the completion of the programme.
Most delays concern outputs in Cluster II - support to strengthened Parliamentary oversight.&#xA0;
The outputs in Cluster III- Judicial authorisation and review of Special Investigative Methods are generally on track to be achieved. The manual on parliamentary oversight was completed in November 2018 while the judicial Benchbook is scheduled to be completed in October 2019.&#xA0;
Progress in implementing outputs has been most advanced with regard to provided trainings and study visits in all Programme clusters.
The programme has engaged with local CSOs which were integrated into project activities especially performing their watch-dog role in monitoring&#xA0;the function of the intelligence service. For example, trainings were delivered for beneficiaries by the representatives from the Directorate for Protection of Classified Information and the Directorate for Personal Data Protection. Nevertheless, there is scope for this to be increased. The interest and demand exist among the&#xA0;local CSO&apos;s to acquire greater expertise in this area to be able to better follow and understand the reforms in this sector. Cooperation with the CS Sector should be reinforced, securing transparency in the work of the intelligence service to the extent it is acceptable.
The EU integration process have been attended by the project as an overall target, but stronger focus and reference to the EU integration process and related requirements could be beneficial, and it will strengthen the overall commitment by the Government to this sensitive reform process. The fact that the intelligence sector reform is set as one of the three key reform priorities for the country in the Priebe report, positively influences the acceleration of pace of reforms.
Gender equality is attended by the project through provided statistics on number of participating women and men in project organized activities and events. There is limited progress in awareness raising among key stakeholders regarding gender issues and intelligence sector reform. Strengthened support and continued encouragement&#xA0;to women participation in the reform and monitoring of the intelligence service should be targeted and implemented through&#xA0;gender-related activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11965" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
