<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-12006004-DMCDD-15-A-01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-12006004" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Mission Council Development Organisation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Including education and conducive environment for marginalized children in Singida Region Tanzania</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project development goals that are marginalized because of their disability and social challenges have equal opportunities for education as theirs. Do you have children and experience an environment of acceptance and support from their parents / community and community in Singida? is achieved through networking with 7 organizations involvement of teachers from schools in 2 municipalities in the target area and strategic advocacy towards authorities in Singida region. The project&apos;s target group is experiencing improved educational opportunities for acceptance and protection through community groups and awareness-raising for the surrounding community. Former groups of groups seek and society is strengthened through training to get a voice for their handicapped and weak children. The local partner STCC is strengthened as a change agent through training exchanges and renovation of an existing youth center to be an advocate for the target group and to provide services for the disabled and challenged children in the form of basic education in relevant skills and life skills .</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="PK-VSWA-511-2007" role="1" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acid Survivors Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="91010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction ref="Test-1.1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-07-17">234.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a test file</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="DK-CVR-12006004-DMCDD-18-A-15" ref="DK-CVR-12006004" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization responsible for transaction type.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
