<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>JO-MSD-2009011100178-JO-MSD-2009011100178-JO-MSD-2009</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="JO-MSD-2009011100178" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Princess Alia Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Education through Renewable Energy In the Northern Governorates - FIFth Quarterly Progress Report</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">An education system that develops and nurtures creativity and innovation amongst its students is a cornerstone to the development of any society. Despite high enrolment rates and access to schools throughout the Kingdom, the quality of education remains uneven. Schools in remote areas suffer from insufficient access to electricity to operate daily services such as providing efficient heating and cooling systems within the classroom and connecting computers and online learning. Additionally, with an influx of Syrian refugees, institutions and services are overwhelmed with the increase of demands by an ever-growing population. This project aims to contribute to the overall efforts aiming at mitigating the impact of the Syrian crisis in line with the Jordan Response Plan (JRP) focusing on the Northern governorates (Mafraq, Ramtha, Irbid, and North of Balqa&#x2019;a Governorates) that are most affected by the Syrian crisis. This will be achieved through the use of Renewable Energy (RE) and Energy Efficiency (EE) systems to reduce the growing energy demands improve the learning environment in schools, increase enrollment and retention of Jordanian and Syrian students, improving the livelihood of surrounding communities and promote the social cohesion at the same time. ABOUT THIS REPORT This quarterly report provides an overview of activities that took place during the fourth quarter of project implementation (April &#x2013; June 2018). The Report covers the work carried out by Princess Alia Foundation (PAF), Future Pioneers for Empowering Communities (FPEC), Horizons for Green Development (Horizons) and the National Energy Research Center (NERC). THE TEAM PAF was founded by H.R.H Princess Alia Al Hussein and is registered under the Ministry of Social Development. The Foundation aims to promote compassion and respect for all livings beings, using a holistic approach and bringing different stakeholders together to bring forth change. FPEC is specialized in community empowerment through poverty reduction, community building, capacity development, awareness raising and supporting small and medium-sized enterprises in the educational, environmental and social fields. FPEC&#x2019;s target populations are those who are most vulnerable in society: women, youth, and other marginalized groups. Horizons works to develop a green environment and way of living within Jordan. Through civic engagement, socio-economic empowerment of vulnerable groups, awareness raising and capacity building within the environmental sector, Jordanian society can move towards become more sustainable and environmentally friendly. Following the first three quarters of project implementation, substantial progress had been made. With the roadmaps established and additional preparations made, the project team has moved forward with activity implementation. PAF continues to manage the project&#x2019;s overall implementation, procurement and the lobbying and advocacy of the work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective: This project aims to contribute to the overall efforts aiming at mitigating the impact of the Syrian crisis in line with the JRP focusing on the Northern governorates (Mafraq, Ramtha, Irbid, and North of Balqa&#x2019;a Governorates) that are most affected by the Syrian crisis. This will be achieved through the use of Renewable Energy (RE) and Energy Efficiency (EE) systems to reduce the growing energy demands, improve the learning environment in schools, increase enrollment and retention of Jordanian and Syrian students, improving the livelihood of surrounding communities and promote the social cohesion at the same time. Project Specific Objectives: 1. Improve the learning environment and reduce the present challenges in schools with high numbers of Syrian students at schools located in remote areas through providing them with a free source of needed electricity; renewable energy coupled with energy efficiency devices to operate various learning tools such as computers, access on-line curricula, sufficient lighting, cooling and heating systems to provide a safe and healthy learning environment and increase student retention. 2. Provide a sufficient sustainable income by savings in the electricity bills and by connecting these schools to the national grid enabling the sale of excess electricity generated. This additional income will be used for the daily maintenance of the system and the schools such as replacing broken windows, doors, painting, procuring educational resources and others. 3. Improve the livelihood of surrounding communities through creating new job opportunities for youth in the energy sector. They will be trained by the RE private sector and at least 10% will be hired to ensure the sustainability of the systems. 4. Empower the role of women CBOs in the targeted areas as training centers for local youth in the field of installing and maintaining Renewable Energy (RE) and Energy Efficiency (EE) systems. 5. Promote the social cohesion and community solidity between the Syrian refugees and hosting communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Renewable energy and energy efficiency systems for the (100) schools. As mentioned in previous reports, three companies are awarded to install RE and PV systems for providing heating and cooling equipment, lighting and maintenance to the (100) selected schools. Support rendered by the Ministry of Education to this particular project made it possible to pay an outstanding balance identified in a concluded electric survey (JOD 126.007) due to the Electric Company. While this amount could have severely influenced available budget, demonstrated MoE support made it possible that suppliers proceed with schedule as initially planned. The MoE also paid the accumulated electricity bills on behalf of all identified 100. It is expected that the work of these companies at the selected schools will be completed by Dec 2018/January 2019. This directly benefits 41,406 Jordanian and Syrian students of which 17,145 boys (%41) and 24,261 girls (%59). AWARENESS WORKSHOPS IN COMMUNITIES: Host communities are actively engaged in conducting awareness workshops in cooperation with women CBOs. Thematic topics address social cohesion and best practices on renewable energy targeting Syrian and Jordanian women who will in return dispersed awareness to their respective communities. So far, the project managed to conduct 80 workshops in Ramtha, Irbid, and North Shouneh (40 days on social cohesion and 40 days on energy awareness). The workshops will be next rolled out in Mafraq&#x2019;s different villages. Evaluating the pre and post surveys proved the gained knowledge and the shifted positive approach of 3,011 people: 2,640 women (1,777 Jordanians and 863 Syrians) and 371 men (252 Jordanians and 119 Syrians). As the preliminary direct feedback and impressions from both of the participants and the CBOs in Ramtha were very positive, the same approach was adopted in Irbid and North Shouneh workshops. Here are examples of questions that show the improvement in gained knowledge of participants after attending the awareness session: 1. Do you know the difference between climate change and weather? The participants&#x2019; knowledge in this questions was improved from 82% to 97% 2. What are the reasons of climate change? The participants&#x2019; knowledge in this question is improved from 11% to 37% 3. How to Reduce the Effect of Climate Change? Participants&#x2019; knowledge in this question was improved from 49% to 76% 4. What are the methods that could achieve Rationalization of Energy Consumption at the household level? Participants&#x2019; knowledge to this questions was improved from 64% to 75% . TEACHERS &amp; STUDENTS ACTIVITIES: 1. The 100 selected schools profited further through their inclusion in the Eco-Schools program; where an international certified body is teaching students how to be active in changing others actions by rationalizing energy use through following best practices. Focal points and teachers from each school were selected, with assistance from the Royal Marine Conservation Society (JREDS). Focal points and teachers will remain in constant communication with the project team and will be participating in a training to gain further knowledge on climate change, energy challenges in Jordan, best practices and tools for rationing energy use and reducing costs and CO2 emissions, and how to organize and implement team building activities between students from different backgrounds to ensure social cohesion and interaction. JREDS management of the 100 schools became official with the signing of a contract on 1 February 2018. So far, JREDS managed to complete the TOT for 200 teachers (125 females and 75 males). This enhanced extra-curricular activities in these schools. 2. In consequence, three components are brought to life; Shammousa Manual, distributed to schools outlining all relevant information related to renewable energy and the environment, development and distribution of (10,000) copies of an interactive CD game to the 100 schools, and the Educational Toolkit which is developing of a Virtual Reality program to teach students about the environment and energy in an engaging way. These measures will fully engage students and introduce them to best practices on energy saving and to promote green culture. Students participated in an interactive virtual reality video that takes viewers on a dream like journey through space to better understand the operation of PV systems demonstrating how energy is generated and saved. So far 1,434 students experienced the video. 3. A website is in progress through a specialized media company in order to map out the location of schools that are currently receiving funds and/or assistance related to environment or renewable energy and by whom. The map will also include schools that are in need of assistance to ensure there is neither schools overlap nor donors prioritizing similar projects. The 100 selected schools have also been marked on Google Maps for future reference. The project team visited Queen Rania Center for IT to explore possible cooperation channels as they are hosting all the servers responsible for the very detailed data for schools in the Kingdom, their students and staff. It was agreed that the project will develop its own website for the schools equipped with RE&amp;EE systems but the server will be hosted at Queen Rania Center to ensure more sustainability. The website is almost ready and expected to be launched soon. CBOs ACTIVITIES: During the second quarter, 4 CBOs were selected to participate in the program. Socio-economic baseline studies were conducted for the 4 CBOs to evaluate their capacity, how to best use their respective skillset, and potential small initiatives which could take place. Cooperation agreements are signed with the final selected 4 CBOs in April to start implementing the agreed upon small initiatives. A fifth CBO was selected at a later stage to expand the benefits based on positive results. The engagement of women CBOs is further deepened by equipping the selected CBOs with exhibitions that provide citizens with RE &amp; EE systems through revolving funds, or through networking with local support initiatives such as JREEEF. The project has equipped these exhibitions with trained 15 local youth who are keen to raise awareness in the community and encourage them to adopt best practices through conducting the energy audits at a household level. These CBOs are equipped with proper training halls that are used as a hub for the local community to promote green culture. Thus far, more than 20 families have benefited from these services which are mainly: 1. Revolving funds for the local community to purchase RE&amp;EE systems for their houses to reduce the electricity bills and reduce CO2 emissions by using mainly PV systems and solar heaters. 2. Launching exhibitions/shops fully equipped for selling RE/EE systems for the local community supported by the revolving funds mechanisms. 3. Coordinate with JREEEF which supports partially the installation of the PV systems and solar heaters so that the remaining value will be covered by the CBOs through the revolving fund mechanism. Our plan is to collaborate to make the process clear and more transparent for local communities in the northern governorates so this becomes a realistic option for them. 4. Equipping training halls to be used for training and awareness for local communities. These halls will be like a gathering hub for the local people to announce the provided services by the CBO for them under the project and to be used for different awareness events. So far, four workshops are conducted which targeted 200 youth (male and female). 5. Train the recruited CBO staff on doing the energy audit to be rolled-out for the local houses and commercial buildings. 6. Asses CBOs needs and capacities to provide them with needed training and programs to ensure sustainability. VOCATIONAL TRAINING CENTERS ACTIVITIES: To sustain efforts of creating green jobs, and following the signed Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) between Princess Alia Foundation (PAF) and the VTCs, the project has equipped three of the main vocational training centers with on-grid and off-grid educational PV systems. They were also provided with comprehensive TOT that is crucial in order to teach youth how to install and maintain the RE &amp; EE systems and expand the benefits for all communities. An announcement was posted to attract interested youth to apply for the training through filing a specific application. The project team is in the process of reviewing the received applications to select the potential youth (males and females) to join the training. Youth participating in the training course at the VTCs will receive a monthly stipend, transportation and meals. Participants will receive all relevant training material and will receive a professional practicing license and toolkit upon completion. The training course will last 600 hours (4-6 months) with the training material to be developed in collaboration between the VTCs and a project consultant. SOCIAL COHESION: It is worth mentioning that the entire project team including the partner CBOs has ensured the inclusion of Syrian and Jordanian participants (male and female) on equal basis in all the above clarified activities so far especially in the awareness workshops which induce the behavioral changes of both Jordanians and Syrians to rationalize energy use and induce social cohesion. LOBBYING AND ADVOCACY ACTIVITIES: 1. Signing partnership MOUs with different parties mainly VTCs, Mercy Corps, Ministry of Education and Ministry of Social Development. 2. As previously discussed to set-up a central/general fund, where every school can allocate their energy savings/earnings in one location. This was agreed upon and supported by HRH through meetings and discussions held with the Ministry of Education. By equipping schools with RE&amp;EE systems, they will be provided with free and clean energy for the next 25 years, allowing them to create a surplus of produced energy that can be sold to electricity companies and to transfer savings made to this trust fund. In addition, PAF will tackle carbon trade as the installed systems will reduce CO2 emissions by almost 5,000 tons annually. A proposal was sent accordingly to the Minister to be forwarded to the right channels. The project team is planning to recruit a specialized advocacy team of lawyers in order to follow this matter with Parliament. 3. The project is still in discussion with Ministry of Environment to study our project&#x2019;s best options with regard to CO2 credit in compliance with Jordan&#x2019;s&#x2019; share and commitment. So far, and as the price of one ton of carbon is reduced to less than half a dollar internationally, the Minister of Environment is looking for other options to benefit from the installed PV systems especially that the electricity company and big factories and investors are pushing the Ministry of Environment to look and adopt a suitable solution. 4. PAF has managed to lobby for the inclusion of RE systems in building codes for future schools. Moreover, it is in the process of changing the current school electricity tariffs to a lower rate as they are currently being charged with a commercial tariff.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="JO-MSD-2009011100178-JO-MSD-2009" ref="JO-MSD-2015021115123" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Princess Alia Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The duration of the fifth quarterly report is July 1,2018 to Sep 30, 2018</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The duration of the fifth quarterly report is July 1,2018 to Sep 30, 2018</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mafraq, Ramtha, Irbid and North Shouneh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="SDG 13" percentage="15" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="SDG 17" percentage="15" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="SDG 5" percentage="10" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="SDG 7" percentage="30" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <sector code="SDG4" percentage="30" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="JOD" value-date="2017-07-01">5687371</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
