<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="JOD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>JO-MSD-2009011100178-JO-MSD-2009011100178-JO-MSD-2009011100178</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="JO-MSD-2009011100178" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Princess Alia Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final Progress Report</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- The intensive awareness workshops for the local communities surrounding the schools had mobilized the community to be part of the project activities and they are actively inquiring on educational courses to get better understanding on available technology and means of energy savings. - Introduce the revolving fund model at CBO&#x2019;s to ease the economic burden: participating associations engaged in managing fund creation and operation. Once active, community members are sensitized on process and began applying for interest-free loans to finance renewable energy technologies at homes, shops and farms with confidence in the investment made and revenue on the longer term. - Renewable energy showrooms are established and illustrate RE technologies: shops display renewable energy products that the community members can purchase through an interest-free payment system, they have started utilizing the educational material in the shops to learn more on RE and EE. - CBO energy audit teams: recruited focal points and volunteers trained and tasked with energy audits are actively promoting the audit exercise, sensitizing community and illustrating saved electricity bill amounts after installing RE technology. - Community members gain confidence in RE concept and accrued savings, community members approached CBO&#x2019;s to request audits at their homes and businesses and started apply for revolving fund loans. - RE&amp;EE education and certification: youth in communities enrol in training module at the local vocational training centres to qualify for future green jobs. Due to the introduction of practical and theoretical training some post-graduate students are also enrolled. - Eco-school programs: students and teachers are enthusiastically participating in responsible energy practices and are holding science fairs and organizing events to celebrate achievements. As a result, schools falling out of the targeted lists in communities are expressing interest in participating in similar activities. - Parents-teachers councils were created in targeted schools to organize additional awareness sessions in communities while environment clubs were created and became part of the school system. - The remedial classes for students who dropped-out of school and their support in enrolment after the three month period of classes have ended. - The close cooperation with relevant stakeholders such as the VTC&#x2019;s, Parliament, the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elaboration: All outputs have been completed without delays in agreement with the set timeline. The different activities linked and contributed to each other. To give an idea; At the local level youth are targeted through awareness sessions on renewable energy, energy efficiency and green jobs. In schools, the Eco-Program is introduced and teachers are trained on developing an environmental action plan. The program promotes green thinking and children are stimulated to design their own ideas. Complementary educational tools are developed to bring a comprehensive experience; VR, digital games and manual. Training manuals developed and accredited to be taught at local VTC centers. Courses offer theoretical and practical training with available on-off grid PV demonstrations. Graduates receive certified diplomas and are linked for job opportunities with the private sector; contracted suppliers. Furthermore, a mobile application is being developed in order to concretely link job seekers with potential employers. The application is free of charge and will be announced during training as soon as its operational. Simultaneously, targeted CBOs are supported to become green hubs to link all initiatives together those include; financial training, infra-structure support, income generation interventions, RE and EE revolving fund, job opportunities and continued awareness campaigns. Completed Outputs according to the logical framework are: &#x2022; (110) schools selected in communities affected by the Syrian students to have improved learning environment through equipping them with renewable energy systems, energy efficiency lights, Heating /cooling systems, free electricity for operating the learning tools such as computers, internet and access to on-line curricula . This will directly benefit more than 56,205 Jordanian and Syrian students of which are 23,204 boys and 33,001 girls, 45,625 are Jordanian students while 10,580 are Syrians. &#x2022; Targeted schools are sensitized on the Eco-Schools program introduced by an international certified entity to teach students how to be active in changing positive behaviors by rationing energy use and adopting best practices &#xF0FC; The international Eco-Schools program was introduced to 100 schools. &#xF0FC; TOT for 200 teachers (125 females and 75 males). &#xF0FC; (9) Focal points volunteers appointed to follow up on activities in all selected schools. &#xF0FC; (3,127) students were educated through the Eco-schools program &#x2022; Students participated in an interactive virtual reality video that takes viewers on a dream like journey through space to better understand the operation of PV systems demonstrating how energy is generated and saved. So far (3,127) students experienced the video. &#x2022; Additionally, 10,000 digital CDs, 10,000 educational Shamousa manuals support extracurricular activities in schools. &#x2022; Evaluating the pre and post surveys of the awareness workshops conducted for the surrounding communities demonstrated the knowledge gained and the new positive attitude of 3,974 people of which are: 3,182 women and 792 men (2,854 Jordanians and 1,120 Syrians). &#x2022; (15) Local youth have been trained and employed to spread awareness in the community and conduct energy audits at household level. So far, 1,500 citizens were targeted through workshops (male and female). &#x2022; (5) Active CBOs were selected and equipped revolving funds and with proper training halls to become a hub for the local community and promote green culture. So far, more than 120 families have benefited from the provided services such as solar heaters, AC&#x2019;s that save energy as well as other systems that have reduced their energy bills. &#x2022; Training halls in CBOs used for extra learning spaces and remedial catch-up classes for drop-out children. Thus far, 600 students participated in this program: 276 boys (96 Jordanians and 180 Syrians) and 224 girls (101 Jordanians and 123 Syrians). (97) returned to school &#x2022; To sustain the efforts of creating green jobs, the project equipped three of the main vocational training centers with on-grid and off-grid educational PV systems, comprehensive TOT and curricula to expand the benefits of all communities. &#xF0FC; (5) teachers have been trained; one-week ToT session was organized by the EU TA II program manager &#xF0FC; (120) students; 40 females and 80 males, enrolled in a 6 month RE&amp;EE VTC training program. Graduates shall receive a &#x2018;skilled&#x2019; level diploma. &#xF0FC; The Employment Application is launched and will be a platform that connects the trained youth and possible employers. This application will be open to all in order to facilitate job opportunities. &#x2022; Number of people assisted to develop economic income generating activities Number of people in total Host communities Refugees Undefined Male Female Male Female Male Female 18 6 7 2 3 0 0 &#x2022; Number of direct jobs supported Number of people in total Host communities Refugees Undefined Male Female Male Female Male Female 28 11 12 2 3 0 0 &#x2022; (10) Graduates of the VTC; males and females were employed by the contractors who installed the RE/EE systems for the 110 schools. Qualitative indicators: - Introduced an innovative activity; virtual reality, to students in 5th and 6th grade proved to be significantly impressive for the learning experience. Particularly for RE&amp;EE. The model could effectively provide an impactful experience to children in common settings where traditional means of education dominates the learning experience; (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_jHP5YmgZXs) - Eco-Schools is the largest international school program promoting sustainability &#x2013; the program starts in the classroom and expands to the community by engaging generations in action-based learning. Through this program, young people experience a sense of achievement at being able to have a say in the environmental management policies of their schools, ultimately steering them towards certification and the status associated with the Green Flag award. - Established environmental clubs and committees in schools (15 to 20 students aged 10-15) which support the creation of local change agents promoting renewable energy and energy efficiency practices. - Teachers are empowered to organize awareness sessions and diverse initiatives through a participatory approach with students and have created local councils. - Income generating projects supported employment in communities, provide skillsets to beneficiaries and work on improving standard of living for families. - Provided solar powered water purification systems and logistical equipment and allow local groups to benefit from these systems by reinvesting profits into their communities. - Empowered CBO&#x2019;s to better serve communities and promote RE&amp;EE technologies through different models; revolving fund, awareness sessions and energy audit exercises. - Connected CBO&#x2019;s with local authorities to eliminate bureaucratic barriers and create partnerships. - Established energy shops that are managed and run by CBO&#x2019;s. - Supplied targeted VTC&#x2019;s with necessary manuals on RE&amp;EE, these were used to train community members, men and women, Syrians and Jordanians, on installation and maintenance. - Established an energy audit team to provide audits for households, farms and local private companies. In the 5 CBO&#x2019;s a total of 15 volunteers are involved. These energy audits help community members understand their energy spending habits and patterns to modify them in order to reduce energy bills and raise awareness. - Promoted RE&amp;EE in a local youth conference; the Arab Noor Conference, on supporting local businesses and young entrepreneurs. - Activated new actions through Ministry of Environment for the Carbone Trade mechanisms - Facilitated adopting JREEEF as the trust fund for sold electricity by schools to be used to support other schools. Quantitative indicators (segregated by nationality and/or gender if applicable): 1. Schools program Total number of schools 110 Total number of students 56,205 Ages 10-15 Total number of Jordanian students 45,625 Total number of Syrian students 10,580 Total number of Male students 23,204 Total number of Female students 33,001 Total number of Teachers 2,626 Schools equipped with RE&amp;EE systems 110 Capacity building programs conducted 7 Questionnaires used to measure program adoption 3500+ Students reached by eco-schools DIRECT training 3,127 Teachers DIRECTLY targeted with capacity building programs 65 (70% female) Stickers distributed for the &#x201C;Tafeha o benhawesh&#x201D; energy savings program 10,000 (1250 per intern) CD&#x2019;s distributed to students 10,000 VR screening 6800 2. VTC program Number of VTC&#x2019;s 3 Total number of trainees 103 Total number of Jordanian trainees 94 Total number of Syrian trainees 9 Total number of Male trainees 64 Total number of Female trainees 39 Total number of Trainers 5 3. CBO&#x2019;s activities Number of CBO&#x2019;s supported by the project 5 Number of Local youths trained and employed in the CBO&#x2019;s initiatives established by the project 15 Number of energy shops established and equipped with RE&amp;EE technologies. 2 Total number of families that benefited from revolving funds through purchasing AC&#x2019;s and solar heaters that save energy as well as other EE appliances 150 Number of Citizens reached through renewable energy and energy efficiency awareness and Social Cohesion training workshops in three governorates (3,974), 1,120 are Syrian, 2,854 Jordanians, where 792 are men while the remaining are females. Number of children supported by remedial classes to enroll back in school 500 students From both Syrian and Jordanian nations Number of children returned back to school after dropping out 97</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability Expected follow-up: describe the activities that will ensure continuation upon the completion of the project. - Ensure VTC&#x2019;s continue to run training sessions on RE&amp;EE in optimal standards; both at theoretical and practical levels. Trained youth are expected to be equally engaged in the labour market and in their communities to advocate for energy efficiency best practices. - Closely follow interventions launched by CBO&#x2019;s and offer support where needed with regards to effective management and operation. - Running activities within the eco-schools program are intended to continue to enrich and sustain awareness amongst students, teachers, parents and community members in order to fully recognise their capacity and the importance of taking care of the environment so that they have the motivation to continue applying responsible energy practices when the project is complete. - Maintenance follow-up for the installed RE/EE systems at schools including PV&#x2019;s, AC&#x2019;s, and energy efficient light bulbs. This will be done through the contractors and trained youth in the different communities. Sustainability which will be ensured as follow: a. Financial sustainability: &#x2022; All the purchased and installed solar systems shall have a high return on investment; the systems are paid for only once, and will eventually cover their cost in (3-5) years. These systems will operate and generate electricity for at least 25 years. So, the savings for Ministry of Education will be on average JOD500/Month/school which equal to annual savings for the 100 schools equal to almost JOD 600,000 and almost 15.0 million over the 25 years. There will be a documented study produced by NERC once all the systems are installed and operated. &#x2022; The improved learning environment for the upcoming 25 years will contribute to improve the educational achievements and retention in these schools. &#x2022; The equipped VTCs to be certified training centers to train people on installing and maintaining PV systems will continue to run training sessions on RE&amp;EE in optimal standards; both at theoretical and practical levels. Trained youth are expected to be equally engaged in the labour market and in their communities to advocate for energy efficiency best practices. &#x2022; The trained youth through the VTCs shall have better chances to get jobs and therefore to support their families which in consequent shall raise livelihood status of the community. a percentage of these youth will be employed by the three contractors in this project to cover the maintenance of installed systems for the upcoming three years &#x2022; The supported CBOs that are equipped with trained youth, revolving funds, training halls, productive initiatives, and RE/EE systems will continue their business and activities and continue to be the gathering hub for their communities and continue serving them utilizing the provided tools and equipment. &#x2022; The implemented eco-schools program have a direct impact on the students in terms of raising their awareness about protecting the environment, changing their behavior and ensure their commitment to improve their environment through adopting the best practices on the long term. the provided educational games on DVDs and educational manuals will ensure mire sustainability. b. Policy level sustainability: &#x2022; The project is contributing to the government efforts and policies to mitigate the impact of the Syrian crisis. &#x2022; The project is involving the relevant authorities, electricity company , parliament and other relevant stakeholders in order to establish a trust fund for the schools to benefit of the sold surplus of produced electricity through the installed RE/EE systems to benefit the rural schools or to pay the electricity bills for the schools that are not supported by RE/EE systems. &#x2022; Another consultant have been recruited by the project to follow with Ministry of environment, Ministry of Energy and electricity company a new mechanism to benefit from the reduced CO2 emissions especially that the existing mechanism have proved to be not beneficial after a while. There are some plans to establish a trading platform to open the door for the investors and other projects to benefit from the new planned mechanisms. c. Environmental sustainability: &#x2022; The project has contributed to the initiatives established on the local, national and international levels in combating climate change effects and acted as a useful mitigation measure especially on reducing the emissions of Green House Gases &#x2022; Additionally, the capacity building of local youth, students and the awareness workshops for the community members on renewable energy importance and need has supported the environmental adoption of best practices . d. Social sustainability: &#x2022; This project has worked on promoting the social cohesion between the Syrian refugees and hosting communities through conducting more than 50 workshops that gathered more than 2,000 people of both nationalities and improved their knowledge about the importance of social cohesion and community solidarity. &#x2022; Moreover, the project has built the capacity of five of the most active CBOs with infra-structure, training and job creation. Those activities are a concrete component that can serve communities even after the project completion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This report shows the final results that have been achieved through the project duration from July 1, 2017 until August 31, 2019. Deliverables Description: 1.1 A clean source of energy is provided for the selected schools 1.1.1 The project agreement was officially signed on July 1st, 2017 and the planned preparations and activities began shortly thereafter. 1.1.2 A kick off meeting between the project partners has been conducted and a Project Management Unit (PMU) was created to meet on a regular basis. Additionally, a communications plan was prepared for the project to better organize the communication channels, including emails and meetings with relevant stakeholders and other entities and internal meetings within the project Consortium: Princess Alia Foundation, Future Pioneers for Empowering Communities&#x2019; Members (FPEC) and Horizons for Green Development. 1.1.3 A full day meeting was organized for senior team members from the Stabilization and Humanitarian Aid Directorate on August 21, 2017 at PAF premises as part of the Reception in the Region program. The discussion was found to be fruitful as several fundamental points were discussed and clarified during this meeting, including project implementation and reporting. 1.1.4 The logical framework and Theory of Change have been revised to reflect the actual start of the project and the modified indicators to better measure the project progress and achievements. 1.1.5 Several meetings with main stakeholders and partners including Ministry of Education and National Energy Research Centre (NERC) to select the 100 schools that comply with the predefined vulnerability criteria were held. The requested schools have been selected and the project team began its field work to investigate the situation of these schools and the availability of active CBOs within their surrounding communities. 1.1.6 The project contracted the National Energy Research Centre (NERC) in order to assess the current electricity consumption at the selected 100 schools and specify the needed PV systems, heating and cooling systems and lighting systems to reduce the electricity bills to almost zero and improve the learning environment at the same time. The (100) schools were selected at the northern governorates in cooperation with Ministry of Education based on certain selection criteria such as the value of electricity bills, overcrowdings, poverty, number of Syrian students, elementary schools and number of teaching shifts. 1.1.7 Accordingly, three tenders were released and evaluated through an evaluation committee that gathered NERC, Ministry of Education (MoE) and Ministry of Public works. The three tenders were awarded on May and July 2017 and the work is in progress for the 100 schools. Support rendered by the Ministry of Education to this particular project made it possible to pay an outstanding balance identified in a concluded electric survey (JOD 126,007.0) due to the Electric Company. While this amount could have severely influenced available budget, MoE support made it possible that suppliers proceeded with the schedule as initially planned. 1.1.8 Several lessons learned can be documented from this experience. An important one is the necessity of schools&#x2019; roofs inspection before moving ahead with installing the PV systems or even the selection of the school in the first place. An agreement was signed with The Royal Scientific Society (RSS)/Buildings department in order to supervise the inspection of the selected schools&#x2019; roofs. When the roofs were inspected through laboratory testing, it was found that some of the schools&#x2019; buildings&#x2019; were week and can&#x2019;t handle the new PV systems especially if we added the wind force and other weather factors. Some of the schools are 70 years old. Therefore, PAF&#x2019;s team in cooperation with RSS&#x2019;s team and the Ministry of education has extensive site visits to the northern governorates to select 19 new schools that are less than 20 years old and have similar capacities to the replaced ones. These schools have to go through NERC&#x2019;s assessment in order to specify the required heating/cooling systems and PV capacities. An amendment to NECR agreement was crucial in this case to ensure proper technical supervision. 1.1.9 Currently, the Ministry of Renewable Energy has included the roofs&#x2019; inspection as a requirement and perquisite for installing the PV systems to ensure the safety of students and sustainability of the installed systems. 1.1.10 The three contractors managed to complete the final (100) schools by the deadline and have been fully equipped with PV systems, heating/cooling systems, new energy efficient lighting systems and full maintenance especially of doors and windows to ensure efficiency of the installed systems. 1.1.11 The project activities have crossed with the activities of another project which is the National Alliance Against Hunger and Malnutrition (NAJMAH). This project focuses on improving the living conditions of Syrians and Jordanians through employing them in the maintenance activities of schools. This has interfered with the maintenance activities of some of our schools. In order to maximize the benefit, the project decided to leave the schools maintenance of the selected schools for NJAMAH and utilize the saved money to benefit other schools. 1.1.12 The project have utilized the savings to equip ten additional schools that have PV Systems through one of PAF previous projects with heating/cooling systems especially the ones in Jordan Valley in order to improve the learning environment there. 1.1.13 The (110) schools have been completed and handed over by the deadline. This will directly benefit more than 56,205 Jordanian and Syrian students of which are 23,204 boys and 33,001 girls, 45,625 are Jordanian students while 10,580 are Syrians. 1.1.14 In order to celebrate this success, a public event took place in one of the completed schools in North Shouneh on April 29, 2019 under the patronage of HRH Princess Alia Al-Hussien and the Netherlands Embassy. The event gathered the community leaders, relevant stakeholders, local authorities, VTC trainees, teachers and students and local CBOs. The event included clarifying the project achievements and the graduation of the VTC trainees in Al-Mashareh Center. Moreover, there was announcements for the different activities completed in Shouneh Women CBO which is one of the CBOs supported by the project and marketing for their honey products. 1.2 Improve learning environment at the selected schools: 1.2.1 The 100 selected schools profited further through their inclusion in the Eco-Schools program; where an international certified body is teaching students how to be active in changing others actions by rationalizing energy use through following best practices. Focal points and teachers from each school were selected, with assistance from the Royal Marine Conservation Society (JREDS) through a signed MOU with them. Focal points and teachers will remain in constant communication with the project team and they have participated in a training to gain further knowledge on climate change, energy challenges in Jordan, best practices and tools for rationing energy use and reducing costs and CO2 emissions as well as how to organize and implement team building activities between students from different backgrounds to ensure social cohesion and interaction. 1.2.2 So far, JREDS managed to complete the following; - The international Eco-Schools program was introduced to 100 schools. - TOT for 200 teachers (125 females and 75 males). - (9) Focal points volunteers appointed to follow up on activities in all selected schools. - (3,127) students were educated through the Eco-schools program. - Ran capacity building programs for the hired staff regarding action plan development, eco-schools and Shamouseh. - Printed and distributed promotional stickers in the &#x201C;Turn off and save&#x201D; (Tafeha o benhawesh) energy saving program across targeted schools. - Awareness campaign was launched via media outlets; Facebook, the press, e-letters and interviews organized to promote effective energy practices. 1.2.3 The project has conducted the post survey for the schools to measure the progress and achievements and completed the final evaluation. (46) Schools out of (100) have won the international eco-schools certification and a celebration event to honor these schools has been conducted on April 17, 2019. 1.2.4 In so doing, three components were brought to life; Shammousa Manual, distributed to schools outlining all relevant information related to renewable energy and the environment, development and distribution of (10,000) copies of an interactive CD game to the 100 schools, and the Educational Toolkit which was developed for a Virtual Reality program. 1.2.5 The Virtual Reality educational screening was developed in parallel with the Eco-schools program to create a live experience for students about RE/EE and to teach them about the environment and energy in an engaging approach. These measures have fully engaged students and introduced them to best practices on energy saving and promoted green culture. Students participated in an interactive virtual reality video that takes viewers on a dream like journey through space to better understand the operation of PV systems demonstrating how energy is generated and saved. So far (3,127) students experienced the video; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yWPU3kjNCJc&amp;feature=youtu.be 1.2.6 To further support the awareness among students that are younger in age, an interactive song has been developed to teach the children bets practices to save energy and have been broadcasted on famous children channels to reach out to the largest possible number of children. https://youtu.be/smLSVlQwEOk 1.2.7 A website was developed through a specialized media company in order to map out the location of schools that are currently receiving funds and/or assistance related to environment or renewable energy and by whom to ensure no overlapping of schools or donors prioritizing similar projects. The 110 selected schools have also been marked on Google Maps for future reference. The website is launched here. http://solarjordanschools.com/ 1.2.8 Remedial classes and drop out of schools The project in cooperation with the local CBO&#x2019;s have organized Summer remedial classes supported in the northern governorates, targeting Jordanian and Syrian students. Arabic, English and math lessons targeted out of school children, enabling them to apply for placement tests. A further professional program was developed in cooperation with &#x201C;Youth Without Borders&#x201D; CBO who are very active in Ramtha and one of the project CBO&#x2019;s. They have cooperated with the Ministry of Education to attract 150 students who left school; those 150 students will be able to attend remedial classes over a three month time period and will then be enrolled back in schools. So far, (97) of these students have retuned back to school. Additionally, 500 students have benefited from this program: 276 boys (96 Jordanians and 180 Syrians) and 224 girls (101 Jordanians and 123 Syrian). 1.3 Awareness Workshops In Communities: 1.3.1 Outside the school sphere, the project has completed a CBO mapping activity where (60) CBO&#x2019;s were visited and assessed by our team. Almost (10-15) CBO&#x2019;s were selected for the awareness activities while four CBO&#x2019;s have been selected to further enhance the local green initiatives and employment. 1.3.2 The host communities are actively engaged in conducting awareness workshops in cooperation with the selected women CBO&#x2019;s. The project managed to complete the (100) awareness workshops for the communities surrounding the selected schools. Thematic topics address social cohesion and best practices on renewable energy that target Syrian and Jordanian women who will in turn spread awareness to their respective communities. Evaluating the pre and post surveys demonstrated the knowledge gained and the new positive attitude of 3,974 people of which are: 3,182 women and 792 men (2,854 Jordanians and 1,120 Syrians). 1.4 The role of women-led CBO&#x2019;s in empowering women, reducing poverty and promoting the green culture in the surrounding communities 1.4.1 Forged partnership with five women CBO&#x2019;s were established; in Mafraq, Ramtha, Sareeh/Irbid and the Jordan Valley, to develop their organizational and service minded skills for their communities. Women and youth employment is embedded within the activities through small income generating projects and the introduction of RE&amp;EE technologies in close partnership of the private sector. Moreover, these CBOs have been supported by grants of a value of JOD 10,000 &#x2013; 15,000 each in order to distribute revolving funds to people based in specific announcement methodology and selection criteria. 1.4.2 Coordinated with JREEEF who partially support the installation of the PV systems and solar heaters so that the remaining value will be covered by the CBO&#x2019;s through the revolving fund mechanism. Our plan is to collaborate and make the process clear and more transparent for local communities in the northern governorates therefore becoming a realistic option for them. 1.4.3 Youth trained on RE&amp;EE and teams run energy audits in their communities, raising awareness and promoting the added value when adopting those technologies. The teams are working in different environments and can tailor required equipment for each setting. 1.4.4 The progress of the activities in these CBOs is going very well benefiting the local communities while employing more than (15) local youth. Awareness and audit activities have reached out to more than 1,500 citizens who encouraged the people to have revolving funds to purchase RE&amp;EE systems for their houses in order to reduce their electricity bills and reduce CO2 emissions by mainly using PV systems and solar heaters. 1.4.5 Revolving funds have been provide by these CBOs to encourage people purchase RE/EE systems that reduced the energy bills by 30-70%. These systems are ACs that saves energy, Photo Voltaic systems, solar heaters and others. So far, almost 150 families have benefited of these revolving funds and benefited from the provided services such as solar heaters, PV systems, AC&#x2019;s which have been reflected positively as they used the savings to improve the socio-economic conditions of their families. The revolving funds scheme could sustain up to 10 years after the project completion 1.4.6 Two energy shops were created and equipped to showcase renewable energy and energy efficient technologies. The showrooms are managed by women CBO&#x2019;s and employ youth from the local community. The equipped two RE/EE exhibitions have proved a successful business model where the exhibitions will be able to sustain after the project completion. 1.4.7 Linkages between the CBO&#x2019;s and the local authorities are formed for future cooperation and support. 1.4.8 The above small initiatives have proved their success and the positive impact in terms of youth capacity building, employment and long standing green business models. Thus, the project has decided to benefit an additional CBO in Mafraq (making it the fifth) in order to expand the benefits to additional communities. 1.4.9 Forged cooperation and support with other projects that are funded by the Dutch Ministry such as the hydroponic agriculture that is implemented by Eco-Consult Company. Our project has provided one of our CBO&#x2019;s with off-grid PV system for the Hydroponic unit provided by Eco-Consult to reduce their energy bill by 100% from JOD 300.0 to Zero. 1.4.10 Another PV system was provided to Mafraq CBO that has a small plastic house that plant organic products. 1.4.11 The honey production project run by PV system is progressing very well, employing four women and producing 500-800 kg/year. The built showroom is used to market the products. 1.4.12 To ensure synergies in different programs, one CBO was supported with a solar pump in an existing water purification plant. The plant now runs a full eco-system. 1.4.13 Equipped training halls were and will be used for training and awareness for the local communities. These halls will act like a hub for the local community members, to announce the CBO&#x2019;s available services under the project as well as be used for different renewable energy and energy efficiency awareness events. So far, four workshops were conducted which targeted 800 citizens (male and female). 1.4.14 The CBO&#x2019;s premises are maintained and equipped with necessary furniture and equipment in order to improve services and to ensure consistent income generation by renting out the facilities. 1.5 Vocational Training Centers (VTC&#x2019;s) 1.5.1 To sustain the green job&#x2019;s creation efforts, and by following the signed Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) between Princess Alia Foundation (PAF) and the VTC&#x2019;s, the project has equipped three of the main vocational training centers with on-grid and off-grid educational PV systems. - A one-week ToT session was organized by the EU TA II program manager for 5 teachers. The ToT was crucial in order for the teachers to impart to youth how to install and maintain the RE &amp; EE systems and expand the benefits for all communities. - Energy curriculum training material was developed (in cooperation with the EU) where 250 copies were printed and distributed to VTC&#x2019;s. - Photo-voltaic education simulators (on/off grids) were installed in 3 VTC&#x2019;s in the northern governorates; Irbid, Jordan Valley and Mafraq. - Educational tool kits were developed and will be distributed to graduates. - (103) students; 39 females and 64 males, enrolled in a 6 month RE&amp;EE VTC training program. Graduates shall receive a &#x2018;skilled&#x2019; level diploma. 1.5.2 The six months training course for the trainees was completed successfully and they have passed the needed certification exams and received a &#x2018;skilled&#x2019; level diploma. An official graduation took place during a public event on April 29, 2019 under the patronage of HRH Princess Alia Al-Hussien. 1.5.3 The equipped VTCs should be able to sustain after the project completion as it is equipped with all needed PV systems, tools and training materials, and the new certified green job became well known in their area. So, after the project completion, this certification will be opened for the youth with certain fees like the other certifications in the VTC centers. 1.5.4 The Employment Application is completed and it was launched on Android and IPhone, but at later stage and as the same consortium is implementing another project in the area funded by the Canadians where there is more focus on clean technology, enhancing entrepreneurship among women and men, it was decided to postpone a bit little in order to build upon this Mobile App and make it more advanced and provide several options for the trained youth such as employment opportunities entrepreneurship, salesmen and women and brokers. The second project has built upon the results of our project and trained the trainees on sales and business skills to enable them open their own business. Moreover, the second project will conduct large awareness campaigns to teach trained youth how to use this platform. The other project will continue until Dec 2020 which will provide an opportunity for follow up and mentor the function of the App. 1.5.5 (10) Graduates of the VTC; males and females were employed by the contractors who installed the RE/EE systems for the 110 schools. 1.6 Lobbying and Advocacy 1.6.1 Signing partnership MOU&#x2019;s with different parties; VTC&#x2019;s, Mercy Corps, the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Social Development to ensure their cooperation and support for the project. 1.6.2 PAF has managed to lobby for the inclusion of RE systems in building codes for future schools. Furthermore, it is in the process of changing the current school electricity tariffs to a lower rate as they are currently being charged with a commercial tariff (which is the highest). 1.6.3 The project has signed two contracts with two different experienced consultants. The first consultant will follow the establishment and set-up of a central/general fund, where every school can allocate their energy savings/earnings in one location. By equipping schools with RE&amp;EE systems, they will be provided with free and clean energy for the next 25 years, allowing them to create a surplus of produced energy that can be sold to electricity companies and to transfer savings made to this trust fund. The second consultant has tackled the carbon trade mechanism in cooperation with the Ministry of environment as the installed systems will reduce CO2 emissions by almost 5,000 tons annually. Also, he has followed this matter with the Parliament. In order to further follow this assignment, three paths have been followed First Path: Carbon Trade mechanisms - A desktop review was conducted about carbon trading in general revealing the history and the fact that the 2008 global crisis has caused a slowdown in industrial development, causing industrial nations to slow-down their economic activity, and the resulting carbon emissions, which reduced their need to buy carbon credits, and caused a considerable reduction in carbon unit prices. This reduction has been consistent until the present day. - A meeting with His Excellency Dr. Ibrahim Saif, former minister of Planning and International Cooperation, former minister of Energy and Mineral Resources, current CEO of the Jordan Strategy Forum. The meeting revolved around the history of carbon trading in Jordan, especially for the National Electric Power Company (NEPCO), which reported to Dr. Saif when he was minister of Energy. The summary of the discussion is that NEPCO did sell its carbon credits attained from renewable energy projects (solar and wind) with acceptable revenues, but the current prices have become too low and NEPCO is considering alternative trading methods to try and maximize value. - A meeting was conducted with, Secretary General of the Ministry of Environment, to discuss potential alternative mechanisms for carbon trading. His Excellency was very supportive of the initiative and confirmed the Government intent to identify ways to maximize its potential revenues from carbon credits related to mitigation projects such as those in the renewable energy space. The meeting resulted in the setting-up of another meeting with Eng. Bilal Shaqareen, Director of the Climate Change Directorate at the Ministry of Environment. - A meeting with climate change department revealed that the Government has been researching potential trading mechanisms and has been in contact with the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Secretariat to allow them to introduce such new measures. Mr. Shaqareen highlighted the pros and cons of such approach including a potential upside in revenue by trading special cards that would be charged with carbon credit over time and sold to the highest bidder, and cons including a possibility that such mechanism may not allow Jordan to get its due credits towards achieving its sustainable development targets. The full report will include a deep analysis of the possible approaches and will result in a recommendation based on these options. Eng. Shaqareen also indicated that any such platform has to get the approval of the Central Bank of Jordan (CBJ) as the central authority regulating such transactions. - A meeting with the CBJ was conducted to discuss the Government&#x2019;s appetite for using such unconventional mechanisms and the potential risk of missing out of credit allocation as per Mr. Shaqareen&#x2019;s comments. - A meeting was conducted with the NEPCO leadership and carbon specialists, which concluded the required meetings and data gathering component of this engagement. - Based on the above meetings and gathered data a detailed report clarifying the positon of Jordan in regard to Carbon Trade and environmental foot prints at global and national level was prepared and presented to the decision makers mainly Ministry of Environment based on their request. Also, it presented the position of the carbon trade mechanisms and recommendations. - The detailed report main sections are: Paris agreement, Evaluation of Carbon Trade, Main schemes of Carbon Trade, Case of Jordan, Jordan&#x2019;s foot prints, Jordan&#x2019;s GHG Inventory, Energy Planning, Mitigation Scenarios, proposed new Carbon Trade Mechanisms and recommendations. - Results: The project is following currently with Ministry of Environment the actions that they are taking based on the delivered report. H.E Secretary general took some solid and positive decisions to follow this approach. Second Path: Trust Fund for saved electricity bills and sold surplus - On the other hand, we have discussed with the Directorate of Administrative and Financial Affairs the possibility of establishing a fund to invest the electricity savings resulting from schools using solar energy, and the establishment of an independent fund specifically for this purpose requires a technical and legal study. These meetings have revealed that no trust fund shall be established except under a system issued by the Council of Ministers which requires the political well of the competent minister. - Meet with relevant parliamentary committees: (Education Committee, Rural and Badia Committee, Environment Committee, Energy Committee) to find a new mechanism in cooperation with the electricity companies, the Ministry of Education, the Authority for Energy and Minerals and the Renewable Energy Fund to benefit from the surplus to support schools in poor and marginalized areas. - Discuss the alternatives to the proposed fund: such as Fils Rural Fund: The possibility of calculating surplus amounts and the need to balance them as money for rural villas and then load the cost of energy bill for poor schools at the expense of rural villages. - Also. The Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Fund (JREEEF) is another option: To invest money in favor of the Fund so that it can continue to provide solar 1. The final results were as follow: - Ministry of Education has informed us that they have established recently a trust fund within the Ministry in order to deposit the saved electricity bills and use them to cover the maintenance activities for rural and remote schools. - In regard to the money resulted from selling the produced surplus energy, the best option was JREEEF as it is an existing fund and mechanism within the Ministry and there is no need to establish new scheme associated with needed laws and legislations. JREEEF is already supporting schools with RE/EE systems and the transferred money will be used to continue these efforts. JREEEF president has welcomed this decision and to facilitate this solution. Third Path: Prime Ministry 1. HRH Princess Alia has met with the former Minister of Education who became now the Prime Minister in order to discuss the possibility of establishing a Trust fund for the saved electricity bills for schools and the sold surplus energy to be used to support the schools located in rural and remote areas. The minster at that time welcomed the idea, but her moved to his new position as Prime Minister shortly 2. So, PAF has sent an official letter to the Prime Minister emphasizing again the importance of the above previously discussed proposals. 3. Result: the most preferred solution was to use an existing system mainly JREEEF trust fund instead of establishing a new one</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Pioneers fo Empowering Communities</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horizons for Green Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="JO-MSD-2015021115123" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Princess Alia Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The actual project duration was July 1, 2017- August 31, 2019</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The entire project was implemented in Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13" percentage="15" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal 13 = 15% ,</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="15" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal 17 = 15% -</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="30" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal 4 = 30% ,</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="5" percentage="10" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal 5 = 10% ,</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="30" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal 7 = 30% ,</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="JOD" value-date="2019-08-31">5687371</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
