<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11246</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maldives Villa Shipping 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VSTC was incorporated in April 1986 by Mr. Qasim Ibrahim to represent his interests in trading and shipping.  In 1988 the company diversified into tourist resorts, which now dominate VSTC&apos;&apos;s operations.  The company, with US$ 108.4 million in total assets and a net worth of US$ 60.9 million as of June 30, 2001, is one of the larger private companies in the Maldives.    Having received land for storage purposes from the government of Maldives, VSTC is now expanding its trading operations by implementing storage facilities at Thilafushi island. VSTC also intends to make its resorts world class by improving environment compliance and safety facilities. VSTC corporate investment program consisting of :    i)    Infrastructure for Trading Operations (US$23.2 million)    including installing storage tanks for diesel, kerosene and petrol (38,000 cubic meters), LPG storage and filling plant (2,538 MT), and cement storage silos and packaging plant (8,000 MT).    ii)    Energy Saving Equipment (US$4.3 million)     including solar water heating systems, heat recovery systems and rationalisation of the installed power generating capacity. These systems would reduce energy consumption by 10-20%, resulting in savings of about US$0.65 million per annum.    iii)    Environment and Safety Infrastructure (US$3.8 million)     including fire detection and safety systems, exhaust chimney systems, and waste water treatment plants.     iv)    Debt Restructuring    of up to US$ 9.5 million of short-term debt.      IFC Role      IFC would provide long term funding for the proposed project which is not available in the Maldives.  The banks operating in the Maldives restrict funding to 3-4 years and offer small amounts at high fixed interest rates of 12% - 14% p.a. in US$ terms.  Resort owners have to rely mainly on financing arrangements with tour operators, which have high hidden interest costs of 20% - 30% p.a.  IFC would help the company to demonstrate its commitment to protecting the local environment and improving its own environment and safety infrastructure.  The Sun Island, partly funded by an IFC loan, has demonstrated good environmental performance (being the first winner of the &quot;Presidential Green Globe Award&quot; in the Maldives) and the current investment is expected to bring the other resorts to similar standards of compliance. IFC would also encourage VSTC to improve its corporate governance and management structure.      Development Impact     The proposed project benefits tourism, the most important and fastest growing sector in the Maldives with considerable spillover effects on the national economy.  The proposed upgrade of VSTC&apos;&apos;s environmental and safety facilities and implementation of energy saving measures, will further yield quantifiable and non-quantifiable economic benefits.    The expansion of VSTC&apos;&apos;s trading activities increases the choices available to the Maldivian consumer and leads to more efficient delivery and market linked prices of essentials goods such as diesel, LPG and cement. The project will extend the fuel distribution network to the more remote islands, which are at present not fully served.       World Bank Group Strategy     The project is consistent with the IFC strategy for the Maldives which includes encouraging private sector participation in promoting key sectors such as tourism, and related infrastructure, and the World Bank strategy of assisting development in an environment friendly way.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VILLA SHIPPING &amp; TRADING COMPANY PVT.LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11246" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-05-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2003-06-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr Qasim Ibrahim   Villa Shipping &amp; Trading Co. Pvt. Ltd.   Villa Building Ibrahim Hassan Didi Magu P O Box   2073, Male Maldives   Phone: +960 325195   Fax: +960 325177</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MV" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maldives</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MV-Maldives">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project site consists of 5 resorts located in the Maldives, namely: Fun Island (Bodufinolhu) in South Male Atoll; Holiday Island (Dhiffushi) in South Ari Atoll; Paradise Island (Lankanfinolhu) in North Male Atoll; Sun Island (Nalaguraidhoo) in South Ari Atoll; and Royal Island (Horubadhoo) in Baa Atoll and (ii) Villa Hakatha on Thilafushi island near Male.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>3.2000000000 73.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Resort Hotel (Including Lodges)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $15.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2003-05-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2003-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-05-13">15000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2003-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2003-05-13">15000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VILLA SHIPPING &amp; TRADING COMPANY PVT.LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11246/maldives-villa-shipping-3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
