<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9292</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">American British Cowdray Medical Center I.A.P.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Mexico - Hospital ABC      RegionLatin America and the Caribbean   Sector   Project No09292   Projected Board DateApril 5, 2000   Company NameAmerican British Cowdray Medical Center I.A.P. (Hospital ABC)   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Hospital ABC is an Institution de Asistencia Privada (IAP) a non-profit private hospital regulated under the &quot;Ley de Institution de Asistencia Privadas&quot;. According to this Law, IAPs must have a philanthropic objective and their profits should not be distributed but be reinvested.   	Hospital ABC was established in 1941 and it is governed by a Board of volunteers, all prominent Mexican and expatriate individuals. In addition to its medical reputation, the hospital prides itself on its charitable activities and runs extensive teaching and research programs. The hospital&apos;&apos;s facilities include 200 in-patient beds and state-of-the-art medical technology. It offers a full range of diagnostic, medical and surgical services.     Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	Total project cost is estimated at about US$82 million. IFC&apos;&apos;s proposed investment is expected to be in the form of an A loan of up to US$20 million, a syndicated B loan of up to US$14 million and a Stand-by loan of up to US$10 million.     Location of project and Description of site    	The project will be located in the Santa Fe section of Mexico City, a fast growing part of the city.     	The site was acquired from the Mexico City development agency.  It is approximately 67,200 square meters and is empty of any construction or settlement.     Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project involves the construction of a new hospital facility in Santa Fe that will complement the existing one at Observatorio. It will initially focus principally on out-patient services and will include a specialized ambulatory center (including day surgery), all related diagnostic services, a 24-hour emergency room, a preventive center, 60 beds for hospitalizations and a 100-unit medical offices building. The facility will also include a welfare clinic intended to deliver services to the poor, as per Hospital ABC&apos;&apos;s mandate.          Demand for private medical services in Mexico City has grown very fast in the last 5 years. ABC Hospital is operating at high occupancy rates and needs to increase its capacity. In addition, the new facility&apos;&apos;s location will greatly benefit the hospital. In a large and congested city like Mexico City, the location of services is a most critical element. In a fast growing competitive environment, location constitutes one of the main criteria determining the relative comparative advantage among the four leading hospitals in Mexico City. Due to space constraints, there is no scope for expansion at the current site, which in addition is located in a slow growing area of Mexico City.          The IFC financing will allow the hospital to increase its capacity and rationalize its operations. Hospital ABC will be able to serve its clients better and in a more efficient manner. IFCs long term financing is a key element of the projects financial feasibility. Finally, the proposed transaction is expected to have a demonstration effect to private banks and encourage future support of Hospital ABC and other private sector hospital projects.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental and social review procedure because specific impacts may result which can be avoided or mitigated by adhering to generally recognized performance standards, guidelines or design criteria. The review of this project consisted of appraising technical and environmental information submitted by the project sponsor, and the technical appraisal and site review completed by IFCs Technical and Environment Department staff.     The  is  from the InfoShop.       Host country location of environmental documents    Mr. Santiago Vidal or Mr. Alejandro Alfonso,  The American British Codray Medical Center I.A.P.,    Calle Sur 136 No 116 Col. Americas,    Apartado Postal 18901.     Delegacion Alvaro Obregon,    Codigo Postal 01120    Mexico, D.F.      Date SPI sent to InfoShop March 6, 2000   This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The American British Cowdray Medical Center, I.A.P.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9292" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-02-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-07-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MX-Mexico">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>23.0000000000 -102.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Hospitals and Clinics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2001-02-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-02-07">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2001-02-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-02-07">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The American British Cowdray Medical Center, I.A.P.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9292/american-british-cowdray-medical-center-i-a-p">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
