<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-187326</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Empowerment of Girls in Post-conflict Situations through Vocational Training</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is implemented in Guinea, Somalia (Puntland) and Senegal by Forum for African Women Educationalists (FAWE) over a period of three years. The project has as its goal to give girls, who are not part of the traditional education system a chance to get access to vocational training and information on how to start a business to enable the young women to support themselves as well as their families by working in both the formal and informal sector. FAWE started a technical education institute in Senegal, &quot;Centre of Excellence&quot; in 1999, a pedagogical experimental centre, which was actively involved in the work within the programme in Senegal.

The project will, through the establishment of partnerships with vocational educational institutions, make it possible for girls to enter vocational training centres. Through the establishment of an educational environment for girls, the development of courses directed at girls as well as the enhancement of the teachers&apos; capacities - both professional and pedagogical - will make sure focus is on the girls&apos; special needs. The education will be implemented in cooperation with the national ministries of education. 
The girls&apos; families and the local communities will be involved in the work both before, under and after the training programme in order to make sure the education is accepted and the knowledge and experience of the girls recognised and later utilised.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-187326-24480" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
