<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-196738</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution to the 16th replenishment of the International Development Association (IDA16).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International Development Association (IDA) is the part of the World Bank that helps the world&apos;s poorest countries. Established in 1960, IDA aims to reduce poverty by providing loans (called &quot;credits&quot;) and grants for programs that boost economic growth, reduce inequalities, and improve people&apos;s living conditions.
 
IDA complements the World Bank&apos;s original lending arm - the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD). IBRD and IDA share the same staff and headquarters and evaluate projects with the same rigorous standards.

IDA is one of the largest sources of assistance for the world&apos;s 82 poorest countries, 40 of which are in Africa. It is the single largest source of donor funds for basic social services in these countries. IDA-financed operations deliver positive change for 2.5 billion people, the majority of whom survive on less than $2 a day.
 
IDA lends money on concessional terms. This means that IDA charges little or no interest and repayments are stretched over 25 to 40 years, including a 5- to 10-year grace period. IDA also provides grants to countries at risk of debt distress.
 
In addition to concessional loans and grants, IDA provides significant levels of debt relief through the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative and the Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative (MDRI).
 
Since its inception, IDA has supported activities in 108 countries. Annual commitments have increased steadily and averaged about $16 billion over the last three years, with about 50 percent of that going to Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="73.C.95.a.IDA.16">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sectors not specified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-196738-25140" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-196738-29711" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
