<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-187402</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children: Tibet Basic Education Project, Phase 4, 2011-2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Denmark has since 2002 supported in-service training for the Tibetan primary school teachers in seven counties in the Lhasa prefecture, later, nine counties in Lhoka and Nagchu prefectures of Tibet Autonomous Region (TAR), China, in close collaboration with the local educational authorities. A model reflecting the demand from Chinese national education reform for pedagogical methods for in service training has been developed and documented. By the end of 2013, 298 schools in TAR had completed Save the Children&apos;s twelve step basic teacher training programme, contributing towards the goal of developing child friendly schools in remote rural schools in Tibet. Save the Children handed over this initial training model to local partners for further replication. More recently, Save the Children has developed an advanced teacher training model for schools where the basic training has already taken place. In 3 schools all staff were involved in developing, furthering and implementing child friendly concept, approaches and practices. 

In phase 5, the project will focus on further developing and sustaining the cooperation with Lhasa Advanced Teacher Training School with the aim of institutionalizing the application of child-centered teaching/learning methods. 140 mentor teachers will be trained to support students during practice placement and 150 new teachers will receive pre-service training. The prefecture education bureau will establish a strong and stable trainer group in three countries in the Lhasa valley project sites. Through this project 7-10,000 teachers and 150,000 primary school students will be reached indirectly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.A.1.b.MRD.2.Kina.5-7.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2010001535</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-187402</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Teacher training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-187402-24440" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
