<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-182732</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fisheries programme (2011-2015) of the Mekong River Commission</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Fisheries Progammes of the Mekong River Commission (2011-2015) constitutes the third and last phase of the programme. The purpose of this last phase is to guarantee the final anchorage in the member countries and hereby contribute to a coordinated and sustainable exploitation and protection of the Mekong River ressources. A large part of the habitation - not least the poor - is dependent on these ressources. 

The overall purpose of the programme is to ensure that regional and national organisations implement initiatives in order to ensure a sustainable development of the fisheries administration and the improvement of life conditions in rural areas. 

In addition to a general objective of phasing out, the fisheries programme has four specific goals: 1)To guarantee that relevant decision makers have a solid understanding of the fisheries situation in the region - based on scientific results.
2) That planning institutions are able to monitor status and tendencies in the fisheries and aquaculture administration and -development and to communicate this information.
3)To maintain a high level of regional and national dialogue between sectors and programmes of relevance for the fisheries, and that relevant initiatives are supported in order to guarantee the sustainability of fisheries in the region.
4) To guarantee that national and local fishing organisations and -societies have the requisite capacity to improve the administration and development of fishing.

During 2010 the programme was prepared and approved. Activities will begin in 2011 as planned.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Mekong.20</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2010001361</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-182732</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-182732-23901" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
