<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-193899</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Sector Programme Support phase V</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Component 1: The goal of Danida&apos;s sector budget support has been to enable achievement of the six health objectives put forward in the Sector Medium Term Development Plan: 1) Bridge equity gaps in geographical access to health services; 2) Ensure sustainable financing for health care delivery and financial protection for the poor; 3) Improve efficiency in governance and management of the health system; 4) Improve quality of health service delivery including mental health services; 5) Enhance national capacity for the attainment of the health related MGDs and sustain the gains; 6) Intensify prevention and control of non communicable diseases. This has been done by providing sector budget support combined with active engagement in the policy dialogue and provision of long term technical assistance. From 2015 and until the programme phases out in 2016, the support will be focused the MDG Acceleration Framework (MAF), which focus on improving maternal health. 

Component 2: Providing around 35% of health services, especially in areas with substantially poor and marginalised populations, the members of Christian Health Association of Ghana (CHAG) makes the CHAG Secretariat a central actor in the health sector. Danida&apos;s support enables CHAG to become a strategically positioned, respected, and even more credible actor in the sector. This development is further supported by the well-functioning public-private partnership between Ministry of Health and CHAG (as a non-profit organisation). The objective of Danida&apos;s support is to promote the health needs of the poor and vulnerable across the country through assisting the institutional development of the private non-profit sector. Based on the positive experience with CHAG, Danida&apos;s support will continue as core funding to support implementation of CHAG&apos;s Strategic Plan and Programme of Work (2012-2016).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Ghana.810-500.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2011001567</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-193899</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-193899-25303" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-193899-25304" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-193899-25305" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-193899-25308" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
