<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-172652</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Sector Programme - 2nd phase</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Danish support to the education sector 2010-2014 is based on the results reached during the initial phase of the program &#xBF; focusing on support to the strategic plan 2010-14 of the Ministry of Education through the joint donor fund as well as on support to civil society, in particular the education council of the indigenous peoples.
The primary target is to contribute to the implementation of the national education policy and to the Education Law approved in 2010, concentrating on equal access for all (including girls) to a high quality education with a view to creating a just and sustainable society. Support to civil society will maintain the focus on securing the rights of indigenous peoples in the education system.
The program&#xBF;s challenges are primarily to secure the quality and relevance of the education. The Danish priority is especially to promote bilingual education and eduaction relevant for the labour market. There is still a task guaranteeing that the target of a basic education for all can be reached, eventhough the number of children participating in primary education is relatively high (92% in 2010). By 2015 95% of all children in Bolivia should finish primary education. Through a joint donor dialogue with the Ministry, the Danish support will also be used in support of an improved distribution of resources within the education sector and of a continued financial sustainability for the public financing of the sector. 
The support to the education council of the indigenous peoples (CEPOS) is meant to secure that the results achieved during the first phase regarding inclusion of the rights of indigenous peoples in the new law will be followed by concrete initiatives. A main element in this is to secure the sustainability of CEPOS through capacity building in order to improve access to other sources of financing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Bolivia.813-200</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-172652</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="111" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Level Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172652-24116" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172652-24117" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172652-24118" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172652-24119" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
