<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-172593</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Commission. University, Research, Agro-Business initiative URABI, (FARA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the programme is to strengthen innovation and entrepreneurship in the African agricultural sector. This is done through establishment of Incubation centers owned by consortia composed of agricultural research institutions, universities and other tertiary education institutions and the private sector. Six directly supported incubators are in place in five countries: Ghana, Kenya, Mali, Uganda and Zambia. The programme is implemented by seven collaborating partners, with the Forum for Agricultural Research (FARA) as the lead partner. The duration of the programme is five years, with a total budget of originally DKK 129 million. The programme has the following main outputs :
A: Commercialisation of agribusiness innovations supported and promoted.
B: Agribusiness graduates with potential to become efficient entrepreneurs produced by tertiary education institutions; and 
C: UniBRAIN&apos;s innovative outputs, experiences and practices shared and up-scaled.
UniBRAIN conforms to the African Commission&apos;s recommendations to address job creation and better incomes through creation of linkages between education, research and private sector development in sustainable agriculture and development. The implementation phase of UniBRAIN (2012-2015) commenced in January 2012, after an inception phase of 18 months. The budget for the present phase is supporting the operations of 6 innovation centres/incubators in five countries namely Ghana, Kenya, Mali, Uganda and Zambia; and the supporting services of 7 implementing partners, FARA being the lead. The innovation/incubation centres deal in various value chains as follows: Ghana (livestock), Kenya (Sorghum), Mali (Non-timber agroforestry products and rice), Uganda (Coffee and Banana); and Zambia (Horticulture).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172593-23000" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172593-23159" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172593-25590" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-172593-445" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
