<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-197327</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Peace and Reintegration Programme (APRP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Afghan Peace and Reintegration Programme has as objective to support the peace negotiations with Taleban and give former insurgents a possibility to be reintegrated in the afghan society.

The program is run by an afghan managed common secretariat. The utilisation of the funds placed in the Trust Fund is decided in a financial committee headed by the Ministry of Finance. The larger donor countries are also members of the committee on a rotation basis. The Danish contribution to the program is channelled through UNDP.

The program has two tracks. The first is to have peace negotiations with the leaders of the insurgency. This is dealt with through The High Peace Council. In the other track the objective is to offer ordinary insurgents, who lay down their arms and refrain from violence, a possibility to be reintegrated in the afghan society. This is done by offering job opportunities and job training. The program also offers economic support to villages and societies that receives former insurgents.

The program was established in 2010. By the end of 2013, 7.500 former insurgents were enrolled in the program. The program is now up and running and local peace councils and secretariats have been established in all 34 provinces of Afghanistan.

During the year 2013, the HPC and Provincial Peace Committees (PPCs)
implemented nation-wide outreach and peace promotion activities to mobilize and
consolidate support for peace and reintegration efforts around the country. 
As of end of 2013 the total number of reintegrees as mentioned above reaches 7,500 reintegrees. Progress continues to be made on the small grants projects where one hundred and sixty four projects in twenty five provinces covering six regions have been funded and mor proposals were received and reviewed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-197327-24601" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-197327-25541" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-197327-26261" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
