<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-197344</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greshk Electricity Services Improvement Project (GESIP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark, in December 2009, invested 32 million. million in the renovation of the waterworks in Gereshk MHP. achieving increased and improved access to electricity in the area. Improved power supply is also one of the prerequisites for the development of the emerging private sector in Gereshk. The project is financed with DFID and the Asian Development Bank (ADB). ADB manages the funds and implement the project in collaboration with the Afghan electricity utility (DABS).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The $75.4 million grant from the Government of Denmark ($12.4million), Government of UK ($20 million), and ADF ($43 million) was approved on 22 December 2011, signed on 21 January 2012, and became effective on 20 March 2012 with an original grant closing date of 31 March 2015. The grant closing date was extended six times from 31 March 2015 till 28 November 2020, because of a delay in turnkey contract implementation due to volatile security in Helmand province and the poor performance of the contractor. Grant 0280-AFG and 0281-AFG were closed on 3 August 2016 with a disbursement of $8.04 million out of $12.4 million and $13.11 million out of $20 million, respectively while Grant 0280-AFG was physically closed on 28 November 2020 and will be financially closed by 31 December 2022. The winding-up period for financial closure was extended from 28 March 2021 to 28 May 2021 and then extended till 31 August 2021 and further until 31 December 2022. The project outputs are: (i) Gereshk power supply system rehabilitated and improved, (ii) end-user connections increased with improved distribution facilities, and (iii) the executing agency&#x2019;s operational capacity increased. Da Afghanistan Breshna Sherkat (DABS) is the executing agency of this project. 

The project outputs are: (i) Gereshk power supply system rehabilitated and improved, (ii) end-user connections increased with improved distribution facilities, and (iii) the executing agency&#x2019;s operational capacity increased. Da Afghanistan Breshna Sherkat (DABS) is the executing agency of this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-197344-22410" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-197344-26292" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
