<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-171933</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Private Sector Development - Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development objective of SPSD II, which is aligned and contributing to these policy goals and the PSDS II vision, is defined as:

Creation of sustainable and decent jobs

The SPSD II outlines two main strategic objectives: (i) to improve the conditions for business operation, enhance local and foreign investor confidence, as well as foster the development of sustainable corporate strategies for enterprise growth and job creation. 

Challenges to be addressed with SPSD II include: (i) low competitiveness of agriculture and small and medium-sized enterprises; and (ii) a small formal sector which has insufficient capacity to absorb Ghana&#xBF;s youth and realise their potential. Since there are more students and apprentices than the entire formal sector labour force, a significant number will have to seek their livelihood in the informal economy where productivity and incomes are low.

The emphasis on &#xBF;sustainable&#xBF; jobs implies that: (i) jobs are created in firms that are commercially viable and can face the competition without the need for continuous public subsidies/protection; and (ii) the jobs are not based on exploitation of a finite non-renewable resource or on unsustainable use of natural resources (e.g. soil mining resulting in declining soil fertility and yields). 

The emphasis on &#xBF;decent&#xBF; jobs indicates that: (i) the enterprise or farm generates a value added per employee/entrepreneur/farmer which allows for an income/salary that is decisively above the poverty line; (ii) the jobs generate production and services which are of value to society (which excludes e.g. crime, prostitution, some types of petty trade etc.); and (iii) the general labour conditions are satisfactory (e.g. occupational health and safety standards, social protection, gender equality, no utilisation of child labour etc.)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-23276" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-23291" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-23292" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-29369" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-29370" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-29371" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-29372" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-30805" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-30807" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-30808" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-171933-32942" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
