<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/ESNFI/INGO/21603</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter Construction support to Flood affected Population in Herat Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In line with the AHF 1st RA Strategy 2022, and ESNFI cluster priorities, Cordaid proposes to provide cash for shelter repair and cash for transitional shelter in Herat Province, for all population groups in need. Cordaid will ensure people&#x2019;s privacy and dignity whilst mitigating protection and health risks by providing short to medium-term support to vulnerable HHs affected by natural disaster through transitional shelter construction. Extremely vulnerable HHs whose shelters have either been severely or partially damaged (category B or C) will also be assisted through cash for shelter repair. Complementary, technical capacity-building activities aimed at communities&#x2019; leaders and affected households, construction and maintenance of the shelter and to ascertain the quality, and safety of the shelter will be provided, including trainings on flood preparedness, as well as BBB and flood resilient foundations. 
In Herat (Obe, Pashtoon Zarghoon, Injil districts), Cordaid will target a total of 735 HHs: 156 HH cat A, 574 HH cat B and 5 HH cat C damaged houses, based on a rapid assessment at the start of the project. The level of damage is assessed by a shelter score card. Following the ESampNFI cluster recommended standard modalities, HHs with cat A (transitional shelter support) will receive either $1472 or $1859 (7+HH) in 4 installments cat B damaged houses will receive $550 and HH with cat C damaged houses will receive $330, both in 2 installments. Payments will be done in cash, to allow people to take control of their own construction works. Installments are delivered by an FSP (Bolero) through cash in envelop in local currency, as other options are not available cash. Market monitoring has confirmed availability of required materials and will be conducted throughout to monitor prices and availability of goods. 
The project is designed based on the ESNFI cluster analysis, the ESNFI cluster priorities for the 1st RA and Cordaid&#x2019;s presence/experience in the area. In Herat, people have been severely affected by conflict and natural disasters, which damaged and/or destroyed people&#x2019;s houses, lives and livelihoods. On top of that, winter is ending, a period with high unemployment, and it is projected that floods between April and June 2022 will affect many HHs in the targeted districts. According to the WoAA 2021, 85% of the HH indicated to have at least one sort of shelter need, and 55% of the people indicated the need for a shelter upgrade. Drivers of those needs are caused by a high percentage of people living in damaged shelter. According to the latest IPC report, people in Herat are in IPC4. With the majority of the people in Herat depending on animal husbandry, people have little income and lack the means to ensure sufficient food let alone to repair their houses: most people have unreliable sources of income. HHs on average have 7 or more people drought and flash floods are making them even more vulnerable, displaced people in particular as IDPs are unable to tend to their fields to provide for their families. The lack of appropriate shelter is representing health and protection risks for elderly, (chronically) ill and women/ girls in particular. The cash support for transitional shelter and cash for shelter repair, together with basic repair training will enable selected HHs to improve their immediate living conditions either through the construction of a transitional shelter, or though house repair. Cash is used as markets are functional and materials are locally available, based on market monitoring of Cordaid. Prioritization is based on vulnerability, need for assistance and level of damage. Cordaid will ensure as well the inclusion of HHs with PSN in the assistance through an inclusive approach securing their meaningful participation. Gender, protection and C-19 will be mainstreamed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CORDAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CORDAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Judith Manni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HA Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>06-51057579</telephone>
   <email>judith.manni@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammadrustam Shahab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Assistance</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93782134035</telephone>
   <email>mohammadrustam.shahab@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sayed Latif Basardost</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programmes Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 796 32 3000</telephone>
   <email>slb@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sayed Wais Wardak</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93(0)791611620</telephone>
   <email>sww@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hirat</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.34194400 62.20305600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-19">654065.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-19">127969.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21603">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-19">782035.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305585109">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-26">469221.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
