<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/ESNFI/NGO/21610</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transitional Shelter and Shelter Repair/Upgrade Assistance for Natural Disaster (floods) affected households in Farah Province (Farah City)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2022 HRP seeks US$ 4.4 billion to reach 22.1 million people with emergency life-saving humanitarian and protection assistance across the country. The strategic objective1 of the HRP focus on &quot; Timely, multi-sectoral, lifesaving, equitable and safe assistance is provided to crisis-affected people of all genders and diversities to reduce mortality and morbidity.&quot; The multiple challenges facing the people of Afghanistan, including La Ni&#xF1;a-induced climatic anomalies, political turnover, economic downturn, and the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, are exacerbating the pre-existing needs and vulnerabilities of millions of Afghans. The humanitarian outlook for 2022 remains grim, with 24.4 million people (59 percent of the population) projected to be in urgent need of humanitarian assistance, compared to 18.4 million in 2021.

The main purpose of the 1st RA 2022 is to provide urgently needed funds for strictly prioritized life-saving humanitarian assistance in Afghanistan. According to the recently &#x2018;Whole of Afghanistan Assessments (WoA) assessment, more than 70 percent of households reported living in a significantly or partially damaged or fully destroyed shelter. Considering the high cost of shelter repairs, and the already negative net income of households, reconstruction comes at a high cost that may not be affordable for most. Afghan households must make choices between meeting basic needs and repairing their shelters. The ES-NFI cluster plans under this allocation to provide humanitarian assistance to vulnerable people cyclically affected by seasonal floods expected to occur from April to June 2022.

ORD intends to provide cash Transitional Shelter (80 two rooms each 39 sqm@ US$1,859/HHs and 57 one-room each 29 sqm@ $1,472/HHs) in cash for a total of 137 HHs (959 individuals) and major Shelter Repair/Upgrade in cash for 274 HHs (1,918 individuals) @US$ 550/HHs to natural disaster households in Farah city. ORD has a strong presence in 2022 and is delivering emergency responses. Currently, ORD is in partnership with UNICEF implementing WASH-related activities in Farah province. This response will scale up and fill the ORD&apos;s current response gap of 137 HHs for transitional shelters and 247 HHs for shelter repair based on the ORD need assessment conducted in Feb 2022. The proposed intervention of cash for the transitional shelter and shelter repair will fill the identified gap. ORD will ensure that the most vulnerable people in need are among the affected population groups prioritized for this action and that 411 HHs (2,877 individuals) following ES-NFI cluster standards for natural disaster (floods) affected households to respond to their shelter needs. Moreover, the ORD project team will coordinate its project activities with other partners on the ground to avoid duplication and synergize its activities in terms of coordination and need assessment.

In addition, ORD will provide this response (two-room and one-room Transitional Shelters and major Shelter Repair/Upgrade in cash due to availability and market functionality as well as the beneficiary preference based on the ORD Need Assessment Report that is uploaded under the documents section in GMS. ORD will use the HAWALA system (FSP) for cash transfer to project beneficiaries as other means of cash transfer is difficult in the current situation, each transfer value should be based on the construction progress per household at four installments or trenches. ORD transfers money to FSP accounts and then FSP manages the transactions and cash transfers to distribution points. The project team will carry out PDMs and ORD MEAL will perform additional verification by phone. ORD will share the project information project participant profile with AWAAZ Afghanistan and integrate further AAP activities, including having other communication channels for project participants to give feedback complaints to ORD and get a response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Relief Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Relief Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Khalid Salimee</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799319429</telephone>
   <email>director@ord.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Iqbal Shahzada</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93772627928</telephone>
   <email>iqbal.shahzada@ord.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohibur Rahman Mohib</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93795855950</telephone>
   <email>pm.humanitarian@ord.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="31">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.49532800 62.26266270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-09">382370.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-09">80853.71</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21610">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-09">463224.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Relief Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
