<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/FSAC/NGO/21606</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Assistance in Kuz Kunar and Behsud districts of Nangarhar province targeting IPC level 4 households</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis reveals that 23 million people in 
Afghanistan, or 55 per cent of the population, are expected to be in crisis or emergency levels of food insecurity (IPC 3+) between November 2021 and March 2022, a nearly 35 per cent increase compared to the same season last year (16.9 million people). 8.7 million People are projected to be in IPC 4, globally the highest number in absolute and relative terms. Food consumption declined significantly. The proportion of households falling into the &#x201C;poor&#x201D; category of the Food consumption score (FCS) nearly tripled from 2020 (14 per cent) to 2021 (close to 40 per cent) across all population groups. The food crisis severity has been compounded by the economic sanctions placed on Afghanistan following the change in government in August 2021.

According to the IPC analysis, Nangarhar province is facing emergency level of acute food insecurity. The drought conditions driven by La Ni&#xF1;a, the current political crisis and conflict further compound the food security situation of a population which was already on the brink of a hunger crisis. As per the AHF 1st RA strategy paper, even after harvest, 57 percent of households do not have food reserves that would last for 3 months. In urban areas, income loss (driven by economic shocks) has contributed to the rapid deterioration in food insecurity. 10 out of 11 most densely populated urban areas are anticipated to be in IPC 4. Additionally, the higher food prices are negatively impacting the purchasing power of lower-income groups across the country, reducing their access to food. Rural areas, and particularly farming and livestock rearing households, have been hard-hit by the 2020-21 drought, the worst in 27 years. The drought is estimated to have caused a deficit of up to 3 million Metric Tons of wheat in the country and reduced agricultural labor opportunities by up to 60 per cent.

Through the proposed project, AWRO will provide cash for food assistance to 1,063 HHs (7,440 individuals &#x2013; based on average family size of 7) in Kuz Kunar and Behsud districts of Nangarhar province classified in  &#x2018;Emergency&#x2019; (IPC Phase 4) food insecure, and those anticipated to be affected by flood, dry spell and other risks, as per the IPC analysis 2021. Based on the FSAC cluster standards and the allocation strategy paper, every eligible HH will receive 360 USD to cover 75% of the food basket for six months (60 USD per month). This will help the families have food for their families during the tough situations. This will make sure the vulnerable households have acceptable food consumption score.

1. Behsud district
4,200 individuals in 600 IPC 4 HHs (902 Men, 1,135 Women, 1,020 Boys and 1,143 Girls) 
2. Kuz Kunar district
3,240 individuals in 463 IPC 4 HHs (700 Men, 900 Women, 752 Boys and 888 Girls)
Will receive cash for food assistance (75% of the Full package of FSAC Standard food basket of family) in three rounds to cover food needs for six months.

AWRO will use the local Money Service Providers (Hawala/MSP) system based on CVWG response criteria as there are MSPs available in Nangarhar. The MSPs are the most available and easy to access to right-holders. AWRO already has agreement with an MSP to provide service in the target province. The availability of MSPs is ensured and physically checked. The cash will be distributed in envelop AFN currency. Food Markets are available and accessible to all right-holders without any barriers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sayed Farhadullah Ebadi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Managing Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93786126612</telephone>
   <email>director@awro.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mustafa Ahmadi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Focal Point</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93700189189</telephone>
   <email>mustafa.ahmadi@awro.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.17183130 70.62167940</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">486697.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">70833.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21606">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">557531.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
