<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/SA1/ESNFI/INGO/22139</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transitional Shelter and Shelter Repair Assistance in Dawlatyar (Ghor)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable populations in Dawlatyar district of Ghor face a complex set of needs. Drought and economic recession have resulted in reduced food availability and decreased income opportunities, depleting households&#x2019; productive assets and reducing their capacity to cope with shocks. In addition to this, many of Ghor&#x2019;s communities are prone to spring flooding and other natural hazards which destroy households&#x2019; shelter and assets, and leave them displaced and vulnerable to further hazards. In consultation with the ESNFI Cluster and based on an analysis of the past flooding data and Rapid Assessment Mechanism findings, Afghanaid proposes to provide crucial shelter assistance to an estimated 1,505 vulnerable households whose shelter has been damaged by flooding, conflicts or other crises in the Lokah Mazar and Sumak areas of Dawlatyar. Also these areas are noted by the ESNFI Cluster as priority locations for this allocation. 
In line with the ESNFI Cluster&#x2019;s analysis, Afghanaid proposes three different shelter assistance packages, tailored to the needs of different groups, in the form of cash-for-shelter where feasible: 
1) Transitional shelter assistance for 100 Category A households whose shelter has been completely damaged and is uninhabitable. At the Cluster&#x2019;s request, Afghanaid has based its calculations on an average household size of 7 members and has used the medium-sized shelter design and BoQ with a total value of $1472 per household for households with more than 7 members, the larger shelter design and BoQ may be used with a total value of $1859 per household. Afghanaid will consult with the cluster to adjust the total number of target households and the value of assistance per household where needed.
2) Major repairs and upgrades assistance of up to $550 in assistance for 301 Category B households whose shelter has been severely damaged, but remains inhabitable.
3) Minor repairs assistance of up to $330 for 1,104 Category C households whose shelter has suffered only minor damage to windows, doors and walls etc.
Participants will be selected using ESNFI cluster vulnerability criteria to ensure that households in most acute need are targeted. Final assistance amounts will vary based on participants&apos; particular needs as determined through an engineer-led assessment, but major repairs and minor repairs packages will not exceed the Cluster-set maximums of $550 and $330 respectively. Transitional shelter assistance values may vary based on market prices of construction materials and the households&#x2019; capacities vulnerable households unable to contribute labor may receive additional assistance to cover the cost of hiring construction workers.
Afghanaid proposes conditional cash transfers as the modality for the assistance to address the shelter needs of each vulnerable households, pending a thorough market assessment to be conducted at the outset of the project. The assistance will be complemented with training and coaching for participants throughout the repair and construction works. Where prices of labor and key materials increase significantly, Afghanaid may facilitate procurement from other markets, or pivot to in-kind assistance provision.
Due to the absence of formal banking solutions in the target area, Afghanaid will in principle work with an established Saraf (hawala agent) to distribute the cash from central distribution points. The assistance tranches will be paid on completion of pre-agreed progress milestones, in line with Cluster standards.
Afghanaid is well placed to implement this project, with over 20 years of continuous presence in Ghor, and extensive humanitarian programming experience including numerous ESNFI responses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ayub Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director of Finance  Administration</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93790897166</telephone>
   <email>akhan@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Johannes Jansen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728630493</telephone>
   <email>jjansen@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najibullah Namiq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants and Partnership Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799733944</telephone>
   <email>najeebullah@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zodiac Maslin-Hahn</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programme Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+442035596647</telephone>
   <email>zmhahn@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-28">744544.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-28">221779.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-22139">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-28">966323.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
