<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/ESNFI/UN/21649</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of community resource centres and mobile CCCM teams in underserved communities in Sari-pul and Jawzjan provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under this AHF grant, IOM&#x2019;s seeks to provide support to IDPs, returnees and host communities through access to multisectoral assistance, such as primary health care, water supply and WASH hygiene promotion. This will be undertaken through Community Resource Centers (CRCs), setting up a system of interconnected CRCs and mobile outreach teams to ensure the provision of humanitarian aid and essential services, especially in the most underserved and hard-to-reach areas in the North Region of Afghanistan, specifically in Sari-Pul and Jawzjan. 
&#xB7;	Regular monitoring of service provision using tools harmonized with the CCCM WG and site community, and dissemination of site information and needs to partner and clusters. This includes weekly and monthly site service monitoring, organizing regular site-level and area-level coordination meetings with service providers, authorities and site leaders, and the dissemination of the Awaaz Afghanistan complaint and feedback mechanism to have a more constant information of the needs of the population in displacement/ informal sites.
&#xB7;	Formation and capacity building of site committees, site committees will be comprised of representatives from various groups in the settlement and host community and designed to assist the population in meaningful decision making and give voice to the different groups among the displaced communities. Working in the community will establish which ones will be most essential but potentially include a general site management committee, a protection and inclusion and women&#x2019;s committee, a youth committee, a hygiene committee and a care and maintenance committee in coordination with relevant cluster and workings groups, depending on the specific needs of each site. The aim of these groups will be to provide the population opportunities to express their views during decision making related to humanitarian assistance and develop action plans to inform humanitarian and development actors to address needs in the site jointly.
&#xB7;	Information sharing with community will be established so that regular interaction can take place including raising awareness regarding  using the Awaaz feedback mechanisms, the inter-agency feedback mechanism in Afghanistan, a toll-free hotline, conducting risk communication and Infection prevention and control awareness related to COVID-19, encouraging community participation in various services provided in the site, creating opportunities for often excluded groups such as women and youth to take part in  leadership and other self-reliance and empowerment initiatives, in close coordination with IOM programs and relevant clusters and working groups.

Sites targeted under this project will be assessed by the mobile teams and supported to map and monitor the services existing at the site through a service monitoring, safety audits and perception tool developed jointly with the Accountability Affected Population Working Group and the CCCM WG. The tool will be used not only to inform on the existing services provided, gaps and risks at the site but also to have a better understanding on the perceptions on the community regarding the humanitarian assistance provided by the partners and identified a better way to engage with the communities and provide assistance with people-centered approach, with its focus on community cohesion. The mobile teams will conduct visits weekly to the CRCs and scattered communities surrounding the CRCs locations and follow up on priorities identified by the community. and will reach indirectly with assessments more than 92,995 IDPs, returnees, and host communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Mavengere</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Resource Management Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>251929001380</telephone>
   <email>dmavengere@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nicolas Vexlir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCCM Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728004177</telephone>
   <email>nvexlir@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Susan Price</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93794795117</telephone>
   <email>sprice@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jawzjan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.89696920 65.66585680</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sar-e-Pul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.67074730 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-28">603813.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-28">590687.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21649">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-28">1194500.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_AFG_2022_1000122">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-30">1194500.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
