<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/APC/INGO/21710</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving human security and livelihood opportunities through the removal of improvised explosive devices (IEDs) and the delivery of explosive ordnance risk education in Chaghcharan district, Ghor province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fighting between Taliban and former Afghan National Army forces involved prolific emplacement of improvised explosive devices (IEDs) in Ghor province, especially in Chagcharan district. Between 2019 &#x2013; 2021, 79 IED casualties were recorded in Chagcharan, with IED casualties rates in 2021 (33) almost triple that of 2019 (13) and showing no signs to decreasing. A mountainous and previously unstable province, relatively few mine and IED clearance operations have taken place in the area. 
In alignment with the priorities of the mine action sub-cluster, HALO proposes to implement a project focused on life-saving IED clearance and explosive ordnance risk education (EORE) to address the emergency needs of the village of Ahangaran in Chagcharan district of Ghor. HALO proposes to achieve these objectives through conducting the following activities:
Activity 1.1.1: Provision of Explosive Ordnance Risk Education (EORE). Along with Comprehensive COVID messaging delivered by a 2 full time mixed-gender EORE teams.
HALO will deploy two mixed-gender EORE teams in Chagcharan district of Ghor province between May &#x2013; October 2022. The teams will deliver EORE sessions to educate EO-affected communities about the dangers of explosive items including IEDs, landmines and other explosive ordnance. HALO will promote safe behavior by informing the project participants about the appearance and dangers of mines, including IEDs and other EO, common signs of contamination, and how to respond to and report contamination. In addition to delivering EORE messaging, HALO has trained EORE personnel to deliver COVID-19 messaging during EORE sessions to contribute to national efforts to raise awareness and mitigate the spread of the virus. COVID-19 messaging will be delivered in accordance to the DMAC) curricula and have already been consulted with the health clusters.
Each of these teams will include 2 mahram people (one male and one female) and a driver. Each team will provide 4 sessions per day. The length of each session is two hours. 90 minutes (75%) of each session is dedicated to EORE, which is enough amount of time to convey the education. And the remaining 30 minutes (25%) of each session is dedicated to COVID-19 messaging.
Activity 1.2.1: Clearance of explosive hazards
Improved local security conditions across the country is increasing access to many new and once hard-to-reach and heavily EO-affected communities such as Ahangaran. Over a period of six months, May to October 2022, HALO will deploy seven manual IED clearance teams and two IED mechanical demining units (MDU) to Ahangaran. Under this project, HALO&#x2019;s activities will support the DMAC and the Mine Action Programme of Afghanistan (MAPA) to advance progress towards achievement of Afghanistan&apos;s international obligations under the Ottawa Mine Ban Treaty. 
The Manual IED clearance teams of the HALO Trust consist of: One team leader, One medic deminer, five deminers, one senior medic and one driver. Each manual IED clearance team can clear up to 6000 square meters. The mechanical IED clearance teams of the HALO Trust consist of one team leader, one section commander, two mechanical asset drivers, one low loader driver, one medic, one senior medic and one driver. Each Mechanical IED clearance team can clear 13200 square meters of land montly.
Activity 1.3.1: Protection monitoring activities including Victim data collection to improve records about people with disabilities, including those affected by mines and ERW
Through delivery of the above activities, the project will achieve these outputs:
1. 10 hazardous areas released and removed from the national database (IMSMA)
2. At least 410,720 square meters of hazardous ground cleared of IEDs 
3. Clearance of IEDs directly benefits 895 project participants and indirectly benefits a further 222 individuals
4. Delivery of 1,024 EORE sessions to 15,360 project participants</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HALO TRUST</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HALO TRUST</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farid Homayoun</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93707921788</telephone>
   <email>donorrelations@haloafg.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">699999.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21710">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">699999.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HALO TRUST</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305629385">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">559999.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HALO TRUST</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
