<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/H/NGO/21596</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of COVID-19 response and case management services through 20 beds COVID-19 hospital in Zabul province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this funding opportunity (1st Reserve Allocation 2022) AADA is seeking support to secure funding for the operation of a 20 beds COVID-19 hospital in Qalat city of Zabul province for a period of six months. This funding will precede the two-months bridge funding of WHO(March-April,22) to ensure the continuation of the COVID-19 hospital services without interruption. As the sustainability of the COVID-19 response services is highly concern and strategically being discussed to be integrated/streamlined into the BPHS/EPHS service delivery system in the future, therefore, through this allocation, we are proposing financial support only for six months to sustain the bridge funding until July 2022. In case the World Bank supports COVID-19 hospitals, AADA in consultation with the Health Cluster, will consider and agree on the re-programming for the available balance. 
The hospital will provide a comprehensive COVID-19 response service in terms of case management and clinical care, case reporting, contact tracing as well as surveillance and RCCE related activities. These services will be initiated immediately after the agreed start date as the hospital is fully functional and ready for delivering the services. 
The hospital has been already equipped with all the required equipment, AADA will maintain and keep functional the essential equipment such as ventilators, and oxygen delivery equipment as well as regularly maintain the effective logistic and supply system to make available the required supplies. 
The action will support the hospital to be supplied with required pharmaceuticals and supplies on a monthly and ad-hoc basis while the required pharmaceuticals and supplies will be procured on a quarterly base and will be stored in the provincial stock.
Considering the occurrence of 3rd wave of COVID-19 and the potential of Omicron variant spread in Afghanistan, the COVID-19 cases that need inpatient services might be increased dramatically. In order to be prepared for the unexpected burden/load of the COVID-19 cases, AADA has allocated an amount of contingency fund (10% budget of the total contract amount) to be prepared for such impending fluxes of COVID19 on the provincial level.
Moreover, for safety and security, all staff of the hospital will be provided with the required protection and infection prevention material and equipment. The protection and infection prevention materials will include medical masks, whole-body gowns, specialized PPEs (only for staff handling the COVID - 19 patients), disinfection material, hand-washing material and other facilities recommended by the WHO/MoPH.
Technical guidance and adherence to the guidelines on COVID - 19 will be considered amid delivering the services as well as the awareness-raising and RCCE activities will be part of the response through this action.
AADA will pro-actively participate in all coordination mechanisms at the provincial level. AADA will be engaged and work in close coordination with the Provincial Center for Combating Coronavirus (PCCC) headed by provincial counterparts and stakeholders. AADA will update team members on progress against the project work plan and will join/support all the collaborative activities at the provincial level. 
The action will be overseen by the deputy technical manager, based in Zabul province who will support the overall management of the action and will provide required administrative and technical support to the project team as well as liaise and maintain close working relation/ coordination with all provincial stakeholders on a routine and ad hoc manner on the project related issues. The contract of the existing supervisor will be extended to conduct support supervision and on-the-job hands-on training to hospital staff. Whenever possible, joint monitoring exercises will be conducted by AADA, WHO, and PPHD to identify implementation gaps and challenges and propose/implement remedial actions for improved service delivery.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emran Sultani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 704 120 513</telephone>
   <email>esultani@aada.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Mohammad Najeeb Baleegh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 799 057 623</telephone>
   <email>nbaleegh@aada.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdul Qadir Baqakhil</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 765 197 616</telephone>
   <email>qbaqakhil@aada.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Yasamin Yousofzai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 700 012 254</telephone>
   <email>yyousofzai@aada.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zabul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.19187820 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-16"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">331520.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21596">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-03">331520.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305629388">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-15">265216.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Assistance  for Development of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
