<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-22/3481/RA1/FSAC/INGO/21692</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life Saving Food Assistance for acute food insecure households in Ghomarch and Qadis districts of Badghis Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acute food insecurity conditions are expected to continue through spring 2022 and thereafter. Impacts of the 2021 drought and likely higher than normal temperatures through spring may result in cumulative negative impact on pasture conditions and food availability. Shocks and stressors which include drought induced crop reduction, reduced income and unemployment, surging food prices, and a broad economic crisis are key drivers of food insecurity in early 2022. 
The food crisis severity has been compounded by the economic sanctions placed on Afghanistan following the change in government in August 2021. Rural areas, and particularly farming and livestock rearing households, have been hard-hit by the 2020-21 drought, the worst in 27 years. The drought is estimated to have caused a deficit of up to 3 million Metric Tons of wheat in the country and reduced agricultural labor opportunities by up to 60 per cent. Food reserves continue to dwindle with 57 per cent of households assessed in in the 2021 Seasonal Food Security Assessment reporting not having food reserves lasting three months, this situation is even worse in the current situation. Sharp drops in income, surging food and other commodity prices, growing unemployment and severed remittances are expected to contribute to the deterioration of food security. 

Badghis province was classified in IPC 4 in the previous post -harvest IPC analysis of 2021 and with the current situation will mostly prevail considering the circumstances on the ground. The food insecurity situation remains dire and continues to be exacerbated by the continued economic decline, predicted 2021/22 drought, low crop yields, loss of livelihoods, sudden shocks (earthquakes) amongst others. The drought risk is predicted to be extreme for the current season with over 72% of the population in Badghis having been affected by shocks in the past 6 months. 
In line with FSAC priorities detailed in the cluster&#x2019;s specific objectives in the 2022 HRP, specifically Strategic objective 1 to provide Timely, multi-sectoral, life-saving, equitable and safe assistance is provided to crisis-affected people of all genders and diversities to reduce mortality and morbidity.
WVA proposes to provide Food assistance  through cash or 6 months 75% of the food basket to IPC Phase 4 10, 696 (1, 528 HH vulnerable people emergency food assistance in the Qadis and Ghomarch districts of Badghis provinces. WVA will provide food assistance through unconditional cash for food (6 months 75% ration) to acutely food insecure (IPC4. As per cluster priorities for this allocation, the intervention will provide in each district with 6 standard &#xBE; (75%) rations for a total of 360 USD in 6 months ($60/household/month (2022 FSAC&#x2019;s guidelines).
WVA already has a long term agreement (LTA) with the financial service provide (Hawala)  who has experience in working in the selected areas. Distribution will be done over 6 rounds of 60 USD per HH per month. Participants with limited mobility will be brought to the distribution point or receive the assistance at home. 

This intervention will provide 10,696 vulnerable IPC4 men, women, boys and girls with urgent live saving food assistance, to address their immediate food gaps whilst reducing illness and mortality as a result of the current food crisis. The cash will be provided over a period of six months (6 rounds of half ration distributions) through use of a reputable Hawala agent who already has a long-term agreement with World Vision Afghanistan. WVA will through its community engagement facilitators and cash officers raise awareness on the use of cash received , and sensitize them on aspects around usage and ownership , potential diversion, taxation and if any of these are observed the communities should report immediately though the established complaint and feedback mechanisms .</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asuntha Charles</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799-209-720</telephone>
   <email>Asuntha_Charles@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Faisal Danesh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance/Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 792 494 002</telephone>
   <email>Faisal_Danesh@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Faraidoon Osmani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GAM Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799861573</telephone>
   <email>Faraidoon_Osmani@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biruk Kebede Beyene</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 797088426</telephone>
   <email>biruk_beyene@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-05-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">736069.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">69315.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21692">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-06">805385.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2022" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
