<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-4315</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition integration</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Combine treatment programs for patients referred to the 8 already established PHC clinics, focusing on the Gedo and Lower Juba regions. 2. Maintaining and enhancing nutrition services in two integrated clinics for primary health care and outpatient clinics. 3.Improved ability to determine community / family level and screening and refer malnourished children to outpatient clinics. 4. Provide training and counseling to 100 clinical health and nutrition employees who are on the job in all ten integrated primary health care centers and outpatient clinics. 5. Purchase and supply of nutritional commodities to targeted treatment centers. Coordination and promotion of participation in nutrition and health groups at the national and regional levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Each of the 10 sites will receive the nutrition commodities (RUTF and medicines) needed to treat severe acute malnutrition for one year. 48,000 children under 5 years of age will be examined for SAM in the health facility and in the water pool community. 4,080 children with SAM will be treated and discharged. 54,310 individuals will be sensitized to nutrition education in the community, including counseling on infant and child nutrition. 10 clinical staff in each office will be well trained and continuously directed to provide high quality services. 100 community outreach volunteers are able to conduct health promotion on nutrition and follow up on strugglers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IOM will integrate nutrition through existing health interventions that currently lack integration / integration with nutrition services, while building the capacity of the national health workforce to provide integrated health and nutrition services. The main objective of the response is to contribute to the management of people with severe acute malnutrition (SAM) in children under five years of age through Integrated Outpatient Therapy Centers (OTP), and to improve the family and community&apos;s ability to promote appropriate nutrition for infants and young children (IYCF).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="40000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organisation for Migration (IOM)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="4315" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-01-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-26">1682066</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-20">1682066</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
