<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHAS-HPC6770-4156</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the capacity building of the Ministry of Humanitarian Affairs and Disaster Management in the Republic of Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening systems and setting work priorities and procedures - Supporting a minimum level of human capacity at the regional level and working on training programs for employees - Supporting information technology solutions and wireless communication equipment - Establishing an early warning system - Allocating funding under partner management and coordination with the government represented by the Ministry of Humanitarian Affairs for Ministry support to respond to emergency situations and immediate logistical support purposes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to set priorities and guide the development of the implementation plan, the development of systems and links between and within systems, technical capabilities, emergency preparedness and response planning. The project also aims to find a minimum level of trained human capacity to raise the efficiency of response in the three regions in which the trainees will work and find basic technological solutions that contribute to raising the level of communication, coordination and early warning according to criteria and mechanisms that ensure finding a good level of early procedures for crises. Contributing through the human cadres in strengthening the regional humanitarian and disaster management centers working with the ministry. And contribute to support these centers at the central and regional levels with appropriate equipment and services in the field of information technology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="4156" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-OCHAS-HPC6770" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="AR">King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="40000" ref="XM-DAC-41140" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations World Food Programme (WFP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-11"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-12">500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-11">500000</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
