<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA2/P/UN/9812</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of critical frontline child protection services to extremely vulnerable children and women living in hard to reach areas through integrated rapid response mechanism (IRRM) missions to provide critical protection services, including family tracing and reunification, psychosocial support and strengthening of community based networks with a focus on Western Equatoria and other priority conflict affected areas.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By February 2019, UNICEF will reach 21,000 extremely vulnerable children (9,870 boys 11,130 girls) and 12,000 adults (5,640 men 6,360 women) with critical child protection (CP) services through frontline service delivery with a special focus on Mundri East and West in Western Equatoria, as provider of last resort, as well as other high priority protection hotspot areas where there is no other child protection presence or access. Through IRRM missions in hard-to-reach locations UNICEF will deploy experienced Child Protection in Emergencies personnel to deliver critical child protection services such as FTR, PSS, monitoring and reporting of grave child rights violations. The SSHF funding will be complemented with funding from other donors to achieve these goals. 

Outreach missions will be conducted to Mundri East and West and extremely critical areas where no other CP actors are available. Other locations will be reached through routine or one time IRRM missions. If access is granted, Mundri East and West will be accessed through IRRMs as well. A three-fold strategy will be employed: 

(1)	Routine IRRM missions (by air) and outreach missions (by road), to locations in-line with 60 days&#x2019; routine food distributions of WFP. 
(2)	Provision of immediate critical frontline CP services through IRRM missions where there is less opportunity for routine services. 
(3)	Protection outreach missions - in Mundri East and West the interventions will be outreach missions or a static response as there are no IRRM missions in those locations. These missions assess and respond to rapidly changing needs in areas of critical need and provide the following key CP services: 

Key activities planning through missions
1.	Identification, registration and family tracing and reunification (FTR) services and temporary care placements for separated, unaccompanied and missing girls and boys
2.	Community-based psychosocial support (PSS) including PFA, and referrals when needed for women and children including survivors of GBV 
3.	Provide life-saving prevention messages to the affected population including children through large scale awareness raising in communities
4.	Monitoring and reporting of grave child rights violations through verification and assessment and documentation 
5.	Conduct rapid CP assessments to better understand needs, map available services, and help to identify vulnerabilities and risks and support GBV and CP mainstreaming
6.	Establish and build capacity of community based child protection networks (CPNs), on child protection complaints mechanisms, monitoring and reporting and community based care arrangements 
7.	Training and capacity building activities will be conducted by community based organisations (CBOs) who are implementing CP or humanitarian assistance
8.	UNICEF will transport critical lifesaving child protection supplies 
9.	UNICEF will charter flights in situation no other mode of transportation or no IRRMs taking place to ensure critical CP services are provided to children and communities 

UNICEF will provide information and technical support to other partners and the broader Protection Cluster to ensure continuity of service delivery and promote the sharing of good practices and lessons learned. Principles of centrality of protection will be applied throughout the project to ensure that those who are most at risk are identified and responded to, taking into account the vulnerabilities that underlie these risks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief of Child Protection</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>vnsanzugwanko@unicef.org</telephone>
   <email>Vedasto Nsanzugwanko</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Louise Sherwood</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0926526550</telephone>
   <email>lsherwood@unicef.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.34717990 28.29943500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-30">100148.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-30">99321.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-9812">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-30">199469.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SSD_2018_1000024">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-30">199469.72</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
