<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA1/WASH/NGO/7893</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute sustainable health improvements among 12,000 female and male community members at risk of getting cholera in Rejaf and Northern Bari Payams of Juba County.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to contribute improved health standards for the prevention of cholera among 12,000 individuals living in the villages of Gumbo areas (of Guduge, Sherikat, Gumbo III, Gumbo Centre in Rejaf Payam and provision of safe water supply for conflict affected populations in Northern Bari Payam.

Based on the existing cholera risks, project activities will be geared towards reinforcing gains made in previous WASH interventions and recent assessment needs for reduction of vulnerabilities.
Major effort will be on improving the access to basic WASH services for mitigation of morbidity and mortality related to diarrheal-illness by at list 85% among target group. Main activities will focus on behavior change that ensures water, food and hand safety at household levels, schools, public and community gathering places are at a good standard.
The project will also ensure protection of women and girls by creating access to safe water supply which is secure to reduce further risk of Sexual Gender Based incidences in Northern Bari Payam.
In these locations, girls and women spend most hours of the night at wells or move long distances to bushy streams to collect water. In the target areas, incidences of sexual Gender based violence were reported in the course of accessing water.

Capacity of community members will be strengthened alongside provision of sustained access to basic WASH services and to ensure active participation of community members, key stakeholders will be involved at grass-root level. Recent needs assessments will jointly be reviewed at each project to tackle existing gaps.
15 Community Hygiene Promotion will be trained to improve access to hygiene knowledge with practical demonstration of messages of food hygiene, handwashing with soap, water treatment and storage.
5 Community Hygiene Supervisors will be recruited and trained to trace and report cases of acute watery diarrhea and also to supervise bucket chlorination, disinfect households of persons with confirmed cholera cases.
Homes of malnourished children benefiting from feeding programmes will be also be traced and mothers helped to observe good hygiene habits.
Supervisors will also support events of Focused Group Discussions that are aimed at involving the community members to play active role in cholera prevention and elimination open defecation through community based approach to curb water contamination at the sources.
4 boreholes will be drilled to reduce risks associated to consumption of contaminated surface water and further risk of sexual Gender Based Violence women/girls face in the course of collecting water from isolated wells and streams in Jebel Yesua, Nakulujo, Joppa and Mangaten.
5 boreholes will be rehabilitated in Northern Bari Payam.
4 water user committees will be formed and trained (at list 3 females and 2 males in each group) refresher training will be given for water user committees of 5 rehabilitated boreholes.
5 school hygiene promotion clubs will be formed and teacher, PTA and pupils will be trained to support sustainability school hygiene.

NSDO has own capacity to complete activities and will collaborate with the Ministry of Water Resources and irrigation during Hydro-geological survey, actual drilling, quality tests, and training of water user committees and ensure handover is properly done.
During project period NSDO will keep participating in WASH cluster activities and provide weekly and monthly reports. Support will also be given for other cholera mitigation activities under the WASH/HEALTH cluster especially mobilization of target communities during Oral Cholera Vaccination campaigns, World Water Day, Global Handwashing Day and World Toilet Day.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jimmy Joseph Jamba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emmergency Preparedness and Response Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0954908980</telephone>
   <email>jimmyjamba5@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Repent Taban</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0928416545</telephone>
   <email>rtabanus@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-20">130000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-7893">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-20">130000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00073395">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-29">90655</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00075450">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-10">39335</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nile Sustainable Development Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
