<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA2/NFI/NGO/9783</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency provision of lifesaving shelter and NFIs interventions to newly displaced persons and most vulnerable host community populations through timely mobile and static presence in Fangak and Uror county of Jonglei State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to UN OCHA Humanitarian situation overviews 2018 report. The South Sudan crisis has led to humanitarian crisis across the country, and it has deepened and spread, affecting people in areas previously considered stable and exhausting the coping capacity of those already impacted. Since December 2013, Violence and rights violations are widespread and continue unabated. About 2 million people are still displaced into protection sites and IDPs settlements across the country with limited or no access to protection services. However, nearly 4.6 million people are in need of humanitarian assistance and protection across the country as a result of armed conflict, inter-communal violence, economic crisis, disease outbreaks and climatic shocks. The multiple hazards have continued to erode the capacity of people to cope and mitigate risks to life, livelihoods and well-being. 

The population of Fangak according to South Sudan 22nd April 2008 Census is 110,130 individuals (Females 52,025, Male 58,105), and according to Population project 1st July, 2017 is 151,727  individuals and Uror county obtaining a population of 179,907 according to 2008 census.The ADA&#x2019;s static and mobile response team will aims to response to an emergency response to a newly displaced IDPs, returnees and most vulnerable host community and to unreachable locations in Islands of Fangak that are multiply affected by conflict through the provision of lifesaving assistance in form of NFIs and shelter support. ADA will exercise it response by conducting an need assessment that will determine the context of the finding gap across the response.

This grant request is to boost the already existent ADA static team based in Fangak and Uror with rapid response capability particularly to area. The presence of ADA in Fangak and Uror enable it for immediate response in supporting newly displaced IDPs, returnees and most vulnerable host community, this has fit and sharpen the understanding of ADA across the two counties However, as the project will emerge whilst rain curving to an end, most of the shelter and NFIs distribution will take place in secure and accessible areas. During the project implementation, all S/NFI items will be provided by the cluster pipeline and is not budgeted under the project. These items will include NFI kits and Shelter items of plastic sheets provided by the pipeline. The beneficiary calculation for both mobile response teams is in line with the USD $13 per beneficiary targeted by the cluster, including household members (i.e. one S/NFI kit directly benefiting all members of a household).

In Fangak and Uror county, numbers of the population also moved deep into remote areas such as Pagil and Guwai to avoid the atrocities that characterized the conflict. Many more are expected to return back home from Bor PoC and Juba PoC to Fangak and Uror county. A huge influx of IDPs from Waat and Walgak of Akobo West,are also seen in Fangak and Uror county.  In may 2018 incident of Southern Unity State has topically increased the Fangak IDPs population and this was verified by NRC , IOM and ADA assessments, verification exercise conducted in May,June and July, 2018.

 Most number of men were mainly engaged in conflict leaving behind the women with children, However, according to REACH Resource Center Report, IDPs make up about 25-35 percent of the population and over 60% of the IDPs are women and children. these target groups are the most vulnerable and in most need of support. Furthermore, both IDPs and host populations suffered extreme problems with drinking water accessibility, lack of non-food items (NFIs) and food security. an average of 70% of the IDPs are integrated into the host communities, which are congested and the sanitation is poor most of the IDPs intend to stay until the situation in their places of origin. Uror is a county in Jonglei State, South Sudan.However, despite the Continued displacement in Jonglei,in particu</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Betim Madol Betim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ES/NFIs Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0927744773</telephone>
   <email>betimadology@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Riek Yior</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0920222200</telephone>
   <email>yior.ada@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-10">67223.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-10">32778.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-9783">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-10">100002.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00076839">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-20">48901</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00078666">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-11">51101.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Development Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
