<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA1/NFI/NGO/7988</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to shelter and non-food items to people in need and with protection concerns in WES and CES.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will respond to the need of the most vulnerable 1,798 HHs (10,793 ind.) among the conflict-affected population of Central and Western Equatoria State. The project targets the most vulnerable newly displaced people and protracted IDPs, a small number returnees and host community, particularly focusing on people with protection concerns and most acute needs. The project activities will target 6,477 individuals (1,079 HHs) in Mundri West county (WES) with direct distribution of life-saving ES and life-sustaining NFIs. Assessments will determine the areas where intervention is sustainable, and the people most in need, particularly where beneficiaries&#x2019; movement is precluded, but humanitarian access is granted, and the population does not have purchasing power/access to the local market. 
Additionally, LCED will implement a CBI targeting 200 HHs (1,200 ind.) in Mundri West county (WES) with restricted, unconditional cash vouchers. It will be implemented only in areas where the population has access to the market, and it will imply a market and needs assessment beforehand, to determine the beneficiaries&#x2019; access (physical, economic, financial, socio-cultural) and the capacity of local suppliers. After defining the ES/NFI package for the targeted beneficiaries, according to their needs, LCED will engage suppliers in Mundri West, to set the price of the items, according to the Minimum Expenditure Basket (MEB) for Greater Equatoria, and sign a binding contract, specifying modality of procurement and payment. In Mundri West it makes sense to implement a cash-for-work project, as cash vouchers in exchange for repairing community roads or helping in shelter constructions. However, such activities are performed by men, and targeting only them for the distribution of cash vouchers will undermine our aim of empowering women economically, hence LCED prefers to use unconditional cash vouchers. The CBI will be integrated by procurement of pipeline items, due to the fact that some essential S/NFI are not present in the local market. 
Finally, the project activities will target 4,316 individuals (719 HHs) in CES and WES, for direct distribution of ES/NFI through regional mobile response. Among these, LCED estimated the distribution of survival kits to 200 HHs (1,200 ind.), in order to deliver a multisector and integrated approach to reduce acute needs. This intervention will target extremely volatile population in areas where there will be a limited window of opportunity for humanitarian assistance and access. For all mobile interventions, the target population will be identified according to the need and to the cluster prioritization.
LCED estimates local procurement of framing material (wooden poles, bamboo bundles) for 200 HHs (1,200 individuals), in situations where the material is available, but not accessible by the beneficiaries. This is especially the case of women and elderly people, experiencing protection concerns on the road, including harassment and looting. The reasons for procuring material locally rather than through the cluster core pipeline are the higher quality and lower cost of local supplies and transportation, and the possibility of revitalizing the local market. The reason for not using CBI in such cases, is that the beneficiaries targeted do not have access to a market, particularly due to their vulnerabilities.
LCED will integrate the static response and mobile response, and will collaborate with other mobile partners to develop efficient interventions and avoid duplication. In the past six months LCED has strengthen its mobile capacity by hiring a Programme Associate with a strong background in reporting, CBI and ES/NFI distribution, and one NFI Assistant, as well as a WASH officer in order to develop an integrated and multisector approach to identify and reduce acute needs. The LCED management will be involved in initial assessments and the MampE exercises, to guarantee transparency and accountability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lacha Community and Economic Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lacha Community and Economic Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Driuni Jakani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0920700097</telephone>
   <email>driuni@lachalced.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monica Berti</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0915621712</telephone>
   <email>monicaberti@lachalced.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU27">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.61440630 31.26263660</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Equatoria</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.34717990 28.29943500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-20">140309.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00073368">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-29">60949.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lacha Community and Economic Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-7988">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-20">140309.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lacha Community and Economic Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00074732">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-11">47680</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lacha Community and Economic Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00076280">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-29">31680</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lacha Community and Economic Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
