<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA2/H/INGO/9921</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing access and strengthening capacities of PHC to provide emergency lifesaving health care services through an integrated response in 2 mobile units, 1 PHCU and 1 PHCC in Nyirol County</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCI is seeking to deliver a six months&#x2019; emergency lifesaving health project in one priority hot spot county where the health situation is critical and with IPC 4. The project will be implemented in isolated areas under opposition having displaced or and returnees people in Nyirol County. The overall objective is to support the implementation of critical lifesaving frontline activities to populations facing greatest needs, compound effects of armed conflict, displacement, hunger, disease and natural disasters such as floods with a focus on populations with the greatest protection risk. The critical lifesaving activities will reduce morbidity and mortality among internally displaced children and adults and those from the host community. 
The project&#x2019;s thematic sector focus will be health, and it will be effective 1 September 2018 to February 29. 2019. Nyirol has a projected population of 169,493 of which the direct beneficiaries are (31,915) include IDPs, returnees and host communities. The proposed activities will complement existing ICCM and nutrition services (mobile outreach) currently implemented by SCI in Nyirol. Trained nutrition community health works (NCHW) will conduct community mobilization and referrals of the seriously sick patients to PHCU/C.
The projected project budget is $ 200,000. The funds will strengthen the delivery of PHC in the existing PHC facilities Keath PHCC, Dengdor Two PHCU and two (Kapnak amp Nyambor) mobile sites. These PHCs were run down during the war the dilapidated Tukuls currently used will require major renovation. In the PHCC, the fund will support quality integrated health services delivery with WASH, Nutrition and FSL to the displaced, returnees and host community. Further, one stabilization center will be set up in collaboration with nutrition department. The Lifesaving health services will be delivered through 
1)	Increased access to PHC services by supporting two mobile sites, 1 PHCU and 1 PHCC. The PHCC will respond to SAM with medical complications, GBV, CRM BEMoNC and MHPSS and 1 PHCU, and two mobile outreach services. 
2)	Integrated response to provide components of WASH, FSL and Nutrition in the PHCC to address famine mitigation of nutrition and food security. . 
SCI will collaborate with UN bodies like WHO, WFP, UNFPA, UNICEF, PSI and other implementing organization in the integrated response. Food security and livelihood (FSL) will address morbidity and mortality related to acute hunger and food vitamin deficiency common among children and women in the proposed project area (SMART survey 2017). lt5 and pregnant women/lactating women will be screened for malnutrition by the NCHW. The identified children and breast-feeding mother will get micronutrient supplements (Vit A to children 6-59 months and breast-feeding mothers will get iron and folic acid) and LLITN. The health facilities will be supported with the following: aqua tabs for safe drinking water, handwashing with soap and improved waste management (incinerator/rubbish pit, toilet/pit latrine).
SCI will support human resources in the facility and community. The staff will be employed to fill gaps identified in the PHCU/C.  The SCI nutrition project in Nyirol supported by NCHW (male and female) will mobilize, and conduct health awareness to community members during health mobile outreach. They will also identify and refer lt5years children and pregnant/lactating women with malnutrition to stabilization center in Keath PHCC. They will also conduct health awareness on EPI, ANC and prevention of endemic diseases. The NCHW will work closely with health committee to report suspected epidemic outbreaks, which will be investigated within 48 hours. Any maternal and neonatal death reported will be investigated. The two mobile outreach services will be provided once a week by the PHCC staff and an additional clinical officer will be employed in Keath PHCC to support the mobile unit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Duncan Amayo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Technical Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211922300184</telephone>
   <email>Duncan.Amayo@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lizzy Ongoro</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposal Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211922700750</telephone>
   <email>Lizzy.Ongoro@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-20">134444.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-20">65555.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="9085">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-10">808</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00076824">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-19">38899</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-9921">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-20">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00078840">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-13">161101</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
