<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA1/H/UN/8088</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delivery of life saving emergency health, Wash and nutrition services to the populations who are displaced, affected by famine and disease in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan has been experiencing protracted humanitarian crisis which now is in its fifth year. It has continued to intensify and expand due to effects of armed conflict and deteriorating economic situation. The armed conflict has expanded and engulfed almost the whole country. According to UNOCHA the number people displaced since the start of the conflict in 2013 has reached more than 4million, including 1.9million internally displaced, 2 million south Sudanese refugees in neighboring countries. It is estimated 1.1 million children under five are acutely malnourished. 5.1 million people are food insecure and this number is expected to increase with 20,000 people projected  to experience famine (IPC 5) in multiple locations all this due to insecurity and displacements. The figures are indicative of an extremely serious situation, where severe acute malnutrition (SAM) remains a persisting and major public health challenge, exposing children at risk of mortality ten times more than their healthy peers.
As the conflict intensify, more populations will be displaced in hard  to reach areas. The disrupted routine immunization to vaccine preventable diseases is likely to lead  to major disease outbreaks like measles, meningitis and pertussis. As the rainy season sets in we are likely to see the  upsurge of acute watery diarrhea including cholera. As most health facilities are looted and health care workers get diplaced, vast displaced population will not have access to essential basic life-saving medical care.
Presence of functioning communicable disease surveillance including Early Warnining Alert and Response Network (EWARN) in deep front line areas is paramount and will require additional  investment so as to  immediately detect, verify, investigate and respond to acute public health events as they are reported.
 Crossed and or nosocomial infections in treatment centers expanding to communities are among some of problem observed over the years during the cholera outbreak. This high lights the magnitude of an urgent needs of essential WASH services including infection control, water quality surveillance and treatment in selected health care facilities, stabilization centers and cholera treatment centers
This project will support provision of front line health  services to  the displaced populations affected by  famine and communicable diseases.
The focus is to ensure  communicable disease control is strengthened through use of Mobile medical outreaches, support to reactive campaigns and capacity building of frontline responders and support to surveillance and EWARN in new displacements and existing IDP locations.The aim is to promply  detect, investigate and respond to  diseases outbreaks particularly cholera, Malaria, Meningitis and measles among others. This will also include capacity building for infection control, waste quality control  in selected  health care facility, stabilization center and cholera hot spots.
In deep front areas where the primary health care facilities are operating sub-optimally, we will ensure essential life-saving medical provision is undertaken focusing on commonest causes of mortality and morbidity (including cholera, shigellosis, typhoid, measles, malaria, meningitis). The project will also anticipate outbreaks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr Argata Guracha</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211956268932</telephone>
   <email>guyoa@who.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.53604490 26.79678490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.64523990 25.28375850</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-13">700000.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-8088">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-13">700000.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_SSD_2018_1000021">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-15">700000.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Health Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
