<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA2/E/INGO/9889</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting personal development and well being of affected youth in Unity State and Upper Nile</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the present project, INTERSOS proposes to meet the needs of affected youth in Unity and Upper Nile States. INTERSOS will support 8 more ALP (Accelerated Learning Program) centers and establish 2 drop-in-centers in Bentiu and Malakal. Among the new 8 ALP centers, 4 belong to World Relief who requested support to run them. INTERSOS will further continue to support the current 13 ALP centers and 2 drop-in centers in Malakal by providing additional resources to increase youth accessing services. This brings to 21 ALP centers: 13 in Bentiu and 8 in Malakal. The current 2 drop-in-centers will be maintained with 2 more in Bentiu town and Malakal town outside the PoCs. The targeted youth in Bentiu and Malakal will receive quality literacy and numeracy learning opportunities, where they receive regular classes supported by qualified teachers who are incentivized. Furthermore, the ALP students will receive teaching and learning material support that enhances the quality of teaching and learning activities. A literacy and numeracy training to uplift their standard of teaching will also be offered. 150 more teachers will receive ALP pedagogy training and 250 teachers, including the 100 teachers trained in the first SSHF allocation, will receive professional mentorship to improve teaching practices and deliver quality education. The 150 new ALP teachers will be added to the current supported ALP centers and new ALP centers will be selected in Bentiu and Malakal. Further, UNICEF ALP textbooks in the pipeline will be used. The ALP centers will receive school supplies such as chalks and stationery. The ALP centers and drop-in-centers will work hand in hand. 

The drop-in-center will provide various youth services including peer support and case management, recreational activities, decorative skill classes, and other activities listed herein: 

 Peer support - The peer educators and other youth accessing the drop-in-center will have educational sessions where a professional is invited to lead a 2-hour session. The experts are identified from NGOs partners and community at large, their involvement is aimed at supporting the empowerment of peer educators who in turn organize youth-led awareness inside and outside the PoCs on the same topics

 Case management (light) &#x2013; Through the expertise of the caseworkers, any youth that is identified or come forward with protection concerns, PSS or health needs will receive support according to external referrals or internal support through the education programme and YFS. Counselling and PFA may be offered if required (INTERSOS is currently working on training on increasing PFA capacity)

 Recreational activities including sports like football, volleyball, or indoor games to support the PSS and recovery processes and space for refreshment

 Art and crafts classes for the production of traditional cultural crafts complement PSS activities and allow for an opportunity to enhance their skill-set and support in their future livelihood attainment. 

By supporting youth to choose to interact in a protection-oriented, safe space, access is provided to acquire knowledge, capacities, and skills needed to fulfill personal development goals and to contribute to the well-being and combat violence and anti-social behavior by promoting social inclusion, tolerance, and peace. Offering this within the unstable environment and volatile context encourages youth to express themselves, improve their state of mind, enhance their protection space and support them in realizing their potential as vehicles of stability for their community at large.

Finally, to support sustainability, INTERSOS will set up ALP committees (5 members) in every ALP center, and drop-in-center committees to support and oversee youth activities. These committees will be supporting INTERSOS in the smooth running of the centers. Daily monitoring of these facilities, technical support and resources will be provided.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bashir Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211915655052</telephone>
   <email>education.ross@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alba Cauchi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211923313819</telephone>
   <email>south.sudan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-17">134662.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-17">168049.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-9889">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-17">302711.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00076730">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-18">38948.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00079064">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-19">196182.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00081382">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-10">67580.49</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
