<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA1/NFI/INGO/7953</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI support to displaced persons in hard to reach areas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to provide emergency shelter and nonfood items to the most vulnerable persons specifically the displaced and some host communities. This is a proposed 9 months project starting from 1st April 2018 focusing on distribution of Shelter and NFI kits using a rapid response mechanism to reach out to 14,000 beneficiaries across- Jonglei, WBeG and Unity States.
The proposed counties within the selected states are Leer, Panyijiar, Raja and Nyirol counties. The exact locations will be confirmed during the assessment in the first month of the project but they will fall within the mentioned counties already prioritized by the shelter cluster. The project locations will be selected based on the priority of cluster and where the assessment reports show the need. 
NRC will plan distributions as per the need assessments.  When blanket targeting is not the applicable, the action will target mainly lactating and pregnant women, households with malnourished children, and households with members who have certain health complications. Besides unaccompanied children, unaccompanied elderly and persons with no community linkages will be targeted. 
In terms of mode of delivery, NRC will be in line with humanitarian priorities for 2018 as outlined in the Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) as well as the nature of the emergence in South Sudan. The project will promote timely delivery of assistance through deployment of rapid response teams. NRC&#x2019;s mobile response teams will be ready for deployment within 8 days for assessments and 14 days for full-fledged delivery of NFIs/emergency shelters and other activities per location.
The team will work in close consultation with the Shelter cluster and its activities will be informed largely by the gaps identified through the multisector/agency assessment missions in which NRC will participate and/or carry out alone depending on the situation between April and December 2018. Through this assessment, NRC will adapt the project to the specific needs of men, women, girls and boys and respond accordingly or refer to relevant service providers in case the needs cannot be covered by the response. NRC also apply its check list of protection mainstreaming to complement the multi sector assessment. NRC will also internally coordinate its response with its Food Distribution, WASH and Education rapid response teams to achieve holistic and integrated NFI/shelter response. Since NRC is also working in WASH, Food security and education sectors therefore a synergy will be sought when responding to the shelter/NFI needs.  

The distribution of Shelter and NFI kits will be done in distribution sites which will be identified together with the community and will put into consideration the minimum standards of protection. The locations which will not expose women and girls to risk of sex and gender based violence (SGBV) with shade and which are not in long walking distances will be chosen. In case drinking water is not available in nearby locations, water will be provided by the NRC team at the distribution site. Elderly, physically incapable, pregnant women and others who require special attention will be prioritized during distribution. Feedback desk will also be provided at each distribution side.
NRC will complement its distribution by community awareness campaign and information sessions. Besides, NRC will organize practical demonstrations to improve the understanding and proper usage of distributed items. Due to the nature of the distribution, NRC will try to conduct PDMs at least at 50% locations where distribution is taken place. NRC will use its M and E software Mobenze for all assessments and PDMs.
Since the war erupted in 2013, NRC has been delivering food, WASH, Shelter and NFI and emergency education to conflict affected beneficiaries in hard to reach areas through well equipped amp experienced 6 rapid response teams composed of national and international experienced staff.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sirak Mehari W</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211955243277</telephone>
   <email>Sirak.mehari@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehana Zawar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>211954981295</telephone>
   <email>rehana.zawar@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sultan Mahmood</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASHShelter Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211959300268</telephone>
   <email>sultan.mahmood@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SU22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.64523990 25.28375850</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-26">169962</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-7953">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-26">169962</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00073680">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-18">76285.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00077422">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-18">93676.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
