<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA1/H/NGO/8064</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of essential life saving time critical emergency clinical health care packages including emergency obstetric care services in Rubkona County</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Rubkona county, Bentiu POC which was established in December 2013 with 117,046 people seeking protection in the site as of May 2017 (IOM data base), is getting depopulated steadily. Between the years, the population in the POC kept fluctuating the cluster projected a population of 76,110 as of 2018. The latest BMR data from IOM for Bentiu and Rubkona towns stands at 36,617 individuals.
Health conditions have deteriorated with communicable diseases such as Malaria, acute respiratory infection (ARI) and diarrhea causing significant morbidity and mortality among this population especially children under 5 years (Health Cluster February2017 report) with malaria accounting for 30% of consultations followed by ARI at 19% and diarrhea at 17% and malnutrition have already skyrocketed at 17% as indicated by the SMART Survey conducted by CARE during the pre-harvest period of May 2017. The result is a population chronically prone to disease with some 31,429 People mostly women and children currently in dire and urgent needs of health services. 
The population movement out of the PoC escalated following the recent communal fight between the youths from Northern Liech State (NLS) (Rubkona and Guit Counties) and those who hail from the Southern Unity Counties (Koch, Leer, Mayendit and Panyijiar). The government at the request of UNHCR/ DRC provided land in Koithie Boma for IDPs staying at collective sites in Bentiu and Rubkona towns to settle. According to DRC records, there is up to 15,000 individuals living in 3200 households in this location with about 20 - 25 households arriving daily. The state health cluster, UNICEF, WHO and SMoH and other partners are considering this population of over 40,000 individuals as part of the PoC population and health need of the PoC is considered incomplete once this population&#x2019;s health needs is not address.
The project is aligned to Health cluster objective of improving access and scaling up responsiveness to essential health care by focusing on the major causes of mortality among U5C (malaria, diarrhoea, pneumonia, measles), this will ensure 90% of the population of the vulnerable communities to have access to Primary Health Care by focusing on the treatment of major causes of mortality among U5C (malaria, diarrhoea, pneumonia, measles),immunization services, among the displaced population that have settled in Koeithe and Nhialdiu of Rubkona County. The project will take care of PHCUs project and the mobile teams among the displaced and the host communities and SC in Nhialdiu Payam.
The beneficiaries of this project are the host community and the IDPs who are in who moved from Bentiu POC and settled in Koieth of Rubkona county, and some 7,000 newly displaced persons in Nhialdiu payam of Rubkona county.

CASS is situated to be the best partner to implements project in Koeithe IDPs of Rubkona county because of its establishment of the base in the payam and the present of the local staff who are responsible for the implementation of the project. CASS has also established a very good rapport with the local authority and the local community through the previous project which will give a maximum support from the community for the success of any future project. Despite CASS intervention in the payam, morbidity and mortality still remains high mostly from areas such as Koeithe and Nhialdiu. CASS couldn&#x2019;t extend the services near them due to the inadequate funding. With this SSHF 1st allocation, CASS is seeing it as an opportunity for closing this gap by providing a PHCU services in Koeithie and Mobile clinic service at the area of Tong and SC service in Nhialdiu.

Being a national organization, CASS has a better understanding of the local context as well as the capacity to provide the most critical services during emergencies even within limited humanitarian corridor where international agencies cannot operate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children Aid South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children Aid South Sudan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Drici Gilbert</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programs Implementation</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211925293762</telephone>
   <email>gilbert.childrenaid@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oyet Sisto</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211955500886</telephone>
   <email>sisto.childrenaid@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU19">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unity</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.92772110 29.78892480</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-19">220045.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-8064">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-19">220045.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children Aid South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00073415">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-29">137295</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children Aid South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00075414">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-05">82750.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children Aid South Sudan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
