<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA2/FSL/NGO/9903</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance food security and livelihood resilience building through Integrated emergency response program for conflict affected IDPs and vulnerable host communities in Aweil South in Northern Bahr el Ghazal a States.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization will focus on households and community level as delivery platform with emphasis on gender base violence prevention by awareness rising on the accountability to affected population
ASCO will increasingly  recognize  the response need of the IDPs, vulnerable host  population and returnees  with an objective of Protecting , stabilize and safeguard rural and urban livelihoods bridging humanitarian, resilience and development activities and  taking into account  the livelihoods of the affected  population by saving their lives, protecting  and strengthening  their livelihoods  through  increasing their long term resilience  and reduce their vulnerability to future shocks. 
ASCO will engage closely with Nutrition, health and WASH partners to integrate Food security sensitive intervention into other sectors. Food security and livelihood status is compromised where people are exposed to high level of infection due to unsafe and insufficient water supply, limited access to basic healthcare, poor food security and inadequate sanitation.
ASCO will carry out integrated respond by supporting the households within the communities with livelihood kits, dry season response fishing and vegetable kits. ASCO will coordinate with WASH partners on ground to ensure all targeted households follow water treatment and storage, hand washing promotion with soap distribution and hygiene promotion for small stock open defecation free at proximity domiciliary level around the households and the nutrition sites. 
 IASC GBV guidelines is considered as a key protection mainstreaming tool globally and implementation of the guidelines will enhance protection of vulnerable population i.e. girls and women. Women will involve in participation in project design implementation of activities and information sharing to express their views. The project will also increase availability of GBV prevention and response services in Aweil South County where women are suffering from different forms of gender base violence 
Male and female shall be targeted in receiving livelihood kits and knowledge to improve food production. Train farmers to obtain farming skills to improved food Security and Livelihoods.

In terms of health, ASCO will coordinate with partners on ground at households&#x2019; level distributed with livelihood kits to ensure management of medical complications among children with SAM, provision of infant and young child feeding to children with SAM and vaccination of children under 5 on polio and measles and pregnant and lactating mothers. 
In terms of nutrition, based on February IPC report released by food and security cluster, areas affected by conflict people including children under 5 and PLW are severely food insecure and have increased nutritional requirements.  ASCO will integrate by advocating for prevention and treatment of malnutrition to children under the age of 5 and nursing mothers, Provision of nutrition education at nutrition sites, provide micronutrients supplementation to children under 5 and PLW and other vulnerable groups including elderly, HIV/AIDS and TB Patients male and female

ASCO will scale up further the provision of dry season livelihood kits. Fishing kits and vegetable kits to the most severely affected households targeting affected beneficiaries men, women, boys and girls including elderly people and disabled by involving or participating in seed distribution.

Right based approach will be used in selecting the 36000 beneficiaries constitute of Women 12000,Men 6000,Girls 9000 and boys 7000 to undertake different roles and activities of the project.  Local Authorities of Aweil South County will be involved in the identification and selection of beneficiaries. Women shall be given equal opportunity in decision making and group discussion and have equal access or control over assets created and prioritize activities with greater participation in project cycle.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ropani Neema Emosa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance  Admin Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211926332900</telephone>
   <email>ascogroup1@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thomas Mawien Yel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211912565611</telephone>
   <email>mawienthomas@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tom Musekese</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FSL Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211926096957</telephone>
   <email>tomusekese@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU12">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Bahr el Ghazal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.53604490 26.79678490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-08">119766.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-08">58398.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="NA">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-14">74.76</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00077123">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-05">89082.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-9903">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-08">178165.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00078668">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-11">89082.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Support Community Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
