<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-18/HSS10/SA2/NFI/NGO/10056</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A direct intervention to provide immediate life-saving shelter and life-sustaining non-food items to the most vulnerable IDPs in Pibor, Bor South and Uror in Jonglei</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aimed at providing emergency lifesaving shelter and non-food materials in Pibor, Bor South and Uror all in Jonglei, in response to the emergency needs of conflict affected populations within 6 months from the project start date in September. It is anticipated that the assistance provided alleviate the suffering of those in need especially the most vulnerable pregnant and lactating mothers, unaccompanied elderly (60+ years), people with physical disabilities or chronic illness, female-headed households or single parents, unaccompanied minors (under 18 years old) persons with no effective community links, etc by giving them chance to kick-start their livelihood recovery.

These 3 locations (Pibor, Bor South and Uror all in Jonglei) were prioritized by the cluster as having critical needs and have also been confirmed by needs assessments done in these locations.
HDC as a static national NGO in 2 two of these locations will use this project to effectively and efficiently provide life saving shelter and essential non-food items to the most vulnerable. The team will jointly with other organisations or individually assess, verify/register, and deliver assistance according to identified needs of affected populations and appropriate cluster methodologies of response. The team will carefully consider and modify the response to the verified needs on the ground, paying particular attention to the most vulnerable while incorporating specific needs of different groups (women, men, youth and children) into needs assessments and response. This will most importantly strengthen community coping mechanisms and improve their resilience to other shocks that indirectly affect them like the current deteriorating economic situation in the Country.
 
The quality of the project will be strengthened through vigorous AAP initiatives and building of community resilience. This will be done through engaging the recipient community throughout the project cycle guided by HDC Community Engagement Strategy policy document that most of its contents are already embedded in the project programming. Consultative community meetings and first with authorities will precede each activity to help the community shape the nature of assistance, encourage two-way communication and eventually minimise complaints and misunderstandings that usually arise in the process. Community focal points (CFPs) will be selected during the first community meeting and will be engaged more directly in the project as community representation. This group, preferably three, balanced in age, gender and diversity will be sensitized on the selection criteria and important principles of humanitarian response. The team of technical enumerators will also be got from the community to assist in the assessment and quickly trained on the use of smart phone to collect data. The use of smart phones for assessment that HDC is already experienced in will greatly enhance the speed, accuracy and analysis of the data and save on cost.

The key activities done by HDC field staff in the response will start the needs assessment which will involve mobilizing the community for focus group discussions, individual household interviews and observations and/or Key Informant Interviews with the beneficiaries. Once the assessment report is approved, verification of identified needs and subsequent registration of beneficiaries is done which is then followed by distribution of needed life-saving shelter and essential non-food items. During distribution, rapid post distribution monitoring will be conducted by HDC MampE Officer to ensure AAP. Meaningful access to the distribution site will be determined during the community meetings and prior to the exercise. The MampE Officer who also has experience in protection will be able to refer cases related to GBV and also ensure the field staff assisting in the work are sensitized and have got S/NFI GBV and protection mainstreaming guidelines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian and Development Consortium</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian and Development Consortium</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bronson Kiprono</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0926149331</telephone>
   <email>bronson.kiprono@hdcafrica.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peter Deng</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0927339315</telephone>
   <email>peter.deng@hdcafrica.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">William Ngabonziza</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0928330991</telephone>
   <email>william.ngabonziza@hdcafrica.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-17">67222.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-17">32777.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-10056">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-17">100000.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian and Development Consortium</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00076910">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-26">17572.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian and Development Consortium</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00078347">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-26">82428</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian and Development Consortium</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
