<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-EBRD-41158</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-IATI-EBRD" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oyu Tolgoi Mine Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EBRD is part of a project involving the development, construction and  operation of an open pit and underground mine and ore processing facility at  the Oyu Tolgoi copper, gold, silver and molybdenum deposit located in the  southern Gobi region of Mongolia, in the eastern part of Omnogovi aimag in  Khanbogd soum, approximately 220 km from the aimag capital of Dalandzadgad and  45 km southwest of Khanbogd soum centre.  Oyu Tolgoi, one of the world&apos;s largest copper-gold deposits, contains a  currently identified commercial resource (JORC compliant) of almost 40 billion  pounds (Blb) of contained copper and 20 million ounces (Moz) of contained gold  plus further identified reserves of 40 Blb of contained copper and 25 Moz of  contained gold which are in the process of being defined through geological  investigation and modelling.  The project is being developed in phases, with commercial production from a  100,000 tonnes per day (tpd) concentrator (due to start in 2013) to be sourced  initially from the Southern Oyu open pit mine. In parallel, construction is  under way to develop infrastructure at the underground Hugo North deposit. A  dedicated road to the Chinese border will be built to export mine output. Power  is to be sourced initially from China.  The project is expected to have a material positive impact on the economic  development of Mongolia and, at full production, is anticipated to increase  national GDP by 30% by 2020. The fiscal benefits for the country will include  greater tax revenues, as well as royalties and dividends. The project will  adopt best transparency standards through compliance by the project company  with the EITI requirements and serve as an example to other private sector  investors in the Mongolian mining industry.  In addition, the project will act as a catalyst for the development of  supporting infrastructure in the region, including utility services and  transportation, and will contribute to the development of the necessary  vocational skills in the country through the establishment of two vocational  training centres in the South Gobi, and the provision of full financial support  for 3,300 Mongolians to attend technical and vocational education training  schools across the country. .  Employment generation, both directly at the project and indirectly through  the development of a supply chain providing goods and services to it, is  expected to be significant. The project will maintain a greater than 75%  Mongolian workforce for direct mining operations and at least 90% of the  remainder of the workforce will be Mongolian during the operational phase.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-EBRD" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OYU TOLGOI LLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2030-12-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+44 20 7338 7380</telephone>
   <email>projectenquiries@ebrd.com</email>
   <website>www.ebrd.com</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Exchange Square, London, EC2A 2JN</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-id code="2028462" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ULAANBAATAR</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>47.90771  106.88324</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="32210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.1.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">384522951.21</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OYU TOLGOI LLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="50"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.ebrd.com/work-with-us/projects/psd/oyu-tolgoi-.html">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Summary Document - Transition Impact Environmental Social Summary</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.ebrd.com/work-with-us/projects/psd/oyu-tolgoi-.html">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Summary Document</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.ebrd.com/what-we-do/strategies-and-policies.html">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Strategy</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://ecepp.ebrd.com/delta/noticeSearchResults.html">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procurement/Tenders</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A10"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">please refer to the project summary document at https://www.ebrd.com/view/psd/41158</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
