<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-ZIM667</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilient communities, protected landscapes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gokwe North is in semi-arid areas known for low rainfall, usually poorly distributed; climate change has exacerbated the effects of already erratic rain patterns. In 2017, within the MF4 programme, a solar piped water scheme was installed in Gokwe North district, extracting water from a spring on a wetland, providing water to 10 villages in 2 wards. The piped water scheme helped reducing time spent fetching water by women and girls, freeing time to engage in productive socio-economic activities. However, there have been persistent challenges of expansion of agricultural activities and uncontrolled deforestation, livestock grazing and extraction of water through digging wells within and around the wetland. All these challenges are exacerbating the already dire socio-economic, political and governance situation in the community, contributing to environmental degradation. There is anticipated increase in conflicts among the community members due to limited availability of water, and further disempowering women and girls, who are the most marginalised and most exposed to the negative consequences of climate change.  
CAFOD is working jointly with Caritas Gokwe to protect and rehabilitate the wetland through the Holistic Management of Resources approach (funded through the Africa Fund); focussing on wetland regeneration through controlled grazing and water use; the IEPM funds would sustain and expand programme integration, supporting the responses to agricultural-related challenges threatening the wetland. The proposed intervention tackles the problematic linkage between the needs of communities &#x2013; particularly around livelihoods &#x2013; with the commitment towards environmental preservation, using locally led, environmentally adequate solutions. Its focus on the mitigation of the effects of climate change and environmental crisis, at the same time responding the most urgent needs of marginalized communities aligns with the characteristics of the Integral Ecology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM667" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM667" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ZIM667" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">50003</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55840">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-11">50003</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70811">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-03-11">50003</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
