<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-ZIM560</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZCBC Child Safeguarding Policy Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will improve the capacity of existing structures within the Catholic Dioceses of Zimbabwe to implement the newly approved Church&apos;s Child Protection Policy. It will ensure that the Child Protection Policy is implemented in an efficient and effective manner warranting sustainability of the project results. CAFOD&apos;s main deliverable on this project include
1. Providing technical assistance on the simplification of policy and production of products 
This entails input and review of materials produced for the project. CAFOD&#x2019;s Child Protection focal person will participate in the policy review process by inputting to the policy, review of materials produced, as well as taking part of some of the trainings as agreed with ZCBC.
2. Monitoring and Evaluation support 
This will include developing a monitoring framework for the project in consultation and agreement with ZCBC Education Commission, developing TORs for baseline and end line studies in conjunction with the ZCBC Education Commission, and facilitating the conduct of the studies. In addition, CAFOD will support the development of monitoring tools for the project, in line with the agreed monitoring framework and with the input and agreement of ZCBC Education Commission.
In addition, CAFOD will provide support on the design of a KAP survey as well as development of TOR for research questions identified in project implementation.
3. Learning and networking 
CAFOD will support the Education department in promoting cross organisational learning both within Zimbabwe and regionally, through supporting the hosting of learning events, peer visits to relevant organisations.
4. Capacity strengthening support to the Education Department on project and financial management and reporting.
CAFOD will conduct of a Mango Health Check and an agreed capacity development plan in response to the findings of this assessment. CAFOD will provide support on voucher review and financial reporting.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM560" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM560" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ZIM560" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">9302.3255</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="50139">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">9302.3255</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
