<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-ZIM585</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community taking the lead in Ending GBV in Muzarabani Communities- working with St Alberts Mission H</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This  project aims to raise awareness on gender-based violence and influence people&#x2019;s behaviour and attitudes in communities of Muzarabani/Centenary Districts , working with St Alberts Mission Hospital. In addition this project will seek to challenge negative social norms, cultural beliefs, as well as harmful religious practices that perpetuate gender-based violence in Muzarabani/Centenary Districts.

Gender Based Violence continues to be pervasive in Zimbabwean society. It is estimated that at least one in every three women face violence in their lifetime (UNDP 2017). According to the UNDP (2017) gender-based violence is rooted in negative social constructs of gender that are inculcated at a very early age and are often built upon unequal power relations and unjust attitudes leading to violent behaviours. Patriarchy, male dominance, perceptions of masculine moral authority, social privilege are oftentimes used to justify the perpetuation of violence against women and girls. There are clear links between violence against women and girls, the inabilities of women to fulfil their rights, social exclusion and negative health consequences including HIV infection.  Women living in abusive relationships fail to negotiate for safer sex and those that are living with HIV sometimes fail to disclose their status and access essential health services because of fear. Culture and religious beliefs contribute significantly to the perpetuation of such violence. It follows therefore that tackling harmful cultural and religious norms will significantly reduce violence against women and the proportion of women living in such circumstances. In Muzarabani and Centenary districts, gender-based violence takes the forms of early marriage, failure to retain girls in schools as families prioritise boys education, sexual violence and intimate partner violence. 

Communities will be mobilised to speak out about violence as well as identify actions to lower incidences of violence in their communities. The process of challenging deep-rooted mindsets requires the use of multiple approaches as such, the project will assist survivors by providing referral information on available services in the District and Province.

.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM585" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM585" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">St Albert&apos;s Mission Hospital</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ZIM585" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="13040" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-01">32000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="51335">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-02">32000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="65691">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-02">32000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">St Albert&apos;s Mission Hospital</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
