<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-ZIM496</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecumenical Climate Action Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ecumenical Climate Action Project is an incubator Project to support the major church bodies in Zimbabwe to develop an unprecedented mega-consortium on Climate change, attract funding for it and develop the necessary coordination and implementation mechanisms to implement Climate Change initiatives building on the gains of the historic COP21 Agreement. With technical support from CAFOD the four Ecumenical Coordinating Organisations in Zimbabwe (EFZ, UDACIZA, ZCBC and ZCC) representing close to all of the recognised Churches in Zimbabwe and 75% of the population, have come together to collaboratively work on a common climate change agenda preliminary titled Ecumenical Climate Action. The aim of this coming together is to create a unifying platform for Ecumenical bodies to engage on climate change issues through a range of coordinated actions inclusive of mass mobilisation, lobby and advocacy, research, adaptation initiatives etc. Bearing in mind the fact that climate change is by far one of the most urgent crises confronting Zimbabwe today a robust intervention by Church bodies is vital to help ensure that millions of vulnerable Zimbabweans are able to adapt to the negative impacts of climate change and to hold the State accountable for the implementation of the National Climate Change Response Strategy and the fulfillment of its international obligations under various International treaties. In addition the Ecumenical consortium will play an important role to lobby the International community to fulfill longstanding demands by the faith community for the implementation of the Paris Agreement, Lima Work-plan on Gender, Warsaw International Mechanism for Loss and Damage etc; make drastic cuts to emissions; increase funding to help developing countries to take decisive climate action both in terms of mitigation and adaptation; establish clear fixed timelines for achieving gender-responsive climate policy and transfer sound mitigation and adaptation technologies and know-how to developing countries. In light of these challenges and opportunities the Ecumenical Climate Change Project will lay the groundwork for  Church bodies collaborative work on Climate Change by i. convening a high level meeting to review the outcomes of the COP21; ii. developing a fund-able Programme with clear deliverables and an implementation/coordinating structure; iii. mobilise resources through strategic engagements with major back-donors and responses to calls for proposals and iv. strengthen the Zimbabwe faith community&apos;s collaboration with other regional and global networks on Climate Change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM496" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM496" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Catholic Bishops&apos; Conference</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ZIM496" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="23030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-01">10915.4954</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="49729">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">-70.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="48125">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">10985.9154</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="61991">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">6795.77</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Catholic Bishops&apos; Conference</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="62393">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">1690.14</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Catholic Bishops&apos; Conference</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="62392">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">2429.58</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Catholic Bishops&apos; Conference</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
