<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-ZIM454</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated food income and nutrition security for Binga and Hwange districts- CAFOD</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The EC called for proposal that would address food, nutrition and income security for marginalised communities in a sustainable manner. Therefore the Integrated Food, Income and Nutrition security programme was developed as a response to the call for proposal by the EC, Zimbabwe office. This programme will target vulnerable farmers with access to labour and land in the Binga and Hwange districts of Matabeleland North Province of Zimbabwe. Binga and Hwange are two of the most marginalised districts in Zimbabwe, with generalised poverty compounded by external shocks such as droughts. According to the 2010 Nutrition Survey, less than 5% of children in Binga and Hwange between the ages of 6-23 months receive the minimum acceptable diet and 30%-34.9% of children between 6 and 59 months are stunted. The 2012/11 Zimbabwe Demographic Health Survey reported that Matebeleland North has the highest percentage of children that are wasted (at 6%) and underweight (at 14%).The overall objective of this programme is to improve smallholder farmer productivity for food, nutrition and income security. The specific objectives are: 1: to develop and implement diversified and appropriate value chains for small holder farmers; and 2: to increase production and consumption of nutritious foods.  This will be achieved through development and implementation of private sector led value chains for income and food security. Value chains will concentrate on dryland and irrigated agriculture focusing on small grains and oil seeds (sorghum and sesame), horticulture (through irrigation schemes and household gardens) and small livestock (fish, goats and poultry). The action&#x2019;s theory of change is anchored on the fact that facilitating sustainable (private-sector led) access to agricultural inputs and output markets coupled with appropriate extension services will lead to increased production and diversification hence reducing food insecurity and improving nutrition security of the targeted beneficiaries. SNV will be leading the consortium with CAFOD, Environment Africa and Caritas Hwange as co applicants. SNV will lead on activities relating to specific objective 1 whilst CAFOD will lead on activities relating to specific objective 2. Caritas Hwange and Environment Africa will lead activities in Binga and Hwange district respectively.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM454" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM454" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ZIM454" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-01-01">145615.064</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-04-01">108749.6058</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">112705.0847</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="45900">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-31">145615.064</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="47213">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-05-28">108749.6058</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="49188">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">112705.0847</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
