<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-ZIM434</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated WASH Project &#x2013; Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall purpose of this project is to increase access to potable water to marginalized women, men and children of Gokwe North wards 13, 23 and 36. This project will directly target  25453 community members(13235females and 12217males) from 5090 households in the targeted 3 wards
To achieve that the following outcomes will be pursued;
Improved access to clean water &#x2013; To achieve this outcome, the following works are proposed; These are based on the water technical assessment done in Gokwe North and further stakeholder discussions.
Village  Summary of major Works
Tubu
- Rehabilitation of Chiwashira Dam 
- 150 households, comprising 390 women and girls and 360 men and boys will have access to clean water through the installation of slow sand filters.
- 150 people receive training in soil and water conservation.
- Upgrading of one (1) well
- Installation of  solar powered submersible pump, storage tank for drinking water and a livestock drinking trough

Shingayi
- Drilling and equipping one borehole powered)
- Installing of a solar powered pump and 2 storage tanks at Shingayi School.

Mashayanyika 
- Digging of 1(one) deep well besides Kanwa River
- Installing a   solar powered pump  
- Install 2 storage tanks. One for the community and one for the school. Cattle drinking trough will be also be constructed.

Following the establishment of these water points, water point committees will be formed on new and resuscitated on existing sites. These will be local management structures responsible for the operations and maintenance of the water sources. Caretakers and pump minders will be selected and trained on facility maintenance and repair to ensure that water points are at all times functioning.   Multiple water uses including small scale irrigation and cattle watering will be promoted in this project and will result in efficient utilisation of water. Water quality testing, both chemical and bacteriological will be done at all water points before facilities are officially handed over to communities. Caritas Gokwe will provide initial water quality testing consumables and the community will work with the Ministry of health for routine water quality monitoring.   
Improved hygiene practices will be achieved through hygiene promotion activities using the Participatory health and Hygiene Promotion (PHHP) approaches within communities and also Child Hygiene and Sanitation Training at Shingayi and Buno primary schools.  Approximately 14000 people are to be reached by this activity. This will be spearheaded by 100 Village Health Workers and 24 School health teachers who are to be trained. The CHAST approach in schools will include theatre for development training of school children. Theatre for development technique will e used in schools. These two approaches will complement each other to enhance behaviour change amongst the targeted communities. The hygiene behaviours that children learn at school are skills that they are likely to maintain as adults and pass on to their own children.
Hygiene promotions sessions will be held in order build the community and household capacities and understanding around safe hygiene practices. There shall be formation of hygiene clubs at 19 villages and within 12 schools. Information, Education and Communication (IEC) materials will be developed to compliment the hygiene promotion session in schools and communities. The targeted communities will also participate in the WASH commemoration days such as World Water day and Sanitation Week. 
Community Based Management: The functionality of water points and maintenance of water facilities is affected by the ability of communities to manage and maintain them. Weak capacity of communities lead to limited enforcement of rules and accountability leading to neglect of facilities. This calls for community capacity building in operation, maintenance and repairs. The following activities will be undertaken:
A Dam management committee will be established and trained with (50%) representation of women. Three Water Point committees Comprising (WPCs) of 50% women representation will be established and trained in management of water points.  Facility operation and maintenance, fund raising, equity, record keeping and conflict resolution are key training areas. Two (2) pump minders for Shingayi village borehole and 4 facility caretakers for wells will be identified and trained to maintain the facilities. They will be selected through a community participatory process. Training modules will be tailor made in order to mainstream gender, HIV/AIDS and the environment. These are cross cutting issues that have not been seriously considered and yet they are key in enhancing the sustainability of water pints and their facilities. 150 community members will be trained on soil and water conservation.
Women empowerment will be enhanced through ensuring active participation of women and girls in decision making on issues that affect them. This include advocating for over 50% composition in local water decision making bodies such as Ward and  Village development committees, water point committees, ISALs committees and Parish Committees.
Gender mainstreaming will be done through building the capacity of the partner to mainstream gender in programming. A gender audit will be done and through this specific partner and parish development committees   gender training needs will be identified and form the basis for training. There shall be an establishment of a gender mainstreaming policy at partner level as a result of the gender audit
This ensures consideration of special gender needs in all project aspects. If needs for women, men, boys and girls are seriously considered in project design and implementation, the project impact is easily achieved and measured. Gender training will also be cascaded to community leaders such as chiefs, village heads, councillors and other government agencies such as DDF. All the training manuals used in this project will be tailor made to meet needs of women, men, boys and girls.
The project will be implemented in Nembudzia and Tsungai parish that is ward 13, 23, and 36 in Gokwe North. This project is expected to build on lessons and successes recorded under the IPDF Integrated WASH project implemented in the same wards. Among the key lessons learnt from this project is the need to do a thorough technical assessment before implementing a water supply project. In the previous water supply project, boreholes fitted with Type B-Bush pumps were only used as a water supply option and did not yield the desired results as they dried up, leaving communities without safe water options. This experience has taught the importance of using appropriate technologies for water supply as different areas respond differently to different technologies. As a result, This proposed project will use different technologies, depending on the geophysical conditions in each ward. 
The project will be implemented over 18 months for the period August 2013 to January 2015.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM434" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="ZIM434" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ZIM434" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-08-01">163631.87</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="44509">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">91296</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="48479">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">-6.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="45853">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">11695.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="45091">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">14997.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="45395">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">45649</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-1-202669">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="58714">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">45780.29</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="58993">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">28811.46</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="59497">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">814.11</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="59698">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">6558.56</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60066">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">150.6</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60025">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">47085.19</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60077">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">209.94</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60078">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">372.29</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60228">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">0.62</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60229">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">216.22</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60673">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">10327.96</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60672">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">13411.12</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="60671">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-09-10">8532.51</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="61788">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">1326.89</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="61939">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-28">34.1</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Gokwe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
