<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27248417-16045-7850</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27248417" secondary-reporter="0" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua for All</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FINISH Mondial</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">**Improving health outcomes and poverty indicators requires an inclusive approach to sanitation and health.** An approach that strategically uses donor funds with a focus to scale. And which links behaviour change in communities with government leadership as well as business development and finance opportunities. So markets are developed that service base of the pyramid populations, and change sanitation behaviour for good.

To this end, WASTE together with Actiam, TATA-AIG and UNU developed Financial Inclusion Improves Sanitation and Health (FINISH) in India in 2008. Due to its success and its potential scalability, the approach was replicated in Kenya (FINISH INK), where Amref Flying Doctors, representing Amref Health Africa (&#x201C;Amref&#x201D;), joined as partner.

**FINISH aims for sanitation market development for BoP populations.** As a public private partnership it fosters stakeholders from four domains, ie communities, government, business and finance to work together on this objective. So that by the end of the day:

- people know they need a toilet (through health awareness creation)
- people want a toilet (through demand creation)
- people want to buy a durable toilet with safe management of human waste (through sanitation marketing)
- people are ready to utilise safely treated human waste from individual household toilets
- local people can build those (through mason training)
- people can afford those (through financial inclusion and loans, design improvements and economies of scale)
- particularly in India and Bangladesh focus will be on faecal sludge management

**Finish is designed to scale.** It aims to institutionalize new ways of working while unlocking economies of scale. In short it is about B&#x2019;s: Base of the Pyramid, Bottom up, Behaviour Change, Business, and Brokering. As such, it has the potential to transform sanitation sectors where safely managed sanitation is yet to be introduced and where FINISH can contribute to let it become the new normal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guaranteeing sustainability of not only the facility, but more so the service level provided requires rigorous action. Current progress on FIETS sustainability:

- _(F) Financial_ :Financial sustainability activities involved working with financial institutions to mainstream/ include sanitation loans in their portfolios. In addition, we have engaged local financing institutions to reach the &#x2018;bottom of the pyramid&#x2019; population. Loans are issued at the market rates minimizing distortion to the market. The price of toilets is brought down to make them more affordable. This has been found to make lending to the poor viable.
- _(I) Institutional_ :FINISH works in close collaboration with the government in all six countries, as one corner of the diamond. As such it works to embed the FINISH approach within government practice.The programme, in collaboration with the Ministry of Health (Kenya) and the Institute of Capacity Development within Amref, has developed a universal sanitation marketing curriculum. This enables capacity building of sanitation marketers at scale with minimal cost. In Tanzania we are exploring opportunities to integrate WASH related training of artisans and entrepreneur skills at Government Vocational Training Centres. In Uganda will institutionalisation of mason training be through St Joseph / university. In Tanzania we are also in the process of negotiating an MOU with the District government which includes the sustainability clause.
- (E) _Environmental_ We seek to minimize underground water pollution by promoting shallow pits construction. As practically possible, we promote the use of local materials. The adoption of the innovations such us soil stabilised interlocking bricks cuts down on the carbon emission&#x2019;s emanating from kilning, etc. The reuse of treated faecal sludge for agriculture is a cornerstone of the FINISH approach.
- (T) Technical: \_The household improved sanitation systems that are the hallmark of FINISH Mondial are designed to last 20 years. They comprise of three parts: superstructure, meso-structure and substructure. All of these are designed according to norms and standards of the government (India). Furthermore, we are in the process of assisting other governments to set standards. In some countries, our standards implemented will be higher than the government standard.

o The design will always consider the safe disposal of sludge in the design of the toilet.

o In India, FM is developing asystemofrectifyingandrehabilitatingdefunctsanitation

systems. The lessons learned will be transferred and tailored to other countries.

FM also spends much effort on continuousl yreducing the cost of toilets to make them more affordable (therefore, also more financially viable for a larger group of customers). An example of this includes the bricks introduced in Kenya and the hollow

bricks in Ethiopia, which are low cost, environmentally friendly and locally produced. o Our design philosophy further encompasses a couple of innovations which support

optimal functionality and ergonomics.

_(S) Social Sustainability_

We engage with community-based organisational structures and groups. We align our interventions on premises of their social values thereby reducing social disruptions. Our programming appreciates gender equity and has been consistent with equitable involvement of men and women across the programme activities.

Awareness raising of and Sanitation Marketing with community members is working to create a social change in which improved sanitation and hygiene becomes the new norm. As part of the FINISH INK impact evaluation we can see attitude changes that confirm a positive change towards this.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe sanitation and improved health for all by 2030</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The present project aims to:

1. Kick-start and inclusively scale the PPP for sanitation market development in 6 countries: India and Kenya (inclusive scale), Uganda, Ethiopia, Bangladesh, Tanzania (market development).
2. Develop FINISH Mondial PPP with a 2030 horizon to boost scale, including a roadmap for strategic partnership building and multi-annual multi-country financing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27248417" role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua for All</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41172933" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASTE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="7850" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASTE</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valentin Post</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEO</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>vpost@waste.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bink 36 Binckhorstlaan 36, Unit C174 2516 BE Den Haag The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="8"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="25"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="16"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="7"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="34"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.3 38.016667</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.5388381 37.4596409000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.3750813 37.9952144</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.960391 34.7414436</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.0514721 37.6456042</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.6546257 30.2801165999999</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.1271225 78.6568942</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.9128998 79.7399875</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.7514798 75.7138884</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.7184852 89.0704766</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.8467088 80.9461592</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.0238036 74.2179326</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.2590444 84.0180642</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.5460377 40.6346851000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">1435000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-02">900000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">First disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27248417" type="60">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua for All</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-41172933" type="70">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASTE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-19">100000</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27248417" type="60">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua for All</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-41172933" type="70">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASTE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">400000</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27248417" type="60">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aqua for All</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-41172933" type="70">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASTE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/7850/2013_WASH_075kleiner.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household sanitation financing</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household sanitation financing can be done through self- finance (savings), government financing (see result 3) and through loans.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value of sanitation financing by own- means (savings)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value invested in sanitation systems by the households themselves</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value of household sanitation through loans</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value of loans issued by (M)FI&apos;s, Sacco&apos;s for sanitation system construction</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanitation systems built</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved sanitation systems is described as a system where the human doesn&apos;t come in contact with excreta</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of improved sanitation systems built</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beneficiaries reached with sanitation systems, health awareness and training</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached with sanitation systems, health awareness campaigns and mason training on sanitation technology</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number maisons trained on sanitation technology</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of beneficiaries reached with improved sanitation systems</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached with sanitation and hygiene awareness campaigns</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government investment in sanitation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value of investments done for sanitation by (local/regional/national) governments on sanitation in the countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value of total investments in EUR</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government partnerships</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partnerships established with (local)governments</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of businesses supported in the service chain</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of businesses supported in the value chain</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
