<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1122330-Enhanced TCFD-aligned transparency for an economically and environmentally resilient financial system in Brazil</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1122330" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDP Worldwide</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced TCFD-aligned transparency for an economically and environmentally resilient financial system in Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to catalyze systemic and transformational change with key Brazilian listed companies as well as banks, investors and insurers, and build knowledge and leverage of policy and regulatory authorities, leading to reduced GHG emissions and reduced pressure on deforestation on main biomes of Brazil. 
The outputs are a blend of deliverables that support the increase in awareness levels among target groups through a suite of research papers and publications. This approach intends to reach as broad a group of possible among target groups and create momentum around the opportunities and business case for the adoption of new ways of working, new policies and approaches. In parallel, targeted work is undertaken with a subset of the target groups, through online and face to face encounters (webinars, workshops, roundtables). This is aimed at improving knowledge among the target groups. 
Thus, in 2021 (and beyond) project is expected to contribute to 
Outcome 1: Corporates and financial institutions (FIs) in Brazil motivated and capacitated to integrate climate and deforestation-related risks and opportunities in governance and financial decision and undertake disclosure aligned to the Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD) thereby informing and facilitating the shift of capital towards a greener recovery. 
Outcome 2: Enhanced capacity of corporate and FI actors to measure and report climate and deforestation risks aligned with global TCFD recommendations and become leaders on environmental transparency and action contributing to a sustainable recovery. 
Outcome 3: Enhanced understanding of key banking, regulatory and policy players at national and sub national levels of climate and deforestation risks, and the impact and opportunities of TCFD-aligned disclosure</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1122330" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDP Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-30">380000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Quarter 2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">139943</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 2 Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="Quarter 1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">27823</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter One Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
