<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-19/3884/SA2/P/INGO/13886</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Response and Prevention of Gender Based Violence in conflict-affected areas in Kirkuk and Ninewa governorates, Iraq</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRW is currently implementing two GBV (Gender based violence) projects in Baghdad, Anbar and Kirkuk to provide confidential GBV case management, psychosocial support, awareness raising and counselling through survivor centred approach from a women exclusive space center (WSC). During the four years of UNFPA funded project in Kirkuk, IRW has been managing to provide in and out of camps specialized GBV services through 14 WSCs whereas in third year of GAC (government affairs Canada) funded project Islamic Relief is providing specialized GBV services through establishment of 12 WSCs for the vulnerable women of girls in Baghdad and Anbar. 
AlMesalla (NNGO), implementation partner of IRW is currently managing 7 WSCs in East Mosul with a specialized team on GBV case management.

To contribute to the priorities and unmet needs of the GBV sector in Iraq, the project is in line with the SDG # 3: Good (mental) health and well-being and SDG # 4: Gender equality with exclusively focusing on vulnerable IDPs women and girls in 3 locations  1 camp and 2 out of camps in Ninewa and Kirkuk.. 
The ten months project aims to address the gaps highlighted in 2019 Humanitarian Needs Overview, GBVIMS data (Jan &#x2013; Jun 2019), GBV Sub cluster and coordination with other GBV actors. Through this project IRW will lead the consortium and will technically advise Almesalla to support vulnerable women and girls and persons with specific needs. 

These ten months intervention will support GBV survivors by providing specialized GBV case management, PSS and recreational activities through Women exclusive Space Centres (WSCs). The project will ensure capacity development of field staff to ensure quality of services. The project will also work with women and girls and develop community-based circles of support to enhance resilience and minimize the risks of further harm. To cope with the trauma, isolation and stigmatization, the project will raise awareness by organizing structured interactive activities. This survivor cantered approach and activities will facilitate women and girls to cope with the psychological trauma and emotional stress they have gone through. And from the findings of our GBV programming in other governorates, females shared that having a women exclusive space give them relief and confidence on ourselves. This intervention further supports them to develop community-based circles of support that can facilitate each other, enhance their resilience and also serve as an exit strategy. 

Female health and hygiene are one of the concerns and needs of the female communities. To facilitate further and project will contribute to improve reproductive health of adolescent girls and women through health and hygiene awareness sessions along with dignity kits. This will not only help adolescent girls and women for the time being but also will make them aware of health and hygiene management. Hence, this activity will contribute to change behavior of the communities for better health and hygiene management especially adolescent girls. 

GBV prevention is about addressing the root causes of violence and discrimination. To address the causes, the project is aiming to involve different segments of society to holistically contribute for the prevention of gender-based violence, exploitation and abuse. Considering the context, project will engage men, boys, and ethnic and faith leaders at different levels of project implementation. Project will establish or strengthen male networks and sensitize them around FGM, early marriages and girls&#x2019; education. Project will also work with ethnic and faith leaders (both male and female) to advocate for the girls&#x2019; education, early/forced marriages, FGM and other related issues</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Mesalla</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HIRQ19-15-154635-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akram Sadeq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>07512484278</telephone>
   <email>akram.sadeq@irworldwide.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G013">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kirkuk</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.46670000 44.31670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HIRQ19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">58226.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">233546.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">58226.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-13886">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">350000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304240138">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-02">210000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
