<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-19/3884/SA1/E-P/INGO/11351</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education in emergency and child protection integrated intervention in support of children affected by conflict in Iraq</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The twelve months project aims to provide children and adolescents affected by the conflict access to safe and protective learning spaces inclusive of psycho-social activities.Based on the program experience at the local level and strong coordination with government, Department of Education (DoE) , UN agencies, and Education Cluster, the consortium (composed of INTERSOS as lead and Islamic Relief Worldwide (IRW)) will ensure safe access to quality education and protective learning environment for school aged (4-17) boys and girls in camps setting, including the provision of specialized services of child protection for the most vulnerable IDPs and returnees boys and girls in and out of camp settings.INTERSOS and IRW education interventions will continue to go hand-in-hand with the child protection (CP) ones. INTERSOS and IRW will intervene in camp setting with their own structured Temporary Learning Spaces (TLSs) in Qayarra Air-strip camp, Salamya 1amp2, Nimrood, enlarging the action to Haj Ali camp. IRW intervention will be a continuation of the one ended on 30th October 2018 in Air-strip camp, in the already established TLSs.In coordination with the education cluster, IRW will continue in providing non-formal education (NFE) to the children in the targeted area, mobilizing the same teachers, and (when needed) identifying others with a special focus on female ones among the families in the camp.The established TLSs has been provided with students&#x2019; and teachers&#x2019; kits, recreational kits, and schools box which will be used also for the proposed project while needed required additional supplies and maintenance of the caravans and tents will be provided under this allocation.The project team will also continue working with the formed community education council to raise awareness among parents/ caregivers on providing good parenting, emotional support, and basic child protection concepts.
In order to run the activities in Haj Ali,INTERSOS will capitalize on existing TLS and/ or tents available inside the camp, thanks to the coordination with other educational actors and camp management. Support to formal schools will be provided including a number of formal schools&#x2019;  teachers in the training in held in the camps.In order to ensure a future re enrollment of children in formal schools,INTERSOS will continue on supporting NFE services, improving interaction and complementary with the formal system in coordination with other NGOs and e government structures also in Nimrod, Salamiya 1amp2.The proposed intervention ensures the targeted conflict-affected children IDPs in camps are guaranteed with access to quality education, by building the capacities of teachers and PTA members, providing learning material, delivering NFE, and mainstreaming PSS and CP through awareness raising and parenting programs targeting the communities. In the retaken areas, along with the implementation of awareness campaigns targeting community members have its main focus on returnees and vulnerable children from the host communities promoting, CP case management and structured PSS. INTERSOS is already operating in Tel Afar with an integrated education-CP project IRAQ/11267/05 supporting 8 formal schools. Using the premises of one of the schools targeted, this action will extend the activities engaging a broader target of out of school boys and girls. A community-based approach is followed throughout the action ensuring the participation of teachers, parents, community representatives and children in the design of the activities and in the implementation&#x2019;s phase. The intervention targets school-aged children with a focus on extremely vulnerable girls and boys.Thanks to the cooperation with the(DoE) , the children with more difficulties in catching up with the curriculum will be referred to the TLS. The holistic approach followed throughout the action will allow the children to receive also emotional support enhancing their well-being.OPS: HIRQ19-PRO-CPNEDU-</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Islamic Relief Worldwide</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HIRQ19-3;14-154641-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marta Stermieri</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 773 695 0619</telephone>
   <email>programme.coordinator.iraq@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="75" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HIRQ19" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq 2019</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-09">1099999.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-11351">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-09">1099999.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303793519">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-24">879999.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304540256">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-19">185640.78</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
