<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5103004701-AWE-33110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIS (Swedish Standards Institute), ECOWAS/ARSO, 2015-2017, standardisation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">SIS (Swedish Standards Institute), ECOWAS/ARSO, 2015-2017, standardisation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standards and standardisation can be used as a tool for supporting a more sustainabledevelopment and to promote trade opportunities.&#xA0;The aim of this contribution was to improve stakeholder driven standardisation processes within the ECOWAS region, leading to increased use and harmonisation of ECOWAS and ARSO standards. Enhanced knowledge and experience on regional and international standard setting processes among national standardization bodies (NSB) and other involved stakeholders in the ECOWAS region, leading to enhanced capacity and involvement of ECOWAS stakeholders in both ARSO- and ISO standard setting processes as well as more regional collaboration on standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den svenska standardiseringsorganisationen SIS har ans&#xF6;kt till den regionala sektionen vid Ambassaden i Addis Ababa om 7 050 000 SEK under perioden augusti 2015 till augusti 2017 f&#xF6;r ett projekt som syftar till kapacitetsuppbyggnad i internationell standardisering i ECOWAS-regionen genom ett gemensam insats av den Afrikanska regionala standardiseringsorganisationen (ARSO), den regionala ekonomiska gemenskapen f&#xF6;r v&#xE4;stra Afrika (ECOWAS) och den svenska standardiseringsorganisationen (SIS). 

Genom projektet ska ECOWAS-regionens inflytande &#xF6;ver och anv&#xE4;ndande av ISO- och ARSO-systemen &#xF6;ka. Detta ska uppn&#xE5;s genom att en eller tv&#xE5; p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende standardiseringsprocesser i ISO v&#xE4;ljs ut som fallstudier runt vilka kapacitetsuppbyggnad sker. Arbetet med dessa standardiseringsprocesser i ISO kommer &#xE4;ven att l&#xE4;nkas till liknande p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende arbete i n&#xE5;gon av ARSO:s 13 s.k. Tekniska Harmoniseringskommitteer liksom till p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende harmoniseringsarbete av standarder inom ECOWAS. Fallstudierna ska ligga till grund f&#xF6;r att identifiera arbete med att involvera relevanta intressenter (fr&#xE4;mst fr&#xE5;n den privata sektorn, universitet och h&#xF6;gskolor, frivilligorganisationer, statliga organ samt standardiseringsorgan), &#xF6;kat engagemang av ECOWAS-l&#xE4;nderna i ISO samt synkronisering av de nationella, regionala och internationella standardiseringsagendorna.

Projektet &#xE4;r kort och f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s endast l&#xF6;pa under ca en tv&#xE5;-&#xE5;rsperiod f&#xF6;r att testa samarbetet mellan de tre ansvariga organisationerna och mellan dem och regionen. Tidigare erfarenhet har dock visat att &#xE4;ven ett korttidsprojekt som involverar en hel region kan vara avg&#xF6;rande genom att leda till en &#xF6;kad medvetenhet som i sin tur leder till positiva f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar, b&#xE5;de f&#xF6;r l&#xE4;nder som redan &#xE4;r fullv&#xE4;rdiga ISO-medlemmar och f&#xF6;r de som inte &#xE4;r det.

Projektets totala budget &#xE4;r 7 050 000 SEK och parterna har beg&#xE4;rt att den regionala sektionen vid Ambassaden i Addis Ababa st&#xE5;r f&#xF6;r helheten. ECOWAS Kommission och ARSO Sekretariatet, liksom de nationella standardinseringsorganen i regionen kommer dock att bidra med medarbetares tid och engagemang.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Swedish Standardization Body SIS has applied to the Regional Section of the Swedish Embassy in Addis Ababa for funding of 7 050 000 SEK to carry out a project aimed at capacity building in international standardisation in the ECOWAS Region through a joint effort by the African Regional Organisation for Standardisation, ARSO, the Economic Community of West African States, ECOWAS and the Swedish Standarisation Institute, SIS. The project shall enhance the ECOWAS region&apos;s influence and use of the ISO and ARSO systems. 

This will be achieved through the selection of one or two ISO standardisation processes as case studies around which the capacity strengthening will be built. Work on the standardisation processes in ISO will also be linked up with one of the 13 ARSO Technical Harmonisation Committees (THC) that relates to the specific ISO process/es, as well as with the harmonisation work on standards within ECOWAS. The cases will also serve as basis for identifying action on issues such as involvement of stakeholders (primarily the private sector, academia, NGOs, governmental agencies and national standardisation bodies), further involvement in the ISO system, as well as synchronizing national, regional and international standardisation agendas.

It is a short-term project proposed to run over a two-year period to test the collaboration between the three responsible organisations and between them and the region. However, previous experience has shown that by involving a region jointly in this area, even shorter-term actions can prove crucial in increasing awareness and that the exposure can lead to tangible, positive changes both for those countries that are already involved in international standardisation and those that are not.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 7 050 000 million SEK, and SIS has requested the Regional Section of the Swedish Embassy in Addis Ababa to cover the totality. In addition, the ECOWAS Commission and the ARSO Secretariat as well ECOWAS Member States will contribute with staff time and engagement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIS/Swedish Standards Institute/Svenska institutet f&#xF6;r standarder</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SIS/Swedish Standards Institute/Svenska institutet f&#xF6;r standarder</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Western Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">208623.0351194998</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">344509.4185094185</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">174095.5537144435</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">208622.9182492842</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">344509.4185094187</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">174095.5537144436</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-01">740579.288908</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">208622.976684392</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-28">153359.8338598339</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">191149.6431496431</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">174095.5537144435</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aimed to contribute to vital and sustainable, local and regional, standardization processes with broad involvement from the private and public sectors, as well as from civil society, in order to build the capacity necessary to influence the content of international standards.
The Swedish Standards Institute (SIS), the ECOWAS Commission, and the African Organization for Standardisation (ARSO) picked two ongoing standardization-setting processes of the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) as case studies. The was to&#xA0;provide the National Standardization Bodies (NSBs) of the&#xA0;ECOWAS countries with knowledge about standard processes, about standard-setting in general, and about how to influence ISO- and ARSO-standards from a national and regional perspective.&#xA0;
The project was managed in close collaboration with the&#xA0;ECOWAS Secretariat in Abuja, Nigeria and ARSO, African Regional Standards Organization, in Nairobi, Kenya.&#xA0;A key to success of the project was close collaboration between SIS,&#xA0;ECOWAS&#xA0;and ARSO&#xA0;and two coordinators&#xA0;were hired to be based on ECOWAS-&#xA0;and&#xA0;ARSO-&#xA0;Secretariats respectively to strengthen&#xA0;the project and increase ownership.&#xA0;
The project commenced with an inception phase of six months (June-November 2016) and continued with a 13 months implementation phase. Despite the short implementation period, the project has contributed to influencing and highlighting the need for the NSBs in the ECOWAS region to increase their active participation in standard development.&#xA0;By and large, the project has made a positive contribution to the ECOWAS region in terms of building capacity for national and regional standardisation. For example through contributing to strengthening individuals and organizations capacity in standard development; facilitating and support regional harmonization of standards in the region; and support to the countries through ARSO/ISO sponsorship to participate in ARSO/ISO meetings allowing the region to influence the standardisation processes and affect the standards per se.&#xA0;
Some examples of activities&#xA0;are that two regional capacity building activities, sponsorships to five different ARSO/ISO meetings (1 ISO and 4 ARSO) and three online sessions have been conducted during the project lifetime.&#xA0;The two selected&#xA0;standardisation processes as case studies to increase the capacity on how to engage and contribute to standard development were ISO/TC 34 (ARSO THC 02) on Food and Agriculture and ISO/TC 59(ARSO THC 03) on Building and Construction. More than 100 individuals have participated in workshops and trainings. The project led to increased number of approved ARSO/ISO sponsored delegates as well as number of different ARSO/ISO meetings attended. Moreover, increased participation by experts /stakeholders representing private/public sectors in the ECOWAS region was a result of this project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51030047" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
