<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Gateway Projects Co.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is to develop, construct and operate an industrial estate covering about 65 ha (of which about 50 ha would be in Jordan) at the Jordan-Israel border (the project). The project will be developed in three phases.  Phase I of the project will involve: (i) land and infrastructure development of a 50 ha area on the Jordanian side, and (ii) construction of 94,000 m&#xB2; of buildings, offices and factories for rent, on the Jordanian side, which are proposed to be partially financed by IFC. In addition, Phase I will include land and infrastructure development of 5 ha area on the Israeli side, and construction of a 700 m long bridge across the Jordan River, connecting the Jordanian and the Israeli sides of the estate, which will be funded by the Israeli sponsors under a separate legal entity. In the second and third phases, additional 105,000 and 97,000 m&#xB2; will respectively be developed on the Jordanian side.  The implementation of subsequent phases, which are not IFC financed, will proceed in accordance with tenant demand, cash flow generation and project finance availability.    The project will generate significan  t   development impact   a  s follows:     - The project will facilitate creation of up to 15,000 skilled and semi-skilled jobs in Jordan where the unemployment rate is approximately 25%.     - The project will attract foreign investment from Israel, Europe, the U.S. and Asia and stimulate development of export-oriented industries.   - The project will host hi-tech and other high value added industries, that would provide opportunities for technology transfer and improved utilization of Jordan&apos;&apos;s skilled and educated workforce.     - The project will broaden the JRVs economic base and stimulate planned development of the JRV, as it is part of an integrated plan which includes provision of housing, education and training centers, development of complementary enterprises, and raising the standard of living of the population of the JRV.    - The project will assist community development in the health and education sectors, and has attracted a major medical research institute (the King Hussein Research Center), affiliated with the world-renowned Sloan Kettering Medical Center.    - The project can potentially broaden Jordan-Israeli economic cooperation and contribute to peace between the two countries. If successful, the project will create a demonstration effect that may stimulate other similar projects in the pegion.    IFCs role   in the proje  ct is as follows:     - IFC has helped the sponsors structure the project and limit the scope to a reasonable level in Phase I, instead of pursuing open-ended development.    - Given the project&apos;&apos;s political dimension involving Jordan and Israel, IFC has served as a third-party facilitator.    - IFC will help complete the financial plan through its own funds, and to the extent possible, mobilize funds from other investors, who, given the political risk, are unlikely to support the project without IFCs presence.    - IFCs involvement has ensured that best environmental and social practices are followed. This includes changes in the project design as recommended in the Environmental and Social Assessment (ESIA) Reports, such as a different Israeli site, a different bridge design and careful planning of the estate area, so that the development impact of the project could be maximized. Due to IFCs involvement, an ESIA for a Jordanian project has been prepared and publicly released for the first time in the country.    - Finally, IFCs involvement in the project will provide comfort to potential international and regional tenants given the unstable political situation in the region and help mitigate political risk perceived by potential tenants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Gateway Project</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10112" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-06-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-09-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Yousef Dajani, General Manager, Jordan Gateway Projects Company, Jordan   P.O. Box 251, Amman 11118, Jordan   Fax: 962-6-568 6293   Phone: 962-6-568 6294    Mr. Gili Dekel, General Manager, Jordan Gateway Projects Company, Israel   7, Aba Hilel Silver St., Ramat Gan, 552522, Tel Aviv, Israel   Fax: 972-3-575-8137   Phone: 972-3-575-7707</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="JO-Jordan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is located at the Israeli-Jordanian border along the Jordan River, about 70 km north west from Amman and 40 km west of Irbid, Jordan&apos;&apos;s second largest city with a significant industrial base.  The site occupies agriculturally unproductive land in the otherwise fertile Jordan river valley. The project land on the Jordanian side, owned by the Jordan Valley Authority - JVA (which is governed by the Jordanian Ministry of Water and Irrigation) has been designated as industrial by the JVA. On the Israeli side, the land is an unused area surrounded by agricultural land.  The project site area is about 45 km by road from the Israeli port of Haifa.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.0000000000 36.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Construction and Real Estate</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $10.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2001-06-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-06-18">10000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2001-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2001-06-18">10000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Gateway Project</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10112/jordan-gateway-projects-co">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
