<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26760</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KEC Jordan Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following a transparent bid process, Kingdom Electricity Company (KEC), a consortium of investors from the Arabian Gulf countries and Jordan, was selected as the preferred bidder for the acquisition of the Government of Jordans (GoJ) stake in the Electricity Distribution Company (EDCO), covering the East and South of Jordan and the Jordan Valley area, and the Irbid District Electricity Company (IDECO), covering the North of Jordan. KECs bid valued the acquisition of both companies (100% of EDCO and 55.4% of IDECO) at about $104 million. While there were bids by local and regional investors to acquire IDECO, KEC was the only bidder for EDCO and offered the most attractive proposal overall.  KEC is finalizing the transaction and has approached IFC for funding a portion of the acquisition cost, CAPEX and Working Capital with long term debt.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will facilitate the complete privatization of the electricity distribution sub-sector in Jordan by selling the government stake in two Jordanian power distribution companies, thereby significantly contributing to the sectors liberalization and efficient management.  One of the main development impacts of the project is the expected positive demonstration effect as the project will demonstrate the feasibility of electricity distribution sector privatization and increase the attractiveness to foreign investment in the MENA region.  The Jordanian electricity sector may set an example for other countries in the region that are considering embarking on the liberalization and privatization of their own power sectors. Another major positive impact for the Jordanian Government will be the privatization proceeds and the permanent transfer of the burden of investment in power distribution to the private sector.  This will enhance fiscal sustainability and enable GoJ to focus its scarce resources to other priority sectors.  Additional investments into better and more modern equipment as well the management of the distribution sub-sector by specialized private sector companies should also improve the quality of service to the end users in terms of availability, power quality as well as customer service. Moreover, it is also expected that the private sector management will reduce losses and thus cascade the impact of this reduction in minimizing the consumption of fossil fuels and reduce tariff implication of losses on the Jordanian economy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KINGDOM ELECTRICITY COMPANY PSC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26760" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-03-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-04-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saad A. Abu-Odeh Kingdom Electricity Co. P.O. Box 852101    Telephone: +962 6 5922 900 Fax: +962 6 5922 940 E-mail:    saa@jdc.jo    Website:    http://www.jdc.jo</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="JO-Jordan">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Electricity Distribution Company (EDCO) is headquartered in Amman. It currently owns and operates the distribution network in the Southern and Eastern areas of Jordan, a very sparsely populated area of 69,000 sq km. It serves approximately 155,000 consumers. The Irbid Electricity Distribution Company (IDECO) is headquartered in Irbid and owns and operates the electricity distribution network in the northern part of Jordan covering approximately 23,000 sq km, distributing electricity to 283,000 consumers.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.0000000000 36.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA - Distribution Business</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $40.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-03-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-03-26">40000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-03-26">40000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KINGDOM ELECTRICITY COMPANY PSC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26760/kec-jordan-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
