<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="32" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17506" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-WL-LB-14-17506</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quality Instruction Towards Access and Basic Education Improvement</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nearly two-thirds of students in Lebanon attend private schools, which often provide a higher-quality education than public schools, creating a gap between those who can and cannot afford a private education. The new United States Agency for International Development&#x2019;s nationally focused Quality Instruction Towards Access and Basic Education Improvement (QITABI) aims to expand equitable access and improve learning outcomes for vulnerable students in Lebanese public schools.

Running from September 2014 to September 2018, QITABI is a $41.2 million, four-year project that will improve both access and learning outcomes in primary schools, and support institutional upgrades across the sector. QITABI also aims to improve learning outcomes, particularly in reading at the primary level. Better management and higher instructional standards will be institutionalized and become more sustainable. Improved facilities, services, and teaching&#x2014;along with more effectively engaged communities and school councils&#x2014;will not only improve learning but also increase the chances of youth remaining in the formal education system.

The project provides technical assistance and capacity building within the context of three project components:

1) Improving reading outcomes for primary level public school students.

QITABI will institute the use of an early grade assessment to evaluate the reading skills of young learners in 320 primary schools, establish an early warning system for struggling readers, and train primary teachers in early grade reading instruction. The project will also provide technical assistance to the Ministry of Education and Higher Education (MEHE) and Center for Educational and Research and Development (CERD) in the dissemination of early grade educational materials.

2) Expanding access to safe and relevant education for vulnerable public school students.

Under this component, 450 crisis-affected schools will receive new and additional seating and other amenities in order to mitigate tensions from overcrowding. QITABI will strengthen school-based monitoring and management by providing schools with grants so schools are able to organize and support community-based efforts that improve public school education. Working closely with the ministry, QITABI will also partner with local and community organizations to provide non-formal education opportunities to vulnerable students.

3) Strengthening management (resilience) in the education system to better direct and monitor education.

The project will support the relevant departments within the Ministry of Education to develop policies and systems to support reforms that contribute to the management and implementation of the first two interventions.

The project is implemented by World Learning in partnership with Management Systems International, Ana Aqra&#x2019; and AMIDEAST.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">America-Mideast Educational and Training Services (AMIDEAST)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ana Aqra&apos;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Management Systems International (MSI Worldwide)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-03-0179592" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Learning</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="WL-LB-14-17506" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Learning</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>Rajani.Shrestha@worldlearning.org</email>
   <website>http://www.worldlearning.org/</website>
   <website>http://www.worldlearning.org/what-we-do/quality-instruction-towards-access-and-basic-education-improvement/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.worldlearning.org/what-we-do/quality-instruction-towards-access-and-basic-education-improvement/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
