<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="32" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/17490" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-WL-XX-15-17490</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global UGRAD</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Global Undergraduate Exchange Program (Global UGRAD) is sponsored by the U.S. Department of State&#x2019;s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs (ECA). This international educational and cultural exchange program brings future leaders to the United States to experience the U.S. educational system, enhance their knowledge, and explore U.S. culture and values. It also affords students the opportunity to share their cultures and traditions with people in the United States. Global UGRAD is administered by World Learning on behalf of ECA.

Global UGRAD will provide a select group of approximately 250 students with scholarships for one academic semester of undergraduate, non-degree study in the United States. The scholarship will cover international travel, tuition, room and board, accident/sickness insurance, a small monthly stipend, and funding for books. Global UGRAD is a substantive exchange program designed to expose students to the U.S. educational system, society, and culture. Finalists represent diverse disciplines, from architecture to engineering, biochemistry to literature and education.  A small number of students will also receive additional English language training in the US prior to the start of their academic program. Students will live in university dormitories and will have the opportunity to participate in campus organizations and activities. All students are required to participate in volunteer community service activities and are encouraged to participate in professional development activities as part of the Global UGRAD Program. Exposure to U.S. civil society, as well as the cultural and ethnic diversity of the United States, gives the participants a strong example of tolerance in a democratic society.

Since 2008, World Learning has placed and monitored over 1,800 Global UGRAD students at over 75 colleges and universities, including Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic Serving Institutions, and women&apos;s colleges. Participants leave the United States with the tools to become leaders in their professions and communities. Global UGRAD alumni go on to receive Fulbright grants, obtain prestigious international internships, and work in business and government in their home countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of State</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-03-0179592" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Learning</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="WL-XX-15-17490" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Learning</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>academicexchange@worldlearning.org</email>
   <website>http://www.worldlearning.org/</website>
   <website>http://www.worldlearning.org/what-we-do/global-ugrad/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.worldlearning.org/what-we-do/global-ugrad/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
