<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118013201-UGA-22040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pulse Lab Kampala - Collecting radio Data Phase 2</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Pulse Lab Kampala - Collecting radio Data Phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main outcome of this project is to expand the scope of innovative sentiment analysis in Uganda by putting the voices of the people at the centre of the development processes. The project aims at mining FM stations discussions and news and analysing and communicating the results with the intent of improving development planning and service delivery to the communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen syftar till att st&#xF6;dja Pulse Lab Kampala (PLK) som &#xE4;r en del av UN Global Pulse, ett global intiativ lanserad av FNs Generalsekretare 2009 med syftet att &#xF6;ka anv&#xE4;ndningen av big data som underlag f&#xF6;r beslut inom bist&#xE5;nd och utveckling. Med big data menas information som genereras i realtid fr&#xE5;n exempelvis mobiltelefontrafik, internet och sociala medier. Med hj&#xE4;lp av analyser av informationen &#xF6;kar m&#xF6;jligheten att snabbt fatta informerade beslut om olika utvecklingsinitiativ. UN Global Pulse har hittills arbetat med att generera data fr&#xE5;n anv&#xE4;nding av mobiltelefoner och sociala medier som Facebook och Twitter. &#xC4;ven om mobiln&#xE4;t och tillg&#xE5;ng till internet &#xF6;kar snabbt i Afrika s&#xE5; &#xE4;r radio fortfarande den mest anv&#xE4;nda formen av media p&#xE5; kontinenten. D&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r har nu Pulse Lab Kampala tagit initiativ till att, f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rsta g&#xE5;ngen n&#xE5;gonsin, generera data fr&#xE5;n radios&#xE4;ndningar. Insatsen kommer att resultera i en plattform och teknik f&#xF6;r insamling och &#xF6;vers&#xE4;ttning av data fr&#xE5;n radios&#xE4;ndningar, vilket i sin tur g&#xF6;r det m&#xF6;jligt att i realtid sammanst&#xE4;lla vad som upplevs som mest angel&#xE4;get f&#xF6;r medborgare runtom i landet. Informationen kommer att klustras utifr&#xE5;n centrala teman b&#xE5;de f&#xF6;r det svenska bist&#xE5;ndet och allm&#xE4;nt f&#xF6;r utvecklingen i landet vad g&#xE4;ller j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet, sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld. Inledningsvis kommer data att samlas in p&#xE5; de tre st&#xF6;rsta spr&#xE5;ken; engelska, buganda och acholi. 

Genom insatsen kommer det att bli m&#xF6;jligt att fatta mer informerade beslut om olika utvecklingsinitiativ med medborgarnas egna prioriteringar som grund. N&#xE4;r plattformen v&#xE4;l &#xE4;r framtagen kan den anv&#xE4;ndas av flera l&#xE4;nder och efterfr&#xE5;gan fr&#xE5;n framf&#xF6;rallt afrikanska l&#xE4;nder, d&#xE4;r radio fortfarande &#xE4;r den dominerande formen av media. Det svenska st&#xF6;det kanaliseras genom Resident Coordinators kontor p&#xE5; UNDP i Uganda. F&#xF6;rutom UNDP och UN Global Pulse &#xE4;r Makerere, Edinburgh och Stellenbosch universitet, som tidigare har erfarenhet av &#xF6;vers&#xE4;ttning fr&#xE5;n tal till skrift, involverade i genomf&#xF6;randet. 

Den f&#xF6;rsta fasen fokuserade p&#xE5; att utveckla &#x201D;radioverktygen inom gruvindustrin&#x201D; som f&#xE5;ngar tal i tre spr&#xE5;k, att utveckla en spr&#xE5;kmodell, samt att utveckla ett lexikon som automatiskt transkriberar uppf&#xE5;ngade diskussioner i tal p&#xE5; ugandisk engelska, luganda och acholi till engelsk text f&#xF6;r analys och rapportering.   

Fokus f&#xF6;r projektets andra fas ligger p&#xE5; att ut&#xF6;ka radioinspelningarna till fler distrikt och samtidigt st&#xE4;rka analysen av det inneh&#xE5;ll som spelas in. En kommer ocks&#xE5; att engagera strategiska partners f&#xF6;r att l&#xF6;sa ut fr&#xE5;gor kring upphovsr&#xE4;tt och k&#xE4;llskydd.

Det svenska bidraget uppg&#xE5;r till 2 685 000 kronor under 2016.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action aims to support Pulse Lab Kampala (PLK), which is part of the UN Global Pulse, a global initiative launched by the UN Secretary General in 2009 with the aim of increasing the use of big data as a basis for decisions in aid and development. With big data means information generated in real time from, for example, mobile phone service, internet and social media. With the help of analyzes of information increases the ability to quickly make informed decisions about various development initiatives. UN Global Pulse has so far worked to generate data from the use of mobile phones and social media like Facebook and Twitter. 

Although mobile networks and internet access is growing rapidly in Africa, radio is still the most used form of media on the continent. Therefore, now the Pulse Lab Kampala taken the initiative, for the first time ever, generating data from radio broadcasts. The initiative will result in a platform and technology for the collection and translation of data from radio broadcasts, which in turn enables the real-time compiling what is perceived as the most specify the position of citizens around the country. The information will be clustered based on central themes both for Swedish assistance and general development in the country in terms of gender equality, sexual and reproductive health and gender-based violence. Initially, data will be collected on the three main languages; English, Luganda and Acholi.

Through the initiative, it will be possible to make more informed decisions about various development initiatives by citizens&apos; own priorities as a basis. When the platform is well designed it can be used by several countries and demand, particularly from African countries, where radio is still the dominant form of media. Swedish aid is channelled through the Resident Coordinators office of the UNDP in Uganda. Besides UNDP and UN Global Pulse is Makerere, Edinburgh and Stellenbosch University, who previously have experience in translation from speech to writing, involved in the implementation.

The focus of the second phase is to expand radio recordings to more districts and at the same time strengthen the analysis of the content that is recorded. One will also engage strategic partners to resolve the issues surrounding copyright and source protection.

The Swedish contribution amounts to 2.685 million SEK over in 2016.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="220" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communications</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="22040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Information and communication technology (ICT)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">313796.5289545959</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">313796.5289545959</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-10">313796.528954</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">313796.5289545959</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the implementation of the project, the following progress was achieved&#xA0; against planned outputs:
Output 1: Assessment of Radio mining information potential conductedIndicator 1.1: Three pilots initiated to demonstrate the value of radio content to inform development. By end of the project, the Pulse Lab Kampala had completed 5 pilot analysis with partners aimed at understanding and probing the value of public radio on content analysis to advance the Global Goals. The lab received complementary funding from the Development Operation Coordination Office (DOCO) that enabled increase of public radio discussions that were relevant to sustainable development andhumanitarian action.
The pilot studies generated evidence that public radio discussions included reports of local incidents and first hand experiences reported by citizens that are usually not collected by other quantitative or qualitative methods and not formally coded anywhere. Therefore, it can be concluded that the pilots showed how the exploration of unconstrained public radio through systematic analysis can inform programmes to achieve SDGs.Examples of pilots included:(i) Early warning and influx of refugees-Explore the use of radio to provide early warning signs around South Sudan refugee crisis. Analysis indicated that acceptance of refugees, land rights and conflicts, deforestation, increased pregnancies, infectious diseases were commonly discussed concerns on radios. The pilot was able to pick anticedental messages such outbreak of cholera before spreading.(ii) Disaster Risk Management- Partners were National Emergency coordination and operations Centre in office of the Prime Minister and UNDP. The aim was to determine whether public radio content could be used to fill the information gap and contribute to national coordination of of the National Emergency and coordination centre through identification, localisation and evaluate disaster and related small scale damages in a real time. The pilot discovered that reports of local losses and local disasters were available on public radio discussions, accessible and valuable on location and extent of damage for planning and response.(iii) Local Governance and Public Service Delivery- In partnership with Department of political science, Gothenburg University, UNDP and Ministry of health, the pilot evaluated the the availability of public radio content to analyse perceptions of the quality of health service delivery that could be used to inform local government processes. The pilot disclosed that there was a high volume of radio discussion on the topic of health services on ongoing basis. Most of the conversations were local complaints and reports about poor quality of public services including on to what and whom is the poor quality attributed.
(iv) Finding insights to fight malaria- In partnership with UNICEF, UN Agencies and Ministry of health, the pilot aimed at identify talk related to the incidence of malaria that could provide insights of implementation of malaria education programmes. Although some cases of malaria related issues were identified, the pilot did not uncover a substantial amount of new insight due to lack of specific definition of malaria in local languages. This showed potential limitations of radio mining that particularly that certain topics of interest may not be easy to filter, and may also not be discussed frequently.
(v) Radio campaign monitoring in real time- In partnership with Save the Children, and building on Save the Children&apos;s campaign entitled &apos;&apos;Every last Child&apos;&apos; the campaign aimed at reaching children living in remote areas of Uganda and ensure that no child dies from preventable diseases, all children benefit from quality basic education and violence against children is no longer tolerated, the pilot aimed at real time monitoring of the campaign to see whether radio shows were aired at expected dates, times and radio stations as per agreed plans could be provided.
Output2: Radio Mining Prototype deployedIndicator: 2.1 System to monitor radio discussion set in 5 new locationsNew locations for deployment of prototype were identified by pulse lab Kampala together with partners. All needed equipment was purchased, tested and deployed. Deployment in the stations was completed in Moroto, Mbarara, Fort Portal and Arua. A risk assessment was conducted to identify future challenges with IT equipment deployed in the field and appropriate contingency actions developed and how they are resolved.Indicator 2.2 The prototype functions with the manual feed from radio dash boardTo ensure that the filtered radio clips could be analysed and translated at an almost real time speed, Pulse Lab Kampala refined the prototype 1 of the project to improve filtering for relevant speech and facilitate manual feed. To enable fast manual feed from the radio broadcasts to the online dashboard, Pulse Lab Kampala developed a series of filters to ensure only information relevant to topics of interest identified.
OUTPUT 3: Protocols for the use of the radio mining tool developedIndicator 3.1 Real time analysis made available for stakeholdersThis indicator was achieved with and improvement on the functionality of the prototype. The prototype was improved and time public broadcasts to the dash board were reduced to less that 24 hours. The improvement in the functionality makes the analysis in real time possible, note for example the pilot with Save the children on real time data on Radio campaign.
Indicator 3.2 SDGs achievement and monitoring supported with insights in radio miningThe pilots have shown that analysing radio content to evaluate large scale unfiltered public radio discussion can be used to inform development and humanitarian actions such as on issues of like early warning, recording occurrence and losses from natural disasters, perceptions on public service delivery, radio campaigning and monitoring. Radio discussions are open ended, often rich in contextual information which when complemented with other sources of information like surveys can give a better view of the situation on the situation. The radio information then becomes critically important for decision making, planning and development.To protect people&apos;s privacy when using radio application, a risk analysis was conducted and measures and protocols were put in place for data privacy and protection including identification of different technical sub-products generated by the project, definition and identification of different types of data sets that have been generated to develop radio application , data-sets pilot studies, definition of implementation measures and risk analysis.
Partnerships and collaborationsThe project partnered with Universities of Makerere, Edinburgh(Scotland) and Stellenbosch (South Africa).Outreach. Project progress results were disseminated through outreach and knowledge sharing mechanisms including Global Pulse&apos;s communication campaigns, workshops and events organised by Pulse Lab Kampala.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180132" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
