<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118013402-UGA-16020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO Employment Diagnostic Study ILO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">ILO Syssels&#xE4;ttningstudie Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Employment diagnostics&#xA0;anlaysis, EDA,&#xA0;had two key outcomes:
1) increased stakeholder appreciation, participation and ownership of the EDA process and outcomes with a focus on job-rich economic growth and inclusive structural transformation.
2) High-quality information on employment is available an accessible to policy makers and the general public, in order to inform policy and investment decisions towards a just inclusive structural transformation and job-rich growth.
The methodology&#xA0;of the&#xA0;employment diagnostics analysis&#xA0;is based on both&#xA0;analytic research (mainly on&#xA0;macro level) and empirical evidence collected&#xA0;through stakeholder participation.&#xA0;The participatory approach has proved to not only add value to the&#xA0;building of&#xA0;a strong evidence base, but&#xA0;has also been key to strengthen knowledge/capacity and&#xA0;create ownership within the government, its institutions and the private sector.&#xA0;The EDA (employment diagnostics analysis) process can therefore be seen as a result in itself which has&#xA0;created a basis for&#xA0;more evidence based decision making facilitating for&#xA0;labour market development and structural transformation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Huvudm&#xE5;let med detta ett-&#xE5;riga program &#xE4;r att utf&#xF6;ra en syssels&#xE4;ttningsdiagnostisk analys (Employment Diagnostic Analysis EDA) som syftar till att identifiera och lyfta de huvudsakliga hinder och utmaningar som f&#xF6;religger f&#xF6;r skapandet av produktiva arbetstillf&#xE4;llen inom ramen f&#xF6;r en inkluderande och h&#xE5;llbar ekonomisk tillv&#xE4;xt i Uganda. Analysen skall informera och underl&#xE4;tta f&#xF6;r nationella beslutsfattare att sk&#xE4;rpa sitt fokus i utformning av strategier och policy f&#xF6;r arbetsmarknaden. Programmet kommer att utf&#xF6;ras i tre steg, (1) inr&#xE4;ttandet av en nationell styrkommitee, nationell kapacitetsf&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning i EDA-processen och data inventering, (2) genomf&#xF6;rande av s.k. situationsanalys f&#xF6;r kartl&#xE4;ggning av aktuell situation, och (3) workshops f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;rande av diagnostiska analyser p&#xE5; basis av situationsanalysen i syfte att skapa en gemensam f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else avseende hinder och utmaningar. EDA programmet kommer att ledas av den internationella arbetsorganisationen (ILO) i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med nationella akt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla &#xE4;garskap och deltagande. Det &#xE4;r betydelsefullt att skapa incitament och f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else f&#xF6;r nationella akt&#xF6;rer att anv&#xE4;nda EDA-slutsatserna i utformandet av relevanta &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder inom produktiv syssels&#xE4;ttning och inkluderande ekonomisk tillv&#xE4;xt.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of this one-year program is to undertake an Employment Diagnostic Analysis in Uganda (EDA). The purpuse of the EDA is to understand the nature of the deficiency of productive employment and identify the constraints and opportunities for enhancing inclusive job-rich growth. The Analysis is to provide a sound knowledge base for effective policies, institutional reforms and other interventions aimed at reducing the deficiency of productive employment. The program will evolve in three steps; (1) constituting a National Steering Committee, capacity-building on the EDA process and data sourcing (2) performing the situational employment analysis (3) conducting joint participatory diagnostic analysis workshops based on the situational employment analysis with an outlook to subsequent policy and interventions. The EDA program will be implemented by the International Labour Organisation (ILO) in conjunction with national stakeholders to ensure ownership, appreciation and participation in the EDA process but also to ensure sufficient incentive and capacity in subsequently implementing the findings of the EDA process into practice through relevant and informed policy interventions in the area of productive employment and inclusive growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41144" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO/International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41144" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ILO/International Labour Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-7827.7054537379</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">-7827.720259309</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results as per the Employment diagnostics has already been approved (statement on report) and concluded on in the previous Conclusion on Performance.
According to the no-cost extension agreement, ILO was to submit a final technical report for the period 1 October- 30th November (extended as per correspondence up to 2019-02-28). ILO was also to submit a concept note for complementary studies (EDA extension) as well as a work plan and budget for complementary studies. ILO was also to secure engagement of consultants of a cost extension period. The following should be noted:
Sida and ILO agreed on an extension of the EDA process (see extension agreement signed 28/9 2018) in order to complement the Employment diagnostics analysis with sector studies. The main aim being to deepen analysis from certain aspects where the EDA fell short (mainly due to methodological issues) of showing constraints and opportunities for employment creation in different sectors. This is in line with the main conclusion of the EDA on the need for structural transformation of the economy.
The&#xA0;no-cost extension agreement was set to end&#xA0;the 28/2 2019. The period up to that date&#xA0;would give the Ministry of Labour, in collaboration with ILO, enough time to draft a concept note for the complementary sector studies. The concept note was to form the basis for a costed extension of the EDA during 2019.
ILO engaged in a rigorous process with the Ministry (Labour)&#xA0;to ensure good quality and solid methodology of such sector studies. The Ministry of Labour also contracted consultants to facilitate the work (at own expense). However, despite dialogue on different levels and written feedback on the draft concept note&#xA0;(see also&#xA0;documentation on communication on concept note&#xA0;registered in the file and saved among documents in TRAC), the quality did not&#xA0;live up to standards. ILOs efforts included&#xA0;staff resources from the ILO office in Kampala, but also&#xA0;ILO staff from Pretoria, Dar Es Salaam (regional office) as well as a resource from HQ Geneva (including consultations with the LAB).
The Ministry of Labour called for a validation meeting on the draft concept note the 27th November 2019.&#xA0;ILO was represented through the resource from Geneva and Sida was represented by&#xA0;the programme officer. The messages from both Sida and ILO were clear, that the draft concept note did not live up to standards.
Following the Validation meeting, ILO engaged in further consultations with the Ministry. Further concluding comments were forwarded to the Ministry. Sida&apos;s and ILOs conclusions were however that, with the time at hand (and the time-frame for the no-cost extension of this agreement) it was not considered&#xA0;feasible to agree on a concept note that would hold for an assessment and a cost-extention of the agreement between Sida an ILO.&#xA0;&#xA0;Sida&apos;s assessment is that ILO has done all in its power to contribute constructively to the process but that further engagement should be sought with another time frame. It should also preferrably involve other stakeholders like the National planning authority, NPA.
As a way to continue the discussion with the Ministry on a suitable/qualitative methodology for sector studies, ILO has drafted a new proposal (attached to the statement on report for the final period) that has been presented and discussed with the Ministry of Labour. The proposal has restarted the dialogue on sector studies between ILO, Sida and the Ministry of Labour, but is essentially outside of this assignment and agreement (however catalyzed by the same). The Terms of Reference drafted by ILO as well as a concept note with a new&#xA0;proposed methodology is attached to the statement on final report&#xA0;for institutional memory.
During the no-cost extension period, the&#xA0;planning process of the NDPIII&#xA0;has been&#xA0;ongoing and&#xA0;Sida and ILO have been able to engage in dialgoue with the National Planning Authority (NPA). NPA sees sector studies as something that could enhance the value of, and strengthen&#xA0;the evidence base&#xA0;for&#xA0;the Government planning process&#xA0;and the drafting of the NDPIII.&#xA0;Sida and ILO are therefore planning for continued consultations with NPA and Ministry of Labour. NPA is about to initiate conversations with Ministry of Labour (dialogue ongoing on Director level). Sida and ILO will look into how that could be facilitated through us as development partners.
The overall conclusion (as is also&#xA0;elaborated on statement on reports)&#xA0;is that the Employment diagnostics analysis has contributed not only to strengthening of the evidence base, but also to a multi sector and cross ministerial dialgoue on employment. In that sense Sida has contributed to both catalyzing partners and potentially capital towards employment creation. The work with the EDA proves the value of using (support to) evidence as a way to convene stakeholders. In that sense too, the support to the EDA has been very successful. It has given Sweden a platform from which we can further strengthen the achivement of strategy results.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180134" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="2400000000" strategy-end-date="2023-12-31" strategy-start-date="2018-01-01">
    <sida:title>Uganda 2018-2023</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Uganda 2018-2023</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
