<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118005601-UGA-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA SRHR 2015-2017</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNFPA SRHR 2015-2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNFPA har formulerat ett projekt som ska &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE4;ngligheten och anv&#xE4;ndandet av r&#xE4;ttighetsbaserade, integrerade SRH tj&#xE4;nster. Tj&#xE4;nsterna ska uppfylla kvalitetsstandard p&#xE5; v&#xE5;rd och j&#xE4;mlikhet i tillg&#xE5;ngen f&#xF6;r kvinnor, ungdomar, personer som sex-arbetar och hbt-personer. Projektet ska implementeras i 10 i distrikt med stora behov och som ocks&#xE5; &#xE4;r bel&#xE4;gna i Ugandas post-konflikt omr&#xE5;den. Ytterligare fyra hiv-centra inkluderas ocks&#xE5; i projektet. Effektm&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r projektet &#xE4;r 1) att st&#xE4;rka h&#xE4;lsosystemets kapacitet i att kunna leverera r&#xE4;ttighetsbaserade reproduktiva-, m&#xF6;dra-, nyf&#xF6;dda- och ungdomsh&#xE4;lsotj&#xE4;nster i geografiska omr&#xE5;den med h&#xF6;g m&#xF6;drad&#xF6;dlighet och 2) att mobilisera strukturer, s&#xE5;som grupper p&#xE5; landsbygden, religi&#xF6;sa och kulturella ledare f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka anv&#xE4;ndandet av SRH och hiv tj&#xE4;nster fria fr&#xE5;n stigmatisering. 

De personer som direkt gagnas av projektet &#xE4;r befolkningen i de post-konflikt drabbade omr&#xE5;dena Acholi och Karamoja,  speciellt unga flickor och marginaliserade grupper. Den totala populationen som kommer gagnas av projektet ber&#xE4;knas uppg&#xE5; till 1 770 224 personer

UNFPA kommer vara ambassadens kontraktspartner och den enhet som &#xE4;r ansvarig f&#xF6;r utvecklingen, implementeringen, uppf&#xF6;ljningen och rapporteringen av projektet. UNFPA kommer vara ansvariga f&#xF6;r projektresultaten och finansieringen. Medel kommer att vidarebefordras till tredje part.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA has designed an intervention to increase availability and use of rights-based, integrated SRH services that meet standards of quality of care and equity in access for women, young people, sex workers and LGBT persons in 10 high-need districts in post-conflict areas of Uganda (plus 4 HIV hubs). The strategic objectives of the intervention are 1) To strengthen the capacity of the health system to deliver rights-based Reproductive, Maternal, New-born and Adolescent Health services to high maternal mortality burdened regions of the country; and 2) To mobilize institutional structures including community, religious and cultural leadership for increased utilization of stigma-free SRH/HIV services. 

The direct beneficiaries in this project are the rights holders in the post-conflict areas of Acholi and Karamoja, including women and young people, especially adolescent girls, and most at risk populations focusing on districts with poor sexual reproductive health indicators (total population 1,770,224).

UNFPA will be Sweden&apos;s contracting partner and responsible for development, implementation, monitoring and reporting of the project. UNFPA will also be accountable for project results and finance.  Project funds for implementation will be forwarded to partners (almost all of the project oriented funds).  Procurement will mainly be handled through the UNFPA system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41119" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFPA/United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2372676.260187679</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2337404.3125109565</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2372676.260187679</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2337404.3125109565</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-01">4745352.520375</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">2372676.260187679</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">2337404.3125109565</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: The majority of planned activities are on track and some of the planned results for the whole agreement period have already been reached or exceeded. Results for 2016 summarised:

There was an increased number, within the supported districts, of facility based deliveries in 2016, total 49,424 (compared to 28,116 in 2015). The increase uptake can be partly attributed to the improved quality of service delivery in the health facilities following the health systems strengthening and demand interventions supported by this program. 

Mentoring, training and follow up of 124 health facility based health workers on basic EmONC and PAC service provision based on Human Rights approach in the 10 districts took place during the reporting period. 

So far 10 students from Kotido and 10 from Kaabong have enrolled to the Pre-service Midwifery training Bursary Scheme and 5 from Napak are in final stages. The target of 200 students enrolled by the end of the program is still by UNFPA envisaged to be achieved. 20 midwifery tutors (100% of target) have also been supported to undertake the Bachelor of Medical Education. 

From the target districts 498 service providers were trained on insertion and removal of implants and Intra Uterine Device (IUD) family planning methods. 350 VHT&#x2019;s from 7 of the 10 target districts were trained to provide the Sayana Press family planning method. 140 health workers were trained in supply chain management in 14 districts (including some of the target districts). This in conjunction with the development of the Implementation Manual for Alternative Distribution Mechanisms (ADM), Public facilities in 2016 were able to access contraceptive supplies through ADM, and this has helped reduce stock outs and lead time in the districts. 

The activities within support have increased uptake of FP services in the target districts with four fold increases in new users in 2016 compared to 2015. The number of FP users in the 10 target districts served by Village Health Teams (VHT) with injectable family planning methods and pills rose from 8,831 in 2015 to 11,342 in 2016, indicating that the role played by VHT&#x2019;s has increased. 

A total of 97 health facilities (40%) of existing health facilities in the 10 target districts have been supported to provide Youth Friendly Services (YFS), as against the target of 50. In total the program has contributed to 168,705 young people in the 10 districts accessing SRH services. 

In 2016 the subject of Sexuality Education gained prominence from government and other stakeholders. There were numerous debates in the media on whether Ugandan children need sexuality education and what kind should they be provided with. The Ministry of Education &amp; Sports with support from UNFPA and UNESCO embarked on developing a National Framework on Sexuality Education. UNFPA plans to continue supporting the finalization of the framework most importantly because the planned curriculum rollout has been put on hold.
 
Through the combined efforts of partners, about 60,000 members of MARPs groups are estimated to have accessed services in the various regional hubs in 2016. Specifically, 10,000 were reached with services during the UNFPA supported HIV prevention drives conducted in the 7 hubs during World AIDS Day week. 

About 700 religious and cultural leaders were through the support oriented on SRMNCAH/HIV/GBV. About 2.5 million people are estimated to have received SRH/HIV messages through cultural and religious leader&#x2019;s platforms. High level leadership dialogues were held at International Religious Council Uganda (IRCU) level on various issues including comprehensive sexuality education (CSE).  These leaders are scheduled to discuss the outcome from their dialogue processes with the First Lady of Uganda and Minister of Education to inform consensus on a national sexuality education framework.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180056" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
