<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118001901-UGA-32110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade QUISP Prog (MTTI)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Trade QUISP Prog (MTTI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ministry of Tourism, Trade and instustry (MTTI) has implemented a five-year programme: Quality infrastructure and standards programme. The programme seeks to develop a market driven, holistic and coordinated insitutional framework for the Uganda Quality infrastructure and standards framework; which supports trade, industry, health, safety, consumer protection and a sustainable environment while at the same time promoting use of best practices in the production and service sectors.
The programme commenced in 2010 with the support of Sida and was set to close in December 2014. However, an extension was given until March 2017.
The overall objective is to promote the use standards and quality infrastructure so as to improve the competitiveness of Ugandand products, processes and service delivery systems in domestic, regional and international markets.
The following goals have formed implementation of the programme:
- To develop a policy for standardization and review strategies for policy implementation.
- To develop a comprehensive and effective legal framework for the implementation of standardization.
- To establish an effective coordination mechanism with clearly defined mandates and responsibilities for the different actors in the standards and quality area.
- to rationalize the institutional set up of service providers for standards development, confirmity assessment and measurement services.
- to enhance public awareness on standards and quality products and best practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">QUISP &#xE4;r ett fem&#xE5;rigt program under den Ugandiska regeringen med      uppgift att fr&#xE4;mja anv&#xE4;ndningen av standarder och                     kvalitetsinfrastruktur. M&#xE5;let &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra konkurrenskraften f&#xF6;r  ugandiska produkter, processer och tj&#xE4;nsteleveranssystem p&#xE5; inhemska, regionala och internationella marknader. Programmet innefattar bland  annat en omarbetning av det r&#xE4;ttsliga ramverket i Uganda, utveckling.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The QUISP is a 5 yr GoU programme with the goal to promote the use of standards and quality infrastructure to improve the competitiveness   of Ugandan products, processes and service delivery systems in        domestic, regional and international markets. it entails a review of  the legal and regulatory framework, development of a coordinaition    mechanism and a communication stragegy amongst others.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="32110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industrial policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja utvecklingsinriktad politik som st&#xF6;der produktiv verksamhet, skapande av anst&#xE4;ndiga arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, f&#xF6;retagande, kreativitet och innovation samt uppmuntra att mikrof&#xF6;retag liksom sm&#xE5; och medelstora f&#xF6;retag v&#xE4;xer och blir en del av den formella ekonomin, bland annat genom tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.3 - Promote development-oriented policies that support productive activities, decent job creation, entrepreneurship, creativity and innovation, and encourage the formalization and growth of micro-, small- and medium-sized enterprises, including through access to financial services.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">9.b - St&#xF6;dja inhemsk teknikutveckling, forskning och innovation i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, inklusive genom att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla en gynnsam policymilj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r exempelvis industriell diversifiering och f&#xF6;r&#xE4;dling av r&#xE5;varor.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">9.b - Support domestic technology development, research and innovation in developing countries, including by ensuring a conducive policy environment for, inter alia, industrial diversification and value addition to commodities.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">1196098.8309127765</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1056655.2117364237</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1243628.3240189152</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1150747.9861910243</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">523334.6578624438</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">1196098.8309127768</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1056655.2117364234</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1243628.3240189154</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">-8e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1150747.986191024</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-02-01">5241357.224181</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-04-28">191928.0219932798</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-12-28">1004170.7839271333</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-10-28">1056655.1423904332</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1243628.3240189154</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">1150747.9861910243</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">-70336.4264015465</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/uganda/15a.-amend-agree-quisp-signed-150527-incl-agr-from-2010.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall programme objective for the period was centered around four areas/components:
1) Component 2: Legal and regulatory framework review for SMCA
2) Component 3: Coordination standards, Metrology, Conformity Assessment and Accreditation (SMCA) stakeholders
3) Component 4: Capacity development of SMCA service providers
4) Component 5: Awareness raising and implementation support.
&#xA0;
The aim for the component &quot;Legal and Regulatory framework review&quot; was to establish an effective legal and regulatory framework for the Standards and Quality Infrastructure and to enable legal basis for implementation of the Standards and Quality policy and Strategy as established in component 1 (ended ahead of the no-cost extension period). The result of the component was expected to be a well-established and legally backed Standards and Quality infrastructure. The component has supported the review and updating of laws and regulations enabling legislation and the elaboration of new bills for identified gaps.
What can be drawn out from several sources (also in regards to the state of laws in Uganda)&#xA0;three bills (instead of 5 as in the log-frame) have been finalized. The Accreditation bill was adpoted. All technical inputs and stakeholder consultations in relation to that bill&#xA0;have been carried out in accordance to the workplan. Two bills on Legal Metrology and on Scientific and Industrial Metrology were supported for adoption by the Cabinet. These&#xA0;bills have been cleared by the Office of Solicitor General and are ready for submission to the Cabinet Secretariat. Once enacted into laws they will help strengthen the national quality infrastructure institution for efficiency, international recognition and promote fair practices.
MTTIC reports that the Accreditation law will lead to the establishment of the national accrediation body, leading to more accredited service providers who will provide credible technical support services to operators.
The semi-annual report and the end of implementation report&#xA0;states that the technical working group composed of key stakeholders with the fruit value chain has held a number of consultative meetings on implementation measures to address export challenges. It also stated that the process will contribute to the long term development of a robust quality assurance mechanism and certification in the sector. However this is not verified and the correlation between the consultative meetings and improved quality assurance mechanisms cannot be validated.
The end of implementation report also shows activity in the Meat Standards implementation. For example awareness materials have been developed and training for operators held. The meat standards implementation camapign in Kampala City has, according to the report, enabled meat butchery owners and operators to adopt good hygiene and meat handling practices. Also, that as a result of the trainings and sensitization that infrastructure has improved with floors being tiled etc. There is not any evidence for this being financed through Sida&apos;s support, rather these seem to be initiatives taken by the sector itself. This can indicate that the programme had a catalytic effect. The end of implementation report also states a set of trainings carried out and how the programe have supported officials from MDA, private sector and consumer advocacy organisations to represent Uganda in different meetings at EAC, COMESA, Tripartite FTA, WTO and ISO. The report states that this will contribute to fast tracking of African Free trade agreements and more use of the quality infrastructure, increased exports, incomes and improved livelihoods for citizens. These types of stated results have not been validated through the Embassy but&#xA0;are also confirmed by the report by the TA to this component.&#xA0;The TA also&#xA0;confirms that the deliverables&#xA0;within this component has contributed to that 19 Export companies were assessed by MAAIF (the only&#xA0;ones that are allowed to export to&#xA0;Europe). The number of interceptions&#xA0;for exportes has reduced by 40% which is&#xA0;an example&#xA0;of&#xA0;a good result.
The Component 4: Capacity development of SMCA service providers had four expected outputs in the logframe relating to 1) skills and knowledge enhanced, 2) a selection of enterprises supported to comply with required standards, 3) a selection of testing and calibration laboratories better equipped and accredited and 4) operational accreditation services established. None of the four outputs have specific goals for 2017 in the logframe, however they are reported on in the end of implementation report. The programme has supported a training workshop for UNBS Standards officers and Technical committee chairperson on good standardization practices (40 people trained). A course (on ISO/IEC 17025:2005) was also carried out (for 35 staff) from public and private testing laboratories. It is reported that the training has led to that the laboratories have developed QMS documentation in their laboratories and that roles and working methods have been improved.
UNBS and MTTIC staff have also followed up on Micro Small and Medium Enterprises engaged in manufacturing and value addition and guided them on quality standards compliance in preparation for certification. It is reported that QUISP has sensitized and trained 600 MSMEs and provided onsite technical guidance to 220 MSMEs and 61 awarded certificates.
With support of the TA (the consultant procured within the Quisp programme) the programme facilitated three strategic laboratories to prepare and apply for accreditation to internationally recognized institutions. This was done in regards to the UNBS materials laboratory, the Government Analytical Laboratory and the Uganda Fisheries laboratory. Due to a number of challenges (lack of funding to replace broken down equipment in the laboratory and delays by their institutions to review the laboratory management structure) none of the three laboratories have attained accreditation. &#xA0;
The TA consultant also reports that the QUISP communications and awareness strategy has been supported, that radio talks have been held to sensitize farmers, traders and consumers on maize standards and the regulations developed by a district. The TA consultant also confirms that national events have been held to commemorate international days for Standards, Metrology and Accreditation (one which was attended to in a field visit by the Embassy in April 2016). Together with Makerere University a draft curriculum for the Masters Course in Food and Safety and Quality Management has also been develpoped and submitted to stakeholders for comments. The curriculum development was not possible to finalize due to the termination of contract on the QUISP programme.
The last component:&#xA0;Awareness raising and implementation support has two specified outputs in the log-frame; that key target groups have been reached by awareness raising activities and that curriculum and training materials on standards and quality have been developed. The component is partly reported under the previous component. The log frame also states activity targets for 2017 in regards to for example number of media reports /articles on SMCA&#xA0;that have been published (target 100 for 2017).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180019" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
