<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118012401-UGA-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to UN OHCHR Uganda 2016 - Extension for 2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to UN OHCHR Uganda 2016 - Extension for 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A- Refer to the Decision on exemption from Sida contribution management rule under DG Decision 2016-000872 as uploaded under saved documents. The exemption is from Sida contribution management rule to allow use of paragraph 3.11.2 for agreement amendments higher than 5 MSEK for decisions on additional support to the UN Office for the High Commissioner for human rights (OHCHR) country programmes in Colombia, Guatemala, Cambodia and Uganda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Intervention will address 5 thematic areas; Widening the democratic space, Strengthening the effectiveness of international human rights mechanisms and the progressive development of international human rights law and standards, Human rights in development and in the economic sphere, Combating impunity and strengthening accountability and the rule of law, Countering discrimination, in particular racial discrimination, discrimination on the grounds of sex, religion and against others who are marginalised.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">The Intervention will address 5 thematic areas; Widening the democratic space, Strengthening the effectiveness of international human rights mechanisms and the progressive development of international human rights law and standards, Human rights in development and in the economic sphere, Combating impunity and strengthening accountability and the rule of law, Countering discrimination, in particular racial discrimination, discrimination on the grounds of sex, religion and against others who are marginalised.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Geneva General Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (extrabudgetary contributions only)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1402442.587506574</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1402442.5875065739</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1402442.587506</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-28">1402442.5875065739</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016 was a politically intense year with contested Parliamentary and Presidential Elections. OHCRHR reported on a number of incidences of violence and human rights violations. In the build up to the elections, OHCHR built the capacities fo UHRC staff, journalists and CSO representatives to monotir and report violations in the context of the elections. In January, OHCHR trained member organizations of the National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders on human rights monitoring, documentation and reporting in the context of the elections. The Office also supported the documentation efforts of the Coalition by disseminating a human rights database tailored to the needs of its member organizations. Additionally, OHCHR supported the Foundation for Human Rights Initiative to document and publish its findings regarding human rights violations committed in the context of the elections. An online database to register human rights violations and monitor the status of the Government&#x2019;s implementation of the recommendations formulated by international, regional and national human rights mechanisms was created. A large number of complaints were registred, the majority reported shortly after the elections.&#xA0; Violent events in November the Rwenzori sub-region claimed the lives of over 100 people and the Rwenzururu King was charged with terrorism, murder and aggravated robbery. These events and their consequenses have also been closely followed by OHCHR. But OHCHR has also engaged in monitoring visits and technical assistance to key human rights institutions&#xA0;(Directorate of Public Prosecution, the Justice Law and Order Sector, Uganda Human Rights Commission, Equal Opportunities Commission etc) as well as building capacity with of rights-holders on e.g. CEDAW and the Universal Periodic Review (UPR) reporting. In the second cycle Universal Periodic Review (UPR), OHCHR provided assistance to civil society organizations through the dissemination of information relating to the UPR process. In March, the Office supported consultation meetings between 120 representatives from civil societyorganizations from different regions in order to coordinate the elaboration of a joint shadow report. OHCHR supported the Equal Opportunities Commission to conduct technical dialogues with 45 technical officers on how to mainstream gender into their financial instruments and ensure that non-discrimination standards were integrated and respected. As a result, technical officers whose financial instruments had failed to comply with gender equality standards were able to revise and re-submit them to the Parliament.  OHCHR has aimed to make Uganda People&#x2019;s Defence Force, the Uganda Police Force and Uganda Prisons Service increasingly comply with international standards on the use of force, arrest, detention and treatment of persons in custody, including in events of counter-terrorism, treason charges and rebellion. Between 2014 and 2016, a significant decrease was noted in the number of allegations related to torture or incommunicado detention allegedly perpetrated by the Chieftaincy of Military Intelligence (CMI). The Office contributed to the improvement of the CMI&#x2019;s human rights record through a series of interventions that began in 2013, including a 2016 training-of-trainers session for 25 CMI instructors on human rights, the right to physical and mental integrity and gender and sexual and gender-based violence. 230 staff members of the Uganda Human Rights Commission were deployed to 92 districts to conduct human rights monitoring during the elections, thereby enabling the Commission to implement its mandate during this sensitive period. In February, the Office trained these staff members on human rights monitoring.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180124" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
