<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118011401-UGA-15130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HiiL A2J-Justice Needs &amp; Satisfaction Survey 2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">HiiL A2J-Justice Needs &amp; Satisfaction Survey 2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PLEASE REVIEW YOUR ANSWER AS THE QUESTION HAS BEEN CHANGED

Det svenska l&#xE5;ngsiktiga sektorprogramst&#xF6;det till The Justice Law and Order Sector (JLOS) avslutades i december 2014. Den nya resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r Sveriges utvecklingssamarbete med Uganda m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d till &#xF6;kad tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa och r&#xE4;ttsstatsprincipen genom icke-statliga akt&#xF6;rer men begr&#xE4;nsar m&#xF6;jligheterna till samarbete med staten under strategiperioden. Ambassaden &#xE4;mnar st&#xF6;dja ett forskningsprojekt vid HiiL Innovating Justice som syftar till att unders&#xF6;ka graden av tillfredsst&#xE4;llelse och behov hos befolkningen av tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttsligt st&#xF6;d/r&#xE4;ttvisa.

Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen &#xE4;r en studie av de viktigaste r&#xE4;ttsliga behoven, missn&#xF6;jet och or&#xE4;ttvisorna i vardagen f&#xF6;r den ugandiska befolkningen. Studiens resultat kommer anv&#xE4;ndas f&#xF6;r design och uppf&#xF6;ljning av insatser inom r&#xE4;ttssektorn. Utifr&#xE5;n ett slumpm&#xE4;ssiga urval och djupintervjuer kommer studien synligg&#xF6;ra befolkningens r&#xE4;ttsliga behov i Uganda, d&#xE4;r m&#xE5;nga lever i fattigdom och mis&#xE4;r. Kunskap om vad som beh&#xF6;ver reformeras f&#xF6;r att r&#xE4;ttssektorn ska fungera effektivt finns men behoven utifr&#xE5;n befolkningens perspektiv har inte unders&#xF6;kts eller beaktats i tillr&#xE4;ckligt h&#xF6;g grad tidigare. Insatsens evidensbaserade uppifr&#xE5;n-och-ner perspektiv kommer d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r bidra till b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r Uganda, Sverige och andra givare att utforma relevanta och behovsbaserade insatser f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten och tillg&#xE5;ngen till r&#xE4;ttvisa  f&#xF6;r befolkningen i stort.

Ambassaden genomf&#xF6;r en annan studie f&#xF6;r att identifiera l&#xE4;mpliga partners f&#xF6;r framtida r&#xE4;ttssektorst&#xF6;d, och tillsammans kommer resultaten av de tv&#xE5; studierna ge ambassaden ett gott beslutsunderlag f&#xF6;r programmering av framtida st&#xF6;d. Ambassaden f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;r d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r att ett beslut om att st&#xF6;dja detta projekt tas med ett maximalt belopp om 1 500 000 SEK f&#xF6;r 2015.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish long term sector programme support to the Justice Law and Order Sector (JLOS) through Government of Uganda sector programme support ended in December 2014.  The new results strategy provides for support to enhanced access to justice and rule of law through non state actors. The government decision on the new strategy limits possibilities for cooperation with the state during the strategy period.  The embassy is therefore interested in supporting a research project by HiiL Innovating Justice to carry out a scientific research in the area Justice needs and Satisfaction Survey.

The proposed intervention outlines a rigorous study of the key justice needs, grievances and injustices in the everyday life of the Ugandan people and links this new knowledge to actions aimed at more justice and fairness. Considering the random nature of the survey sample as well as the strategies for conducting in-depth interviews the data will be able to reveal the justice needs of the Ugandan people, many of whom live in poverty and deprivation and thus the embassy will be able to use the finding to effectively design relevant and needs based interventions in the area of access to justice and rule of law. 

The intervention is a bottom-up and evidence-based approach to interventions and implementation of projects in the field of rule of law and access to justice. The aim to improve the delivery of justice to poor Ugandan citizens and therefore increasing performance, societal accountability and development in Uganda.

The outcome of this survey will be complemented by the ongoing study on access to justice to enable the embassy develop a holistic and focused support to rule of law and access to justice through non-state actors that would enable the results of this support to underpin and strongly contribute to the results areas of the strategy for development cooperation with Uganda 2014-2018.  The embassy therefore proposes that a decision to support this project be taken with a maximum amount of 1,500,000 SEK for 2015.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HIIL/The Hague Institute for Innovation of Law</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HIIL/The Hague Institute for Innovation of Law</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">177950.7195140759</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">50137.32250336</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">177950.7195140759</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">50137.32250336</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-01">228844.625295</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">177950.7195140759</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">50137.32250336</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2016 the embassy supported HiiL to undertake a Justice Needs and Satisfaction (hereafter referred to as JNS) survey. HiiL produced a very good informative and comprehensive report that was highly appreciated and very well received by the Justice Law and Orde Sector Leadership (JLOS) and all JLOS stakeholders. Their report brought out new and innovative ways to analysing and measuring justice needs and clearly focused onon how ordinary Ugandans appreciates their access to justice, the level of fairness and trust in different parts of the formal and informal justice system and the most prevalent justice challenges faced. The findings of the report highlight the critical justice needs and confirms that the most prevalent justice problems people face are related to land, family matters and crime, and that more than a third of the people with these and other problems do not take any steps to resolve it.
The report also provided a number of recommendations and best practices that the JLOS Leadership committed themselves to take forward and have adopted in their work and planning to improve on the delivery of services by the sector and information that can be used to develop effective change strategies.
For the short and medium term, the study provided the following outputs;
- A data set with the justice needs and experiences of a sample of 56000 Ugandan citizens- Knowledge (embedded in reports) about the justice needs that the people experience and the fairness that they receive on the paths to justice.
- Geographical (GPS) map of the justice needs in Uganda
- It provided a clear idea about the ownership of the two most frequent problems and Terms of Reference for the resolution of these problems
- A Ugandan Justice Box which organises the available justice data around the justice needs of the people.- An enhansed evidence base within the justice delivery supply chain.- Development of accountability and communication mechanisms between the public and providers of justice- The empowerment of local CSO through capacity building to ensure effective and sustainable monitoring of bottom justice in Uganda.
- Improved delivery of justice services to Ugandan citizens
- Increased accountability of the justice providers in Uganda
Most importantly, the report provided information and data during the development of the JLOS Strategic Development Plan IV and the&#xA0;Judiciary Fourth Strategic Investment Plan.
Key conclusions were:
Prioritizing the most urgent justice needs that emerged from the data, in a way that is seen as legitimate. Then, for each of the prioritized justice needs, undertaking a detailed analysis of bottlenecks and needs per problem type. For each justice problem the key stakeholders should be identified and a problem owner should be selected. Measurable targets were set so that problem owners can start working towards the goals.
Finally, the knowledge infrastructure per justice problem was strengthened, including the development of and delivery of legal information, the development of a network of hybrid providers of justice services, the support of dispute resolution with online tools and continuous assessment of the evidence about needs for and supply of justice services is being undertaken by JLOS and other Justice stakeholders.&#xA0;
Also the report provided information which helped JLOS and justice stakeholders to focus on the rules of the game, the roles of different stakeholders and the indicators of success. This has formed a basis proper development of verified indicators to track progress as well holding specific institution to address the challenges.For the embassy, the report provided valuable and evidence based data and information that has enabled Sweden to design appropriate interventions within the Access to Justice and Rule of Law programme.
Building on the these findings, the Embassy further supported HiiL with a 6 month cost extension to deepen the understanding of the family related justice problems that Ugandans face were further evaluated in the survey and possible solutions and justice pathways explored. This was because of Swedish special focus on improving gender equality specifically preventing and addressing gender based violence.&#xA0; The family justice report was also highly received by JLOS stakeholders who committed to undertake the following measure to address the outcomes of the report as follow:&#xA0;
&#x2022; To convene a Family Justice Summit of around 30 leaders from the field of family justice: from the ministry of justice, judiciary, police, lawyers, law reform commission, LC&apos;s, legal aid network, civil society organisations, and more.&#xA0;&#x2022; That group would take ownership of the problem and agree on a set of terms of reference that need to be met to make justice processes in this field better and more effective . The HiiL Report and the &apos;User Stories&apos; it contains can serve as a basis for the discussion.&#x2022; Such a summit should have as outcomes: (1) family justice is publicly prioritized; (2) concrete goals for improvement are proclaimed and disseminated; and (3) an (national) innovation/improvement process is launched.
The summit was conducted and the outcome of the summit led to the development of the &quot;access to justice dashboard&quot; that will be launched in 2019.&#xA0;
Also, the report provided variable information and data on family justice which helped the sector to clearly understand the extent and magnitude of the problems when it comes to family justice challenges. It also provided a detailed overview of the needs of women, men, boys and girls, as well as clear lessons on what works and of what can be improved.
These two reports formed the basis for the Embassy continued support to HiiL to build on the findings and develop programmes that helps the justice sector to be more innovative, open, transparent and accountable. To provide solution that ensure stress, violence and poverty is reduced and opportunities are improved by increased access to justice and a justice system that is more inclusive and responsive to poor people.
The reports deepened the understanding of specific justice needs of the society as well as satisfaction levels in the justice system in Uganda. This provided direction on how these needs could be best addressed and which justice pathways to quickly and efficiently resolve justice challenges.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180114" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
