<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5118006801-UGA-31120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conservation Cotton TechnoServe</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">H&#xE5;llbar bomullsodling TechnoServe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">TechnoServe har ans&#xF6;kt om USD 680 374  f&#xF6;r genomf&#xF6;randet av fas tv&#xE5; av projektet Conservation Cotton Initiative Uganda (CCIU) i distrikten Gulu, Amuru och Nwoya under perioden 2014-2016.

M&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka inkomsterna f&#xF6;r cirka 8000 bomullsodlare (kvinnor och m&#xE4;n) i regionen genom att etablera ett kommersiellt och inkluderande marknadssystem f&#xF6;r jordbruksproduktion i distrikten. Detta skall &#xE5;stadkommas genom att 1) St&#xE4;rka kapaciteten hos bomullsodlare organiserade i produktionsgrupper och l&#xE4;nka dessa till uppk&#xF6;pare, 2) St&#xE4;rka kapaciteten hos tj&#xE4;nsteleverant&#xF6;rer inom bomullssektorn och l&#xE4;nka dessa till produktionsgrupperna, 3) Sammanbinda odlare och tj&#xE4;nsteleverant&#xF6;rer med finansiella institutioner f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE5;ngen p&#xE5; krediter, 4) St&#xE4;rka organisationen kring driften av vattenbrunnar viktiga f&#xF6;r odlare och tj&#xE4;nseleverant&#xF6;rer, 5) Etablera ett system f&#xF6;r uppf&#xF6;ljning och utv&#xE4;rdering av resultaten. 

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r fas tv&#xE5; av projektet &#xE4;r USD 994 966 , varav Sverige bidrar med USD  680 374 . Resterande del finansieras av modef&#xF6;retaget Edun som &#xE4;r en viktig uppk&#xF6;pare av bomull fr&#xE5;n norra Uganda. Fas ett av projektet - total budget USD 1,5 miljoner - finansieras helt av Edun. D&#xE4;rmed utg&#xF6;r Sidas bidrag till den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r CCIU, fas ett och tv&#xE5;, 27 procent. Resten finansieras av n&#xE4;ringslivet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TechnoServe has applied for USD 994 966 for the implementation of phase two of the project Conservation Cotton Initiative Uganda (CCIU) in the districts of Gulu , Amuru and Nwoya during the period 2014-2016 .

The goal of the initiative is to increase the incomes of some 8,000 cotton farmers (women and men) in the region by establishing a commercial and inclusive marketing system for agricultural production in the districts. This will be achieved by: 1 ) Strengthening the capacity of cotton farmers, organised into production groups, and linking these to the purchasers of cotton, 2 ) Strengthening the capacity of service providers in the cotton sector and linking these to the production groups, 3 ) Linking farmers and service providers to financial institutions in order to increase access to credit , 4) Strengthening management of boreholes important for growers and service providers, 5 ) Establishing a system for monitoring and evaluation of results.

The total budget for phase two of the project is USD 994 966, of which Sweden is contributing USD 680 374. The remainder is financed by the fashion company Edun, which is a major purchaser of cotton from northern Uganda. Phase one of the project - total budget of USD 1.5 million &#x2013; is financed entirely by Edun. Thus Sweden contributes 27 percent of the overall budget for CCIU phase one and two. The rest is financed by private capital.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TechnoServe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">349859.3273954431</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">284721.1512225214</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">349859.3273954431</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">284721.1512225214</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">699718.65479</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">174929.6636977216</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">174929.6636977216</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">142360.5756112607</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">142360.5756112607</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2016Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Funded by the Swedish International Development Agency&#x2019;s (SIDA) and Edun Apparel Ltd (EDUN), the Conservation Cotton Initiative Uganda Phase II (CCIU-II) project was launched in May 2014 to increase incomes and advance gender equality for smallholder cotton farmers in Northern Uganda over two years while providing a supportive range of social initiatives and setting the farmers on a path to commercial sustainability. The project focused on facilitating increased access to inputs and outputs markets for male and female farmers and providing access to financial services and social initiatives, including Village Savings and Loans Associations (VSLAs) and water user committees. The project was implemented in Northern Uganda, Acholi sub-region, in the districts of Gulu, Nwoya, Amuru and Omoro. The project reached out to 10,147 farmers (40% female) organized in 150 Producer Business Groups (PBGs) with various tailored trainings and interventions intended to increase farm production and productivity for cotton, maize, beans and groundnuts, consequently increasing farmer incomes.

During this period, TechnoServe adopted a hybrid model of project implementation consisting of both direct service delivery and market systems facilitation. TechnoServe worked with partners such as Invisible Children on the Village Savings and Loans Association (VSLA) implementation; Victoria Seeds and Cotton Development Organisation (CDO) on access to input markets; Crane Bank, DFCU Bank, Post Bank and Micro Finance Support Centre on access to finance; Pentagon Technical Services and Agrinet on postharvest handling training; and Gulu Agricultural Development Company Limited (GADC), AFGRI, Opit &amp; Sons and Gira on output markets. The project coordinated well with the district local governments, lower local governments, Gulu University and other development partners in the areas of implementation.

Over the two years, the project nearly met or exceeded most targets and as a result, income for smallholder farmers increased for cotton and staple crops.  I  terms of the goal (Increased income and gender equality of 8000 small holder farmers) the project achieved the following:
1. Increased 10,000 smallholder farmers&#x2019; incomes by an average of 75% above the 2014 baseline; with 78% of female and male farmers reporting increased gender equality.

In terms of output targets, the following were achieved.

Output1: Increased inclusive market for small holder farmers
TechnoServe partnered with private sector companies, such as Gulu Agricultural Development Company Limited (GADCO), Victoria Seeds, Pentagon Technical Services, AFGRI, Cotton Development Organisation (CDO), and Agrinet, to increase farmers&#x2019; access to improved seeds, training, better and reliable markets, and access to credit. Strong progress on the indicators associated with this outcome were noted, including:
o 39% of PBGs capacity was enhanced to negotiate farmers&#x2019; access to better
markets/prices, compared to the 16% project target.
o 52.9% of farmers accessed credit versus a project target of 40% and baseline of 35.7%
Under Output 2: Increased adoption of production techniques by women and men, the following were achieved
o Farmers&#x2019; adoption of improved production techniques for cotton and staple crops increased from 52% in 2014 to 58% in 2016, just 2% below the project target.
o Improved incomes and yields were seen across all four targeted crops (beans by 44%, Ground nuts by 16%, Maize by 47% and Cotton by 40% between 2014 and 2016.
o 91 of 172 Business Service Providers (BSPs) interviewed reported increased annual turnover above UGX 500,000, with 34% of businesses growing from micro to mid-size enterprises, above the 20% project targets and 2% baseline though many BSPs have ceased their business efforts altogether.
o VSLAs remained the major source of credit to farmers despite the small loan values advanced.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51180068" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
