<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-07676886-5</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-07676886" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publish What You Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transparency on DFI (development finance institutions) use of public finance for development objectives</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment is research-informed advocacy aimed at increasing transparency of DFI financing (including concessionality and use of ODA, expected results, and realized impact) as a first step to influencing more accountable and effective use of public resources in relation to private sector investments targeting development objectives. Publish What You Fund seeks to influence DFIs to share more information that will enable policymakers to more accurately assess the public sector costs and development efficacy of DFI investments, to inform the appropriate mix of funding mechanisms/modalities to address the SDGs. The approach for influence will involve: (a) consultation/collaboration with DFIs by appealing to their interest to demonstrate added value and contribution to development objectives to their shareholders and building on the internal momentum of &#x201C;first mover&#x201D; DFIs like the IFC; (b) pushing on DFI justifications where they may be reluctant to share certain information by employing a variety of research &amp; advocacy levers including comparison and benchmarking; (c) advocacy through shareholder governments and DFI governance/oversight bodies; and (d) additional amplification from credible non-governmental stakeholders. While greater transparency on its own isn&#x2019;t sufficient for changing allocation decisions, the current increased political scrutiny of DFIs and calls for greater transparency at a global level intersect with momentum from a few influential institutions like the IFC both to improve their internal processes for allocating subsidies and to provide more public transparency on use of concessionality, development impact, etc. We see this investment as part of fulfilling our commitment to Bill during DPAF&#x2019;s Strategy Review to bring more transparency and evidence-based rigor to the conversation on blended finance and private sector instruments for development.

The objective of this investment is to increase transparency on the use of public funds (particularly ODA) to make private sector investments through DFIs, as a first step to enable shareholders/policymakers, practitioners and other stakeholders to assess the efficacy and cost effectiveness of these investments. This should enable more informed decisions about the allocation of funding to address the SDGs. In the longer term, the goal is to attain more efficient allocation of capital to have a greater impact on poverty alleviation and attainment of the SDGs. In order to achieve this, Publish What You Fund intends to engage the relevant stakeholders, including key DFIs, in a credible process to identify and understand the interplay between transparency and impactful investing, to produce transparency recommendations, and then advocate with key stakeholders for adoption of the recommendations. Finally, the project will analyse, define, and recommend the set of appropriate public good deliverables to measure progress on the transparency recommendations</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DAC-1601" role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-07676886" role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publish What You Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-07676886" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publish What You Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publish What You Fund</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Linda Grimsey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+44 20 3176 2512</telephone>
   <email>info@publishwhatyoufund.org</email>
   <website>http://www.publishwhatyoufund.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">China Works, Black Prince Road, London SE1 7SJ. United Kingdom</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
