<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GH-DSW-2046-LFSActivity#1-2020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GH-DSW-2046" secondary-reporter="0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEADING FROM THE SOUTH- GENERAL PROGRAMME 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading from the South is an initiative conceptualized for Women&#x2019;s Funds working on women&#x2019;s rights issues and gender equality within Africa and the MENA region, Asia, Latin America, and the Caribbean and globally. The fund is managed by four prominent Women&#x2019;s Funds: Fondo de Mujeres del Sur &#x2013;FMS- (Latin America and the Caribbean), the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund &#x2013;AWDF- (Africa and the MENA Region), the South Asia Women Fund &#x2013;SAWF- (Asia) and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum &#x2013;FIMI- (Global); supported and financed by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands. The aim of the initiative is to resource and support Women&#x2019;s Rights Organisations (Small grassroots, Intermediate, Large, and consortium/Networks) in the Global South in their advocacy work to achieve gender equality. African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund (AWDF) is a Pan-African grant-making organisation that funds local, national, and regional autonomous women&#x2019;s rights organisations in Africa and the Middle East, that are working towards the promotion and realisation African Women&#x2019;s Rights. Since the beginning of its operation in 2001, AWDF has awarded grants and provided technical support to over 1,340 women&#x2019;s organisations in 43 out of the 54 countries in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resource Women&apos;s Rights Organisations working on women&apos;s rights activism and gender equality in the Global South to achieve maximum results in their regions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The four Women&#x2019;s Funds: Fondo de Mujeres del Sur &#x2013;FMS- (Latin America and the Caribbean), the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund &#x2013;AWDF- (Africa and the MENA Region), the South Asia Women Fund &#x2013;SAWF- (Asia) and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum &#x2013;FIMI- (Global)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="LFSACTIVITY#1-2020" ref="GH-DSW-2046" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The date indicated above signifies the completion date for  the first phase of the four-year Leading from the South initiative.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The date indicated above signifies the start of activities under the LFS initiative for 2020.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-24">5500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="NOV/18/MAG/FRC/03">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-24">4400000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA-Donation towards the LFS initiative year four (4).</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSActivity#1-2020" ref="GH-DSW-2046" type="23">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region code="298" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">462935</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA-Opening Balance as at 01-01-2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSActivity#1-2020" ref="GH-DSW-2046" type="23">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region code="298" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MACRO-LEVEL: IMPROVED PRE-CONDITIONS / ENABLING ENVIRONMENT FOR WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Positive changes (adoption of new preconditions, blocking of negative ones, improvement of existing ones, implementation of existing ones) in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality, by type of changes (5 domains of change): 1.Change in control. 2.Changes in values and norms. 3.Changes in actions. 4.Changes in association. 5.Changes in resource allocations. Categories: 1) Processes towards positive change; 2) Actual change. Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </document-link>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of positive changes in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Positive changes (adoption of new preconditions, blocking of negative ones, improvement of existing ones, implementation of existing ones) in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality, by type of changes (5 domains of change): 1.Change in control. 2.Changes in values and norms. 3.Changes in actions. 4.Changes in association. 5.Changes in resource allocations. Categories: 1) Processes towards positive change; 2) Actual change. Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between 2017 and the first half of 2020, duty bearers took notice of the increasing public discourse around
women&#x2019;s rights issues and worked to put laws and policies in place that
protect women&#x2019;s rights to freedom from violence, economic security and
justice and political representation.
Advocacy work undertaken by grantees contributed to the reviews of at least 24
laws relating to VAW.
Furthermore, advocacy work undertaken by grantees contributed to the review of at least 12
laws regarding land reforms and succession as well as women&#x2019;s economic empowerment at national and district levels. 
The outcomes reported above will be updated once all grantee reports are received.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MESO-LEVEL: STRONG SOUTHERN WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS ORGANISATIONS ADVANCING WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations engaged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organisations (Small grassroots, Intermediate, Large and consortium/Networks)&#xA0; who are engaged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc.) Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions on different levels (formal and informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="107">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between 2017 and 2020, 107 organisations were resourced by AWDF under the Leading From the South initiative, to engage in
advocacy initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality in their constituencies and
countries.  The figure reported represents organisations that received support from the start of the project till its completion in  December, 2020.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MICRO-LEVEL: MORE WOMEN EXERCISE THEIR LEADERSHIP TO PROMOTE WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women and girls actively promoting/advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc). Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions on different levels (formal or informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Grantees&#xB4;beneficiaries (girls and women participating on the activities implemented by the grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1100"></target>
     <actual value="66551">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall, approximately 66,551 women  and girls across Africa and the Middle East have had access to information and learned about their human rights, marginalised communities of women and girls began to feel seen and heard as there has been a development of self-esteem and a sense that they matter-leading to the willingness to be visible, form networks, access services and demand rights. Gatekeepers such as traditional leaders understand why it is important to support and defend women&#x2019;s rights. 
Between 2017 and the first half of 2020, 19,882 women and 6091 girls worked with by AWDF grantees became actively engaged in advocating to end Violence Against Women.
Around 1,523 women and 387 girls have increased their participation in policy advocacy and are influencing some decision-making processes at all levels.
12, 114 women and girls showed a stronger sense of entitlement to rights and inclusion. About 1,817 women and 618 girls currently have access to decent and fair employment. Furthermore,  approximately 5590 women and 1014 girls actively participated in public
and political spaces at different levels. 
The outcomes reported above will be updated once all grantee reports are received.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
