<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GH-DSW-2046-LFSACTIVITY#1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GH-DSW-2046" secondary-reporter="0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading from the South- General Programme 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading from the South is an initiative conceptualized for Women&#x2019;s Funds working on women&#x2019;s rights issues and gender equality within Africa and the MENA region, Asia, Latin America and the Caribbean and globally. The fund is managed by four prominent Women&#x2019;s Funds: Fondo de Mujeres del Sur &#x2013;FMS- (Latin America and the Caribbean), the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund &#x2013;AWDF- (Africa and the MENA Region), the South Asia Women Fund &#x2013;SAWF- (Asia) and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum &#x2013;FIMI- (Global); supported and financed by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands. The aim of the initiative is to resource and support Women&#x2019;s Rights Organisations (Small grassroots, Intermediate, Large and consortium/Networks) in the Global South in their advocacy work to achieve gender equality. African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund (AWDF) is a Pan-African grant making organisation that funds local, national and regional autonomous women&#x2019;s rights organisations in Africa and the Middle East, that are working towards the promotion and realisation African Women&#x2019;s Rights. Since the beginning of its operation in 2001, AWDF has awarded grants and provided technical support to over 1,340 women&#x2019;s organisations in 43 out of the 54 countries in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resource Women&apos;s Rights Organisations working on women&apos;s rights activism and gender equality in the Global South to achieve maximum results in their regions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The four Women&#x2019;s Funds: Fondo de Mujeres del Sur &#x2013;FMS- (Latin America and the Caribbean), the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund &#x2013;AWDF- (Africa and the MENA Region), the South Asia Women Fund &#x2013;SAWF- (Asia) and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum &#x2013;FIMI- (Global)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSACTIVITY#1" ref="GH-DSW-2046" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-26" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The African Women&apos;s Development Fund received funds from the Dutch Foreign Ministry towards the 3rd year of the Leading from the South initiative on the date stated above.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The date indicated above signifies the scheduled end date of the four-year LFS initiative.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-26">7500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">1881817.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Opening Balance as at 01-01-2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSACTIVITY#1" ref="GH-DSW-2046" type="23">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region code="298" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="NOV/18/MAG/FRC/03">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">5929720.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MFA&apos;s donation towards the 3rd year of the Leading from the South (LFS) initiative.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSACTIVITY#1" ref="GH-DSW-2046" type="23">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region code="298" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MESO-LEVEL: STRONG SOUTHERN WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS ORGANISATIONS ADVANCING WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations engaged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations (Small grassroots, Intermediate, Large and consortium/Networks)&#xA0; who are engaged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc). Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions on different levels (formal and informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="31">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, 31 Women&#x2019;s Rights organisations in 16 countries across Africa and two (2) countries in the Middle East were resourced by the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund to engage in advocacy initiatives to advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality in their communities, nations and regions.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations establishing or consolidating alliances to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality.&#xA0;(Language: English)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations who are establishing or consolidating alliances to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality. Categories:1) Creating new alliances/undertaking joint actions or campaigns; 2) Strengthening existing alliances (for example, reactivating old alliances). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-01-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, seven women&#x2019;s rights organisations consolidated alliances and movements in their constituencies, nationally and regionally. Five organisations played leading roles in their alliances, 2 organisations were coordinators in their alliances and one organisation played a convening role. The women&#x2019;s rights organisations have established 4 new consortia and one technical group. There have been 13 joint actions with other women&#x2019;s alliances and collaboration on various advocacy initiatives. One organisation reported that they have formed a Human Rights club in 4 schools.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MICRO-LEVEL: MORE WOMEN EXERCISE THEIR LEADERSHIP TO PROMOTE WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women and girls actively promoting/advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc). Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions on different levels (formal or informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Grantees&#xB4;beneficiaries (girls and women participating on the activities implemented by the grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1100"></target>
     <actual value="24399">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, a total of 5390 women and girls (3,823 women and 1,567 girls) beneficiaries of AWDF grantees became actively engaged in advocating to end GBV within Africa. A total of 12,031 women and girls have shown a better sense of inclusion and entitlement. 1,024 women and 1,065 girls whose rights were violated accessed relevant support services (legal, medical, psychosocial and economic empowerment) they needed. The medical support was provided free of charge to the women and girls. Most of the cases of SGBV survivors were referred to the relevant agency for support. 2,040 women and 453 girls were engaged in advocating for economic participation and rights of women and girls. Approximately 1528 women and girls (1,253 women and 275 girls) increased their participation in policy advocacy and influencing decision making processes at all levels. Approximately 868&#x202C; women and girls (723 women and 136 girls) have accessed decent and fair employment through the support of AWDF grantees.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Macro-level: Improved pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of positive changes in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Positive changes (adoption of new preconditions, blocking of negative ones, improvement of existing ones, implementation of existing ones) in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality, by type of changes (5 domains of change): 1.Change in control. 2.Changes in values and norms. 3.Changes in actions. 4.Changes in association. 5.Changes in resource allocations. Categories: 1) Processes towards positive change; 2) Actual change. Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Qualitative"></target>
     <actual value="Qualitative">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, there were reviews of 6 laws regarding Land reforms and Succession in Uganda, Togo and Zimbabwe on the national level. The concerns of women and girls with disability were factored in the reviews. Two laws were enacted as a result of the constant advocacy and engagement of women&#x2019;s rights organisations with policymakers. The Law No. 2018-005 of 14 June 2018 on federal land codes which takes into account gender equality and the empowerment of women and the Code of Persons and Family of Togo in its Chapter III, Articles 413, 414, 427 are examples of laws that have been reviewed and enacted. There reviews of 7 laws relating to VAW in Uganda, South Africa, Nigeria and Kenya. These laws include the Protection against Domestic Violence Act of 2015, The Computer Misuse and Cybercrimes Act, The Children&#x2019;s Act and Sexual offences Act. New laws related to emerging forms of violence, for instance, Online Blackmail, Online solicitation of Minors, and issues are being considered. The combined efforts of women&#x2019;s rights organisations and civil society led to one law on VAW being enacted in Nigeria in 2019. Advocacy efforts of women&#x2019;s rights organisation and civil society in Liberia resulted in a national dialogue of traditional leaders which cumulated into a policy suspending the Sande (FGM) for a year Liberia. The Enugu State Violence against Persons (VAP) Bill was passed into law by the Enugu State House of Assembly in April 2019. 17 child marriages were annulled as a result a by-law that was enacted in consultation with traditional leaders. On the community level, 181 key influencers, including village heads, councillors, traditional and religious leaders, service providers and ambassadors were engaged to advocate against VAW. All the key influencers pledged their commitment to continuously advocate against VAW. 78 civil society organisations were also involved in advocating against VAW. Over 669 grassroots women, 10 persons living with disability and 1,468 members of the public have become aware of their rights and have engaged in advocacy against discriminative laws and VAW. 980 key influencers were engaged to advocate for women&#x2019;s economic independence and agency. Traditional leaders have demonstrated their commitment by donating 7.5 Acres (3 hectares) of land to 56 grassroots women collectively. 102 women also initiated an innovative revolving fund in June 2019. Over 20 women have gained the confidence to advocate with their husbands for inclusions as joint owners of their properties. Generally, more women are gaining access and ownership to land and other properties. 80 media houses including print and electronic (TV and radio) nationally and locally were engaged in discussing and educating their audiences on issues related to Gender-Based Violence and gender inequality. The topics discussed include issues related to women&#x2019;s rights, women&#x2019;s health, land ownership and VAW.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
