<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GH-DSW-2046-LFSActivity#1-2020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GH-DSW-2046" secondary-reporter="0" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LEADING FROM THE SOUTH- GENERAL PROGRAMME 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading from the South is an initiative conceptualized for Women&#x2019;s Funds working on women&#x2019;s rights issues and gender equality within Africa and the MENA region, Asia, Latin America, and the Caribbean and globally. The fund is managed by four prominent Women&#x2019;s Funds: Fondo de Mujeres del Sur &#x2013;FMS- (Latin America and the Caribbean), the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund &#x2013;AWDF- (Africa and the MENA Region), the South Asia Women Fund &#x2013;SAWF- (Asia) and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum &#x2013;FIMI- (Global); supported and financed by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands. The aim of the initiative is to resource and support Women&#x2019;s Rights Organisations (Small grassroots, Intermediate, Large, and consortium/Networks) in the Global South in their advocacy work to achieve gender equality. African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund (AWDF) is a Pan-African grant-making organisation that funds local, national, and regional autonomous women&#x2019;s rights organisations in Africa and the Middle East, that are working towards the promotion and realisation African Women&#x2019;s Rights. Since the beginning of its operation in 2001, AWDF has awarded grants and provided technical support to over 1,340 women&#x2019;s organisations in 43 out of the 54 countries in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resource Women&apos;s Rights Organisations working on women&apos;s rights activism and gender equality in the Global South to achieve maximum results in their regions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The four Women&#x2019;s Funds: Fondo de Mujeres del Sur &#x2013;FMS- (Latin America and the Caribbean), the African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund &#x2013;AWDF- (Africa and the MENA Region), the South Asia Women Fund &#x2013;SAWF- (Asia) and the International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum &#x2013;FIMI- (Global)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="LFSACTIVITY#1-2020" ref="GH-DSW-2046" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The date indicated above signifies the completion date for  the first phase of the four-year Leading from the South initiative.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The date indicated above signifies the start of activities under the LFS initiative for 2020.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-24">5500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="NOV/18/MAG/FRC/03">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-24">4400000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA-Donation towards the LFS initiative year four (4).</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSActivity#1-2020" ref="GH-DSW-2046" type="23">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region code="298" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">462935</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MFA-Opening Balance as at 01-01-2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29479" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GH-DSW-2046-LFSActivity#1-2020" ref="GH-DSW-2046" type="23">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Women&apos;s Development Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-region code="298" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MACRO-LEVEL: IMPROVED PRE-CONDITIONS / ENABLING ENVIRONMENT FOR WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Positive changes (adoption of new preconditions, blocking of negative ones, improvement of existing ones, implementation of existing ones) in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality, by type of changes (5 domains of change): 1.Change in control. 2.Changes in values and norms. 3.Changes in actions. 4.Changes in association. 5.Changes in resource allocations. Categories: 1) Processes towards positive change; 2) Actual change. Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of positive changes in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Positive changes (adoption of new preconditions, blocking of negative ones, improvement of existing ones, implementation of existing ones) in preconditions for enabling environment for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality, by type of changes (5 domains of change): 1.Change in control. 2.Changes in values and norms. 3.Changes in actions. 4.Changes in association. 5.Changes in resource allocations. Categories: 1) Processes towards positive change; 2) Actual change. Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-07"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2020, duty bearers took notice of the increasing public discourse around
women&#x2019;s rights issues and worked to put laws and policies in place that
protect women&#x2019;s rights to freedom from violence, economic security and
justice, land rights and political representation.
During the reporting period, grantee reports showed the review and formation of at least 4 laws and policies at the national , district and community levels. They also reported an improvement in the implementation of already existing laws and also increased commitment and support from duty bearers in the form of signing declarations and statements to uphold the law and apply it to the benefit of women and girls. Grantees also reported the formation of 3 committees and subgroups to  advocate and lobby for the change in laws and practices in their nation and communities.   Grantees engaged 1,012 key influencers including over 800 traditional and religious leaders, 47 local authorities, over ten civil society organisations, 25 councilors, 292 Sub County Land control board members and several other stakeholders to advocate for women&#x2019;s economic independence and agency. Grantees also engaged over 200 grassroots women and 793 members in the community in advocacy. Currently, the various projects have engaged women, men, traditional leaders, civil society, Police and media houses. These stakeholders increasingly recognise women&#x2019;s economic contributions and rights and have pledged their commitment to advocate for women&#x2019;s economic rights.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MESO-LEVEL: STRONG SOUTHERN WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS ORGANISATIONS ADVANCING WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations engaged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organisations (Small grassroots, Intermediate, Large and consortium/Networks)&#xA0; who are engaged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc.) Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions on different levels (formal and informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-07"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="48">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2020, 48 Women&apos;s Rights  Organisations (WROs) were resourced by AWDF under the Leading From the South initiative, to engage in advocacy initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality in their constituencies and countries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MICRO-LEVEL: MORE WOMEN EXERCISE THEIR LEADERSHIP TO PROMOTE WOMEN&#x2019;S RIGHTS AND GENDER EQUALITY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women and girls actively promoting/advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc). Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions on different levels (formal or informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Grantees&#xB4;beneficiaries (girls and women participating on the activities implemented by the grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-07"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1100"></target>
     <actual value="47447">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall, approximately 47,447
women  and girls across Africa and the Middle East have had access to information and learned about their human rights, marginalised communities of women and girls began to feel seen and heard as there has been a development of self-esteem and a sense that they matter-leading to the willingness to be visible, form networks, access services and demand rights. Gatekeepers such as traditional leaders understand why it is important to support and defend women&#x2019;s rights. 
In 2020,19,355 women and 6,672 girls became actively engaged in advocating for an end to violence against women across 16 countries in Africa and 3 countries in the Middle East
Per grantee reports, 1,479 women and 542 girls have increased their participation in policy advocacy and influencing some decision making processes at all levels.
 Furthermore,  Over 9,234 women (25 years and above) and 2,467 young women (18 - 25 years) reached were through awareness-raising on labour and economic rights. 
Approximately 4,547 women and 321 girls engaged in advocating for their economic and labour rights. 410 women (25 years and above) and 153 young women (18 - 25 years) have access to decent and fair employment through support from LFS projects, which have led to women gaining respect in their communities and households and becoming more involved in decision-making processes.
Also, from grantee reports, 1,104 women and 450 girls who experienced rights violations accessed support, including psychosocial, legal redress, educational, and medical support whenever the need arose. In addition, grantee organisations have worked towards the expansion and improvement of services for violence against women survivors by bringing to light, primarily through social media platforms, the trauma experienced by survivors.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
