<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-51756811-China-P1745</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asian Sustainable Palm Oil Network:Sustainable Palm Production &amp; Trade in Asia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the most significant achievements of the project has been the development and launch of the Indian Palm Oil Sustainability (IPOS) framework. IPOS provides India&#x2019;s own sustainability benchmark to the Indian palm oil industry for sustainable production and procurement. IPOS has been developed with the engagement of key Indian, Malaysian and Indonesian stakeholders. Through working committees and negotiations, this has resulted in &#x201C;national standards equivalence agreements&#x201D; between IPOS and the Malaysian Sustainable Palm Oil (MSPO) and between IPOS and the Indonesian Sustainable Palm Oil (Indonesian Sustainable Palm Oil (ISPO), signed in 2019. 

In China, we engaged with the China National Vegetable Oil Association (CNVOA) and leading companies such as COFCO. We facilitated the China Sustainable Palm Oil Working Group to mobilize Chinese stakeholders to support sustainable palm oil production and trade in Asia. Further, we support the CNVOA to develop a China National platform for better sector governance and the development of CPOS (China Sustainable Palm Oil Framework). Our work with key national stakeholders has been instrumental in promoting national sustainability initiatives and greater Asian alignment. 

This resulted in the establishment of the Asian Sustainable Palm Oil Network (ASPN) with representation of leading stakeholders of the palm oil sector from Malaysia, Indonesia, India and China. ASPN fosters regional cooperation and facilitates coordination, cooperation and alignment of the national sustainability standards on palm oil production and trade in Asia. This provides an important alternative for international standards, which are often very much Western lead firm dominated initiatives.  

Due to the political tensions between India and Malaysia, especially in the palm oil trade, some of the planned follow-up of the IPOS-MSPO equivalence agreement could not be implemented. However, with the change in government in Malaysia, the situation has improved in 2020. The Covid-19 crisis has significantly reduced our ability to convene dialogue and organize Network conferences. Most meetings were held online.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-51756811" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@solidaridadnetwork.org</email>
   <website>https://www.solidaridadnetwork.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">10000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41150939-00000578" ref="NL-KVK-41150939">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidaridad Europe</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">10000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
