<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2016160024</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AgroBIG II: Programme for Agro-Business Induced Growth in the Amhara National Regional State second phase</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">AgroBIG II: Tuki maatalousvetoiselle talouskasvulle Amharassa toinen vaihe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Hanke on toinen vaihe maatalousvetoista talouskavua tukevaa AgroBIG ohjelmaa (Programme for Agro-Business Induced Growth in the Amhara National Regional State). Hanke toteutetaan Etiopiassa Amharan osavaltiossa. OECD luokittelee Etiopian vahiten kehittynei
siin LDC maihin. Hankkeen ensimmaisen vaiheen tuloksiin kuuluu hankkeen kautta tuettujen maanviljelijoiden lisaantynyt sipulin ja maissin tuotanto. Hankkeessa perustetuista rahastoista on myonnetty tukea yli 170 erilaiseen projektiin.AgroBIG hankkeen toine
n vaihe toteutetaan 2017-2021. Toisen vaiheen pitkan aikavalin tavoitteena on etta maatalous tarjoaa osalle Amharan osavaltiossa asuvaa vaestoa kestavan kunnon elinkeinon seka parantuneen ruokaturvan.  Hankkeella on kaksi tavoitetta jotka sen odotetaan saa
vuttavan lyhyella aikavalilla:  1. Hankkeen alueella on kehitettyja arvoketjuja ja nama arvoketjut tuottavat maanviljelijoille osuuskunnille prosessoijille kauppiaille ja yksityisille palveluntuottajille lisaa tuloja. 2. Arvoketjut tuottavat tyopaikkoja ja
 tuloja mikro- pien- ja keskisuurille yrityksille seka naisille ja nuorille.Hankkeen tavoitteisiin paastaan saavuttamalla nelja konkreettista tulosta:  1. Arvoketjujen toimijoiden paasy rahoituksen piiriin ja siihen liittyviin palveluihin on parantunut .  
2. Valikoitujen maataloustuotteiden tuotanto on kasvanut. 3. Osuuskuntien tehokkuus arvoketjujen yhtena toimijana on tehostunut ja niiden toiminnan taloudellinen kestavyys on parantunut. 4. Mikro- pien- ja keskisuurilla yrityksilla on tarvittavat taidot ja
 resurssit ansaita tulonsa maatalouteen perustuvien aktiviteettien kautta. Hanketta tulee johtamaan valtiovarainministerion toimisto Amharassa. Suomi kilpailuttaa hankkeen tueksi myos asiantuntijatiimin.Suomen tuki hankkeelle on 94 miljoonaa euroa joka jak
aantuu: 2017: 1 miljoona 2018: 2 miljoonaa 2019: 23 miljoonaa 2020: 26 miljoonaa ja 2021: 15 miljoonaa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is the second phase of AgroBIG  (Programme for Agro-Business Induced Growth in the  Amhara National Regional State) that  supports rural economic development. The project will be implemented in  the Amhara National Regional State of Ethiopia wh
ich is one of the LDC countries. The results of the first phase include increased production of onion and maize by the beneficiaries. Over 170 projects in Amhara have been supported from the funds established in the project. The second phase of AgroBIG wil
l be implemented in 2017-2021. The aimed impact of the project is that agriculture provides decent and sustainable livelihood and increased food security  to its beneficiaries in rural Amhara regional state.  Two outcomes contribute to the impact of the Pr
ogramme and the first outcome needs to be achieved before the second can be achieved. They are 1. Value Chains in selected clusters provide increased income for farmers cooperatives processors traders and private service providers. 2: Agricultural value ch
ains provide jobs and income for Micro Small and Medium Enterprises (MSMEs) and for women and youth. The expected outputs are:1: Value chain actors access to finance and financial services is improved. 2: Agricultural farm productivity in selected crops is
 increased. 3: Cooperatives effectiveness as value chain actors is increased and  their economical sustainability is improved and 4 MSMEs  and women and youth have skills and resources to earn their income from agriculture-based activities. The project wil
l be managed by the Bureau of Finance and Economic Cooperation in Amhara National Regional State. Finland will also procure via open tendering a technical assistance team to support the project.Finland&apos;s support is on 9.4 millions with following annual div
ision:  2017: 1 million 2018: 2 million 2019: 23 million 2020: 2.6 million and  2021: 15 million.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="61009" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niras Finland Oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-2016160024" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-13" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the secondary priority area in t
his activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2130610</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2517000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2850000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">3000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">900000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2385527</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-2016160024" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
