<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2009091236</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the electric power supply reliability in Dar es Salaam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the project is to support sustainable economic and social development in Tanzania by strengthening the power distribution network in Dar es Salaam through rehabilitation and provision of a SCADA system. The project will improve the reliabi
lity of power supply and reduce technical losses in the power distribution network. The distribution network is overloaded and over-aged which increases losses and leads to constant operational shutdowns. Without well operating power supply the development
 prospects of the private sector remain weak which will have a negative impact on the national economy. The reliability of power supply will have impact on the operations of the companies and industries public sector institutions (schools hospitals and hea
lth centers) and on daily lives of individuals. One important beneficiary group are small entrepreneurs many of which are women. Inefficient power distribution with an obsolete system that causes constant power cuts is also harmful to the environment. Tane
sco (Tanzanian governments power supply company) is in charge of the project. Hifab Oy provides consultancy services for  the design and supervision of the contract works and Eltel Group Oy is the contractor. The projects planning phase started in 2010 and
 contract work in 2013. The contract work is delayed. It is estimated to be completed by the end of April 2016.  Major part of equipment and materials have been delivered to Tanzania. The new substation and control center buildings and equipment are pendin
g finalization. Commissioning of the SCADA/DMS system is under completion.  Most of the underground cables have been installed. Tanescos personnel has been trained for the tasks of the substations and centralized power system control. The remaining works i
nclude finalization of the buildings completion of the installation and commissioning of  the equipment and cables. The training of Tanesco personnel will continue till the completion of the contract.Finlands financial contribution of the original budget o
f the project is 265 million . For the completion of the project  there is need for additional financing out of which Finland s share is 02 million .Additional financing will be used for the supervision of the contract works training of the local personnel
 and additional variations of the contract work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="3" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultants</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="23630" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2646</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
