<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-1999993693</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida International ry</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tavoitteena tulevaisuus ? turvallinen koulutuspolku ja elinymparisto lapsille ja nuorille</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida&apos;s Development Cooperation Programme Transformed People - Transformed Communities began in 2014.  The biggest change in the programme has occurred in regard to cooperation countries. In 2014 Fida had 32 countries of cooperation and in 2016 only 17. The
 programme emphasizes the empowerment of partners which affects the reduction of poverty as well as the strengthening of equality civil society and human rights in the partners&apos; sphere of influence. The main concentration of the work is the improvement of 
the wellbeing of children and youth improvement of pre- primary- and vocational education preventive health care livelihood practice food security and peacebuilding promotion. Equality democracy and human rights are promoted through training partners into 
social responsibility. The cross-cutting objectives of the programme are gender people living with disabilities HIV/AIDS the environment and climate change culture and peacebuilding.The following guidelines and strategic principles still drive Fida&apos;s devel
opment cooperation work; partnership  rights-based approach community centered action inclusive cooperation ownership holistic well being sustainability growth and multiplication of work and the transmission of love for one&apos;s neighbour.Fida&apos;s new vision fo
r development cooperation strategy (Fida catalyzes and equips churches to act as strong societal advocates so that the rights of vulnerable children and youth are realized) will steer Fida&apos;s work more and more towards rights-based advocacy work.In 2017 Fid
a will have five regional programmes in South-East Asia Eastern Africa South Asia East Asia and the Middle-East and Central Asia. There are 17 cooperation countries and 32 projects.Fida International ry has been granted  4 700 000 euros for 2017 for its de
velopment co-operation activities.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Fidan kehitysyhteistyoohjelma 2022-2025 ?Tavoitteena tulevaisuus ? turvallinen koulutuspolku ja elinymparisto lapsille ja nuorille? muodostuu 11 maaohjelmasta joita toteutetaan paikallisten kumppaneiden kanssa Itaisessa Afrikassa Aasiassa ja Lahi-idassa se
ka Kotimaan ohjelmasta johon sisaltyy kehitysviestinta globaalikasvatus ja vaikuttamistyo.Ohjelman pitkan aikavalin kehitystavoite on Lasten ja nuorten parantuneet mahdollisuudet koulutukseen ja turvallisempi elinymparisto ohjelmamaissa.Ohjelman valittomat
 tavoitteet ovat1) Lasten ja nuorten erityisesti tyttojen ja vammaisten lasten oikeus koulutukseen ja sen toteutuminen on vahvistunutFida International | Ohjelmamuotoisen kehitysyhteistyon valtionavustushaun 2022-2025 vaihe 2.2) Lasten ja nuorten erityises
ti tyttojen ja vammaisten lasten oikeudet turvallisen elinymparistonsaavuttamiseksi ja niiden toteutuminen ovat vahvistuneet3) Kumppaniorganisaatioiden hallinto- ja talouskaytanteet ovat parantuneet ja heidan sitoutumisensatoimia innovatiivisesti lasten ja
 nuorten erityisesti tyttojen ja vammaisten lasten oikeuksientoteutumiseksi on vahvistunut.4) Kotimaan ohjelman kohderyhmien lisaantynyt sitoutuminen edistaa lasten oikeuksia laadukkaaseenkoulutukseen ja turvalliseen elinymparistoon globaalisti.Maaohjelmis
sa keskitytaan lapsen oikeuksiin saada koulutusta seka liittyen turvalliseen elinymparistoon.Koulutus keskittyy laadukkaan ja inklusiivisen opetuksen kehittamiseen informaaliin ja jatkuvaanoppimiseen. Turvallinen elinymparisto huomioi henkilokohtaisen yhte
ison ja terveydellisenturvallisuuden seka ruoka- ja taloudellisen turvan. Lapileikkaavat tavoitteet gender vammaiset henkilotseka ymparisto ja ilmastokestavyys ovat osa jokaista teemaa.Oikeuksienhaltijat ja vastuunkantajat ovat osallisena Ohjelmassa suunni
ttelusta toteuttamiseen.Paahyodynsaajina ovat lapset ja nuoret oikeuksienhaltijoina joiden oikeuksien toteutumiseksi toimintojakohdistetaan myos vastuunkantajiin ml. vanhemmat opettajat ja viranomaiset. Ohjelma tukee avointaja tasa-arvoista valtion ja kans
alaisyhteiskunnan vuoropuhelua. Valittomia hyodynsaajia on n. 484 000joista lapsia ja nuoria 269 000 ja vammaisia henkiloita 32 300. Valillisia hyodynsaajia arvioidaan olevan 35miljoonaa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida International ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-1999993693" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-03-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Afghanistan;Bangladesh;Bhutan;Burundi;Cambodia;Eth"></location>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the secondary priority area in t
his activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is the main priority area in this activ
ity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">4700000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">4700000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">5600000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">5600000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">624561</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-1999993693" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
