<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2018181651</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Livelihood and Small Business Training in refugee settlement and urban Kampala</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Most refugees in Uganda live at subsistence level, and over 70% depend on the food assistance. Lack of land but also skills and knowledge, low educational level to improve livelihoods and income generation are challenges the refugees, and Ugandans, face da
ily. In line with the CRRF of the Govt of Uganda the project contributes towards increased self-reliance of refugees by strengthening resilience capacities of beneficiaries to cope better with current obstacles and to become less vulnerable in future, by i
mproving their livelihood skills and access to resources. The project arranges short courses on Business Skill for refugees and for Ugandans living near settlements and in Urban Kampala. The other support provided is facilitation of formation of saving and
 loan groups  the project trains the group on principles of VSLA activity and donates a saving kit to each group formed. Both Business Skill and saving trainings are followed by mentoring and advisory services from the professional project staff. The benef
iciaries are expected to enhance their ability to meet essential needs and to enjoy social and economic rights as part of their progress towards self-reliance.The general target group is refugees above 15 years old, who reside in Uganda in settlements or u
rban Kampala area, and their educational and skill level is in need of improvement. Special attention is put on the equal participation of women and youth. The target for women participants is 50% whereas target for people with special needs is 3 - 5% of b
eneficiaries. As recommended by OPM and UNHCR, the project will also target Ugandans living nearby settlements so that they are about 20%. As direct beneficiaries the 160 individual Business Skill Facilitators gain important skills and capacities in teachi
ng and facilitation, and knowledge in business and livelihood related matters. They are trained to teach the 8-module course for the business learning group, and have a key role in implementing the project. Largest nationality group targeted will be South 
Sudanese in settlements in North Uganda, followed by refugees from DRC, Burundi, Rwanda and Somalia in settlements in South West Uganda. Majority of refugees arrive from villages with skills and experience related to agriculture and livestock rearing. Howe
ver, at settlements their opportunities to practise agriculture are limited due to restricted access to land, farm inputs and markets. The project is implemented by FRC field staff.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-11-02" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Kampala, Isingiro"></location>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">577190</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">577190</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
