<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2017170009</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FLC: The Future is better for The Egyptians and Refugees Children and Women project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">The Future is better for The Egyptians and Refugees children and Women project FBER-CW it is Bashayer NGO response for the education services needs for 5629 refugees accommodated in Helwan and another Egyptian target groups ?the out of school children and 
illiterate women in Helwan?. The overall objective is: Enhance the access to education opportunities (formal and non-formal) for the Refugees unaccompanied minors Egyptians out of school children the young women and women in Helwan.FBER-CW project will pro
vide a comprehensive development interventions for 610 direct beneficiaries and 3571 as indirect beneficiaries. The main activities in the propose project: local authorities and civil society actors capacity building on the Refugees and Egyptians education
 rights in Helwan advocacy camping for the Education rights Support the enrollment for the Egyptians out of schools and illiterate women in the public schools and the community education provide a Community Based Psychosocial Support services teachers trai
ning M+E and communication documentation and project visibility activities. FBER-CW project is Human Rights Based Approach project and targeted to enhance the capacity of the Rights-holders Duty-bearers and Responsible Actors in Helwan as well as prompting
 the education rights for the project target groups.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Future is better for The Egyptians and Refugees children and Women project FBER-CW it is Bashayer NGO response for the education services needs for 5629 refugees accommodated in Helwan and another Egyptian target groups the out of school children and i
lliterate women in Helwan. The overall objective is: Enhance the access to education opportunities (formal and non-formal) for the Refugees unaccompanied minors Egyptians out of school children the young women and women in Helwan.FBER-CW project will provi
de a comprehensive development interventions for 610 direct beneficiaries and 3571 as indirect beneficiaries. The main activities in the propose project: local authorities and civil society actors capacity building on the Refugees and Egyptians education r
ights in Helwan advocacy camping for the Education rights Support the enrollment for the Egyptians out of schools and illiterate women in the public schools and the community education provide a Community Based Psychosocial Support services teachers traini
ng M+E and communication documentation and project visibility activities. FBER-CW project is Human Rights Based Approach project and targeted to enhance the capacity of the Rights-holders Duty-bearers and Responsible Actors in Helwan as well as prompting t
he education rights for the project target groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="23000" ref="23000-1" role="3" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kehitysmaan kansalaisj&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-2017170009" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-16" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edist&#xE4;v&#xE4;</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muut momentit</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other budget lines</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is the main priority area in this activ
ity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">37400</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-2017170009" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
