<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2014140770</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Tax Administration Forum - ATAF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Tax Administration  Forum - ATAF (http://www.ataftax.net/en/) is an organisation of Tax Administrations of 38 African countries. It was established in 2009 to promote efficient and effective tax administration to improve the living standards of the
 people of Africa. ATAF strives to provide a platform to improve the performance of tax administration in Africa. Better tax administration will enhance economic growth increase accountability of the state to its citizens and effectively mobilise domestic 
resources.The following strategic objectives have been defined for 20162020:1. Developing a sustainable member-orientated African organisation on tax matters2. Fostering efficient and effective African tax administrations3. Driving the knowledge hub on Afr
ican tax matters4. Informing and influencing the regional and global dialogue as the African voice in the field of taxationATAF provides to its member countries peer learning networking consultation research conferences and training such as the master prog
ramme on taxation. The activities are based on the needs of member states. ATAF has quite fast become a respective international Pan-African organisation. According to its evaluation (2016) the capacity developing programmes have not only become larger but
 they also respond better than before to the needs of their members related to the substance method and quality. For example developing the statics or training on mining industry are new elements in its programme. African networks on tax research and legal
 advice were started in 2015 and technical support was also increased. Finland has pledged its support to strengthening the tax base of developing countries in the Agenda 2030 and in the Addis Abeban Action Plan where Finland committed to double the suppor
t for Tax and Development. To develop taxation is in accordance with 3. priority area of Finnish development policy (Societies have become more democratic and better-functioning).Finland&apos;s contribution for ATAF is 600 000  in 2017-2019.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47141" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Tax Administration Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-25" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Africa"></location>
  <sector code="15114" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">200000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
