<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2018180391</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">School of Independent Life - Employment and economic sustainability of women with disabilities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women with disabilities are not covered by quality education and lead an isolated lifestyle more often. They are one of the most vulnerable groups in society. Safoi Konibodom -PO was created by women with disabilities who know the problem from the inside. 
This process will give an opportunity to identify the needs and problems of women with disabilities in their life activities as well as to identify among them interesting active personalities who will later participate in the School.The goal of the project
 is to improve the life standard of 20 girls and women with disabilities by conducting the School (training) on the topics of employment and economic sustainability of girls and women with disabilities. To ensure that in the future they were able to indepe
ndently manage their life and dispose of their financial means.1. Conducting focus groups to identify interested girls and women with disabilities to participate in the School conducting 6 focus groups in the city of Kanibadam (2 focus groups) Khujand (1 f
ocus group)Gafurovsky district (2 focus groups) Istaravshan (1 focus group) of the Sugdi region are necessary for identifying potential personalities strong personalities or with competitive business ideas among girls and women with disabilities who will l
ater participate in the School.2. The school will include a 5-day training program that will be conducted by experienced trainers from Helsinki Mavluda Peiponen and Novikov Dmitry - representatives of the organization The Association of the Central Asian n
ation&apos;s Julduz ry which successfully implemented the project in Uzbekistan.The project development objective is to improve the social position of people with disabilities. This project will promote small businesses and related training and regional network
ing with other organizations and private sector.The main features of the project are; support environment allowing training to invest into entrepreneurship development of responsible business create decent jobs and stimulate private sector and civil societ
y partnerships networking. The project will reinforce the existing structures and support the anti-poverty development. In Uzbekistan 24 trainings were held with 100 beneficiaries. 100 women with disabilities had courses in needlework and craftsmanship. 20
 fairs of sales of their products were established. 100 beneficiaries received self-employment skills. Five home needlework businesses were established.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11001" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="67102219" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="FI-3">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-17" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TJ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Central Asia"></location>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muu</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP1 is primary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP2 is secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PP3 is secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">14214</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">14214</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
