<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2017170053</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Wildlife Society - promoting sustainable management of Mt. Suswa conservancy for community livelihood improvement and security</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mt. Suswa conservancy management is faced by a number of governance issues that have inclination on the overall governance of the conservancy. Firstly there is lack of women inclusion in the conservancy leadership. Currently there is no inclusion of women 
in the conservancy leadership yet women are the most affected by decisions made in the governance of natural resources. This project will therefore train the conservancy management on the need for inclusion of women in the decision making process and help 
them develop policies that puts inclusion of women in the management as a requirement as enshrined in the Kenyan constitution 2010. Women inclusion will also be addressed by helping the conservancy develop a business plan that will provide women with more 
opportunities. In addition a few women will be trained as rangers to enhance their participation in natural governance. In addition the conservancy currently has only five trained rangers who cannot patrol the expansive area with only few equipment to unde
rtake surveillance and monitoring of this expansive conservation area. In order to address this EAWLS will train the management on the aforementioned enhance their capacity to discharge their mandates effectively and efficiently thus improving the overall 
management. An exchange visit will be facilitated between the conservancy management and rangers between Mt. Suswa conservancy and Mara conservancy to enhance cross learning and further horn their skills. Furthermore the rangers will be provided with suppo
rt tools such as GPs sets bicycle and cameras among others to enhance their daily operations. Mt. Suswa conservancy is faced with varied challenges including illegal logging for charcoal burning destruction of trees and shrubs for medicinal purposes poachi
ng of wildlife for meat and human wildlife conflicts. These threats have far reaching impacts on the ecosystem. . Local communities are the perpetrators of these threats and can be attributed to high poverty levels low levels of environmental awareness and
 lack of diverse livelihood sources. Besides these threats Mt. Suswa conservancy also faces a myriad of governance challenges given the expanse of land it covers. These includes inadequate equipment needed for surveillance and ecological monitoring inter-c
ounty conflict on revenues (considering the conservancy is inter-county) inadequate technical capacity among the personnel on governance and lack of enough human capacity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">6000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
