<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2017170307</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Consolidating and strengthening the human rights gains made for female sex workers? and MSMs? sake in Kisumu</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the project is to contribute to the realization of sex workers &apos;rights, particularly access to justice and access to health services by increasing the awareness of the sex workers&apos; rights of the relevant authorities and health-care pr
oviders and the general public. Kash has done similar work for several years in Kisumu, but there  is a strong need to continue.Paralegals are trained in the project in order to increase the legal awareness of sex workers and  to help the access of sex wor
kers to legal and other aid if necessary. There will be more  dialogue between the authorities and the sex workers and sex workers will more easily to get proper service and help, for example form  the police, judicial authorities and health professionals,
 and are less likely to be victims of human rights violations by the authorities. The project will also increase understanding of the challenges that the sex workers are facing and to improve the measures to promote the implementation of their rights.The p
rimary target group of the project are sex workers, and in particular sex workers acting as paralegals, who will be trained during the project and participate in the dialogues  with various authorities. The project also provides legal advice in larger numb
er of  number of sex workers, as well as support for at least six victims of sexual violence in processing the case. The second target group of the project consists in the police, health authorities and judicial authorities, who will participate in the tra
inings of the project and discussion forums. The third target group are other organisations, which visit KASH in order to learn  how Kash puts into practice the work for  the promotion of  the rights of sex workers. Keeping Hope Alive Societies Kash was or
iginally established in 2004, as a community-based organization and was registered in 2004 as an NGO. Kash works in western Kenya to promote primarily sex workers and sexual minorities&apos; rights and to reduce the stigma against these groups.  Kash promotes t
he dialogue between the different parties and do  advocacy, information and training work to achieve its objectives. Kash cooperates with the police and the health authorities. www.kash.or.ke</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Kisumu"></location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">3510</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">3510</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
