<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2016161138</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: TUNDANDOTO TANZANIA PROGRAMME  SUSTAINABLY TRANSFORMED CHILDHOODS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main beneficiaries of the Programme are Tanzanian children and youth. Children, youth with disabilities, and girls are the special target groups. The Programme has 23 530 direct and 68 840 indirect beneficiaries. The activities are carried out in 6 dif
ferent geographical areas that act either as a demo project for the other sites or in which a special set of barriers obstructing the fulfilment of childrens rights have been identified. The main problem in the society is the lack of knowledge on childrens
 rights for both rights holders and duty bearers. For this reason, civil society and authorities do not pay so much attention to the wellbeing and development of children. The Programme will be implemented by a Tanzanian partner, Free Pentecostal Church of
 Tanzania which is a remarkable influence in the Tanzanian civil society. In addition to its approximately 800 000 members, FPCT has an extensive network of local and government actors within its realm of cooperation and influence. The Programme seeks to s
trengthen the advocacy roles of different civil society actors and FPCT regarding childrens rights. The Programme theme, right to health is addressed in different levels through a knowledge increase regarding nutrition and preventive health, care takers ab
ility to respond to health challenges of children with disabilities, and sexual and reproductive health and rights. In the latter the Programme especially targets menstruation management, hygiene and psychosocial support for traumatized children. That the 
beneficiaries organize into civil society groups that promote the right to health is among the main activities. The theme right to education is addressed in the Programme through multiple activities: by empowering caretakers to realize childrens right to e
ducation, by providing support for better school performance and self-esteem development through childrens clubs, by sensitizing communities on the importance of education and strengthening participatory methods in education. Regarding the theme right to a
dequate standard of living, the activities include introducing initiatives that strengthen family livelihood, improved food security, improved living environment, and life and entrepreneurship skills especially among women and PWD. #The quality of the part
ners advocacy work is strengthened through developing platforms, where the voice of children with and without disabilities can be heard by the wider public.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fida International ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-2016161138" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Losikito, Tanga, Zanzibar, Mwanza, Kigoma, Lindi"></location>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">1499642</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">1499642</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">347706</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-2016161138" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
