<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2016160225</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding Facility for Immediate Stabilization in Iraq (FFIS) UNDP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Irakin vakauttamisrahasto FFIS UNDP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Irak kamppailee lukuisten haasteiden kanssa joiden ratkaisemiseksi se tarvitsee pitkaaikaista kansainvalisen yhteison tukea. Vuonna 2003 alkaneen konfliktin ja viime vuosina etenkin terroristijarjesto ISIL:in aiheuttaman sekasorron vuoksi maan turvallisuus
- ja humanitaarinen tilanne jatkuu vaikeana. Tarpeet ovat valtavat: Maassa on yli kolme miljoonaa sisaista pakolaista ja lahes yhdeksan miljoonaa ihmista elaa hataavun varassa. UNDP:n Irakin vakauttamisrahasto (FFS) tukee ISIL:lta vapautettujen alueiden va
litonta vakautusta ja mahdollistaa paikallisvaeston paluun koteihinsa kestavalla tavalla viidessa maakunnassa: Salah al-Din Ninewah Anbar Kirkuk ja Diyala. Rahasto toimii tiiviissa yhteistyossa Irakin viranomaisten kanssa ja se on keskeinen osa Irakin kans
allisia vakauttamistoimia.Kaytannossa rahasto 1) toteuttaa ISIL:ta vallatuilla alueilla julkisen infrastruktuurin jalleenrakennushankkeita; 2) tukee paikallisten elinkeinojen elpymista ja tyopaikkojen syntymista; seka 3) edistaa paikallishallintojen kehitt
amista ja oikeusvaltioperiaatteen toteutumista. Vuonna 2017 rahasto laajeni merkittavasti samalla kun Irakin hallinto sai vapautettua laajoja alueita ISIL:ilta. Rahaston tulokset ovat vaikuttavia: Rahaston tuella on edesautettu jopa 3.9 miljoonan maan sisa
isen pakolaisen palaamista koteihinsa.  Eniten toteutettuja hankkeita on opetussektorilla mutta rahallisesti eniten tukea on annettu terveyssektorin jalleenrakentamiseen seka sahkoverkkojen kunnostamiseen.Naiset on huomioitu hyvin hankkeen hyodynsaajina: t
oiminnassa annetaan erityishuomiota naisten elinkeinojen kehittamiseen. Vuoden 2017 aikana edunsaajista 1.4 miljoonaa oli naisia. Suomi on mukana hankkeen ohjausryhmassa Bagdadissa: Suomen vaikuttamistavoitteina keskitytaan edistamaan naisten oikeuksia ja 
osuutta hyodynsaajista seka syrjimattomyysperiaatteen toteutumista.FFS-rahasto toimii hyvin korkean riskin alueella valittomien sotatoimien juuri paatyttya. Irakin vaikeasta sisapoliittisesta tilanteesta johtuen myos poliittiset riskit ovat korkeat. UNDP:n
 riskienhallinta on kuitenkin hyvalla tasolla. Riski on siis perusteltua ottaa.Rahaston koko oli vuoden 2018 alussa 703 MUSD. Suomi myonsi rahaston kayttoon vuonna 2016 yhteensa 4 MEUR. Nyt tehtava lisamyonto on kooltaan 5 MEUR ja kattaa rahaston toimintaa
 vuosina 2018?2019.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq is struggling with a multitude of challenges needing long-term support by the international community. Security situation is challenging due to presence of ISIL and due to tensions between ethnic groups. After a long internal conflict the humanitarian
 situation continues alarming. An estimated 9 million people are in need of support. Internally displaced persons (IDPs) amount to over 3 million.UNDPs Funding Facility for Immediate Stabilization (FFIS/FFS) aims to support the Iraqi Government to address 
the immediate stabilization needs in newly accessible areas allowing the sustainable return of IDPs. Currently the Fund is active in the governorates of Salah al-Din Ninewah Anbar Kirkuk and Diyala. The Fund operates in close cooperation with the authoriti
es and it is an integral part of the Governments national stabilization efforts.The fund implements projects through the following windows: 1) Public works and light infrastructure rehabilitation in areas occupied from the ISIL; 2) Support to jump-starting
 livelihoods and jobs creation initiatives; 3) Local governance and rule of law capacity building. In 2017 the Funds operations increased substantially as the Iraqi authorities managed to liberate new territories from the ISIL. The results have been signif
icant. The Fund has supported activities in liberated areas that have enabled the return of 3.9 million IDPs to their homes. In terms of number of supported projects the education sector has received most support whereas in terms of amount of financing the
 health sector and the energy sector have been the largest recipients.A special focus has been taken to increase the number of women as beneficiaries. In particular women&apos;s economic empowerment is emphasized. In 2017 1.4 million women were beneficiaries of
 the activities funded by FFIS. Finland participates in the Steering Committee in Baghdad and advocates for advancing women&apos;s rights and non-discrimination in the supported activities.The activities are implemented in a very high risk environment often dir
ectly after the fighting has ceased. Due to the difficult internal political situation the political risks are also high. However the UNDP risk management system is considered adequate. By 2018 the contributions to the Fund amount to 703 MUSD. Finland has 
funded the FFIS by 4 million euros in 2016. The funding decision for 2018 is 5 million euros covering operations in 2018-2019.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Development Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n kehitysohjelma</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-2016160225" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-19" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">5000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">5000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-2016160225" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
