<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2013130480</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development cooperation programme Fairtrade Finland</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Reilu kauppa ry:n kehitysyhteistyoohjelma</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fairtrade is a non-profit movement focusing on the empowerment of small farmers and workers through fair and sustainable trade. Certifications are vital tools to enable development but are not sufficient to tackle the persistent challenges like climate cha
nge child + forced labour exclusion of immigrants or people with disabilities and gender equality.The programme aims to ensure the rights of the producers and workers to a dignified life. This goal will be pursued through 3 components: -right to a sustaina
ble livelihood for producers -right to a sustainable livelihood for workers -fair and sustainable tradingThe programme also promotes 3 cross-cutting themes based on the values of Fairtrade: environmental sustainability vulnerable people and gender equality
. The comprehensive programme communication component raises awareness about the impact of the programme among Finns who ordinarily are not informed about development cooperation. The programme focuses on the LDCs and fragile states in Latin America and Af
rica + Middle East. Three upper middle income countries are included because they host target groups with particular vulnerabilities: integration of Syrian refugees and Zimbabwean and Haitian migrants. The partner organizations in the South are local netwo
rks representing farmers and agricultural workers. The programme supports a total of 295000 rightsholders of which 47 % are women.The effectiveness of the programme is based on results-oriented approach local ownership harmonization strong partnerships tra
nsparency rights-based approach and efficiency. The programmes sustainability is embedded in Fairtrade standards participatory planning robust programme-level monitoring system minimal aid dependency sustainable exit strategies rigorous risk management and
 anti-corruption policy. Fairtrades expertise in linking the whole value chain enables us to ensure the sustainability of the programmes results and impact.The programme draws substantial additional co-financing from companies and other Fairtrade organizat
ions as well as license fees from Fairtrade sales. The administrational costs will be kept low at around 3-4% of total.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Reilu kauppa on voittoa tavoittelematon kansanliike ja globaali muutosagentti jonka tavoitteena on turvatahaavoittuville viljelijoille ja tyontekijoille saallinen ja kestava toimeentulo. Suomen Reilu kauppa ry on Reilunkaupan ohjelmatyon pioneeri ja sen ke
hitysyhteistyo taydentaa Reilun kaupan interventioita haasteissa joitatiukatkaan sertifiointikriteerit eivat yksin ratkaise: ilmastonmuutos lapsi- ja pakkotyo metsakato biodiversiteetinheikkeneminen seka ikaan sukupuoleen ja vammaisuuteen perustuva syrjint
a.Ohjelman viitekehyksena on Kate Raworthin donitsimalli. Se maarittelee sosiaalisen perustan ja ekologisenkaton valissa olevan alueen jonka sisalla ihmistoiminta on kestavalla pohjalla. Ohjelman kehitystavoitteena onnostaa oikeudenhaltijat kestavan elaman
 perustuksille aiheuttamatta saroja kestavan elamanpiirin ulkokehalle.Muutosteorian osat koostuvat sosiaalisesta taloudellisesta ja ekologisesta kestavyydesta.Hiilinegatiivisen ohjelman lapileikkaavat tavoitteet ovat sukupuolten tasa-arvo nuoriso ja haavoi
ttuvat henkiloterityisesti vammaiset. Ohjelma vahvistaa haavoittuvien tyontekijoiden ja viljelijoiden jarjestojen kapasiteettia jakehittaa niiden - esimerkiksi ammattiliittojen - toimintaymparistoa. Tahtaamme koko arvoketjun kattavaansysteemiseen muutoksee
n monitasoiseen vaikuttamistyohon ja muutosta kirittavaan aktivoivaan viestintaan.Ohjelman vaikuttavuus perustuu tehokkuuteen paikalliseen omistajuuteen seka holistiseen tulos- jaoikeusperustaiseen lahestymistapaan. Sen kestavyys pohjaa Reilun kaupan krite
ereihin osallistavaansuunnitteluun vahaiseen apuriippuvuuteen kestaviin exit-strategioihin hyvaan riskienhallintaan ja kattavaanseurantajarjestelmaan. Pilotoimme innovatiivisia toimintatapoja kuten reiluja paastohyvityksia tuotesivuvirtojenhyodyntamista ja
 oikeudenhaltijalahtoista HREDD-dialogia.Ohjelma keskittyy hauraisiin ja LDC-maihin erityisesti Afrikassa. Kumppaneina ovat viljelijoiden jamaataloustyontekijoiden paikalliset verkostot. Mukana on myos merkittavia yrityksia kansalaisjarjestojakaupunkeja ja
 muita sidosryhmia. Suorina hyodynsaajina on noin 139 000 oikeudenhaltijaa joista 61% onnaisia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fairtrade Finland</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Reilu Kauppa ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-2013130480" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-13" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Dominican Republic;Ethiopia;Ghana;Guatemala;Haiti;"></location>
  <sector code="31162" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 4, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving food security, access to water and sustainability is the secondary priority area in t
his activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">900000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">1040000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">1391000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">1391000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">115784</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">209774</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-2013130480" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
