<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2018-2013130273</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNODC Regional Programme for Afghanistan and Neighbouring Countries 2016-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">UNODC alueellinen huumeidenvastainen ohjelma 2016-19 Afganistan ja naapurimaat (jatkohanke)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finland supports UNODC Regional Programme for Afghanistan + Neighbouring Countries (2016-2019). The Programme promotes cooperation between Afghanistan and its neighbors namely Iran Kazakhstan Kyrgyzstan Pakistan Tajikistan Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan and s
upports creating a better common response to countering the destabilizing impact of illicit drugs and crime. The Programme supports the build-up of new approaches strengthens the existing good practices and increases capacity in the region to enable greate
r counter-narcotics achievements both regionally and globally. Countering cross-border narco-trafficking requires coordinated regional and international measures as acknowledged in many UN Security Council Resolutions and international conferences.  Politi
cal and practical regional cooperation and finding common solutions is a key in solving the challenges. Drug control is not a one-dimensional stand-alone issue but it is an integral part of a wider process that delivers development security and governance.
 It is important to mainstream counter-narcotics throughout wider efforts in bringing stability and economic growth to Afghanistan and the wider region. Beneficiaries are the people living in the region law enforcement agencies as well as wider internation
al community. The Programme takes into account vulnerable groups such as women youth refugees and prisoners. Current Finnish contribution is one million euros and Finland has supported the previous Programme phase (2011-2015) with one million Euros and the
 current Programme (2016-19) with also on million Euros. Suggested additional funding for current Programme would be 2.4 million Euros.The current Regional Programme builds on the results gained in 2011-2015. Some examples of results: 1) increased cooperat
ion between authorities on drugs in the region 2) seizures of drugs or precursor chemicals 3) increased information sharing on illegal cash flows 4) training on drugs drugs addiction and treatment for experts authorities and schools 5) series of systematic
 data collection and analysis capacity-building activities.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Suomi tukee UNODC:n alueellista huumeidenvastaista ohjelmaa (Regional Programme for Afghanistan and Neighbouring Countries 2016-2019) joka edistaa Afganistanin ja sen naapurimaiden  (Iran Kazakstan Kirgisia Pakistan Tad?ikistan Turkmenistan ja Uzbekistan) 
kykya yhdessa torjua huumeista ja siihen liityvasta rikollisuudesta johtuvaa epavakauttavaa vaikutusta. Ohjelmalla edistetaan uusien lahestymistapojen rakentamista vahvistetaan olemassa olevia ratkaisumalleja ja lisataan alueen toimijoiden kapasiteettia to
imia tehokkaammin huumeita ja huumekauppaa vastaan. Huumekaupan globaali luonne tuo monia kerrannaisvaikutuksia paitsi alueen maille myos koko kansainvaliselle yhteisolle Suomi mukaanlukien. Rajat ylittavan huumekaupan torjunta edellyttaa koordinoituja alu
eellisia ja kansainvalisia toimia mika on todettu YK:n paatoslauselmissa ja kansainvalisissa konferensseissa. UNODC:n ohjelma tehostaa alueen maiden ja toimijoiden yhteistyota yhteisen huumeongelman ratkaisemisessa. Huumeidenvastainen toiminta ei ole erill
inen kysymys vaan se liittyy myos laajempiin kehityskysymyksiin turvallisuuden ja vakauden lisaamiseen ja hyvan hallinnon vahvistamiseen ja talouskasvun mahdollistamiseen Afganistanissa ja laajemmin alueella. Hankkeen edunsaajina ovat paitsi alueen valtioi
den asukkaat ja lainvalvontaviranomaiset myos laajempi kansainvalinen yhteiso. Ohjelmassa otetaan huomioon haavoittuvien ryhmien (kuten naiset nuore/lapsett pakolaiset ja vangit) tarpeet. Suomi on tukenut aiempaa ohjelmakautta (2011-2015) miljoonalla eurol
la ja nykyista ohjelmakautta (2016-2019) myos miljoonalla eurolla. Lisarahoitusta nykyiselle ohjelmakaudelle esitetaan yhteensa 2.4 miljoonaa euroa.Voimassa oleva alueellinen ohjelma pohjautuu vuosien 2011-2015 ohjelmakauden tuloksiin ja rakentuu niiden pa
alle. Esimerkkeja ko. kauden tuloksista: 1) alueen maiden viranomaisten huumausaineisiin liittyvan yhteistyon lisaantyminen 2) huumausaineiden seka niiden valmistukseen tarvittavien aineiden takavarikot 3) laittomien rahavirtojen paljastamiseen liittyvan t
iedonvaihdon lisaaminen 4) huumausaineisiin ja -riippuvuuteen seka HIV:iin liittyvan koulutuksen tarjoaminen mm. asiantuntijoille ja kouluille. 5) huumausaineisiin liittyva systemaattinen tiedonkeruu ja analyysikapasitetin kehittaminen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41128" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Office on Drugs and Crime</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">YK:n huume- ja rikostoimisto</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2017-2013130273" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Afghanistan;Iran;Kazakhstan;Kyrgyzstan;Pakistan;Ta"></location>
  <sector code="16063" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is a secondary
 priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights sensitive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeudet huomioiva</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is the main priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2400000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2400000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">2400000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2017-2013130273" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
