<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-1762840-MAL015-NG32-01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-1762840" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flood response in Nsanje, Blantyre and Chikwawa Districts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Given the significant identified needs on the ground, and the limited resources available for a response at this stage, the consortium is proposing a set of activities that specifically supports the most vulnerable groups to meet their food and NFI needs,  with broader awareness raising and camp management support that would positively benefit a much larger population. Specific activities include the following: (1) community outreach to identify the most vulnerable households and assist them to have access to support through camps and/or are adequately supported in their own homes; (2) support for camp set-up, management and coordination to ensure effective supplies, protection and support to those in camps; (3) distribution of a basket of key food and non-food items to the most vulnerable families currently residing in camps in Nsanje &amp; Chikwawa where access to markets is limited in the immediate term; (4) multi-purpose cash transfers (worth 25,000 MKW) provided to key vulnerable households in Blantyre urban where markets are operating and easily accessible to allow households to procure vital food, NFI or shelter materials (amount to be confirmed by Cash Working Group); (5) WASH advocacy and provision of chlorine/water guard to reduce risk of cholera and other water-bourne diseases; (6) support for district level emergency response coordination efforts. These activiites were identified following needs assessments conducted on the ground (on 11 March in Blantyre, 8 March in  Chikwawa and Nsanje assessment) and on the basis of reports received from local authorities. The identified activities also take into account what is known to date of existing response efforts by the Government, other NGOs UN agencies, etc. Coordination and collaboration with other stakeholders on the ground will be a key priority for the consortium.  Goal will lead in Nsanje and IR will lead in Chikwawa and Blantyre. MANEPO will take technical lead in the three districts in relation to older persons and people with disabilities; GOAL will take technical lead on WASH, NFIs, camp management, advocacy around wash/cholera and IR will take technical lead on food distribution.

Broad support (including community engagement, awareness raising and camp management and coordination efforts) will benefit the entire population of those living in the 18 targeted camps in Nsanje and Chikwawa (16,933 people) as well as those in surrounding areas reached through house-to-house support (approx. 5,000 HH or 25,000 people). In addition, targeted distributions of food and NFI will directly benefit 3,500 affected households in Nsanje and Chikwawa, and targeted cash distributions will benefit an additional 1,000 HH in Blantyre city, with a focus on the most vulnerable in all districts. In total, when accounting for overlap, the proposed activities are expected to benefit an estimated 21,933 individuals (with average family size of 5). Data sources are from OCHA, Government and local reports and needs assessments conducted in Nsanje, Chikwawa and Blantyre urban during the period 8-11 March.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1128267-8" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-1762840" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Network of Older Persons Organization (MANE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HelpAge International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Enquiries</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>iatiinfo@helpage.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tavis House, 1-6 Tavistock Square, London WC1H 9NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="SS" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://helpage.sharepoint.com/:w:/s/Operations2/Edb-pIuRExFOh4VJef0FD3gBda8kj_jAGwxAEcGyUw1Xag?e=W5dO2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitaritan</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-03-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-14">115870</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-05-13"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-14">115870</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-06-30">225501</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement for period 2019/003</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi Network of Older Persons Organization (MANEPO)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-31">231741</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Incoming Funds for period 2018/012</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age International</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
