<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-MM-19/DDA-3415/SA2/WASH-FS/INGO/14892</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH assistance and livelihoods support for vulnerable populations affected by conflicts in Kachin State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The humanitarian crisis in Kachin (KCN) started in June 2012 following a mass population displacements resulting from clashes between the Tatmadaw (Myanmar Army) and the Kachin Independence Army (KIA). Even though, since July 2018 the fighting decreased between the KIA and the Tatmadaw, 97,500 people remain displaced, with over 38,000 of them located in areas controlled by ethnic armed organizations (NGCA), inaccessible to most international partners but still reached by national partners. The skirmishes are located around strategic areas (such as Hpakant and Tanai for the control of amber and gold mines). Moreover, as a consequence of the &#x201C;National Strategy on Resettlement of IDPs and Closure of IDP Camps&#x201D; officially released by the Government on November 19th 2019 and the reduction of skirmishes, around 6,485 displaced people have resettled or gone back to their original villages. SI expected this trend to be reinforced in 2019 with more pressure put by the GoM on camp management agencies, and advocated for the provision of decent living conditions in resettlement/return places.

Due to the status quo of peace process in KCN since the announcement of a unilateral ceasefire end of December 2018 and extended 3 times until 21/09/2019, the camp population did not change much in 2019 and only &#x201C;intentions&#x201D; to move out of camps have been collected for 2020 so far. The UNHCR 2019 Intention Survey shows that while a majority of IDPs would like to return home, 94% of them expressed they are unable to return to their place of origin at the moment mainly due to insecurity. In addition, pendulum movements have been observed with IDPs going back and forth from the camps to their home villages, hence taking time to analyze the situation of safe and dignified return.

The relative improvement of the security situation has however provided opportunities for increased dialogue around durable solutions. While significant obstacles to large-scale solutions remain, including the lack of long-term security guarantees, landmine and unexploded ordnance contamination, a lack of access to services and livelihood opportunities and complex housing, land and property (HLP) rights issues, small-scale return and resettlement will continue and be built upon moving forward.

In this context, SI proposes to address Lwegel Camps WaSH facilities that urgently need rehabilitation to provide camp population with minimum WASH standards, ensure safety and mitigate public health risks. 
In addition, KBC HDD Bhamo address the uncovered gaps in Je Yang camps (NGCA), as the maintenance of the water supply infrastructures, distribution of sanitary kits for women and girl, critical sanitation activities related to desludging and vector control. Moreover, under this grant, KBC will also implement the celebration of 2 international events (world Water Day and MHM Day). 

Following the floods that occurred in July 2019 in KCN, SI proposes to support 37 farmers of 3 villages (Bhamo Township) who lost their 2019 monsoon crop due to alluvium cover. Along with the Bhamo Department of Agriculture, SI will support the farmers in cleaning their field and prepare the next monsoon through cash grant (including land preparation, paddy seeds and fertilizer). 

SI contributed to a joint assessment (see Annex 06) conducted in March 2019 in Manbung camp, where 14 IDPs families expressed the will to move out from the camp on 06/12/2019. As per the findings, the current livelihood activities that IDPs are relying on are small-scale agriculture, raising livestock, daily labor, carpentry, working in other countries and small-scale buying and selling activities. But those IDPs intending to settle down in the town do not have any plans or preparation to undertake income generating activities. Therefore, SI proposes under this project to support these families with livelihoods assistance through cash grant for small business development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin Baptist Convention</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9;s International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9;s International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rev. Lazum Htun Nawng</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General secretary of Bhamo Zonal Association Office</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09 262 831 035 / 07 450 042</telephone>
   <email>lazumhtunnawng@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Julie Thuriere</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>09 425 007 411 / 09 950 420 134</telephone>
   <email>ygn.hom@solidarites-myanmar.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MMR001">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kachin</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.00000000 97.50000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="46.55" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="53.45" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">256923.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">163076.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="MMR59-14892">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">420000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9;s International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304481094">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-05">252000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9;s International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304760695">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">168000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9;s International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-MMR59-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
