<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FR-RCS-31899089200065-NP-RUPWS</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FR-RCS-31899089200065" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Contre la Faim France</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reaching the Unreached People through WASH Services (RUWPS) in Nuwakot and Rasuwa District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed second phase of this project will further cover around 20,000 beneficiaries in the same districts, through construction of 15 community water supply schemes and WASH facilities in 10 remote schools covering most vulnerable areas of 4 Rural Municipality (6 VDCs). This phase of project considers the evolving context of these two districts (two years after the earthquake) by taking into account the aspirations of people living in the area. The constraints posed by time and funds during the 1st phase are well-thought-out to ensure that this phase of project would leave no one behind. This project employs participatory methodologies that promote inclusion and community decision making, and is building the capacity of community based platforms including users committee, health management committee and school management committee. Considering the new federal structure in Nepal - Action Against Hunger and its local partners are building dialogue between communities and local government in order to increase government support for WASH sector and investment for sustainability of the WASH structure in the long run. Apart from this, this project will contemplate the integration of WASH and nutrition specially targeting the Severe/Acute malnourished children along with under 2 year old children from the targeted areas by implementing intensive WASH behaviour change related activities. Expected results: Unreached earthquake affected as well as nutritional vulnerable population have improved access to safe and sufficient water. WASH governance of water and sanitation user committee at targeted rural municipality is strengthen WASH related Knowledge, Attitudes and Practices/behaviours of the nutritional vulnerable population are improved in the targeted area. Estimated 3,874 household</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will target to reach an estimated 19,370 people from sanitation and hygiene related intervention and among them at least 5,111 will be the direct beneficiaries of water supply activities. All the beneficiaries of the project are so far unreached by other actors in the area and are among the nutritionally vulnerable and earthquake affected population. Within the target community, specific attention will be paid to the most vulnerable groups&#x2019; i.e. Pregnant and lactating women, children, the elderly, and people with disabilities, malnourished cases and adolescent girls as well as excluded group of people i.e. people from Balami, Tamang &amp; Dalit community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1047501-RUPWS" crs-channel-code="21000" ref="GB-CHC-1047501" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action Against Hunger UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-01">927498</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-30">263558</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-01">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="Nov19-Dec19 Cost Extension">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-01">20000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1047501-RUPWS" ref="GB-CHC-1047501" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="FR-RCS-31899089200065-NP-RUPWS" ref="FR-RCS-31899089200065" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="3"></disbursement-channel>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
