<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-4884328-G321</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-4884328" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Action</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting good governance, transparency and accountability at the sub-national level to enable effective citizen participation, oversight and problem solving of service delivery.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Action grant to National Taxpayers Association to promote good governance, transparency and accountability at the sub-national level to enable effective citizen participation, oversight, problem solving and monitoring in the utilization of public funds and service delivery;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective: The goal of the project is to contribute to the promotion of good governance, transparency and accountability in the management of public funds at the sub-national level through effective citizen participation, oversight, problem solving and monitoring.

Specific Objectives:
A.	To establish partnerships and project buy in with institutions at national and sub national for information sharing and redress mechanisms.
B.	To enhance the capacity of citizens to effectively monitor the management of public funds to ensure effective management of the public funds. 
C.	To improve the quality of projects through the monitoring of projects in Uasin Gishu County, Turbo constituency using the CRCs.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Taxpayers Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-12-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-23">27240</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="9396">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-09">13620</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="10036">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-08-26">13620</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
