<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-4884328-G307</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-4884328" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Action</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Based Monitoring of Infrastructure in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific objectives or outputs

The project responds to the following specific objectives and outputs:

1.	Output 1: Improved capabilities of local communities and selected local state institutions to engage in enhancing integrity in service delivery and pro-poor policies in education, health, water and sanitation, roads, gardens and markets in 6 provinces in Afghanistan.
2.	Output 2: Improved responsiveness of public service providers at local level by engaging local communities and key state institutions in joint, collaborative forums and working groups for regular and systematic assessment of pro-poor policies and integrity in service delivery.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of this project is to strengthen the integrity performance of local communities and key local state institutions and to positively impact service delivery.

The purpose is to strengthen social accountability of key stakeholders at the local level and to enhance integrity in delivering services in the fields of health, education, water and sanitation, roads, gardens and markets in six provinces of Afghanistan.
;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Watch Afghanistan (IWA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="40" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-02-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD">79806</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
