<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-4884328-G325</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-4884328" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Action</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovative public monitoring techniques as a tool for integrity in the implementation of external projects for local community development in Osh Oblast</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective: Improvement of the external aid quality and integrity in the implementation of international projects for the local community development in Osh Oblast through public monitoring using innovative techniques.

Specific objectives:
1.	Create conditions for PM development and introduction of the innovative DevelopmentCheck technique among the partner organizations in Osh City and Osh Oblast. 
2.	Improve the quality of external aid and integrity in the implementation of development projects for local communities in Osh Oblast through PM.
3.	Form a public monitoring alliance among partner civil society institutions, local governments and other actors of local development, as well as active citizens with a view to improve the quality and effectiveness of external aid and projects.
4.	To conduct a large scale awareness rising campaign on the peculiarities of the Development Check PM tool in Osh City and Osh Oblast.
;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project initiatives will be aimed at introducing the principles of integrity and transparency in the implementation of the projects under International Programs of external aid as well as increasing the responsiveness of local self-governance to CSO recommendations resulting from PM. Also, the Project activities are to develop associated plans and ways to solve locally identified problems as well as resumption and strengthening of the local civil network Aikyn Kyzmat as an Alliance for PM to improve the quality and effectiveness of external aid and projects, which will allow sustainability of the achieved project outputs and the very process of public control.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mumtaz Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="40" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD">14246</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
