<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-4884328-G326</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-4884328" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Action</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-Based-Monitoring of Schools</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective: To empower and encourage communities to actively participate in monitoring of public education services to increase transparency and accountability and therefrom improve the quality of education.


Specific Objectives:

A). Improved quality of education through mobilization communities to monitor education services delivery.

B). Enhanced capacities and effective funcioning of School Management Shuras through provision of technical assistance.

C). Increased cooperation and coordination between recipients and providers of education services through promulgation of a culture of responsibility and accountability.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to enhance the quality of education by empowering communities to participate in overseeing delivery of education services by the state.  It intends to promulgate accountability through research, advocacy, communities&#x2019; awareness and participation to hold authorities accountable, and increase their participation in monitoring of services, especially in the planning and budgeting at sub-national and local levels. This project will also carry out empowerment and advocacy campaign and will facilitate bottom-up planning and budgeting and encourage communities&#x2019; participation in consultation and management of schools. The original goal is to develop a community based monitoring mechanism that communities find both simple and interesting. We reason that communities feel more committed to their development activities if they were empowered to control its monitoring.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Watch Afghanistan (IWA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-01">77610</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
