<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-4884328-G310</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-4884328" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrity Action</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDF Integrity in South Sudan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives:
1. To create awareness at central level about need to monitor implementation of CDF at county levels.
2.	To assess the implementation of CDF at county level in order to design a monitoring intervention. 
;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan is endowed with a lot of natural resources, including petroleum, gold, rocks, wildlife and vast areas of fertile lands. Despite these resources, South Sudan still remains one of the poorest countries in the world, with development indicators, such as enrollment in schools, livelihood, health care delivery, among others, being the lowest in the world. Meant to support community development priorities, the CDF fund is administered through the national legislative assembly.Sadly, citizens at the community level do not fully understand the CDF act which was established in 2007 and therefore they  are unable to implement and oversee CDF funds according to the provisions of the Act. Consequently, CDF fund is highly mismanaged and at times even used for personal interests by custodian MPs. This project seeks to address this problem through creating awareness at central level on the need to monitor implementation of CDF and Assessing the fund&#x2019;s implementation in the four focus counties so as to improve policy and practice at national, state and county levels by highlighting gaps, lessons learnt and recommendations.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Society for Civic Development (SCD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="40" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD">19600</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
