<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-31669</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCS Property</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(i) The Company&apos;&apos;s activities are focused on improving UB&apos;&apos;s urban infrastructure. As such, they have a direct and immediate development impact with respect to improvements in living standards and inefficiency of doing business in Mongolia&apos;&apos;s capital. In particular, the  Company&apos;&apos;s pipeline of properties scheduled for completion in the near future includes socially important developments, such as 1,617 affordable housing units in an innovative and replicable &quot;Shine Ger&quot; project with the goal  to make home ownership affordable for young professional families;  (ii) MCSP is an important source of indirect employment with 4,782 indirect employees (e.g. contractors);  (iii) Through increased purchasing local materials and services, the expansion of MCSP activities will strengthen the Company&apos;&apos;s linkages to  the local economy;  (iv) MCSP is committed to bringing international property development standards and best practices to a country where the quality of construction  needs to be drastically improved;  (v) The MCS Tower included in the Project will contribute to the development of the UB business infrastructure that lacks quality office buildings at this point in time.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MCS Group of companies (MCS Group or the Sponsor), IFCs repeat client and one of Mongolias leading business groups active in (i) distributing fast-moving consumer goods; (ii) beverage manufacturing; (ii) mobile communications and information technologies; (iii) civil engineering and infrastructure development, (iv) mining, as well as in a number of other industry sectors, is expanding the scale of its property development operations, which are currently focused on a large-scale affordable housing development in Ulaanbaatar (UB). MCS Groups property-focused subsidiary MCS Properties Holdings Ltd (BVI) (MCS Property, MCSP or the Company) has requested a long-term IFC loan of up to US$60 million, which will be used (i) to complete the Companys affordable housing development Shine Ger in UB; (ii) to build an affordable housing residential complex in the vicinity of the Ukhaa Khudag (UHG) mine site, 500 kilometers to the south of UB, as well as (iii) to develop an office tower, which will be an important contribution to the Mongolian capital business infrastructure, and a school building in UB (the Project).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCS PROPERTIES HOLDING LLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-31669" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contact: Purevsuren Ya. CFO of MCS Properties Holding LLC 14th Floor, Central Tower,  2 Sukhbaatar Square, SBD-8, Ulaanbaatar, 14200, Mongolia Telephone: +976 11-312625 Fax: +976-77008085</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mongolia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MN-Mongolia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The office tower included in the Project will be built in the central areas of UB. The Shine Ger affordable housing development is being constructed on the outskirts of UB, approximately 50 kilometers from the central part of the city. In addition, the Project includes affordable housing in the vicinity of the UHG mine site, 500 kilometers to the south of UB. All the Project sites have adequate access to all the necessary infrastructure.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>46.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="236" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">D-AA - Construction and Real Estate</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $60.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-12-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-20">60000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-20">60000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCS PROPERTIES HOLDING LLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/31669/mcs-property">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
