<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-LA-F14AP00966</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening systems for reducing poaching and forest encroachment, and law enforcement monitoring for gibbons in Nam Kading NPA, Lao PDR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. Programs in this element should be integrated with the Agriculture Area under Economic Growth and Conflict Mitigation and Reconciliation Area under the Peace and Security Category, when applicable and appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. This includes The purpose of this proposal is to strengthen defenses against poaching and habitat encroachment for globally significant gibbon populations in the Nam Kading NPA by increasing enforcement staffing and expanding the coverage of patrols and investigations, and implementing a new improved system for law enforcement monitoring. Specifically, this will be done by: 1) increasing the number of staff at three checkpoints from three to six; 2) upgrading the Tad Vang Fong checkpoint to meet increasing threats due to activity related to NT1 feasibility works; 3) providing motorcycles to allow mobility to field teams to quickly respond to emerging situations that require immediate attention; 4) recruiting 6 skilled and highly motivated staff to a mobile rapid response team and ensuring that a vehicle is available for use by the mobile team at all times; 5) training of project staff in use of SMART software; 6) designing a site-specific data model; and 7) implementing the SMART system of law enforcement monitoring..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-DUNS-075209650" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WILDLIFE CONSERVATION SOCIETY</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>075209650</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="LA">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laos</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The primary goal of U.S. assistance in Laos is to demonstrate that the United States is a trusted and reliable partner in the economic and social development of the country. To accomplish this, U.S. assistance programs are designed to address legacy issues arising from the war in Vietnam, support public health efforts to combat child malnutrition and improve maternal and newborn health, increase primary school graduation rates, promote legal and regulatory systems reform, combat drug flows from Laos to other countries, increase regional and global economic integration and adherence to international standards and trade agreements, and strengthen people-to-people ties between Laos and the United States. U.S. assistance promotes good governance and respect for human rights; more sustainable country-based health and education systems; a legal framework that provides greater access to U.S. businesses and facilitates inclusive growth; the removal of unexploded ordnance; and a positive, constructive relationship between Laos and the United States.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-01">52943</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-26">-52943</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">one-time disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2014" end="2016"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2014-09-05"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
