<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>ET-0000433</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-32092131" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edukans</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ET-0000433 Partnership for Quality Ed. in Afar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2016, the UNICEF Ethiopia Learning and Development programme has increased its engagement in refugee-hosting contexts through the integration of refugee education into national systems as a cost-effective and sustainable way to promote equitable access to quality of education. The UNICEF Ethiopia Country Office (ECO) has worked closely with the Ministry of Education (MoE), the Administration of Refugee and Returnee Affairs (ARRA), and UNHCR to develop suitable modalities of implementation including partnerships with NGOs having multi-sectoral capacity and a presence across host and refugee contexts.  Within this context UNICEF is partnering with Edukans to lead the implementation of the UKAid-funded &#x2018;Building Self-Reliance of refugee and vulnerable host communities through improved basic social services&#x2019; (BSRP).
Afar region currently hosts 37,435 refugees mostly from Eritrea, residing in two camps (Aysaita and Bahrale) in the districts of the same name. Children constitute 59 % of the refugee community and 44% of the host community population in the region, where access and retention rates in education are amongst the lowest in the country. 
Although key trends affect Ethiopia drop-out rates broadly (poor readiness for primary due to an almost complete absence of pre-primary education services particularly in rural contexts; socio-cultural barriers to girls&#x2019; education including child marriage and early pregnancy; socio-economic barriers to education amongst the poor, etc.) dynamics across host and refugee contexts in each region/woreda are very specific and will be captured through rapid assessments in target schools and communities. 
UNHCR registration shows that at least 60% of the Afar refugees are not living in a camp, and according to refugee Education Management Information System (EMIS) data there are 80 refugee boys and 43 refugee girls hosted in national schools in the two districts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Expertise Centre Ethiopia - DEC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="kst tm aug 19 uit BC">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-31">4276</value>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
