<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>KE-0000302</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-32092131" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edukans</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KE-0000302 Youth@Work 2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">First, it provides the marginalised youth the tools they need for self-support. The ultimate goal 
(1) is they have a substantial and sustainable income and are food secure for themselves and the children in their care. To achieve this long term goal, the project focusses on the whole chain from attitude change, access to quality vocational training to industrial exposure and accessing the job market, while generating regular feed back on the training method and organizing refresher courses by Kenyan&apos;s Premier Hospitality and Tourism Training School.
The second goal is that Ujima, through its income generating programs endeavors to become self-sustaining, and therefore donor independent in the future.
&#x2022;	240 orphaned heads (146 female and 94 male) of households taking care of at least three siblings, access vocational education in tourism and hospitality in Kisumu and Nakuru per year.
&#x2022;	95% of the trainees complete the orientation program and the skill centre (industrial attachment) successfully and 80 percent of them have gainful employment by the end of 2017.
&#x2022;	Improved curricular for entrepreneurship and ICT training alongside the Employability training to assure its continued relevance to the labour market.
&#x2022;	Inclusion of Sexual and reproductive health within our training model by the end of 2017 to address among other issues the drop out cases.
&#x2022;	Improved collaboration with the line Ministries in view of ensuring proper standards are adhered.
&#x2022;	Hotel classification to international and national standards (Maili Saba Camp in Nakuru).
&#x2022;	The income towards the training program is increased with 5% per year.
240 orphaned heads (146 female and 94 male) of households taking care of at least three siblings
Indirect: 729 sibblings</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ujima Foundation for Training and Development - UFTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="KE-0000302-2019: &#x20AC; 0,00 (29-11-19)">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-30">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
