<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-58279199-DGISQ3-2021-report</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-58279199" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS Q3 Activity Report 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI has committed to deliver the following Core Objectives. 

 
Core Objective 1	Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020. 

Core Objective 2	Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes. 


Core Objective 3	Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019.

Core Objective 4	Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. 

Core Objective 5 	Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact. 

 

Core Objective 6 	Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas. 

Core Objective 7 	Develop measurement and evaluations. 

Core Objective 8	Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. 

 

Additional ATNI Objectives (funded by various, not part of prolongation) 

ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include: 

 

Additional Objective 1	Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g., retailers, food service companies, fast food chains. 

Additional Objective 2 	Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries. 

Additional Objective 3 	Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.). 

Extra activities 2020-2022 (funded by FCDO, not part of prolongation) 

With the additional funding support from FCDO as per amendment No. 01/2020, signed April 16, 2020, to the ongoing Accountable Grant for this project (no. 300590) ATNI will embark on the following extra activities:  

Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020. 

Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 Global Nutrition Summit (GNS)/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 United Nation&#x2019;s Food System Summit (UNFSS) and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020.  

Investor coalition starting October 2020.  

Workforce nutrition action research starting January 2021.  

Action research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets starting January 2021.  

Country approach starting July 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Document Structure 

 

This document presents the progress from July till September 2021 on the activities for which DGIS contracted the Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF, Grant reference number - 4000000128). It is structured in line with the Objectives for the Access to Nutrition Initiative (ATNI) as in the funding proposal, including additional funding support (&#xA3;1,500.000) from FCDO that was approved April 2020.  

 

For 2021, ATNI has been granted a prolongation from DGIS to deliver the objectives in the course of 2021,  due to delays caused by the Covid19 crisis that started in 2020. 

 

Progress on relevant objectives for July-September 2021 

Core Objective 1: Global Indexes 

Global Index  

Chart, bar chart

Description automatically generatedOn July 1, 2021, ATNI published its fourth Global Index, assessing the largest 25 global F&amp;B companies on their efforts on nutrition. The launch of the Index was held across three events spread over two days. On Thursday, the 1st, ATNI held two online meetings: one for companies and one for investor signatories. These were followed by a multi-stakeholder webinar on the 2nd. All events were well attended, filled with constructive discussion with a wide range of attendees including 50 representatives from 19 companies, 45 investors, and over 25 CSOs and partner organisations. Further details on the launch events were included in the progress report of the last quarter.  

After the launch, ATNI invited all companies of the Index to online meetings to dig deeper into Global Index results and recommendations. 19 Companies expressed an interest in joining these meetings. So far, ATNI has conducted these calls with 15 companies. In addition, 2 companies, Nestl&#xE9; and Pepsico, requested separate meetings with their Senior Executives and Board members to communicate the results. 12 senior and board representatives from Nestl&#xE9;  and 7 from Pepsico joined these meetings.  Also, for the first time,  non-engaging companies Suntory and Mengniu reached out and expressed an interest in understanding ATNI&#x2019;s work. 

Overall, the response from all companies has been positive. It is evident that companies do discuss Global Index results internally and use them to make improvements. A few insights from companies expressed in the post-launch meetings are given below:  

&#x2022; Unilever company representatives expressed that they want to act on ATNI recommendations regarding disclosure. The company also wants to engage further on product profile and fortification.  

&#x2022; Suntory shared that the company has created a health policy and expanded their disclosure in response to the 2018 results of the Global Index.  

&#x2022; Nestl&#xE9; applauded ATNI on the growing impact of the Global Index and role specifically in producing evidence for investors engagement.  

&#x2022; Mondelez reviewed and discussed results at the executive level with the promise to use them to inform a heatmap and then a roadmap to work on specific areas of improvement for the different areas of the company.  

&#x2022; Kraft Heinz appreciated ATNI&#x2019;s neutral lens in assessing nutrition. The results of the Index have been discussed at each business unit and at global leadership level including the CEO. The company uses ATNI recommendations to set internal targets on nutrition as part of the company&apos;s 2020- 25 agenda.  

&#x2022; General Mills has shared the results with key leaders in the company. The company followed GI 2018 recommendations to put together a commentary on their lobbying efforts which they published. The company wants to engage more with ATNI on the priority populations and accessibility and affordability.  

&#x2022; Danone staff shared that they are identifying areas of maximum improvement in ATNI methodology to advise senior management on strategic choices that will help improve the company&#x2019;s Global Index scores.  

Next steps: In the last quarter of 2021, ATNI will wrap up post-launch meetings with companies and consolidate key outcomes of these discussions and suggestions for next iteration of the Global Index in a summary report. In October, ATNI will hold a launch event for Japanese stakeholders. UNICEF China has proposed to organize a company presentation co-hosted by the EU Chamber of Commerce in China. ATNI has also acquired funding by Irish Aid to conduct a Spotlight report on lobbying and to benchmark all 25 Global Index companies. The project will start in Q4 2021 and be completed in Q3 2022.  


 

Core Objective 2: BMS marketing policies and practices 

ATNI will assess the top 20 BMS companies in the next iteration of the BMS Index and increase the country assessments to 5-7 countries, to be able to capture all companies on the ground. As a first step, ATNI has been preparing internally for the consultation; working on identifying the themes and stakeholders and coming up with a plan for the milestones leading to the next iteration.  

In the meantime, ATNI has offered post-launch engagement calls to all BMS companies to discuss the results of the Index and the recommendations on the way forward. ATNI has engaged so far with Nestl&#xE9;, Danone and Reckitt. Reckitt has informed ATNI that they are planning to update their policy based on the recommendations of ATNI&#x2019;s report. Nestl&#xE9; is planning to implement their policy to Infant Formula 0-6m globally. Danone is open to explore improvements with a focus on strengthening country manuals and has asked for further insights from the analysis. ATNI plans to hold a meeting with Kraft Heinz as well. 

ATNI is participating in the stakeholder consultation that B Corporation (a certification organisation that certifies businesses on their social and environmental performance, public transparency, and legal accountability) is currently holding to develop new BMS criteria for companies that produce BMS and would like to be qualified as B-Corp. ATNI will continue providing input to this process and follow the developments on this.  

Next steps: In Q4 of 2021 and Q1 of 2022, ATNI will conduct an extensive stakeholder consultation with CSOs, companies and other experts to review the methodology and approach for the next iteration of the BMS Index. As an immediate next step, ATNI will meet with its Expert Group to present initial questions and thinking and discuss areas where ATNI should focus.  

Other BMS work 

FTSE4Good 

Once the ATNI reports were published, as well as the PwC verification assessments, ATNI organised a call with FTSE and PwC in July to reflect on the project cycle, discuss areas of improvement and potential next steps. FTSE explained that they are going through an internal restructuring process and are exploring options for the way forward. FTSE mentioned they are considering drawing from ATNI&apos;s findings in BMS/CF 1 and BMS/CF 2 in the next iteration. ATNI is following up with FTSE to understand next steps. 

BMS Call to Action 

ATNI has been assessing the responses and roadmaps of the companies to the Call to Action. Among the 21 companies that were directly contacted, 17 submitted responses and 5 roadmaps. Some Japanese companies that are interested to participate to the N4G Summit have submitted roadmaps and are following up with ATNI on clarification points; namely Megmilk, Glico, Morinaga and Meiji. ATNI is providing its evaluations on these roadmaps to the Call-to-Action signatories and based on these, it is also advising the Government of Japan on BMS companies participation to the Summit. More information on the latter can be found in the N4G section.  

 
 

Core Objective 5: Outreach activities 

 

Investors 

 

Signatory Recruitment (current AUM is $16.5 trillion) 

ATNI has continued to increase its signatory base. New ATNI Signatories include Mitsubishi UFJ Trust and Banking (JP), Apostle Funds Management (AUS), Aikya Investment Management (UK). For the next quarter, ATNI will continue will collaborative engagement and then continue with signatory recruitment.  

Collaborative Investor Engagement 

50 of the 74 ATNI Investor Signatories, representing $12.3 trillion in assets, are taking part in the Collaborative Investor Engagement facilitated by ATNI, based on the findings of the Global Index 2021.  

In July 2021, the benchmark letters were shared with all publicly listed companies in the Global Index 2021 (i.e., a total of 20 companies) and all companies have been asked to reply in writing to set a date for a first engagement meeting. In September, first engagement meetings with five companies have taken place, namely with China Mengniu, Danone, Meiji, Nestl&#xE9; and Unilever. A member of the ATNI Investor Support team has been attending each of these calls for purposes of notetaking. Notes will be used to write an impact report like the one produced after the 2018-2019 engagement phase.  

ATNI Investor Signatories are currently in conversation with General Mills, PepsiCo, Suntory and Yili to organize a first engagement meeting.  

Ahead of each engagement call with the companies, ATNI provided an in-depth investor briefing about each company, to support investors in their engagement efforts and to ensure the investor engagement is successful. These briefings have been well attended by investors, who have provided positive feedback and indicated that they found the briefings useful in preparing for their engagement meetings with companies.  

To ensure the smooth and successful running of the engagement, ATNI also organized several additional calls and teach-in sessions:  

The first collaborative engagement call took place on September 9. This allowed investors to compare company responses received up to that date, to reflect on lessons learnt from the previous engagement phase, and to discuss any questions.  

Teach-in sessions on three topics of special interest to investors (i.e., the Product Profile, Marketing and Lobbying) were organized in September to brief all investors on the details of the ATNI methodology on these topics as well as on best practices and performance gaps. These calls were also well attended,  

The Collaborative Engagement part of the ATNI Investor Portal was also launched in September. This part of the Portal is only available to investors directly engaging with the companies and includes all documents relevant to the engagement, including recordings of the briefings and minutes of the engagement calls.  

Next steps: The ATNI Investor Support team will continue to support investors in their engagement with companies and will continue to build the track record necessary for the impact report at the end of this engagement phase. Meetings with 6 more companies have been scheduled for October. These include Ajinomoto, BRF, Campbell&#x2019;s, Coca-Cola, Keurig Dr Pepper, and Kraft Heinz.  

ATNI Investor Signatories are also currently in conversation with General Mills, Mondelez, PepsiCo, Suntory and Yili to try to organize a first engagement meeting between the end of October and the end of November. 

 

As several investors have expressed interest in learning more about the BMS / CF Marketing Index 2021, ATNI will offer an additional teach-in session on the topic of breast-milk substitutes and complementary foods.  

Additionally, ATNI will continue to organize quarterly collaborative engagement calls to provide investors with a platform to share successes and difficulties encountered in their engagement with the companies. The next quarterly engagement call is planned for November 2.  

Investor Report 

ATNI has contracted an external consultant to write a report outlining investor action on nutrition. The report will present several case studies profiling current responsible investment approaches to nutrition (e.g., from ESG integration to engagement, from research to public policy work and exclusions of certain companies from an investment portfolio). Case studies will profile ATNI Investor Signatories. This report will be launched during an N4G Side Event (pending official approval). 

N4G and UNFSS Investor Mobilization 

ATNI has been supporting investor mobilization at the two global summits taking place this year. ATNI continues to be in conversation with the Good Food Finance Network, launched at the UN Food Systems Summit, to ensure that the issue of nutrition is part of the Network&#x2019;s agenda as a relevant ESG issue. 

ATNI has drafted the N4G Investor Pledge, supported by most of its Investor Signatories, which will be officially launched at the N4G Summit. This pledge will represent a smart commitment from investors to use the framework of the Investor Expectations on Nutrition, Diets and Health in their engagement, analysis, and investment processes as well as a commitment to directly engage with all listed companies in the Global Index 2021. As part of its efforts to mobilize the investment community for N4G, ATNI has also submitted a proposal for an official N4G side event, which will present the report on existing responsible investment approaches to nutrition.  

Next steps: ATNI will ensure the Investor Signatories sign the N4G Investor Pledge and will attempt to secure a spot in the N4G main agenda for the Pledge to be presented.  

Outreach &amp; Communications&#x202F; 

Social media activity between July and September 2021 contributed to ATNI&#x2019;s burgeoning presence online and to the impact of key publications. In July, ATNI&#x2019;s launch of the Global Index 2021 was accompanied by a social media campaign designed to drive attention to the website and to the launch events. Coverage of the launch on Twitter and LinkedIn was viewed over 36,000 times and drove at least 670 of 7,908 views of the Global Index on ATNI&#x2019;s website.  

The report &#x201C;Nutrition responses from food and beverage companies to the COVID-19 pandemic &#x2013; Report 4: The time for change&#x201D; (the final report of the COVID-19 series) was released in late July during the UNFSS Pre-Summit. The social media campaign surrounding the report garnered 9,270 views in total. The report was accessed 494 times via the website between July and September. A blog written by the ATNI team was also released shortly after the publication of the report, which investigated the role that the food and beverage industry plays in transforming food systems. 

 

Various events were organized during the Pre-Summit of the UN Food Systems Summit in July. See below the section on UNFSS. In the weeks running up to the UN Food Systems Summit, ATNI developed a social media campaign in which ATNI team members were asked to answer the following question: &#x201C;What does the UN Food Systems Summit mean to you?&#x201D;. The campaign generated a total of 7,659 impressions across Twitter and LinkedIn.  

ATNI published a few blog posts on its website to cover a range of topics relevant to the UNFSS. One of these blogs &#x201C;UN Food Systems Summit: now is the time to take action&#x201D; was written by ATNI Executive Director Inge Kauer. 

In September, ATNI published the second U.K. Product Profile on the day of the UN Food Systems Summit. The social media campaign for this report focused on key findings and was jointly disseminated on Twitter and LinkedIn by ATNI and ShareAction. ATNI&#x2019;s campaign was viewed over 2,500 times, accounting for 158 visits to the Product Profile news item and report on the website. 

On September 1, ATNI Executive Director Inge Kauer joined the Accountability Pact launch event as a speaker, to discuss the role of private sector accountability for nutrition. The Accountability Pact, a multi-stakeholder project launched ahead of the UN Food Systems Summit, is a coalition of researchers committed to monitor food and nutrition accountability. 

On September 8, the Opinion piece &#x201C;How to close the global nutrition gap post-COVID-19&#x201D; by ATNI Executive Director Inge Kauer appeared on development magazine Devex.  

 

 

 

Next steps: On October 5, ATNI will co-host the Global Index 2021 Japanese Launch Event, together with the Japanese Investor Signatory Nomura Asset Management and with the Japanese ESG Consulting Firm Neural Inc. The event will be supported by the Japanese Sustainable Investment Forum (J-SIF).  

On October 26, ATNI team will present the findings of the UK Product Profile 2021 in a webinar organised by ShareAction. This webinar is titled, &#x201C;Health Matters: Assessing food and drink manufacturers&#x2019; progress on health.  

 

 

 

Core Objective 6: Develop action research activities 

ATNI is conducting various action research activities to develop knowledge on nutrition topics relevant for its work. 

Action Research on Complementary Foods 

ATNI published its first landscape study for the Philippines looking at Commercially Produced Complementary Foods in May. The study comprised of two sections: a landscape analysis of the market and dietary partners for CF in the country, and a product profile analysis of all CF products found in the market. ATNI was also working on another country &#x2013; Mexico, focusing only on the first part which is the landscape analysis. ATNI is currently working on finalizing the l study for Mexico and will be publishing it in Q4 2021.  

 

ATNI is continuing participating to COMMIT &#x2013; a new consortium by UNICEF EAPRO looking to replicate the study in 6 Southeast Asian countries - Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Thailand, and Vietnam. ATNI has acquired new funding by Irish Aid to conduct a regional study and country briefings, based on the data that will be collected at the COMMIT project.  

 

Action Research on Workforce Nutrition in Value Chains 

ATNI is conducting this project to explore what companies are doing to promote healthy diets and nutrition along their supply chains and how companies could act on this topic. The research also aims to feed into the next Global Index and other ATNI work. ATNI has moved forward with desk research &#x2013; focusing on several supply chains: cocoa, tea, coffee, horticulture, and garment. ATNI is also conducting various interviews to understand the current landscape and the work that has been done so far, as well as to identify case studies from the sectors.  

The output from this work will be a discussion paper and several company case-studies which will be published on the ATNI website in Q4 2021, and the results will be presented in a side event of the Nutrition for Growth Summit together with GAIN.  

Action Research on Product Inequities 

ATNI&#x2019;s latest Global Product Profile, undertaken as part of the Global Access to Nutrition Index 2021 assessed the relative healthiness of the product portfolio of the largest 25 food and beverage manufacturers globally across 25 countries. ATNI has written a short research paper to explore to what extent the healthiness of companies&apos; portfolios varies by country, as an add-on to the Global Product Profile 2021.  

Results show that there is some variability in the healthiness of company&#x2019;s overall product portfolios (mean HSR) across different markets (from 1.8 in India to 2.7 in Canada). In 2018 it seemed high income markets had higher overall HSRs compared to middle income markets. However, in 2021 this is less evident.   

The main message from the Inequities paper is supporting the overall message of the Global Product Profile 2021, that companies should do more to increase the healthiness of their portfolios across countries. The Inequities paper will be launched on the ATNI website and possible steps for follow-up research will be identified. 

Large Scale Food Fortification Scoping exercise 

ATNI started designing the Large-Scale Food Fortification scoping project in September 2021. This action research is part of the 2021-2023 BMGF grant received by ATNI. The topic of Food Fortification is already embedded in a range of activities and accountability tools developed by ATNI. Building up on this knowledge ATNI will conduct a scoping exercise focusing on two countries where specific activities were implemented, namely India, for which two Spotlight Indexes were published, and Nigeria, where the Nutrition Business Monitor tool was tested.  

 

The objective of the exercise is to provide a better understanding of the components and actors of the Food Fortification Value Chains with a specific focus on Nigeria and India and identify knowledge and data gaps on the role companies play in the Food Fortification Value Chains. The findings of the exercise will serve as a basis in defining the role that ATNI can play with regards to monitoring the role of the private sector in the Food Fortification value chain to drive positive change in fighting micronutrient deficiencies. 

ATNI will produce a report presenting key findings from the scoping exercise including desk research and the outcome of the consultations. In addition, case studies (focused on India and Nigeria) will be shared. These will be presented at strategic workshop held with the BMGF with the aim of agreeing on a scenario of integration of Large-Scale Food Fortification in ATNI&#x2019;s methodology. In the second year of the grant, ATNI will start implementing this scenario in either new or ongoing projects.  

 
 

Core Objective 7: Develop Monitoring and Evaluation 

 

ATNI has hired a firm called Steward Redqueen to conduct an independent impact assessment and M&amp;E review of the organization. The draft inception report of this assessment was first shared in July. It outlines the objectives, structure, and workplan of the assessment. Moreover, it presents the Evaluation Matrix, the list of stakeholders to be interviewed, and the documents received by Steward Redqueen to conduct the initial desk review.  

In September, thirty-five stakeholders were invited to participate in the impact assessment interviews. They are categorized as follows: 

Internal stakeholders including ATNI&#x2019;s Board members, management, and key staff, as well as members of the expert group and funders 

Societal and investor stakeholders consisting of NGOs, peer benchmarking organizations, as well as investors 

F&amp;B companies, SMEs, and retailers included in ATNI&#x2019;s Indexes or specific projects 

Experts in the domain of Food and Beverages and Corporate Accountability  

By the end of September, ATNI had received 20 positive responses to the interview invitation. Additionally, all staff members were invited to provide their insights via an online survey.  

The consultancy firm has simultaneously continued reviewing the ATNI M&amp;E system, focusing on the collection of data against the current organization log-frame, thus starting to test and prioritize indicators.  

Next steps: Interviews with external stakeholders will be further conducted through October. The data analysis phase will run through October and November. The draft report of the assessment is expected in the week of the 22nd of November. In parallel, the consultant will review ATNI&#x2019;s Monitoring and Evaluation system and organize two action-oriented workshops around SMART indicators and the enhanced Theory of Change of the organization. The assessment will feed into the final report which is intended to be ready in the week of the 13th of December.  


 

Additional Objective 1: Developing indexes that assess the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g., retailers, food service companies, fast food chains (not funded by DGIS, not part of prolongation) 

ATNI UK Retailer Index 

The UK Retailer Index is assessing 11 retailers in the UK on nutrition. The methodology for this Index was published in May 2021. The pre-population phase, in which analysts added publicly available company data on the internal research platform, was concluded in early June. After the retail webinars end of May/early June to inform the companies on the research process and methodology, the research platform was opened for company input on June 7. Responses during the webinars were positive and the retailers had requested more time to submit their input on our data collection platform. ATNI therefore prolonged the first data-gathering phase to July.  

9 Of the 11 retailers provided additional information on the platform till early July. &#x202F;ATNI has also engaged with several of the retailers in one-on-one calls to clarify outstanding points. All engagement so far has been positive. Four retailers have signed a non-disclosure agreement.  

The ATNI analysts reviewed the company input on the research platform, after which the data platform opened again on August 2 for company clarification phase. Again, nine out of eleven retailers have provided input on the data research platform.   

From September onwards, the platform has closed, and data is analyzed, including peer review of company assessment.   

Next steps: After peer review, the writing of chapters and wider report as well as company scorecards will start. Another meeting with the UK Retailer Expert Group will be scheduled for expert input for elevating the findings. Publication is scheduled for Q1 2022. 

 

UK Product Profile 

 

Also, from this partnership with ShareAction, and funded by Impact on Urban Health, part of Guy&#x2019;s &amp; St Thomas&#x2019; Foundation, the UK Product Profile 2021 was launched on the ATNI website on September 23. The U.K. Product Profile 2021 is the second of its kind, following the first UK Product Profile published in 2019.  

 

The 2021 report assessed the nutritional quality of more than 4,000 products from 16 of the world&#x2019;s largest food and beverage manufacturers active in the U.K., using the data from the 2021 Global Access to Nutrition Index. The products analysed accounted for approximately 50% of total U.K. retail sales of manufacturer brands&#x2019; packaged foods and beverages in 2019.  

 

Key findings: 

Sales from healthy products has grown from 22% to 29% in the 2021 Product Profile 

Average HSR for all products assessed is 2.2 out of 5 stars (similar to previous UK Product Profile).  

Also similar, only 32% of products analyzed using the Health Star Rating met the healthy threshold  

Nine out of the 16 companies assessed were found to have improved to some extent the healthiness of their portfolios  

Overall, only 13% of products analyzed for all companies combined met nutritional standards for products that can be marketed to children, compared to 15% in previous report.  

 

This report was launched on the 23rd of September, the day of the UN Food Systems Summit. The key messages listed above were developed into a set of social media cards that were shared with ShareAction on the day of the launch. The launch was jointly promoted across Twitter and LinkedIn by ATNI and ShareAction (see the Communications &amp; Outreach section of this report for further details on the social media campaign). On October 26, ATNI will present the findings of the UK Product Profile in a webinar organized by ShareAction.  



Additional Objective 2: New Spotlight Indexes (not funded by DGIS, not part of prolongation) 

US Spotlight Index2 

ATNI is conducting research for the second US Spotlight Index in 2021. Based on insights gained through a set of tools to test and improve clarity of indicators and answer options in the US Index methodology (a 15-min survey and cognitive interviews with 6 of the 11 companies of the US Index), adjustments were made this quarter to the US Index methodology. Specifically, lowered number of indicators, simplified answer options, integrated disclosure element within questions, integrated relevant information within questions, and reformulated questions to better link to company actions in the US. 

 

Next steps: In the next quarter, ATNI will have further consultations with the Expert Group on finalization of the methodology. The methodology will then be tested to ensure interrater consistency. ATNI plans to start with the data collection in November. Companies will gain access to their initial company assessment and will be able to respond with comments and additional materials in&#x202F;early 2022. 

India Index 

Following on from the launch of the India Index earlier this year, consultations for the next Index will begin in the fourth quarter of 2021. These will start with a webinar where results of the COVID-19 project will also be shared (more details in the section below). 

Additional Objective 3: Further development of verification-type activities (not funded by DGIS, not part of prolongation) 

Nutrition Business Monitor3 

The Nutrition Business Monitoring (NBM) project is dedicated to developing and testing a self-assessment for Small and Medium Enterprises to test opportunities for improving their impact on nutrition. The project is funded by GAIN and the tool is being tested in Nigeria and Bangladesh. 

This quarter, a second round of testing was organized in Bangladesh. Companies that have tested the tool are now in total 20, with 6 new companies conducting the testing. Following and linked to this, a two-day training was organized in Dhaka, Bangladesh on 8-9 September 2021, for&#x202F;companies that had tested the tool. The training focused on business development and marketing with a focus on nutritious foods. The training was facilitated by Bopinc and co-organized with SBN.  

Next steps: ATNI is currently working on wrapping up the testing phase and is planning for next steps. ATNI will write a public report based on the testing and capacity building results of the project. ATNI is planning to have a side event at the Nutrition for Growth Summit to share initial findings of the project. 

 

 

Responsible Lobbying Framework4 

Irish Aid Grant on Responsible Lobbying 

ATNI is in the process of acquiring new funding by Irish Aid to conduct a new Spotlight on Lobbying with a focus on all Global Index companies. ATNI has received an initial approval and will finalise the funding process in the next quarter. The aim is to start this work in Q4 2021 and publish the report by the end of Q2 2022.   




Extra activities 2020-2022 (funded by FCDO, not part of prolongation) 

Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020  

 

The fourth and final COVID-19 report summarizes company nutrition responses since the start of the crisis and presents recommendations for building food supply chains back better. ATNI researchers undertook a scan of the 39 companies&#x2019; main websites in early June 2021, focusing particularly on recently published annual reports and CSR reports.&#x202F; Interviews as well as email consultations on required urgent steps forward took place with the Consumer Goods Forum (CGF, FCDO, Feed the Truth, UNICEF, GAIN, SBN Nigeria and Food Industry Asia (FIA). Furthermore, media was monitored weekly on industry responses as well.  

The report was launched during the UNFSS pre-summit at the end of July, through social media channels, garnering over 9,000 views. After more than a year since the start of the pandemic, COVID-19 and the responses to it by companies and consumer reactions have presented risks and challenges for nutrition, including issues around increased consumption and marketing of unhealthy foods, donations that may not be of healthy products and concerns around inappropriate labelling of products as being immunity boosting. However, there are clear opportunities for companies to play a more positive role, with examples emerging &#x2013; whether this is responding to consumer demand for healthier products, renewing a focus on equity and priority populations, or leveraging their ability to support supply chains. ATNI calls on all the world&#x2019;s major food and beverage companies to step further along this path, taking consistent steps towards a future in which the food system is more resilient to COVID-19 and its economic and nutrition aftershocks, and also to any crises in the future. COVID-19 has been a moment of reckoning and it must be a moment of change. 

The Nutrition for Growth Summit 

 

ATNI attended all BCG meetings in Q3 as well as the Advisory Group meeting. ATNI engaged bilaterally with the Government of Japan to define a clear process on how BMS companies could participate in the summit. ATNI has been assessing the roadmaps of some of the Japanese companies that want to participate to the Summit. The basis for the assessments is the Call to Action as it is almost fully aligned with the N4G Principles of Engagement. As the deadline for assessments is the end of October, there will be further updates on this point in the next quarter. 

Additionally, the Government of Japan has decided to reinstate the Thematic Working Groups, to provide guidance for the program and speakers of the Summit. ATNI, as the co-chair of the working group on accountability is liaising with GNR and RESULTS UK to organize a meeting and discuss the role of the group for the coming months.  

Moreover, ATNI has developed an N4G Investor Pledge to be signed by its Investor Signatories and to be presented at the N4G Summit &#x2013; either during a plenary agenda event or during an official Summit side event. In early October ATNI submitted a proposal for official Summit side event which will focus on current responsible investment approaches to nutrition as an ESG issue. During this side event, to be co-hosted by ATNI and some of the Investor Signatories, the investor report will be launched.  

ATNI plans to publish the paper on&#x202F;nutrition in supply chains during the N4G Summit (see Action Research). ATNI is also planning on (co-)organizing a few other side events for the summit including on Workforce Nutrition in Supply chains and on the role of SMEs in nutrition and the NBM tool (see earlier section).  

The UN Food Systems Summit 

 

The UNFSS pre-Summit took   place from July 26 to 28.&#x202F;The actual summit was held in September, during the General Assembly of the United Nations in New York.   

Together with GAIN, ATNI co-organized two events on the topic &#x201C;Mobilizing Accountability Mechanisms for Aligned Business Reporting&#x201D; towards the pre-summit of UNFSS. 

an internal workshop that took place on 8 July with other accountability mechanism organizations; and a public event held on the 20th of July, also co-organized by CGF and Nutrition Connect to broaden the discussion and discuss different initiatives 

During the pre-Summit, ATNI launched the fourth COVID-19 report seconded by FCDO (on Tuesday, July 27, at the day of the private sector session).  

ATNI also participated during an online event on July 28 organized by the Food Foundation and WBA on accountability mechanisms in LMICs. The event was a follow-up to a previous event co-hosted in May on company accountability tools together with GAIN, WBA and Food Foundation (see earlier in this report). 

ATNI was involved in the launch of the UNFSS Accountability Pact on September 1, which gathered over 200 signatures from researchers and food and nutrition experts to promote better monitoring mechanisms for food systems.  

ATNI also attended the launch of the World Benchmarking Alliance&#x2019;s Food and Agriculture Benchmark on September 21, an official side event of the UNFSS. ATNI contributed nutrition data for the Benchmark, which assessed 350 companies on their sustainable business practices, including nutrition.  

The UN Food Systems Summit was held on September 23, with side events ranging from September 14 to September 24. The Summit took place in New York, meaning that the Opening Plenary began in the afternoon at 3pm CET. On the morning of the 23rd, ATNI published the second UK Product Profile 2021, and conducted a social media campaign in conjunction with ShareAction to disseminate the key findings of the report ahead of the Opening Plenary. ATNI attended the main sessions of the Summit and actively reported on the event through live tweeting.  

Following the Summit, Inge Kauer published a LinkedIn blog entitled &#x201C;UN Food Systems Summit: now is the time to take action&#x201D;, which provided commentary on how UNFSS and the upcoming Nutrition for Growth Summit create momentum for the nutrition agenda this Nutrition Year of Action.  

WHO Global Monitoring Mechanism 

 

ATNI is collecting data from companies that are members of the International Food and Beverage Alliance (IFBA) in order to report on commitments to WHO on reducing trans fats. 10 out of 11 companies have agreed to participate to this work. ATNI is currently working on updating the methodology and WHO will reach out to the companies to distribute it. Some of the companies have already provided the required data to ATNI &#x2013; Coca-Cola, Mondelez, Ferrero, Grupo Bimbo, Mars and Kellogg. The project timeline has been extended to the end of 2021.  

Collaboration with World Benchmarking Alliance 

 

To continue efforts to work together to drive private sector change in safeguarding human health and providing nutritious and healthy foods at affordable prices, ATNI has collaborated with WBA to align data collection efforts between WBA&#x2019;s Food and Agricultural Benchmark (FAB) and ATNI&#x2019;s Global Index 2021 on a set of overlapping indicators. In May 2021, ATNI shared with WBA, company assessments from the Global Index 2021 research for the 50 indicators relevant for the 6 nutrition indicators in the FAB based on publicly available information, that ATNI has collected from the public domain before starting a first round of engagement with companies along with a list of publicly available evidence used. These assessments did not include scores or rankings. This data was used in FAB&#x2019;s assessment, and the benchmark was launched this quarter. The findings were similar to ATNI&#x2019;s Global Index especially in areas of accessibility and affordability, with 80% of the companies assessed having no statements on affordability/accessibility. 

WBA and Food Foundation launched a coalition to strengthen accountability mechanisms for benchmarking the food industry in one of UNFSS pre-summit events in July. ATNI was one of the first members to sign up for the coalition and has been involved in the process of reviewing a toolkit developed by WBA and FF to inform national benchmarks. In October a call is planned with WBA to discuss how to work together in the next cycle.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation Arthur van Schendelstraat 650 3511 MJ Utrecht, the Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="GOALS 2 (ZERO HUNGER) AND 3 (HEALTH AND WELL-BEING FOR ALL), SDG 12 (TARGET 12.3)" percentage="100" vocabulary="9">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goals 2 (zero hunger) and 3 (health and well-being for all), SDG 12 (target 12.3)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2400000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/1D-INTERLEAVED-PARITYFEC" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/ATNI-Activity-Report-to-DGIS_Q3-July-to-September-202---FINAL-20211202041232.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core Objective 1	Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020. 

Core Objective 2	Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes. 

Core Objective 3	Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019.

Core Objective 4	Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. 

Core Objective 5 	Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact. 
 
Core Objective 6 	Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas. 

Core Objective 7 	Develop measurement and evaluations. 

Core Objective 8	Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. 

Additional ATNI Objectives (funded by various, not part of prolongation) 

ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include: 

Additional Objective 1	Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g., retailers, food service companies, fast food chains. 

Additional Objective 2 	Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries. 

Additional Objective 3 	Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.).</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
