<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-58279199-India Index</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-58279199" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 3: Publish three India Indexes for c. 10-14 manufacturers in 2016, 2018 and 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consumers, CSO&apos;s, private sector, Governments, Academia</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Objective: Publish three India Indexes for c. 10-14 manufacturers in 2016, 2018 and 2020</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publish three India Indexes for c. 10-14 manufacturers in 2016, 2018 and 2020</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs (DGIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Next to the Global Index, ATNF develops and publishes Spotlight Indexes that score and rate the ten largest Food &amp; Beverage manufacturers in each Spotlight Country. In 2013 ATNF piloted spotlight Indexes in Mexico, South Africa and India. The first Spotlight Index was the India Index, which was published in 2016. The first India Spotlight Index (2016) was well received and gained much media attention as well as interest from the public and private sphere. The full India Spotlight Index can be downloaded here After the launch of the 2016 India Spotlight Index, calls with all engaged companies in the India Index (7 out of 10) were set up. These companies had discussed the Index internally, at management level, and said that the Index provided new insights in nutrition. They have expressed interest in looking further into specific topics, such as marketing, employee health, Nutrient Profiling and undernutrition strategies. Many suggested that more Indian companies should be included in future indexes, e.g. growing soft drinks companies. Furthermore, the Indian government, FSSAI (Food Safety Standards Association India), expressed its commitment to continue working on nutrition, e.g. through improved labelling regulations and fortification standards to fight micronutrient deficiencies. The India Index results were discussed in an international investors webinar meeting in January to particularly discuss the rankings of the multinational companies in India with investors. In April, ATNF visited India, to discuss the impact of the first India Index as well as the roll out future India Indexes. Meetings were held with FSSAI, CII (Industry Association), GAIN India, TATATrust Foundation, Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, the Dutch embassy, DFID India and several companies. All expressed their support of the India Spotlight Index. In June ATNF participated in the India AgriProcessing visit to the Netherlands, organized by &#x201C;Rijksdienst Voor Ondernemend Nederland&#x201D; (RVO), and was able to present the India Index to participants and further engage with the Ministry of Commerce and Industry, Confederation of Indian Industry (CII), and the Dutch Embassy in India, whom were all present. Several in-depth articles referring to the first India Index were written after the launch, confirming new developments, both government and industrial; &#x2022; &#x2018;CSR through food fortification&#x2019; &#x2013; Published in January talks about how Food Fortification is a flagship corporate social responsibility initiative that can afford companies the opportunity to address a humanitarian challenge in an economically sustainable way. &#x2022; &#x2018;Leading Food And Beverages Brands Fail India&#x2019;s Double Nutrition Challenge&#x2019; &#x2013; published in March is a summary of India Spotlight Index findings and how F&amp;B companies should be addressing the double burden. &#x2022; &#x2018;Salt-free, fat-free, sugar-free: The new mantra of food makers in a health-conscious India&#x2019; &#x2013; published in March is addressing rising consumer demand for healthy products and how companies should meet this demand in order to grow &#x2022; &#x2018;Unfortified young India; published in March addresses the double burden and illustrates this with ATNI India data and analysis. ATNF developed and discussed the roll-out strategy for the India Index in its board meeting in May and concluded that for future Indexes ATNF will work on creating a deeper, more widespread awareness among the industry and other stakeholders about India&#x2019;s nutrition challenges and articulate the need for the growing F&amp;B industry to become a leading player in addressing these challenges. For this it needs to be more visible in India, e.g. through permanent on-the ground representation of ATNF, local research capacity, expanding the India Expert Group and intensified local partnerships with organizations such as CII, GAIN India and The Indian Nutrition Initiative (TINI). Indian funding would contribute to this mission. ATNF is currently writing a concept note for discussing future funding of the India Indexes with TATATrust Foundation. Next on the agenda Over summer ATNF will present and discuss the concept note with TATATrust Foundation and will further collaborate with CII on its nutrition and business agenda. In the fall, ATNF will start consultations as a preparation for the second India Index and it will organize in-depth meetings with industry, policymakers and civil society organizations. The Indexes will be presented at investor round-tables at the annual Asian Corporate Governance Association in India.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The publication of the first U.S. Spotlight Index was postponed from September to November 2018. The report is being finalized. It will rank the ten largest food and beverage manufacturers in the United States: nine that are also in the Global Index plus one other. The Index will score and rate the ten companies on their nutrition policies and practices in the United States, with specific attention paid to what they do to offer affordable healthy food to vulnerable consumers, such as children, and the urban and rural poor. U.S. Index Corporate Profile research activities Q2: &#x2022; The Expert Group has advised extensively on the report. &#x2022; The Index is scheduled to be published early on November 15, immediately after which the CEOs/Senior VPs of the respective companies will be invited to join a breakfast meeting with ATNFs Executive Director. &#x2022; A multi-stakeholder meeting is scheduled to take place on November 16 in Washington DC, followed by a BMS marketing roundtable. Additionally, an investor event is being organised for for November 19 with investment bank Bernstein in New York. In the week after the launch, a webinar will be offered to investors unable to attend the in-person meeting. &#x2022; ATNF was present, and facilitated a presentation, at the Healthy Eating Research meetings (April), and Partnership for Healthier America conference (first week of May).</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">US Spotlight Index In September 2018, ATNF will publish the first US Spotlight Index. It will rank the ten largest F&amp;B manufacturers in the US: nine that are also in the Global Index plus one other. The Index will score and rate the ten companies&#x2019; nutrition policies, practices and disclosure in the US, with specific attention paid to what they do to offer affordable healthy food to vulnerable consumers, such as children, and the urban and rural poor. US Index Corporate Profile research activities Q1: US Index is on track for a September 2018 launch &#x2022; The preliminary results of the US Index are ready. &#x2022; The drafting of the US Index report will start in May following the release of the Global Index, with input from RWJF, ATNF Expert Group and Board. &#x2022; Two meetings are planned to coincide with the launch of the US Spotlight Index: a multi-stakeholder conference (potentially in collaboration with Partnership for Healthier America (PHA)) and an investor event with Bernstein. &#x2022; ATNF + Burness (US PR agency) are planning US Index pre-launch events and media outreach at the Healthy Eating Research meetings (April), the Partnership for Healthier America conference (first week of May) and during the launch of the third Global Index 23 May. Nigeria Spotlight Index: ATNF continued discussions about the potential for a Nigeria Spotlight Index when visiting in February 2018. Several meetings were held with potential donors and interested stakeholders, among which were the Nigeria SUN Business Network, USAID, DFID, Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, Ministry of Agriculture, and the World Bank. The response was receptive but further assessments will need to take place to gauge the feasibility of funding a Nigeria Spotlight Index. Africa Spotlight Index: The Dutch Postcode Lottery (Postcode Loterij), to which ATNF submitted a funding proposal in September to develop a first Africa Access to Nutrition Index, informed us in February that the proposal has not been selected for the 2018 investments. There will be an evaluation scheduled.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">US Spotlight Index In September 2018, ATNF will publish the first US Spotlight Index. It will rank the ten largest F&amp;B manufacturers in the US: nine that are also in the Global Index plus one other. The Index will score and rate the ten companies&#x2019; nutrition policies, practices and disclosure in the US, with specific attention paid to what they do to offer affordable healthy food to vulnerable consumers, such as children, and the urban and rural poor. US Index Corporate Profile research activities Q1: US Index is on track for a September 2018 launch &#x2022; The preliminary results of the US Index are ready. &#x2022; The drafting of the US Index report will start in May following the release of the Global Index, with input from RWJF, ATNF Expert Group and Board. &#x2022; Two meetings are planned to coincide with the launch of the US Spotlight Index: a multi-stakeholder conference (potentially in collaboration with Partnership for Healthier America (PHA)) and an investor event with Bernstein. &#x2022; ATNF + Burness (US PR agency) are planning US Index pre-launch events and media outreach at the Healthy Eating Research meetings (April), the Partnership for Healthier America conference (first week of May) and during the launch of the third Global Index 23 May. Nigeria Spotlight Index: ATNF continued discussions about the potential for a Nigeria Spotlight Index when visiting in February 2018. Several meetings were held with potential donors and interested stakeholders, among which were the Nigeria SUN Business Network, USAID, DFID, Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, Ministry of Agriculture, and the World Bank. The response was receptive but further assessments will need to take place to gauge the feasibility of funding a Nigeria Spotlight Index. &#x2022; Separate meetings took place with key people from the Ministry of Health and the National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC), which both showed support for the idea of the develpment of a Nigeria Index. Africa Spotlight Index: &#x2022; The Dutch Postcode Lottery (Postcode Loterij), to which ATNF submitted a funding proposal in September to develop a first Africa Access to Nutrition Index, informed us in February that the proposal has not been selected for the 2018 investments. There will be an evaluation scheduled.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With a methodology adapted to meet the local context and developments , ATNF research analysts in May compiled preliminary profiles/assessments for the selected sixteen Indian companies based on in-formation available in the public domain. Two webinars were conducted end of May to inform compa-nies on the use of the data gathering platform and further details on India Spotlight Index research process and planning. Seven companies attended the webinars. Others that were unable to attend were informed of its content via email. Companies were also informed about the possibility of sharing information under Non-Disclosure Agreements (NDA), to share any relevant non-public information with ATNF analysts. In June and July, companies had access to the online data gathering platform to see the first reviews and provide additional information or evidence. A second review period will follow in August in which analysts had incorporated company comments and additional evidence. ATNF finalized the contract with India-based communications firm AvianWe and set out a communications plan with specific deliverables for the coming months. On 12th June, ATNF issued a press release among Indian media which featured an announcment of the companies being included in this iteration. The press release featured quotes from Inge Kauer and Mark Wijne drawing attention to the timeliness of this study. Reference was also made to the 2016 edition of the Index to raise the profile of the upcoming Index and reiterate the importance of company&#x2019;s improved scores.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With a methodology adapted to meet the local context and developments, ATNI&#x2019;s research ana-lysts finished an initial analysis of the 16 selected companies commitments, performance and disclosure this quarter. In July companies had access to the online data gathering platform to see the first reviews and provide additional information or evidence. A second review period followed in August after an-alysts had incorporated company comments and additional evidence. In August ATNI organised a visit to India to have face to face meetings with senior management in some of the companies in Kolkata, Chennai, Bengalore and Delhi to explain the rationale and the methodology of the second ATNI India Index and the options to engage in the research pahse. Two companies who had not yet actively engaged on the online platform, at that stage decided to engage. ATNI with its India-based communication counterpart AvianWe managed to get articles and interviews published in a variety of local outlets in this reporting period (see overview in section 5; outreach activities). End of August Inge Kauer was invited to speak at a National Nutrition Conclave in Delhi organised by the Confederation of Indian Industry&#x2019;s Food and Agriculture Centre of Excellence (FACE) and participated in a panel with industry and CSO representatives.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; A new senior program manager and a second research analyst joined the ATNF team in mid-September. They started preparations to visit India in the last quarter of 2018 to engage with companies and other local stakeholders (funders, experts, CSO&#x2019;s and government) and plan for the second iteration of the India Spotlight Index to be produced in the course of 2019 and pub-lished at the end of 2019.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; ATNF developed a concept for rolling out the next India Spotlight Index. This was first submitted and discussed with the Director of The Indian Nutrition Initiative (TINI/TATA Trust Foundation) in September (see Q3 report). &#x2022; In November, ATNF visited India again to discuss its plans with companies, CSOs and with Indian based funders (the Dutch embassy, DFID, US AID, BMGF and Tata-Trust Foundation). There is good appetite to broaden the scope of the India Index by including more Indian companies and by zooming in on nutrition issues at Indian state level. Conversations about partnerships and funding will continue in the new year.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; ATNF&#x2019;s senior program manager and research analyst visited India 20-30 November to engage with companies (all companies in the 2016 India Index were contacted) and other local stake-holders (funders, experts, CSO&#x2019;s and government) and plan for the second iteration of the India Spotlight Index to be produced in the course of 2019 and published at the end of 2019. &#x2022; With ATNF global expert group members Dr Kapil Yadav and Dr CS Pandav from India potential candidates were reviewed for setting up an India-specific expert group panel (from among others the Indian Council for Medical Research, the National Institute of Nutrition, the Scientific panel on fortification of FSSAI -the Food Safety and Standards Authority of India-, and FICCI -the Federa-tion of India Chambers Of Commerce &amp; Industry). Also discussed were the options for a state/district level deep-dive. &#x2022; Other topics discussed with the expert group members and other stakeholders included: ways to reducing methodology complexities/ addressing repetition in indicators; combining nutri-tion/undernutrition indicators; the plan to integrate product profile scores in the corporate profile and the need for enough time for companies to check product lists; capturing impact on popula-tions that lack access to healthy, affordable food the most/ defining priority populations; including more local companies in the next Index (suggestions gathered: segmenting according to sales per product category, use companies who signed up to FSSAI with reformulation pledges). &#x2022; Organizations visited include: WHO India, UNICEF India, GAIN India, Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Founda-tion India, the Food Safety and Standards Authority of India (FSSAI) and the Embassy of the Kingdom of Netherlands. &#x2022; ATNF has taken due note of the following ongoing FSSAI/ Government nutrition initiatives in In-dia: the Eat Right movement; the National Nutrition Strategy 2017; upcoming new labeling regu-lations and new regulations on advertising and nutrition claims, development of a new FSSAI Nu-trient Profiling System with WHO guidance, replacing CODEX with FSSAI regulations; an increased focus on fortification efforts (Anemia free India campaign, FSSAI new fortification rules). ATNF re-ceived positive reactions on our plan to start action research on Complementary Food/ Infant Feeding in India. &#x2022; The importance of maintaining post-launch engagement efforts and in-between Index processes for wider impact, specifically through establishing local representation (exact form to be deter-mined) is another issue shared by several stakeholders. &#x2022; Despite the high compliance rates registered in 2016 with the IMS Act on the marketing of Breastmilk Substitutes some stakeholders advised ATNF to repeat an on-the-ground assessment (BMS 2) but in a different metropolitan area and/or include rural settings.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Following feedback and recommendations from companies and other stakeholders in 2017 and 2018 the number of companies to be assessed in the 2019 India Spotlight Index has been in-creased to 16 companies (in 2016 10 companies were selected, but only nine were ranked). Com-panies are selected based on 2018 sales revenues of packaged foods to consumers. 11 out of the 16 companies are companies headquartered in India, five are multinationals with headquarters outside India. &#x2022; In anticipation of engaging with the investors of the listed companies among the 16 selected companies all their major investors were mapped. &#x2022; ATNF staff visited India 5-15 March to engage with companies (all companies selected for the 2019 India Index were contacted) and other local stakeholders (funders, experts, CSO&#x2019;s and gov-ernment). Eight companies attended a roundtable meeting to discuss our methodology and plan-ning for this year and the ATNF staff had one on one meetings with two more companies. These included two Indian companies that had not engaged before. Companies reacted positively to the proposed methodology changes (one overall ranking and streamlining, resulting in fewer indica-tors) and to ATNI providing more time for engagement with companies and for them to review product lists and preliminary findings. &#x2022; ATNF global expert group members Dr Kapil Yadav and Dr CS Pandav from India indicated, be-cause of time constraints, that they will not be available to review the methodology and initial re-sults this year. With their advice we approached a larger group of local experts and civil society organisations active in nutrition to review our methodology. We found a large group ready to re-view (parts of) the draft methodology in April and initial results and analysis later in the process. These include the National Institute of Nutrition (NIN), the Scientific panel on fortification of the Food Safety and Standards Authority of India (FSSAI), the local Food Fortification Resource Centre (FFRC), The India Nutrition Initiative (TINI), and the India offices of: World Health Organisation (WHO); the World food Program; GAIN; Alive and Thrive; Save the Children; Oxfam; Centre for Responsible Business and the Food and agricultural Centre of Excellence of the Confederation of Indian Industry -CII-FACE-. Most of these organizations attended a separate roundtable meeting the ATNF team organized for civil society organisations in Delhi. &#x2022; In a meeting with the CEO of the Government regulator FSSAI he confirmed the interest of the Government of India to follow the process and results of this year&#x2019;s India Index. Amongst others to see the impact of the Eat Right India movement and many initiatives started in support; the National Nutrition Strategy 2017; upcoming new labelling regulations and new regulations on ad-vertising and nutrition claims, the fortification efforts (Anemia free India campaign, FSSAI new for-tification rules) etc. FSSAI will be present when ATNI launches the 2019 India Spotlight Index by the end of the year. &#x2022; The importance of maintaining post-launch engagement efforts and in-between Index processes for wider impact was stressed again by different stakeholders. Specifically, ATNI was asked to ex-plore the option to follow-up actionable recommendations with companies with specific activities post launch. March 2019: ATNF staff visit Delhi and Mumbai. &#x2022; Stakeholder consultations started for BMGF funded project to develop an improved Nutrient Profil-ing System addressing undernutrition with a micronutrient component and to incorporate it in fu-ture iterations of our Indexes. A literature search into existing nutrient profiling models that con-sider micro-nutrients is initiated through Professor Mike Rayner of Oxford University with partners at Laval University, Canada. Experts are contacted for input on how to add value to our Product Profiles by adding a micronutrient component, relevant to undernutrition &#x2022; The contract with GAIN on a cooperation to develop a self-assessment tool in Sun Business Net-work countries for small and medium scale enterprises was signed end March 2019. In May ATNF will visit Nigeria to start preparations to develop this tool with the local SUN Business Network. A second country for the pilot is to be selected in April &#x2022; Nutrition for Growth N4G summit 2020 Tokyo; ATNF is asked to advice and contribute to the prep-arations for this summit. ATNF is part of the working group on food systems for this summit, coor-dinated by DFIF and FAO, and is part of discussions with GAIN, DFID and WFP to develop concrete stepping stones towards this summit. The summit expects to take the opportunity to deliver a legacy towards achieving the SDG targets to end malnutrition by 2030 by positioning nutrition as an essential driver and by ensuring new, fresh and SMART commitments, also from the private sector.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; The concept note to roll out the next India Spotlight Index was submitted and discussed with the Director of The Indian Nutrition Initiative (TINI/TATA Trust Foundation) in September. ATNF has been invited to present the Concept Note to the COO of the TATA Trust Foundation, the Strategy Director and Nutrition team in November.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-11-06">123900</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">41175</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNF</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">71756</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-31">35457</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-30">43638</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">109061</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">49900</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">36416</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">79510</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">48527</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
