<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-58279199-DGIS Annual Activity Report 2021</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-58279199" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS Annual Activity Report 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI has committed to deliver the following Core Objectives. 

 
Core Objective 1	Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020. 

Core Objective 2	Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes. 


Core Objective 3	Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019.

Core Objective 4	Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. 

Core Objective 5 	Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact. 

 

Core Objective 6 	Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas. 

Core Objective 7 	Develop measurement and evaluations. 

Core Objective 8	Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. 

 

Additional ATNI Objectives (funded by various, not part of prolongation) 

ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include: 

 

Additional Objective 1	Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g., retailers, food service companies, fast food chains. 

Additional Objective 2 	Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries. 

Additional Objective 3 	Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.). 

Extra activities 2020-2022 (funded by FCDO, not part of prolongation) 

With the additional funding support from FCDO as per amendment No. 01/2020, signed April 16, 2020, to the ongoing Accountable Grant for this project (no. 300590) ATNI will embark on the following extra activities:  

Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020. 

Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 Global Nutrition Summit (GNS)/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 United Nation&#x2019;s Food System Summit (UNFSS) and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020.  

Investor coalition starting October 2020.  

Workforce nutrition action research starting January 2021.  

Action research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets starting January 2021.  

Country approach starting July 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Introduction

Reflecting on the Nutrition Year of Action 

2021was a prominent year for nutrition with the United Nations Food Systems Summit (UNFSS) happening in September and The Nutrition for Growth (N4G) Summit in December. Throughout the &#x2018;Nutrition Year of Action&#x2019;, COVID-19 continued to have a large impact on the food sector magnifying the ever-increasing importance of nutrition, particularly for people most vulnerable to malnutrition. 

For the ATNI team, the pandemic meant another year of working mostly from home and travel limitations. Despite the challenges, ATNI continues to grow and play an important role in keeping the food industry accountable in their efforts to tackle malnutrition.  

ATNI played a leading role in engaging businesses in the N4G Summit that took place at the end of 2021. It actively participated as observer and advisor in the Business Constituency Group and (co)hosted and presented in 9 different official side-events of the Summit, all related to the role that companies can and should play in fighting malnutrition. ATNI was also co-chair of the Accountability Thematic Working Group that tracked commitments made by all stakeholders and advised the Japanese government on nutrition accountability. At the Summit, 53 institutional investors that are members of ATNI&#x2019;s investor group published a new pledge acknowledging the global nutrition crisis and pledging to take action on nutrition by committing to use the Investors&#x2019; Expectations on Nutrition, Diets, and Health and to directly engage with all publicly listed companies in the Global Index 2021 on the topic of nutrition. This is the first time that institutional investors came together as part of a multilateral nutrition summit, representing a landmark moment in how we use investment to solve one of the world&#x2019;s most pressing issues. Through this pledge, ATNI is proud to be working with these forward-thinking investors to help reach global nutrition targets and create a healthier future for all. ATNI will monitor the progress towards the pledge going forward.

On the investors front, ATNI facilitated a growing group of investors signatories in engaging with the companies that were assessed in the Global Index 2021. 76 Investors representing 16.6 trillion in assets under management have now signed up for the Investors Expectations. To showcase best-practices of investors and nutrition, ATNI published and presented a paper on this topic during a side-event prior to the N4G Summit.  

In addition, ATNI featured many prominent publications and activities, including the launch of the fourth iteration of ATNI&#x2019;s flagship Global Index that assessed 25 of the largest global food and beverage manufacturers on their nutrition efforts. An important component of the Index was the Product Profile, which presented an independent assessment of the nutritional quality of companies&#x2019; product portfolios, relative product quality within categories compared to peers and changes in portfolio healthiness over time. The results of this iteration of the Global Index showed that companies need to enhance their efforts to encourage healthier diets for all. The data from the Global Index was shared and used by ATNI&#x2019;s partner, the World Benchmarking Alliance (WBA), in its first Food and Agricultural Benchmark which also launched in 2021.

Together with the Global Index, ATNI assessed the worlds&#x2019; 9 largest manufacturers of Breast Milk Substitutes (BMS) and Complementary Foods (CF) on the extent to which they market their products in line with WHO guidance. The results were published as the first separate BMS/CF Marketing Index.  Additionally, ATNI published the second iteration of its UK Product Profile that assessed the nutritional quality of more than 4,000 products from 16 of the world&#x2019;s largest food and beverage manufacturers active in the U.K.

Throughout the year, ATNI conducted and published various action research papers including the fourth report in its COVID-19 series on food industry&#x2019;s nutrition responses to the pandemic, disseminating new knowledge and methodologies on lobbying by baby food companies, nutrition profiling systems, workforce nutrition in value-chains, inequities in the production of healthy foods, and new investors approaches to nutrition. 
 
In terms of country-specific work, ATNI published the second UK Product Profile and conducted research for its first UK Retailer Index, and for its second US Spotlight Index. Both will be published in 2022. 
 
Regarding collaboration with third-party organizations, ATNI continued its on-going work with the World Health Organization (WHO) on monitoring trans fats commitments of 11 companies who are members of the International Food and Beverage Alliance (IFBA).   
 
By the end of 2021, the ATNI team has remained stable at 17 staff members plus a few long-term consultants. 
Looking back at 2021, ATNI is particularly proud at its increased visibility and the leading role that it was invited to play at the N4G Summit in keeping companies accountable on nutrition. An external impact evaluation, based on 52 interviews and comprehensive data review, conducted by Steward Redqueen in the second half of 2021, confirmed the increasing value that ATNI adds. The secondment of the third grant by the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation (BMGF) as well as the highest rating in the internal evaluation by the UK Foreign, Commonwealth &amp; Development Office (FCDO), echoed this message.  
 
In addition to BMGF, FCDO, and the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs, ATNI received financial support from the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (RWJF), Irish Aid, GAIN, the Guy&apos;s and St Thomas&apos; National Health Service Foundation Trust through ShareAction and WHO in 2021.  
 
Looking ahead to 2022 

2022 promises to be an exciting year with new opportunities to expand ATNI&#x2019;s impact on nutrition. ATNI plans to use the outcomes of the impact evaluation to further strengthen its monitoring and evaluation system and to track progress and impact. 
 
ATNI is planning to conduct and publish several accountability reports in 2022, starting with the finalizing of the testing of the SME Nutrition Business Monitoring tool in Nigeria and Bangladesh together with the Global Alliance on Improved Nutrition (GAIN), followed by publication of the UK Retailer Index in May, and the US Spotlight Index in the fall.  
 
On BMS, ATNI will conduct thorough consultations on BMS assessment methodologies and approaches, as well as start in-country assessments for the next BMS Index that is planned to be published in 2023. Funded by Irish Aid, ATNI will also continue its research on commercially produced complementary foods. 
 
In addition to the BMS Index, the fifth Global Index is planned to be published in 2023. ATNI will dedicate 2022 to drawing lessons from the previous iteration and conduct consultations with businesses and other nutrition stakeholders. The lobbying practices of the 25 Global Index companies will be assessed against an adapted version of the Responsible Lobbying Framework in 2022, which was developed in 2021 to assess lobbying policies of BMS companies.  
 
Following a scoping exercise on the opportunities to increase its impact on micro-nutrient deficiencies through Large Scale Food Fortification (LSFF), ATNI will start up consultations for the next India Index (to be published in 2023) and explore a first Nigeria company accountability tool, fully tailored to the Nigerian nutrition context.  
 
Together with GAIN and partners in-country, ATNI will promote the tested SME Nutrition Business Monitoring tool where possible and apply it to a growing group of SMEs. 
 
ATNI&#x2019;s action research activities in 2022 will be focused on Large Scale Food Fortification and the Nutrition business case for investors. The aim is to further grow the group of investor signatories and involve them in company engagement, including after the UK Retailer and US Index publications.  
 
Regarding organizational improvements, ATNI will further strengthen its systems needed for collecting, assessing, and disseminating data and for performing research. It will also further improve its communications systems for disseminating nutrition knowledge and in turn change company behaviour. 
 
A new Executive Director will take over the position from Inge Kauer, who has decided to leave ATNI in the course of 2022, after nine fruitful years of building the organization. The ATNI team is expected to grow further in 2022 beyond 20 staff members. 
 
With regards to funding, part of the core funding will be continued or is expected to be renewed in the course of 2022. In addition, ATNI expects new targeted project-funders to join.  
 
Foremost, in 2022, ATNI will continue to strengthen its collaboration with nutrition partners, stakeholders, and donors, particularly in one or two new countries. For this reason, ATNI welcomes new partnerships on our road to fight malnutrition globally. 

Inge Kauer, Executive Director, Access to Nutrition Foundation &#x2003;

2. Global Index

ATNI spent the first half of 2021 conducting the analysis for its fourth Global Index, assessing 25 of the largest global food and beverage companies on their efforts on nutrition, which published on July 1st, 2021. The Global Index is ATNI&#x2019;s flagship product which is published every two to three years to provide companies, their investors, and other stakeholders with a unique rating of the world&#x2019;s largest food and beverage manufacturers&apos; contributions to addressing obesity, diet-related chronic diseases, and undernutrition. By comparing scores from one Index to the next, companies and other stakeholders can track and monitor progress over time.  
The Corporate Profile component of the Index assesses companies&#x2019; commitments and policies, practices, and disclosure across seven categories. The Product Profile component assesses the healthiness of companies&#x2019; products. Previously, each Global Index has included a Breast-Milk Substitutes (BMS)/Complementary Foods (CF) Marketing sub-ranking. However, this time, the results of the BMS/CF marketing assessment were published as a separate Index (see section 3). Companies of the Global Index that were also assessed on the BMS/CF Marketing Index, received an adjustment to their overall scores.  
This iteration of the Global Index included three additional companies than in the previous Index in 2018. Together, all 25 companies included accounted for approximately 24% of the processed F&amp;B market share in the world in 2018. Their combined 2018 F&amp;B sales were estimated to be over $720 billion.
The results of this iteration of the Global Index showed that companies need to enhance their efforts to encourage healthier diets for all. For the 22 companies that were assessed in both 2018 and 2021, the average score was 3.6. All 10 leading companies, except for Arla, scored lower than in the 2018 iteration, while most companies in the middle and lower rankings scored slightly higher. Like 2018, Nestl&#xE9; led the 2021 ranking with a score of 6.7 out of 10. Unilever came second with 6.3, and FrieslandCampina third with 5. Arla showed a significant improvement from 3.3 in 2018 to 5.1 in 2021, securing fifth rank in the Index and Meiji rose five places. For a summary of key findings, see box below. 


	Key findings of ATNI&#x2019;s Global Index 2021
&#x2022;	The average score of the 2021 Index was 3.3. 9 out of 10 leading companies scored lower compared to 2018, while most companies in the middle and lower ranking companies scored slightly higher.
&#x2022;	There was limited evidence found of a strategic, global approach to the pricing and distribution of healthy products that address micronutrient deficiencies to populations experiencing, or at high risk of, malnutrition. Despite a clear need for action to improve the affordability and accessibility of healthy products, particularly as COVID-19 has further threatened access to nutritious foods and increased micronutrient deficiencies, companies&#x2019; practices showed limited progress in this area.
&#x2022;	Only 31% of products met the independent healthy standard - 11,797 of the 38,176 distinct products assessed (more details in the section below).
&#x2022;	13 of the 25 companies included improved their score in nutritional governance, reflecting strengthened nutrition policies and management systems.
&#x2022;	5 companies showed significant progress in their scores and ranking because of the adoption of new nutrient profiling model (NPM) to monitor the healthiness of their products and/ or new commitments on (re)formulation at nutrient level.
&#x2022;	9 companies committed to follow international guidance by Codex and WHO/the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) to ensure food fortification delivers clear health benefits. In 2018, only four companies assessed did so.
&#x2022;	12 companies disclosed lobbying positions on important nutrition topics, whereas, in 2018, only two companies did so.
&#x2022;	In the BMS/CF Index 2021, three of the six companies that were also previously assessed increased their scores from the 2018 Index.	


Product Profile Assessment

The Product Profile is an independent assessment of the nutritional quality of companies&#x2019; product portfolios. The updated methodology for this iteration also analysed the nutritional quality within product categories, and improvements of product portfolios over time. 
In this iteration, the percentage of global sales represented by the products included in the research for each of the companies significantly expanded compared to the previous Global Index Product Profile in 2018, following the inclusion of new major markets. The number of distinct products assessed increased from 20,685 in 2018 to 38,176 in 2021.
Companies were also more engaging and active in reviewing and, where needed, revising product lists and nutrient information in specific markets. This improved the quality and representation of the Product Profile results and allowed for a better comparison of companies&#x2019; performance relative to peers.
At overall portfolio level, out of 38,176 distinct products sold by the 25 companies globally, 11,797 (31%) meet the healthy threshold (a Health Star Rating of 3.5 stars or more); the same percentage as in 2018. For only five companies, 50% or more of their products included in the assessment met the healthy threshold.

9 companies showed an increase in mean Health Star Rating of products in the markets selected between 2018 and 2021. More companies defined targets for nutrients of concern, with the most frequently reported targets being for sodium and trans-fat. 12 companies provided examples of developing specific products designed to help address malnutrition (e.g., through micronutrient fortification) in the preceding three years, aimed at children over five years old. 9 companies, 4 more than in 2018, adopted fortification policies in line with international guidelines. However, just six companies committed to only fortify products of high underlying nutritional quality or meet certain nutrition criteria.
Micronutrient enhanced nutrient profiling

The NPS+ project, initiated in 2018, aimed to test whether a new or adapted Nutrient Profiling System (NPS) that considers levels of relevant micronutrients can add value in the assessment of and discrimination between companies&#x2019; product portfolios and thereby encouraging to address undernutrition linked to micronutrient deficiencies. During data collection for the Global Index 2021 Product Profile, ATNI took the opportunity to run a pilot test for this NPS+ project.  ATNI commissioned the George Institute for Global Health (TGI) to develop and test a new algorithm that would incorporate micronutrients relevant for public health. All companies in the Global Index 2021 were invited to submit additional micronutrient information for products across three low-and-middle income countries (LMICs). A total of five companies provided additional micronutrient data for this test, and the validation study included 1,890 products. Results showed that the overall mean HSR improved slightly when using the new model, however, overall ranking between different company portfolios did not change. It was concluded that the modified HSR model tested with micronutrient points does not give an additional layer of information about differences in micronutrient quality at portfolio level at this moment. This pilot test demonstrated that the explicit incorporation of micronutrient values into nutrient profiling is plausible and can be objectively evaluated. In July, ATNI and the project partners organized a multi-stakeholder webinar to present the results of the study, discuss project implications and gather additional feedback from academics, industry representatives and leading non-governmental organizations working in the field of nutrient profiling (among others, GAIN, Choices International, Sight and Life).  ATNI will use the results of this project in future country indexes and action research to explore the use of the modified model for specific purposes (e.g. fortification efforts, product category specific assessments).

Launch of the Global Index

The launch of the Index was held across three events spread over two days. On Thursday, July 1st, ATNI held two online meetings: one for companies and one for investor signatories. These were followed by a multi-stakeholder webinar on the 2nd. All events were well attended, filled with constructive discussion with a wide range of attendees from 19 companies, 45 investors, and over 25 CSOs and partner organisations. 
The launch received significant media coverage with several news outlets picking up the story including and op-ed in Devex, news stories in Nutrition Insight, FNB News and Wall Street Online. In total, ATNI has received 497 pieces of coverage including an interview at Dutch Radio. In addition to media news outlets, companies released their own press statements to announce their rankings. These include Nestl&#xE9;, FrieslandCampina, and Unilever. 
 	
Additionally, many key opinion leaders and organizations in the nutrition space shared their thoughts and support for the index on social media including: FCDO Minister Wendy Morton MP, Lawrence Haddad, SDG2advocacy hub, UN working group on NCDs, The Power of Nutrition Group, The George Institute for Global Health, The Question Mark Think Tank, and Food &amp; Drink Tech. 

On October 5th, 2021, the Global Index 2021 was launched in Japan through an online event co-hosted by ATNI, Nomura Asset Management and ESG consultancy firm Neural Inc. The event was supported by the Japanese Sustainable Investment Forum (JSIF). The event saw a wide variety of stakeholders, including company representatives, government officials, academics, institutional investors, and members of trade associations, come together to discuss the findings of the Global Index 2021 and to reflect on how they are relevant to the Japanese market as well as to Japanese companies assessed in the benchmark. The event was well-attended both by Japanese and international stakeholders. 

Post-publication Engagement

After the launch, ATNI invited all companies of the Index to online meetings to dig deeper into Global Index results and use ATNI research in company decision-making, and target-setting. In 2021, ATNI conducted 17 calls with 15 of the companies that showed an interest in these meetings. For 2 Japanese companies, a separate launch event was held. In addition, with 2 companies, Nestl&#xE9; and Pepsico, ATNI has held multiple meetings. These companies requested separate meetings with their Senior Executives and Board members to communicate the results as well as separate meetings with their nutrition teams. 12 Senior and Board representatives from Nestl&#xE9; and 7 from Pepsico joined these meetings. Also, for the first time, companies that did not participate in data collection process, such as Suntory and Mengniu, reached out and expressed an interest in understanding ATNI&#x2019;s work. 

Overall, the responses from all companies have been positive. It is evident that companies discuss Global Index results internally and use them to make improvements. A few insights from companies expressed in the post-launch meetings are given below: 

&#x2022;	Unilever company representatives expressed that they want to act on ATNI recommendations regarding disclosure. The company also wants to engage further on product profile and fortification. 
&#x2022;	Suntory shared that the company has created a health policy and expanded their disclosure in response to the 2018 results of the Global Index. 
&#x2022;	Nestl&#xE9; applauded ATNI on the growing impact of the Global Index and role specifically in producing evidence for investors engagement. 
&#x2022;	Mondelez reviewed and discussed results at the executive level with the promise to use them to inform a heatmap and then a roadmap to work on specific areas of improvement for the different areas of the company. 
&#x2022;	Kraft Heinz appreciated ATNI&#x2019;s neutral lens in assessing nutrition. The results of the Index have been discussed at each business unit and at global leadership level including the CEO. The company uses ATNI recommendations to set internal targets on nutrition as part of the company&apos;s 2020- 25 agenda.
&#x2022;	General Mills has shared the results with key leaders in the company. The company followed GI 2018 recommendations to put together a commentary on their lobbying efforts which they published. The company wants to engage more with ATNI on the priority populations and accessibility and affordability. 
&#x2022;	Danone staff shared that they are identifying areas of maximum improvement in ATNI methodology to advise senior management on strategic choices that will help improve the company&#x2019;s Global Index scores. 
&#x2022;	Conagra shared that they used Global Index results in their citizenship report and discussions with investors.
&#x2022;	Keurig Dr Pepper shared Global Index results with their sustainability governance committee that meets monthly. When the results came out, the company shared that they did a side-by-side comparison of the results with their new strategy and their alliance in partnership with healthier America.

Next steps: In 2022, ATNI will consolidate key outcomes of the post-engagement discussions with companies and investors (see Section 4) and begin preparations for methodology consultations for the next iteration of the Global Index, to be published in 2023.  

&#x2003;
3.  Monitoring marketing of breast-milk substitutes and complementary foods

In June 2021, ATNI published the fourth BMS/CF Marketing Index that was for the first time published as a standalone Index. ATNI spent the first half of 2021 doing data analysis and company engagement for this publication. The BMS/CF Marketing Index feeds into the Global Index, specifically for the companies that are part of both assessments. 

COVID-19 has magnified the critical importance of good nutrition and healthy diets. Baby food companies play a critical role in improving the health and life prospects of infants and young children by protecting and supporting breastfeeding. By following the recommendations of the International Code of Marketing of Breast-milk Substitutes (The Code), they can contribute to the realization of several WHO 2025 nutrition targets and the Sustainable Development Goals. Specifically, to SDG 2 - by preventing child mortality and various forms of undernutrition - and SDG 3 - by decreasing children&#x2019;s risks of developing NCDs later in life. Until such time as all countries have passed laws and regulations to give effect to The Code, baby food companies can contribute to health and nutrition by voluntarily marketing their products in line with WHO recommendations. 

The BMS/CF Index scores and ranks the world&#x2019;s largest baby food manufacturers&#x2019; marketing policies, practices, and disclosure.  Up to 2018, this analysis assessed the extent to which these companies market their products in line with The Code and subsequent relevant World Health Assembly (WHA) resolutions, excluding WHA 69.9. From the 2021 iteration onwards, ATNI included all subsequent WHA resolutions including WHA 69.9 in its scope.

ATNI used a comprehensive, robust, and published methodology, developed with the advice of WHO, UNICEF and many other international experts and not-for-profit organizations dedicated to improving infant and young child nutrition. This Index comprised two elements:  
&#x2022;	BMS/CF 1. Corporate Profile assessment &#x2014; designed to measure the extent to which the BMS companies&apos; marketing policies align to The Code, the strength of their management systems and the extent of their public disclosure. 
&#x2022;	BMS/CF 2. In-country assessments &#x2014; designed to measure companies&apos; compliance with The Code and/or national regulations (whichever is stricter) in two selected countries. The studies were conducted using the NetCode protocol for periodic assessment; data was collected in healthcare facilities, retailers, and various forms of the media.

Additionally, ATNI joined efforts with FTSE Russell to increase efficiency for the country assessments that FTSE uses to determine whether BMS companies meet its criteria for inclusion in its FTSE4Good Indexes.  ATNI provided data to FTSE Russell from its in-country NetCode studies, and PwC was sub-contracted to produce two in-country verification reports for each of the three BMS companies in the FTSE4Good Index &#x2013; Nestl&#xE9;, Danone and Reckitt. ATNI continued to apply its criteria and methodology as previously for its Indexes, providing a subset of data to FTSE.

Company Engagement

In the latest iteration, ATNI extended the Index to nine largest baby food companies globally, compared to six included in 2018 iteration. These included Danone, FrieslandCampina, Kraft Heinz, Nestl&#xE9;, Abbott, Reckitt, Feihe International, Inner Mongolia Yili Industrial Group and China Mengniu Dairy. In addition, two emerging markets, Philippines, and Mexico, were selected in which NetCode studies were undertaken to assess the extent of marketing of BMS and CF products. 

Launch of the BMS/ CF Index

The fourth BMS/CF Marketing Index 2021 was launched on 17th June 2021, together with the two country assessments for Philippines and Mexico. For the day of the launch, ATNI issued a press release, social media messaging and stakeholder emails. As follow up to the publications, ATNI organized 3 webinars. The first webinar took place on May 13th with Filipino stakeholders &#x2013; government and CSOs, where the in-country study results were presented. The second webinar was held on June 24th. This was a closed webinar with experts to present the results of the Index and the two country reports to selected invitees. Participating organizations, in addition to individual consultants and experts, included UNICEF, WHO, BMGF, Alive &amp; Thrive, FHI 360, JB Consultancy, and the Meridian Institute. The last webinar, held on June 29th, organized with CSOs in Mexico to present to them the results of the in-country assessment into details and discuss how these can be used to drive progress. 

Post-launch company engagement

In the third quarter of 2021, ATNI offered post-launch engagement calls to all BMS companies to discuss the results of the Index and the recommendations on the way forward. ATNI engaged with 5 companies: Nestl&#xE9;, Danone, Friesland Campina, Kraft Heinz and Reckitt. These calls included constructive discussions in which all companies agreed to take action. Reckitt informed ATNI that the company is planning on updating their policy based on the recommendations of ATNI&#x2019;s report, as well as wording on labels of BMS products, based on findings from the country assessments. Nestl&#xE9; informed ATNI on its plans to implement their policy to Infant Formula 0-6m globally. Danone said it was open to exploring improvements with a focus on strengthening country manuals and asked for further insights from the analysis. FrieslandCampina informed ATNI that they updated their BMS Marketing Policy following the results of the Index. KraftHeinz shared that it was working on updating their policy and labels globally, based on recommendations and engagement with ATNI.

Call to Action

The BMS Call to Action was the result of the Meridian process, a multi-stakeholder process that started in 2016 with the aim to bring together BMS stakeholders from industry, CSOs and UN agencies and discuss a roadmap for the way forward. The Call to Action was published by WHO, UNICEF and several other NGO signatories on June 25th, 2020. It asked all BMS companies to make a public commitment by September 2020, to achieve full compliance with The Code by 2030. The signatories of the Call to Action actively reached out to the top 20 BMS companies. ATNI has been part of the Meridian process from the beginning, and for the Call to Action, ATNI was asked to be the independent evaluating party and analyze the companies&#x2019; responses for the signatories and assess whether the companies make any of the commitments with regards the Call to Action. 
In 2021, ATNI assessed the responses and roadmaps of the companies to the Call to Action and was asked by the Government of Japan to conduct the assessments of BMS companies against the Principles of Engagement of the N4G Summit which were similar to the BMS Call to Action. Some Japanese companies that were interested to participate to the N4G Summit submitted roadmaps to the BMS Call to Action in the months prior to the Summit and followed up with ATNI. These included Megmilk, Glico, Morinaga and Meiji. ATNI engaged extensively with Meiji that showed continuous interest in complying in advance of the Summit. Despite the discussions, no company was found to be eligible to participate in the Summit.

Development of the next BMS/CF Index

ATNI plans to increase the number of companies in the BMS Index and assess the top 20 BMS companies in the next iteration.  Also, the number of country assessments will be increased to 5-7 countries, to be able to capture all companies on the ground. 

Next steps: To this regard, ATNI will start an internal process of reviewing its current methodology to improve it and ensure that it fit-for-purpose based on the upcoming changes. To achieve this, ATNI will organize regular meetings with its BMS Expert Group, as well as regular internal brainstorming sessions. During the first quarter of 2022, ATNI will hold initial consultation meetings with key stakeholders, such as the Nutrition Center of the Philippines, Alive &amp; Thrive, UNICEF China, Universidad Iberoamericana and WHO Europe to further explore how to approach the country assessments.  In Q2 of 2022, ATNI will finalise the external consultation deck and plan meetings with external stakeholders, including CSOs, companies and other experts to review the methodology and approach for the next iteration of the BMS Index. Preparatory work and data collection will begin later in the year. In addition, in early 2022, ATNI also plans to develop and published a model policy to guide companies on BMS marketing. The model policy will consolidate the latest requirements around BMS marketing to-date to guide BMS manufacturers in fully implementing and complying with the The Code and all subsequent World Health Assembly resolutions in policy and practice. BMS manufacturers will be able to refer to this model policy when revising or developing their own policies on BMS marketing. If a company applies the entire model policy, it will ensure that BMS products are appropriately marketed in line with international standards and public health guidance to protect the health of infants and young children globally. This document is the first of its kind for BMS companies and ATNI hopes that it will become a useful tool for engagement, especially when reaching out to the new companies that will be assessed. 

Action Research on Commercially Produced Complementary Foods

In May 2021, ATNI published a landscape study for the Philippines on Complementary Feeding and the role of Commercially Produced Complementary Foods in young children&#x2019;s diets. The study contained two elements:
&#x2022;	Landscape Analysis: Infant and Young Child Feeding: What is the status of older infants&#x2019; and young children&#x2019;s nutrition, diets, and health, what influences it and how can it be improved?
&#x2022;	Product Profile of Commercially Produced Complementary Foods (CPCF): More specifically, do these products meet the nutritional standards of the WHO Europe&#x2019;s newly developed nutrient profiling model (WHO NPM) designed to assess the nutritional quality of CPCF marketed as suitable for older infants and young children (6-36 months), and whether are they labelled in line with WHO recommendations.
The goal of this research is to improve the nutritional quality of CPCF in the Philippines and to ensure that these foods are appropriately labelled. ATNI is currently also working on a landscape study on the role of Commercially Produced Complementary Foods in Mexico. This report will be published in Q2 2022. 
A consortium led by UNICEF EAPRO called COMMIT, consisting of ATNI, WHO, World Food Programme, Alive&amp;Thrive, and Helen Keller International&apos;s Assessment &amp; Research on Child Feeding,  is looking to adjust the WHO Euro NPM model for CPCF to Southeast Asia and use it to assess products founds in Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam. ATNI will develop a regional company benchmark for Southeast Asia and country briefings to present main findings from each country. The consortium started in 2021 and will continue till 2023. The ATNI reports will be published towards the end of 2022, and they will be the first of their kind. This piece of work is funded by Irish Aid. 
&#x2003;
4. India Spotlight Index

In 2016, ATNI published the first India Spotlight Index, a first-of-its kind independent national assessment to measure the nutrition-related policies and practices of India&#x2019;s 10 largest food and beverage manufacturers. This second 2020 iteration extended the scope of the Index by including the 16 largest food and beverage manufacturers in India &#x2013; nine of which were previously assessed in 2016. In February 2020, ATNI launched and published the main results of the India Spotlight Index 2020 as well as the detailed results and ranking of the assessment on defining, formulating and producing healthy foods (Category B in our Index, the Product Profile). The principal finding, following months of in-depth research, was that the largest food and beverage companies in India are providing only limited options of healthy products to a population faced with major nutrition challenges. However, the report found that companies are showing a greater understanding of &#x2013; and a commitment to fighting &#x2013; the enduring and mounting double burden of malnutrition in India.  

For the other Categories (on Governance, Accessibility, Marketing, Employee and Consumer Lifestyles, Labeling and Engagement), ATNI initially just presented the overall findings and scores. The detailed analyses and results of the other chapters were to be published throughout 2020. Additionally, ATNI planned to organize a CEO Roundtable for the 16 companies assessed in the India Index as well as other high-selling food and beverage companies in India in August 2020. 

Unfortunately, due to Covid-19 this could not proceed. Since then, ATNI explored ways to engage with companies online to take forward previously planned discussions.
 
In February 2021, ATNI launched the detailed findings of the thematic chapters followed by a post-launch engagement phase. 

Next steps: In 2022, ATNI will start up consultations for a next India Index/Accountability tool. In Q1 some online interviews will be held. In Q2, consultations will start-up. ATNI consultations will be aligned with the Large-Scale Food Fortification work. Methodology development will start Q2-Q3, after consultations. For Q3-Q4 data collection and drafting report is scheduled. The launch of the next India accountability tool is scheduled for 2023 (Q2).

5. Investor Engagement 

Investor Signatories recruitment

ATNI continued to work on expanding the membership of the Investor Coalition in the first quarter of 2021. In addition, ATNI began working with a Japanese consultant to reach its profile in Japan ahead of the Tokyo Nutrition for Growth Summit and to include Japanese investors in its signatory base. 
Following a process of stakeholder consultations, the ATNI Investor Expectations on Nutrition, Diets and Health were published on July 1st 2020 and shared with existing ATNI signatories to ask them to reconfirm their support. ATNI has continued to increase its signatory base since then, and 12 new investors have pledged their support to ATNI between January and December 2021: Aikya Investment Management (UK), Apostle Funds Management (AU), CZ Group (NL), Ethos Foundation (CH), Fukoku Capital Management Inc. (JP), Guys&apos;s and St. Thomas&apos;s Charity Endowment Fund (UK), Legal and General Investment Management (UK), MUFG Asset Management (JP), Nomura Asset Management (JP), Pictet Group (only the nutrition fund was a signatory in 2020) (CH), Resona Asset Management (JP), UBS Asset Management (CH). The total number of Investor Signatories at the end of December 2022 is 76 investors, representing $16.4 trillion in assets under management. 
Additionally, in 2021 ATNI has had positive introductory meetings with several investment houses, including Sumitomo Mitsui Trust Asset Management (JP), Invesco (US), HSBC (UK), and Newton Investment Management (UK). 
Collaborative Investor Engagements 
Two webinars for existing signatories were held in March 2021 to present the plans for the collaborative engagement, provide them with timelines and ask them on informing us with which companies they are planning to engage. 50 of the then-74 ATNI Investor Signatories, representing $12.3 trillion in assets, have been taking part in the Collaborative Investor Engagement facilitated by ATNI, based on the findings of the Global Index 2021. 

After the release of the Global Index, in July 2021, the investor engagement letters drafted by ATNI were shared with all publicly listed companies in the Global Index 2021 (i.e., a total of 20 companies). Between September to December 2021, investors held a first engagement meeting with 16 of the 20 companies. Investors had extensive email correspondence with two of the three companies they have not had an engagement meeting with yet. Only one company has been unresponsive to investors thus far. Members of the ATNI Investor Support Team attended these meetings in the capacity of note-takers. 

Ahead of most of the engagement calls with the companies, ATNI provided an in-depth investor briefing about each company, to support investors in their engagement efforts and to ensure the investor engagement is successful. Between August and December 2021, a total of 12 company-specific investor briefings were held by ATNI. Lauren Compere, Managing Director at Boston Common Asset Management (one of ATNI&#x2019;s Investor Signatories) and former Board Member of ATNF, said that &#x201C;the team&#x2019;s really detailed investor briefings are fabulous. The nuance and the detail really make the engagement more effective.&#x201D; Maria Ortino, Global ESG Manager at Legal and General Investment Management, said about the Keurig Dr Pepper briefing: &quot;excellent pre-KDP meeting, well done to the team.&quot;

To ensure the smooth and successful running of the engagement, ATNI also organized several additional calls and teach-in sessions for investors:

&#x2022; On September 9th, 2021, the ATNI team, in collaboration with The George Institute for Global Health, provided an overview of the Product Profile 2021 and presented an in-depth analysis of two companies&#x2019; assessments.
&#x2022; On September 23rd, 2021, the ATNI team delivered a teach-in on the topics of responsible marketing and lobbying.
&#x2022; On November 24th, 2021, the ATNI team provided an in-depth presentation about ATNI&#x2019;s BMS / CF Marketing Index 2021.

These calls were well-attended by investors, with an average of 20 investors attending each teach-in session and additional investors asking for the event recording. 

Investor Portal

Together with website developers, ATNI developed and launched a password-protected investor portal on its website in January 2021, as a repository of investor-authored or investor-relevant reports on nutrition.  In September 2021, the collaborative engagement part of the Portal was launched. This is dedicated to storing all materials relevant to the engagement, including recordings of the briefings about each company and notes for each engagement meeting. 

ATNI Investor Report

On November 30th, ATNI published a report, Institutional Investors&#x2019; Approaches to Addressing Nutrition, Diets and Health, outlining investor action on nutrition. The report was launched, with Vijay Rangarajan, Director General Americas, and Overseas Territories at FCDO giving introductory remarks, during an official side event of the Tokyo Nutrition for Growth (N4G) Summit that was organized by ATNI in collaboration with Chatham House, Nomura Asset Management, Achmea Investment Management, Legal and General Investment Management, and Rathbone Greenbank Investments. The event was well-attended, and the report has been widely shared not only within the networks of ATNI&#x2019;s Investor Signatories but also with a wider range of nutrition stakeholders. The report, intended to help global non-investment sector readers understand the pivotal role those institutional investors play in driving better corporate performance on nutrition and health. It includes eight case studies based on publicly available information and profiling members of the ATNI Investor Signatories group. The case studies outline how investors are tackling health and nutrition using strategies such as ESG integration, negative/exclusionary screening, norms-based screening, engagement, and shareholder action, positive/best-in-class screening, sustainability-themed investing, and impact investing. The report has been accessed over 400 times on the ATNI website.

Next steps: ATNI will continue to disseminate the Investor Expectations on Nutrition, Diets and Health and to recruit new investors who can join the ATNI Investor Group. AUM size, geographical diversity and nutrition / health focus will be important considerations in new signatory recruitment efforts. ATNI will continue to support investors in their engagement with the Global Index 2021 companies and will draft an impact report at the end of the engagement program. Once interest from ATNI&#x2019;s Signatories will have been gathered for the UK Retailer Index 2022 collaborative investor engagement, ATNI will facilitate this engagement in a similar manner. ATNI will explore how and under what conditions data can be shared with third-party data providers, to maximise the dissemination of ATNI&#x2019;s data and their uptake by investors. ATNI will work to facilitate the inclusion of one ATNI Investor Signatory in the Responsible Investor Japan 2022 Conference, which includes a session on &#x2018;Sustainable Food Systems&#x2019;. ATNI will also explore opportunities to take part in other responsible investment conferences (e.g., the Responsible Investor Europe conference and the Principles for Responsible Investment in-person Conference) to continue its outreach efforts with investors. 
&#x2003;
6. Development of new spotlight indexes and accountability tools

Nutrition Business Monitoring Project (funded by GAIN)

The Nutrition Business Monitor (NBM) project is aimed at developing and testing a voluntary self-assessment tool for Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) to identify gaps and opportunities for improving their impact on nutrition. The project was funded by GAIN and was implemented in partnership with the SUN Business Network. The tool was tested in two countries: Nigeria and Bangladesh. 

In the past year, ATNI worked on finalizing the testing of the tool in the two countries. 46 companies in total tested the tool &#x2013; 23 in Nigeria and 23 in Bangladesh. Following the testing, ATNI organized 2-day trainings in Lagos and Dhaka on business development and on marketing with a focus on nutritious food. These themes were identified based on the outcomes of testing the tool.  

In November 2021, ATNI co-organized with GAIN, WFP, FAO and SBN an official N4G side event called &#x2018;Scaling up the contribution of SMEs to nutrition &#x2013; tools and SUN Business Network case studies&#x2019; where the NBM tool and companies that tested the tool were presented.

Next steps: During Q1 of 2022, ATNI team will visit both Nigeria and Bangladesh where ATNI staff will meet with nutrition stakeholders to discuss the NBM tool and the potential for future collaboration on upscaling the tool. In March 2022, ATNI will publish a report, presenting what the tool aims to do and the success factors for further rolling it out.  ATNI, together with GAIN, intends to promote and apply the tool in new LMICs and upscale the number of companies using it. 

US Spotlight Index (funded by RWJF)

ATNI began preparatory work on the second US Spotlight Index in 2021. Based on insights gained through a set of tools to test and improve clarity of indicators and answer options in the US Index methodology (a 15-min survey and cognitive interviews with 6 of the 11 companies of the US Index), the ATNI team adjusted the methodology in Q3 of 2021. Specifically, this exercise resulted in lowered number of indicators, simplified answer options, integrated disclosure element within questions, integrated relevant information within questions, and reformulated questions to better link to company actions in the US. 

In the last quarter of 2021, ATNI held consultations with the Expert Group and subject specialists on finalization of the methodology. Some key topics discussed related to the definition of priority populations in the US context and recent developments around federal assistance programs. After these consultations, the research team reviewed the adjusted methodology together to reach agreement on interpretation of final methodology. Data collection began in December 2021. 

Next steps: Data collection will continue the first quarter of 2022. ATNI will begin analysis of data in April 2022 and the US Index is planned to be launched in Q3 of 2022. ATNI will explore promotion of the US Index during the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition, Hunger, and Health in 2022.

UK Product Profile (funded by ShareAction)

Supported by ShareAction, through a fund from Impact on Urban Health, part of Guy&#x2019;s &amp; St Thomas&#x2019; Foundation, the U.K. Product Profile 2021 was launched on the ATNI website on September 23rd, on the day of the UN Food Systems Summit. The U.K. Product Profile 2021 is the second of its kind, following the first U.K. Product Profile published in 2019. The 2021 report assessed the nutritional quality of more than 4,000 products from 16 of the world&#x2019;s largest food and beverage manufacturers active in the U.K., using the data from the 2021 Global Access to Nutrition Index. The products analysed accounted for approximately 50% of total U.K. retail sales of manufacturer brands&#x2019; packaged foods and beverages in 2019. 

Key findings:
&#x2022;	Sales from healthy products has grown from 22% to 29% in the 2021 Product Profile
&#x2022;	Average HSR for all products assessed is 2.2 out of 5 stars, similar to 2019 UK Product Profile. 
&#x2022;	Also similar, only 32% of products analyzed using the Health Star Rating met the healthy threshold of 3.5 out of 5 stars.
&#x2022;	Nine out of the 16 companies assessed were found to have improved to some extent the healthiness of their portfolios 
&#x2022;	Overall, only 13% of products analyzed for all companies combined met nutritional standards for products that can be marketed to children, compared to 15% in previous report. 

On October 26th, the ATNI team presented the findings of the U.K. Product Profile 2021 in a webinar organized by ShareAction titled &#x201C;Health Matters: Assessing food and drink manufacturers &#x2018;progress on health&#x201D;. The event was well-attended and featured a lively discussion focusing on the nutrition challenges and the relative corporate responses in the UK market.

UK Retailer Index (funded by ShareAction)

As a follow-up to the UK Supermarket Spotlight report that was published early 2020, at ShareAction&#x2019;s request, ATNI drafted a proposal to present to ShareAction&#x2019;s funder, Impact on Urban Health (part of the Guys&#x2019; and St Thomas&#x2019; Foundation), to develop and publish a full UK ATNI Retailer Index in 2022. This was approved mid-2020. 
The methodology for this Index was published in May 2021. The data input and engagement phase were finalized at the end of August 2021. 9 out of 11 retailers engaged on the ATNI data collection platform. ATNI also engaged with several of the retailers in one-on-one calls to clarify outstanding points. All engagement was positive, and four retailers signed a non-disclosure agreement to share more data. In September, the ATNI team began data analysis. 
Next steps: In Q1/Q2 the team will finalize the report and company scorecards, including a thorough review and further quality control checks. Publication is scheduled for May 2022. After the launch, ATNI will offer one-one meetings to all retailers to discuss findings and company scorecards. ATNI will also work on investors engagement on this specific topic.


7. Nutrition for Growth (N4G) summit and aligning global accountability mechanisms

Nutrition for Growth Summit

The Nutrition for Growth (N4G) Summit, originally planned for December 2020 and postponed due to the COVID-19 pandemic, was held in a hybrid format in Tokyo in December 2021. The aim of the Tokyo N4G Summit was to secure new major nutrition commitments from governments, donor agencies and research funders, UN agencies, civil society organizations, academia, and private sector actors in the following five main areas: health, food, resilience, data-driven accountability, and nutrition financing.

Accountability working group

Following the preparatory conference in The Hague in the summer of 2019, co-facilitated by ATNI, ATNI co-chaired the accountability working group which advised the Government of Japan on the accountability mechanism for the Nutrition for Growth Summit. 

Together with GNR and Results UK, ATNI co-led the Thematic Working Group on Accountability which was revived - along with the other Thematic Working Groups &#x2013; two months before the Summit to provide input to the agenda of the Summit. The three co-leads, with input from the members of the working group, defined the agenda on Accountability for the second day of the Summit, as well as led the organization of 2 N4G side events on accountability. The first side event focused on focused on engaging all stakeholders in a discussion on the importance of accountability, specifically challenging the idea of accountability as a barrier to progress. Speakers representing the thematic working groups, as well as speakers from existing accountability mechanisms presented and discussed the importance of accountability for commitment-making and how accountability can be raised as the key element for enhancing nutrition policies. The second event aimed to be an opportunity to take stock of the commitments made - celebrating the tremendous effort from all participants - to discuss the key takeaways and learnings from the Summit and explore the future of accountability, engaging with key accountability mechanisms to understand the way forward for progress on nutrition and strengthened accountability (see also the section on Outreach). 

In 2022 ATNI continues to engage further with Global Nutrition Report (GNR) on how to monitor accountability of commitments that were made at the Summit. Providing sufficient funding ATNI will monitor company accountability in this respect. A Technical Support group with representatives from different angels will be set up by GNR.

Business Constituency Group

In 2020 and in 2021, ATNI continued to regularly advise the Business Constituency Group (BCG), in which it participated as an observer offering advice on how companies can prepare and submit SMART commitments, which include accountability elements. ATNI participated in the monthly Business Constituency Group (BCG) online meetings together with the Consumer Goods Forum (CGF), the International Food &amp; Beverage Alliance (IFBA), Food Industry Asia (FIA), the World Business Council for Sustainable Development (WBCSD), the SUN Business Network (SBN) and GAIN as well as representatives from the United Nations Food Systems Summit (UNFSS). ATNI, together with other BCG members, co-hosted a side event for the N4G on the role of BCG. 

Investor mobilization

Additionally, to its advisory role in the BCG, ATNI led facilitation of investor engagement at the Tokyo N4G Summit, securing possibilities for investor participation in the Summit events and exploring possibilities for an investor Call to Action to companies and governments. 

ATNI drafted the N4G Investor Pledge, supported by 53 of its Investor Signatories representing $12.4 trillion in AUM. The N4G Investor Pledge was officially launched on Day 1of the N4G Summit by Akihiko Nishioka, President and CEO of Resona Asset Management. It was the first time that investors engaged in such a way at a multilateral global event. This pledge represents a smart commitment from investors to use the framework of the Investor Expectations on Nutrition, Diets and Health in their engagement, analysis, and investment processes as well as a commitment to directly engage with all listed companies in the Global Index 2021. To ensure the Pledge received sufficient media coverage, ATNI contracted a Press Agency specialized in the investment sector. This resulted in several articles, most notably in Forbes (an interview with ATNI Executive Director Inge Kauer), Reuters, Nutrition Insight, and much more. ATNI will continue to monitor progress against the Pledge by means of creating the necessary track record of the collaborative investor engagement, which will result in an impact report to be drafted in Q4 2022 / Q1 2023.

Advising the Government of Japan

ATNI played an advising role to the Government of Japan, more specifically on accountability issues and on company engagement. ATNI also assessed the compliance of BMS companies against the Principles of Engagement of the N4G Summit and provided advice to the Government of Japan on whether the companies should be eligible to participate. More information on this point can be found in the BMS section. 

UN Food Systems Summit
ATNI played an active role in preparations of the UNFSS, which took place in New York in September 2021 with a July pre-Summit event hosted by the Government of Italy. The UNFSS, focused on food systems rather than on nutrition specifically, aimed to launch bold new actions to transform food systems, delivering progress on all 17 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). The aim of the Summit was to produce commitments by Governments, UN Partner Organizations, Private Sector, and Civil Society.  See section on outreach activities for details on ATNI&#x2019;s participation in UNFSS. 

 
Responsible Lobbying (funded by Irish Aid)
As a result of the Meridian process, a multi-stakeholder process involving a variety of actors interested in issues relevant to BMS products, a new framework on lobbying called the Responsible Lobbying Framework was developed. The Framework can be used both as a set of globally applicable principles and standards, outlining what responsible lobbying would look like, and as an evaluation tool of a specific organization&#x2019;s lobbying activities. It is sector agnostic, and it is designed to be used by companies, industry associations, investors, and a wide range of other organizations. ATNI decided to develop a pilot methodology based on this framework and use it to assess the lobbying policies, management systems and disclosure of the 9 largest BMS companies globally, based on publicly available information. This work was funded by Irish Aid.

The output was a spotlight on lobbying report focusing on the BMS companies, including company scorecards. Additionally, ATNI conducted research on the taxonomy of influence for the BMS sector, and an internal research report on lobbying &#x2013; the taxonomy of influence and the feasibility of a lobbying observatory was developed to help guide future work. In 2021, ATNI received funding for another year to conduct a lobbying spotlight for the 25 Global Index companies. This work will begin in March 2022 and is planned to be completed by September 2022. 

WHO Global Monitoring Mechanism (funded by WHO)
This project includes an analysis on the levels of total fat, saturated fat, trans fats, industrially product trans-fat (iTFA) and ingredients to see the progress companies have made in meeting their commitment to reduce iTFA in products. ATNI engaged with WHO, IFBA and the 11 IFBA companies being assessed in this project in July 2021. ATNI started data analysis towards the end of 2021.  Upon completion of data analysis. ATNI will continue with writing the final report and discuss a public launch.

Aligning Accountability Mechanisms: WBA and TFF
To continue efforts to work together to drive private sector change in safeguarding human health and providing nutritious and healthy foods at affordable prices, ATNI has collaborated with WBA to align data collection efforts between WBA&#x2019;s Food and Agricultural Benchmark (FAB) and ATNI&#x2019;s Global Index 2021 on a set of overlapping indicators. In May 2021, ATNI shared with WBA, company assessments from the Global Index 2021 research for the 50 indicators relevant for the 6 nutrition indicators in the FAB based on publicly available information, that ATNI has collected from the public domain before starting a first round of engagement with companies along with a list of publicly available evidence used. These assessments did not include scores or rankings. This data was used in FAB&#x2019;s assessment, and the benchmark was launched in September 2021. The findings were similar to ATNI&#x2019;s Global Index especially in areas of accessibility and affordability, with 80% of the companies assessed having no statements on affordability/accessibility.

WBA and Food Foundation launched a coalition to strengthen accountability mechanisms for benchmarking the food industry in one of UNFSS pre-summit events in July 2021. ATNI was one of the first members to sign up for the coalition and has been involved in the process of reviewing a toolkit developed by WBA and TFF to inform national benchmarks. TFF facilitated a pilot of the toolkit in India towards the end of 2021. Since this work overlapped to some extent with ATNI&#x2019;s ongoing work in India, both organizations developed a collaborative approach and are strongly committed to collaborating to strive for alignment in measurement, to reduce duplication of effort and to ensure that engagement between the two organizations and companies is as efficient as possible. ATNI supports the pilot benchmark in India to ensure alignment with ATNI&#x2019;s upcoming work in India in 2022 and 2023. The two organizations are committed to sharing contact information on implementing partners in-country, stakeholders, research data, and align consultations where needed to ensure maximum alignment.

&#x2003;
8. Outreach activities

In 2021, ATNI continued to attend and host a multitude of events and activities. Some of these are listed below with a brief description: 
April
&#x2022;	ATNI was invited, alongside GAIN, to co-host a technical session during the Global Health Science and Practice Technical Exchange, a four-day conference organized by USAID. The session, titled &#x201C;Strengthening Private Sector Accountability and Engagement to Improve the Diets of Infants and Young Children&#x201D; focused on ATNI&#x2019;s latest research on Commercially Produced Complementary Foods.
May
&#x2022;	ATNI co-hosted an Independent Dialogue of the UN Food Systems Summit, together with The Food Foundation, GAIN, and the World Benchmarking Alliance. The session, which was well attended, focused on how benchmarking initiatives could be applied to low- and middle-income countries.
&#x2022;	ATNI participated in the Spring Conference organized by the UK Sustainable Investment and Financial Association (UKSIF) through a webinar on the role of nutrition for public health. Alongside speakers from ShareAction and the Guy&#x2019;s and St Thomas&#x2019;s Foundation, ATNI presented the business and investment case for nutrition.
June
&#x2022;	ATNI was invited to present its work at the National Academies of Science Engineering &amp; Medicine of the US Food and Nutrition Board. ATNI Executive Director Inge Kauer and ATNI Research and Engagement Advisor Amanda Berhaupt-Glickstein delivered a presentation titled &#x201C;The Business Case for Healthy Food at the Level of the Enterprise, Market, &amp; Nation&#x201D;.
&#x2022;	ATNI co-hosted a webinar with the UN Principles for Responsible Investment (PRI), titled &#x201C;Sustainable and Healthy Food Systems: Considering the E and the S of ESG&#x201D;. The webinar was well attended by several ATNI Signatories as well as by the broader investment community.
July
&#x2022;	ATNI launched the fourth iteration of the Global Index. The launch took place over 3 webinars: one aimed for companies, one for investors, and one large multi-stakeholder webinar. See section 2 on Global Index for more details on the outreach.
&#x2022;	During the UNFSS pre-summit in July, ATNI and GAIN co-organized two events on the topic &#x201C;Mobilizing Accountability Mechanisms for Aligned Business Reporting&#x201D;. This included an internal workshop with other accountability mechanism organizations; and a public event also co-organized by CGF and Nutrition Connect to broaden the discussion and discuss different initiatives. 
&#x2022;	During the pre-Summit, ATNI launched the fourth COVID-19 report seconded by FCDO. 
September
&#x2022;	ATNI was involved in the launch of the UNFSS Accountability Pact in September, which gathered over 200 signatures from researchers and food and nutrition experts to promote better monitoring mechanisms for food systems. 
&#x2022;	During the UNFSS, ATNI published the second UK Product Profile 2021, and conducted a social media campaign in conjunction with ShareAction to disseminate the key findings of the report ahead of the Opening Plenary. ATNI attended the main sessions of the Summit and actively reported on the event through live tweeting. 
October
&#x2022;	The ATNI team presented the findings of the UK Product Profile 2021 in a webinar organized by ShareAction, funder of the project, and titled &#x201C;Health Matters: Assessing food and drink manufacturers &#x2018;progress on health&#x201D;. The event was well-attended and saw ATNI members take part in a lively discussion focusing on the nutrition challenges and the relative corporate responses in the UK market.
&#x2022;	ATNI presented the Global Index 2021 to the Japanese audience in a multi-stakeholder event, sponsored by Nomura Asset Management, supported by the Japanese Sustainable Investment Forum (JSIF) and co-hosted by Japanese consultancy Neural Inc. The event was well attended and concluded with a remark by Ms. Keiko Okada, Deputy Assistant Minister/ Deputy Director-General, International Cooperation Bureau, Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan. 
November and December
&#x2022;	In November, ATNI Executive Director Inge Kauer was invited to take part in a n event at the 26th UN Framework Convention on Climate Change Conference of the Parties (COP26) on the topic of food safety. With the UK hosting the COP26 in Glasgow in November 2021, this event represented a unique opportunity to bring together regulators, food and feed scientists, consumer groups, industry experts, and academics from across the food system to discuss how to respond to global food systems challenges. The event was organized by the UK Food Standards Agency and by Food Standards Scotland and included a presentation by ATNI.
&#x2022;	Throughout November and December, ATNI played an active role as host, co-host, or event moderator in nine official N4G side events. These were shared with ATNI&#x2019;s stakeholders via the ATNI website, the ATNI social media accounts, through an N4G-specific newsletter, and via targeted stakeholder emails. 
o	ATNI co-hosted two events on the topic of Workforce Nutrition together with the Consumer Goods Forum. The first event, on November 16th, focused on private sector commitments on supply chain workforce nutrition and saw ATNI Research Director Mark Wijne share findings from the Global Index 2021. During the second event, held on November 25th, ATNI Program Director Marije Boomsma shared preliminary findings from ATNI&#x2019;s report on Workforce Nutrition Programs in Supply Chains: The Benefits of Addressing Malnutrition from Supply Chain Workers and How to Do So. The report was then officially launched on December 13th, 2021 and distributed widely within ATNI&#x2019;s networks.
o	On November 23rd, in partnership with GAIN, the UN Food and Agriculture Organization, the World Food Programme and the SUN Business Network, ATNI co-hosted an event used to present learnings from various organizations supporting SMEs as well as case studies by some SMEs. ATNI&#x2019;s Nutrition Business Monitor tool was a key element of the webinar. The events were graphically summarized by a graphic illustrator, whose drawings can be found on the relative ATNI project page, here.
o	On December 2nd and December 16th ATNI co-hosted two official side events on the topic of accountability for better nutrition, together with the Global Nutrition Report and with Results UK. The first event, which took place before the N4G Summit, focused on the role that accountability mechanisms can play in driving positive change within the nutrition space. The second event, which took place after the Summit, was used as an opportunity to reflect on the work that lied ahead after SMART commitments were made at N4G by governments, businesses, and civil society alike.
o	The full list of all N4G side events organized by ATNI is provided below. The N4G side events not only helped ATNI gain new visibility and strengthen its position as the expert organization on corporate accountability for nutrition, but also helped ATNI grow its network and create new partnerships with a variety of stakeholders. 
&#xF0A7;	16th November: SMART private sector workforce nutrition commitments: Leveraging the workplace to bring improved nutrition to millions of employees 
&#xF0A7;	23rd November: Scaling up the contribution of SMEs to nutrition &#x2013; tools and SUN Business Network case studies 
&#xF0A7;	25th November: Private Sector Nutrition Action: New Data to Inform Private Sector Commitments on Supply Chain Workforce Nutrition 
&#xF0A7;	29th November: Introducing the N4G Business Constituency Group: How business is stepping up to tackle malnutrition 
&#xF0A7;	30th November: The Business and Investment Case for Nutrition 
&#xF0A7;	2nd December: Accountability for action: Breaking down barriers to strong commitment making 
&#xF0A7;	6th December: Responsible Business Pledge for Better Nutrition: Business commits to tackling malnutrition 
&#xF0A7;	7th December: Building sustainable healthy diets and food systems: Aiming to improve nutritional literacy that leads to behavior modification 
&#xF0A7;	16th December: Action on accountability: Lessons learnt and the way forward beyond the N4G Summit 
Mentions of ATNI&#x2019;s work
In 2021, ATNI&#x2019;s work was featured and mentioned in several journals and newspaper articles, most notably the following: 
&#x2022;	In early 2021, ShareAction used the insights from the UK Supermarket Spotlight to form a coalition of institutional and retail investors and filed the first health-based shareholder resolution at Tesco, calling on the UK&#x2019;s largest food retailer to set targets to increase the proportion of healthy products in its sales. Tesco responded to the resolution in March 2021 and set a target to increase the proportion of sales from healthier products to 65% by 2025. The supermarket giant commits to publish a strategy to achieve this goal and to report on its progress annually, as requested by the shareholder proposal filed in February.
&#x2022;	In July 2021, the launch of the Global Index 2021 was covered by NutritionInsight, New Food Magazine, Food and Beverage News, NOS Radio and many more. 
&#x2022;	In September 2021, Devex published an opinion piece written by Inge Kauer titled &#x201C;Opinion: How to close the global nutrition gap post-COVID-19&#x201D;, reflecting on the Global Index 2021 findings in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic. 
&#x2022;	In December 2021, the Nutrition for Growth Investor Pledge was covered by Reuters in an article titled &#x2018;Investors push food &amp; drink companies, govts over &#x2018;nutrition crisis&#x2019;&#x2019; as well as by Forbes, which published parts of an interview conducted with Inge Kauer on the topic. 
&#x2003;
9. Action research (funded by FCDO and BMGF)

Action research is designed to focus on areas where conclusive evidence, international standards and/or company practice is weak or emerging. The goals are to feed into the methodologies for ATNI&#x2019;s Indexes, publish new analysis, and to contribute new insights on these topics to a wide range of stakeholders. In 2021, ATNI continued its action research on COVID-19 impacts and published the final report in the series. ATNI also conducted various action research activities to develop knowledge on nutrition topics relevant to the Indexes: action research on workforce nutrition, product inequities and on Large Scale Food Fortification (LSFF).

Monitoring Food and Beverage Companies&#x2019; Nutrition Responses to COVID-19 

In 2020, with support from FCDO, ATNI developed a framework to identify action (and inaction) by food and beverage manufacturers in response to the COVID-19 pandemic and its consequences, adding an explicit COVID-19 lens to ATNI&#x2019;s existing assessment of companies. 

Throughout 2020 and 2021, ATNI reported on findings in quarterly reports, with each report focusing on a specific aspect of the response. 
In July 2021, ATNI published the fourth and last report, including a comprehensive list of recommendations. This report summarizes company nutrition responses since the start of the crisis and presents recommendations for building food supply chains back better. ATNI researchers undertook a scan of the 39 companies&#x2019; main websites in early June 2021, focusing particularly on recently published annual reports and CSR reports. Interviews as well as email consultations on required urgent steps forward took place with the Consumer Goods Forum (CGF, FCDO, Feed the Truth, UNICEF, GAIN, SBN Nigeria and Food Industry Asia (FIA). Furthermore, media was monitored weekly on industry responses as well.

The final report was launched during the UNFSS pre-summit at the end of July, through social media channels, garnering over 9,000 views. After more than a year since the start of the pandemic, COVID-19 and the responses to it by companies and consumer reactions have presented risks and challenges for nutrition, including issues around increased consumption and marketing of unhealthy foods, donations that may not be of healthy products and concerns around inappropriate labelling of products as being immunity boosting. However, there are clear opportunities for companies to play a more positive role, with examples emerging &#x2013; whether this is responding to consumer demand for healthier products, renewing a focus on equity and priority populations, or leveraging their ability to support supply chains. In the report, ATNI calls on all the world&#x2019;s major food and beverage companies to step further along this path, taking consistent steps towards a future in which the food system is more resilient to COVID-19 and its economic and nutrition aftershocks, and also to any crises in the future.  

Workforce Nutrition

Workforce nutrition programs throughout a company&#x2019;s supply chain can have significant benefits for employees, employers as well as society. In 2021, ATNI conducted action research into this topic to explore what companies are doing to promote healthy diets and nutrition along their supply chains and how companies could act to do better. In the second half of 2021, ATNI conducted desk research focusing on several supply chains: cocoa, tea, coffee, horticulture, and garment. The ATNI team also conducted various interviews to understand the current landscape and the work that has been done so far, as well as to identify case studies from the sectors.

At the end of 2021, ATNI published a discussion paper titled &#x2018;Workforce nutrition programs in supply chains &#x2013; The benefits of addressing malnutrition among supply chain workers and how to do so&#x2019;, along with six company studies namely: Nature&#x2019;s Pride, Nestl&#xE9;, Twinings, Unilever, Olam and VF Corporation. The reports and case studies were published on the website and shared with selected stakeholders. ATNI gave a preview of the results of this research project during an N4G webinar in November. The gained knowledge through this piece of research will be instrumental in further strengthening ATNI&#x2019;s methodologies on workforce and supply chain nutrition but also for other organization, such as the Workforce Nutrition Alliance.

Product Inequities

ATNI&#x2019;s latest Global Product Profile, undertaken as part of the Global Access to Nutrition Index 2021, assessed the relative healthiness of the product portfolio of the largest 25 food and beverage manufacturers globally across 25 countries. ATNI has written a short research paper to explore to what extent the healthiness of companies&apos; portfolios varies by country, as an add-on to the Global Product Profile 2021.

In 2018 it seemed high income markets had higher overall HSRs compared to middle income markets. However, this 2021 paper highlighted that whilst there are differences in the mean healthiness (HSR) of product portfolios across all countries and categories assessed, no evident patterns across income level and/or geographic region were identified. At company level, discrepancies were found in the mean healthiness of products in the same categories across different markets.

The main message from the Inequities paper supported the overall message of the Global Product Profile 2021, that companies should do more to increase the healthiness of their portfolios and ensure that consumers are offered products with high nutritional quality and similar levels of healthiness across all countries where companies sell their products. The Inequities paper was published on the ATNI website in December 2021, following the Nutrition for Growth Summit.

Country Mapping

As part of the additionally funded activities by FCDO, ATNI has planned to develop more country specific approaches and tools to improve its reach to companies&#x2019; and their actions on nutrition in lower- and middle-income countries with a high double burden of malnutrition, to be achieved through two country mapping exercises. Nutrition landscaping studies can map relevant stakeholders and best pathways to better nutrition by also analyzing the role and influence of the private sector in improving nutrition. ATNI selected Nigeria for one of the landscape studies and planned to create a shortlist of countries for the second country selection in early 2021.

ATNI initially planned to begin the desk research for Nigeria in the first half of 2021, with the goal to produce a report and framework for a Nigeria Spotlight Index, to be started in July 2021. In agreement with FCDO, the work on the two landscape studies was put on hold due to budgetary restrictions at FCDO.  ATNI however did continue with other activities in Nigeria, such as testing the SME Nutrition Business Monitoring tool and consultation sessions with Nigerian stakeholders in February 2022 in Abuja and Lagos around a potential Nigeria Index and on Large Scale Food Fortification. Based on these activities, ATNI plans to start consultations for a Nigeria accountability tool in the second half of 2022. 

Large Scale Food Fortification Scoping exercise (funded by BMGF)

As part of the 2021-2023 BMGF grant, ATNI started designing the Large-Scale Food Fortification scoping project in September 2021.The objective of the exercise is to provide a better understanding of the components and actors of the Food Fortification value chains with a specific focus on Nigeria and India, and to identify knowledge and data gaps on the role companies play. The findings of the exercise will serve as a basis in defining the role that ATNI can play with regards to monitoring the role of the private sector in the Food Fortification value chain to drive positive change in fighting micronutrient deficiencies. 
In February, initial meetings took place with BMGF Nigeria and GAIN in Abuja and, online, with other nutrition stakeholders, including FCDO Nigeria and Technoserve. A field visit is planned for April 2022. As part of the India scoping exercise, the ATNI team visited India in March 2022.
ATNI will produce a report presenting key findings from the scoping exercise including desk research and the outcome of the consultations. In addition, 3 to 4 case studies (focused on India and Nigeria) will be shared. &#x2003;

10. Monitoring and Evaluation

Building on the development of ATNI&#x2019;s first comprehensive monitoring and evaluation system in 2020, ATNI undertook an independent impact assessment and M&amp;E review of the organization in 2021. ATNI hired a firm called Steward Redqueen to conduct this review. The objective of the assessment was to: 
&#x2022;	measure the results brought about by ATNI&#x2019;s programs. 
&#x2022;	assess the contribution of the programs to these identified results 
&#x2022;	provide a combination of findings, recommendations and learnings to the commissioner and other relevant stakeholders 
&#x2022;	determine the extent to which ATNI&#x2019;s M&amp;E and Results Framework fits in with ATNI&#x2019;s theory of change. 
In total, 52 key experts including senior management, staff, funding partners, investors, industry experts, civil society partners and food &amp; beverage companies targeted by ATNI&#x2019;s accountability tools, were interviewed. Besides interviews, the team conducted in-depth review of key documents, analysis of performance data, and a survey among staff to support the impact assessment. Using multiple sources of data allowed for robust analysis and triangulation of all findings.
As part of the research, ATNI prepared an extensive list of company impact that the organization made since its establishment. A few highlights are given in Box 3. 

	Box 3: ATNI&#x2019;s impact on Company Policies and Practices

In its 2016 India Index, ATNI recommended Nestl&#xE9; to increase its fortification efforts and programs to reach more vulnerable consumers beyond children. In 2020 the company was actively supporting and following the national guidance on Food Fortification, which was developed and adopted partly after ATNI&#x2019;s 2016 India Index recommendations on this topic, by introducing new fortified products that specifically address undernutrition or micronutrient deficiencies.
In Global Index 2016, FrieslandCampina made no direct reference to low-income populations in its commitments on access and affordability. In 2018, the &#x201C;Broadening access to nutrition&#x201D; strategy of the company was under development but didn&#x2019;t include concrete objectives on increased affordability. ATNI advised the company to create concrete targets to address vulnerable groups. Following ATNI&#x2019;s recommendation, FrieslandCampina effectively adopted a formal policy on affordability and accessibility in 2021, and established concrete, measurable targets linked to it, with reference to low-income groups, especially in lower-income countries.
In the 2018 Product Profile, ATNI estimated that only 10% of Unilever&apos;s food and beverage sales revenues were from products meeting the healthy threshold.  The average Health Star Rating for the company&apos;s products assessed was 2.1 out of 5.  In the 2021 Product Profile this increased to 17% of global sales, and the average Health Star Rating increased slightly to 2.2 out of 5. In 2016, the company reported that 35% of products met company&apos;s own &#x2018;Unilever Highest Nutritional Standards&#x2019;, an increase of just 2% compared to 2014. The company then set the target to have 60% of its products to meet its own standards (UHNS) by 2020. The company achieved this target in 2021, with 61% of its product portfolio meeting the Highest Nutrition Standards.
In 2018, Kraft Heinz did not disclose any information on how it supports its employee health and wellness with programs covering nutrition or physical activity. Kraft Heinz was encouraged by ATNI to improve this by having a more robust, well-designed health and wellness program incorporating nutrition, physical activity, and healthy behaviors, and to make it available to all employees and their family members worldwide. In 2021, KH improved their employee health and wellness programs by including a focus on nutrition and physical activity. The new &apos;LiveWell&apos; health and wellness platform was launched in the U.S. following a successful Canadian campaign.
In 2018, Reckitt did not disclose any policy, commitment or information about its management systems related to BMS marketing. ATNI recommended the company to increase its transparency and share more information publicly. In 2021, the company disclosed its lobbying policy and its engagement objectives in relation to addressing BMS-related issues with policymakers. The improvement was such that it achieved the highest score on disclosure among all the nine companies assessed in the 2021 BMS/CF Marketing Index.	

	
Next steps: The outcomes of these discussions as well as the insights gathered from board meetings are used to develop a management response to the assessment, including concrete actions that ATNI will take to act upon the main recommendations of the report. The management response will be shared with core donors, serving to track progress against action-points identified to address the recommendations of the report. A public version of the report will be made available on ATNI&#x2019;s website, including the executive summary as well as highlighted case studies. 
In 2022, ATNI will further strengthen its M&amp;E framework and reporting. Key follow-up activities include the enhancement of its TOC and alignment of its logframe to the updated TOC. The M&amp;E system will be further operationalized with the development of a simple and centralized data-collection tool with a roles and responsibilities&#x2019; matrix. Templates for stories of impact will be developed and support will be provided to staff to continuously collect and share information on changes brought about by ATNI&#x2019;s projects. Overall, ATNI intends to nurture a learning culture and improve its information management systems. 

&#x2003;
11. Risks 

At the organizational level, ATNI identifies risks continuously through the stream of the regular staff meetings as well as in the context of the quarterly Board meetings. The results are furthermore reviewed by and discussed with the ATNI Board Audit and Risk Committee. Over the last year, two Committee meetings were held, in April and in September 2021. No major changes were made to the Risk Register.  
 
Major other risks have been mitigated over the year by: 
 
COVID-19 and other unexpected effects: Over the entire year, ATNI continued to monitor Covid-19 (and other risks) closely and adjusted timelines, work plans, and financial/funding forecasts accordingly. 
  
Fundraising: To fill ATNI&#x2019;s funding gap in 2022 and beyond, ATNI is prioritizing fundraising. It attracted new funding in 2021: BMGF new grant, ShareAction, Irish Aid, WHO. It continued conversations with existing (e.g., FCDO) donors and actively started approaching new donors building upon ATNI&#x2019;s increased visibility in 2021. It also aims to partner with other organizations in fundraising (e.g., GAIN).   
 
Reputation: ATNI continues to be highly consultative with all its stakeholders, be inclusive and transparent following international standards and guidelines. ATNI also continued not to include on the Board or Expert Group any members currently or recently employed by major food manufacturers and not to receive funding from industry.  With regards to loss of reputation because of making errors in analysis and commentary, ATNI hired more senior staff members and continued extensive QA processes including information checks with companies prior to publication and intensive oversight of all research and analysis. ATNI also continued to implement and adhere to safeguarding policies that meet international standards and to monitor legal &amp; donor requirements regularly. ATNI has adequate policies and procedures in place to manage fiduciary risk. This includes oversight by its Board, and quarterly financial and annual external audit reports 
 
Competition: To prevent companies, investors and other stakeholders losing interest in the Access to Nutrition accountability tools because of competing with other accountability mechanisms and/or loss of interest in nutrition, ATNI continued in finding ways to make its tools and research more impactful and efficient in use (e.g., Global Index 2021 data-collection). ATNI also continued improving outreach to changemakers (particularly investors and policymakers but also civil society organizations; see SAN framework result in the Annex I). Moreover, ATNI keeps track of international priorities and other initiatives and identifies ways of aligning and partnering with them (e.g., GAIN, WBA, Food Foundation, GNR and Informas).  
 
Impact on all countries, also LMICs, and Visibility: ATNI continues to be recognized as an organization that leads to companies changing their actions or products which benefit all countries, also low-income countries. ATNI started to increase its focus on ATNI&apos;s impact on malnutrition in low-income markets through BMS work; through its work with SMEs, through the NBM tool, in Nigeria and Bangladesh; and through starting the Food Fortification scoping mission in India and Nigeria. It will continue increasing its scope on LMICs in 2022 and beyond through expanding its activities to other countries (India, Nigeria and potentially others for the SME tool). ATNI continued to clearly communicate in ATNI&#x2019;s Theory of Change, publications, media and in fundraising, ATNI&#x2019;s activities and impact on fighting malnutrition in LMICs. Moreover, ATNI strengthened strategic and impactful communication around the outcomes/ messages of research, which is described in the above Section on Engagement. ATNI hired a new Senior Comms Manager, who will start working for ATNI April 2022. 
 
Loss of data: breaching or loosing data due to data platform provider issues or internal file and back-up management issues. ATNI has a data protection policy for detailed measures in place, back up data is available (having several back-ups including internal and regular checks on the back-ups are being done) and contractual arrangements are in place. 
 
Staff and workload: ATNI has been a fast-growing organization in terms of projects and in terms of staff. ATNI prioritizes fundraising (see earlier) so that more (senior) staff can be recruited to strengthen the capacity of the relatively young team, while simultaneously focusing on consolidating and strengthening its team and organization and reducing workload. ATNI&#x2019;s Board oversees balance staff/workload and consistent quality and credibility, while donors monitor ATNI&apos;s performance through regular meetings with the Executive Director and Program Director of ATNI. The Executive Director has decided to leave ATNI after 9 years of building up the organization in the course of 2022. She is supporting the ATNI board in recruiting and onboarding her successor.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation Arthur van Schendelstraat 650 3511 MJ Utrecht, the Netherlands</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="GOALS 2 (ZERO HUNGER) AND 3 (HEALTH AND WELL-BEING FOR ALL), SDG 12 (TARGET 12.3)" percentage="100" vocabulary="9">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goals 2 (zero hunger) and 3 (health and well-being for all), SDG 12 (target 12.3)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">2400000</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/1D-INTERLEAVED-PARITYFEC" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/ATNI-Annual-Report-2021-to-DGIS_FINAL_25042022-20220516020545.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI Annual Activity Report 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNI has committed to deliver the following Core Objectives.
 
Objectives highlighted with a * will not be reported on as they are not applicable for this reporting period. 
Core Objective 1	Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020.
Core Objective 2	Publish comprehensive analysis of companies&apos; breast-milk substitutes (BMS) marketing policies and practices in both Global and Spotlight Indexes.
Core Objective 3	Publish two India Spotlight Indexes for c. 10-20 manufacturers in 2016 and 2019.  *
Core Objective 4	Publish Product Profiles for all India Spotlight Indexes. *
Core Objective 5 	Extend outreach activities for different stakeholder groups, particularly investors, to amplify impact.
Core Objective 6 	Develop action research activities to advance thinking and practice in key areas.
Core Objective 7 	Develop measurement and evaluations.
Core Objective 8	Conduct a feasibility study on expansion and innovation. *

Additional Objectives
ATNF also sees various options for expansion, on top of the Core Objectives, for which additional funding would be needed. These include:

Additional Objective 1	Developing one or more Global Indexes that assesses the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g., retailers, food service companies, fast food chains.
Additional Objective 2 	Development of new Spotlight Indexes for other priority countries.
Additional Objective 3 	Further development of complementary verification-type activities, such as the Product Profile (that could be expanded to assess labelling compliance and marketing spending; more or wider BMS marketing assessments, etc.).
Extra activities 2020-2022 (funded by FCDO, not part of prolongation)
With the additional funding support from FCDO as per amendment No. 01/2020, signed April 16, 2020, to the ongoing Accountable Grant for this project (no. 300590) ATNI will embark on the following extra activities: 

1.	Map and monitor food and beverage (F&amp;B) sector companies&apos; responses to COVID-19 starting April 2020.*
2.	Private sector commitment monitoring hub supporting 2020 Global Nutrition Summit (GNS)/Nutrition for Growth (N4G), 2021 United Nation&#x2019;s Food System Summit (UNFSS) and World Health Organization (WHO) starting August 2020. 
3.	Investor coalition starting October 2020. 
4.	Workforce nutrition action research starting January 2021. 
5.	Action research to assess inequities in nutritional qualities of companies&apos; product portfolios across markets starting January 2021. 
6.	Country approach starting July 2021*.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
