<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-58279199-GlobalIndex</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-58279199" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: Progress Global Indexes including US Index</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consumers, CSOs, Government, Private sector, Academics</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: Publish two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020. Jan-June 30th 2017. Objective: preparation for research Global Index 2018. Methodology development, company selection, online platform development, stakeholder engagement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparation and research for the publication of two further flagship Global Indexes for c. 25 manufacturers in 2018 and 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to Nutrition Foundation (ATNF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs (DGIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of this Objective ATNF publishes two Global Indexes: the third Global Index (2018) and fourth Global Index (2020). It is currently working on the preparations for the fourth Global Index. Input from companies and other stakeholders after the third Index has prompted a plan to reduce complexity, perceived duplication and implement other changes and improvements. Main changes and novelties for the new Global Index methodology were presented and discussed with the ATNF expert group and board. Two major changes are addressed in the new methodology: 1. Integration of the Product Profile assessment into the category B in the overall scoring or Cor-porate Profile 2. Integration of undernutrition into the overall scoring or Corporate Profile This second revision of the Global Index methodology started in parallel to the India Index methodolo-gy update. The latter will be published end of August. The research team prepared a second Global Index methodology draft, containing the specific indica-tors resulting from the streamlining process. Also, new indicators have been incorporated to strength-en our focus to work in line with SDGs. An overview of the updated assessment categories and indica-tors is presented in table 1 below. Table 1: Global Index 2020 preliminary Corporate Profile Methodology Overview Category (weight in total score) Description Criteria Section1: Nutrition governance and management A (12.5%) Corporate strategy, management and governance A1 Corporate nutrition strategy A2 Nutrition governance and management systems A3 Quality of reporting Section 2: Formulating and delivering appropriate, affordable, accessible products B (35%) Formulating appropriate products B1 Product profile results* B2 Product formulation B3 Defining healthy and appropriate products C (15%) Delivering affordable, accessible products C1 Product pricing C2 Product distribution Section 3: Influencing consumer choice and behaviour D (20%) Responsible marketing policies and auditing of compliance D1 Marketing policy: all consumers D2 Marketing policy: specific arrangements regarding responsible marketing to children and teens D3 Auditing and compliance with policy E (2.5%) Supporting healthy diets and active lifestyles E1 Supporting employee health &amp; wellness E2 Supporting breastfeeding mothers at work E3 Supporting consumer-oriented healthy eating and active lifestyle programs F (10%) Product labelling and use of health and nutrition claims F1 Product labelling F2 Health and nutrition claims G (5%) Influencing governments and policymakers, and stakeholder engagement G1 Lobbying and influencing governments and policymakers G2 Stakeholder engagement * Product Profile results are integrated as criterion B1 in Category B, which has seen its weight increased in the overall score. The second Global Index methodology draft will be shared with the Expert Group (EG) by the end of August, in preparation for a meeting that should take place during the first half of September. For this purpose, ATNF will also provide the EG members with an ad-hoc document describing the main changes proposed, including a description of the new scoring system and how it will affect the final company scores (especially taking into consideration the integration of the Product Profile into the Corporate Profile). This meeting should enable a more focused discussion, attending at the specific in-dicators proposed, before preparing the final methodology document. ATNF plans to share the updated Global Index methodology draft with stakeholders (including companies) by the end of September-October for further feedback and engagement. The Global Index methodology document will be final-ized in November so company engagement can start early 2020. Tokyo meeting with Global Index stakeholders To gain more insights on the relevance of the Global Index for Japanese companies and stakeholders in the region, ATNF organized a meeting in Tokyo (right) with the assistance of Ajinomoto, one of the companies in the Global Index. Companies, industry associations, representatives from four ministries, academics and other stakeholders affirmed the relevance of the Index to guide and support the nutri-tion agenda of Japanese multinational companies abroad as well as in Japan. For the Japanese con-text, reference was made to the specific needs of an ageing population which could be an element in the methodology of the future indexes.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of this Objective ATNF will publish two Global Indexes: the third Global Index (2018) and fourth Global Index (2020). It is currently working on the third Global Index. The third Index that will publicly rate twenty-two of the world&#x2019;s largest F&amp;B manufacturers&#x2019; nutrition-related policies, practices and disclosure, is expected to be published in March 2018.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of this Objective ATNI publishes two Global Indexes: the third Global Index (2018) and fourth Global Index (2020). In this quarter during and after summer 2019 the methodology re-vision was taken forward; a second methodology draft was shared and discussed with the Ex-pert Group (EG) in September. A selected group of stakeholders will be asked to comment and provide inputs to the methodology through an online survey in November 2019. The Global In-dex methodology document will be finalized in quarter 4 so company engagement can start early 2020. The Board approved the major revisions in the methodology (product profile inte-gration and undernutrition integration in one corporate profile algorithm) and the subsequent new category weightings as shown in table 1. Table 1: Global Index 2020 Corporate Profile Methodology Overview after revisions (&#x2018;old&#x2019; /pre-revision weightings in brackets) * Product Profile results are integrated as criterion B1 in Category B, which has seen its weight increased in the overall score. A start was made to get the data and criteria needed to select the companies for the 2020 Global Index. Company selection will be finalized in the last quarter of 2019.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core Objective 1: Progress Global Indexes The Access to Nutrition Foundation launched the Global Access to Nutrition Index 2018, the third Global Index, on May 23, 2018 in London. This Global Index 2018 assesses 22 of the world&#x2019;s largest food and beverage manufacturers&apos; nutrition policies, practices and disclosure, as well as the nutritional quality of their products in nine markets around the world. In addition, the marketing practices of the world&#x2019;s largest baby food manufacturers are assessed. &#x2022; All CEOs of the respective food and beverage manufacturers received a letter announcing the publication of the Global Access to Nutrition Index 2018. In this letter, the CEOs were offered the opportunity for ATNFs Executive Director to present and discuss the findings of the Global Index 2018 with the respective Board/MT members. The team is in the process of following up on arranging such meetings. &#x2022; In addition, meetings have taken place, and are further arranged, with company&#x2019;s experts to discuss the findings of the Global Index 2018 and the ways forward. &#x2022; A multi-stakeholder meeting took place on May 23 in London (Glazier Hall). Representatives from the following organizations attended: &#xF076; Abbott &#xF076; Action Against Hunger &#xF076; Arla Foods &#xF076; Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation &#xF076; Carnstone &#xF076; CFBAI &#xF076; Changing Markets &#xF076; Context &#xF076; Danone &#xF076; DGIS &#xF076; di:ga communications &#xF076; DSM &#xF076; EAT &#xF076; Edelman &#xF076; European Commission &#xF076; Food Climate Research Network, University of Oxford &#xF076; GAIN/SUN Business Network &#xF076; Global Nutrition Report &#xF076; Glopan &#xF076; IFBA &#xF076; Kepler Cheuvreux &#xF076; Mars &#xF076; Meiji &#xF076; Mondelez &#xF076; Nestle &#xF076; Newcastle University &#xF076; Nomad Foods &#xF076; Public Health England &#xF076; RB &#xF076; Soremartec Italia &#xF076; SustainAbility &#xF076; The Power of Nutrition &#xF076; UNICEF &#xF076; Unilever &#xF076; White Rook Advisory &#xF076; World Obesity Federation &#xF076; WorldFed &#x2022; An investor meeting, organized with the support of investment bank Kepler Cheuvreux, took place on the same day as the multi-stakeholder meeting. A webinar for investors not able to attend in person took place on May 24. The following company representatives and investors attended the in-person meeting: &#xF076; Nestl&#xE9; &#xF076; Mondelez &#xF076; Hermes Investment Management &#xF076; Janus Henderson Investors &#xF076; ShareAction &#xF076; BMO Global Asset Management &#xF076; Tribe Impact Capital &#xF076; Guy&#x2019;s and St Thomas&#x2019; Charity &#xF076; IPCM &#xF076; Impax Asset Management &#xF076; EdenTree Investment Management &#xF076; FTSE Russell &#xF076; Candriam &#xF076; Kepler Cheuvreuax &#x2022; Media outreach: more on the global coverage of the Global Index available in this blog post. - Lawrence Haddad of GAIN authored a blog entitled The 2018 Access to Nutrition Index and the need for a &#x201C;Charter for Responsible Food and Beverage Companies&#x201D; - Lauren Compere op-ed on the Global Index in Responsible Investor. Twitter Outreach:</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Access to Nutrition Foundation planned to launch the 2018 Global Access to Nutrition Index, the third Global Index, in May 2018. It will assess 22 of the world&#x2019;s largest Food &amp; Beverage manufacturers&apos; nutrition policies, practices and disclosure, and, for the first time, the nutritional quality of their products in nine markets around the world. The marketing practices of the world&#x2019;s largest baby food manufacturers will also be assessed. &#x2022; All Index report sections were written by ATNF and then reviewed by the ATNI Expert Group before being shared with the report designer &#x2022; The first draft of the Executive Summary was reviewed by ATNF&#x2019;s Board and Expert Group &#x2022; Scorecards were sent out to all companies for fact-checking and an NDA check &#x2022; Launch events and communications were planned with ATNF&#x2019;s PR agency di:ga Communications. The launch date was confirmed as 23 May, with separate events planned for stakeholders and investors in London (Glaziers Hall). Media outreach was planned, including communications in the US for the Global Index (together with US PR agency). Progress on the BMS Marketing assessments and the Product Profile are presented below.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Access to Nutrition Foundation planned to launch the 2018 Global Access to Nutrition Index, the third Global Index, in May 2018. It will assess 22 of the world&#x2019;s largest Food &amp; Beverage manufacturers&apos; nutrition policies, practices and disclosure, and, for the first time, the nutritional quality of their products in nine markets around the world. The marketing practices of the world&#x2019;s largest baby food manufacturers will also be assessed. &#x2022; All Index report sections were written by ATNF and then reviewed by the ATNI Expert Group before being shared with the report designer &#x2022; The first draft of the Executive Summary was reviewed by ATNF&#x2019;s Board and Expert Group &#x2022; Scorecards were sent out to all companies for fact-checking and an NDA check &#x2022; Launch events and communications were planned with ATNF&#x2019;s PR agency di:ga Communications. The launch date was confirmed as 23 May, with separate events planned for stakeholders and investors in London (Glaziers Hall). Media outreach was planned, including communications in the US for the Global Index (together with US PR agency).</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Access to Nutrition Foundation will launch the 2018 Global Access to Nutrition Index, the third Global Index, in May 2018. It will assess 22 of the world&#x2019;s largest Food &amp; Beverage manufacturers&apos; nutrition policies, practices and disclosure, as well as the nutritional quality of their products in nine markets around the world. The marketing practices of the world&#x2019;s largest baby food manufacturers are assessed too. &#x2022; October: Companies were able to submit final input on the online platform from mid-October until Mid-November. 16/22 Companies participated. Not engaged: Tingyi, Suntory beverages, Kraft Heinz, Lactalis, ConAgra and Brasil Foods. &#x2022; November: The ATNF research team conducted peer reviews during November and December. &#x2022; December: After finalizing peer reviews, initial analysis of company progress and scoring began. A meeting took place with ATNF and the chair of the ATNF Expert Group to discuss Global Index progress. &#x2022; During the last quarter of 2017, context chapters and introductions for the Index were also drafted by ATNF. &#x2022; Moreover, ATNF has started recruiting a PR agency for the Global Index launch in 2018 and wrote a Communication/PR guideline to this extent. Progress on BMS and Product Profiling are discussed below.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; As follow up to the publication of the Global Index 2018, published in May 2018, all companies scored and ranked in the Index were invited to have one-on-one meetings to discuss questions they might have on their scores and ranking, the methodology and the recommendations. In the last quarter of 2018 meetings took place with Ajinomoto, Danone, FrieslandCampina, and Unile-ver. For the first quarter of 2019 further meetings are scheduled (partly combined with follow up of the U.S. Index 2018) with Nestl&#xE9;, Mars, Coca Cola and Kraft Heinz. Companies generally appre-ciate the engagement process with ATNF and the use of the online platform but ask for streamlin-ing of our methodology and ways to appreciate the very different contexts of dairy-, confection-ary- and multi product companies. &#x2022; A review of the methodology of the Global Index that started in the last quarter of 2018 has led to plans to reduce complexity, perceived duplication and other changes and improvements. While ATNF reviews and revises the methodology after each Index iteration, the current revision is more extensive as it aims to integrate two major aspects of our current methodology: The Corporate Profile and the Product Profile, to come to one overall Index score and ranking. Moreover, the methodology needs to be streamlined to ensure we sustain or increase company engagement by reducing the resource burden, as well as enabling ATNF to expand its activities by reducing re-source requirements per Index iteration. The revision of the methodology will be done in parallel to updating the India Index methodology and will run well into 2019, offering experts, companies and other stakeholders to provide input in the process. U.S. Spotlight Index The first Access to Nutrition U.S. Spotlight Index was published in Washington on November 16, 2018. The first-ever U.S. Access to Nutrition Index reveals that the 10 largest U.S. food and beverage manu-facturers lack the policies and action needed to tackle the high levels of obesity and diet-related dis-eases in the United States and ensure consumers have access to affordable, healthy products. The companies are not doing enough to improve the nutritional quality, pricing and distribution of their products nor to improve their practices related to responsible and transparent product marketing and labeling. The Index&#x2019;s ranking of the 10 companies has Nestl&#xE9; leading the Corporate Profile with a score of 5.3 out of 10 for being the most transparent about its progress to help consumers eat healthier through commitments focused on making its product portfolio healthier, better informing consumers, more re-sponsible marketing activities and other efforts. Unilever came in second place and PepsiCo in third. ConAgra leads the Product Profile with a score of 5.8 out of 10 for carrying the healthiest product port-folio, followed by Kraft Heinz in second place and General Mills in third. Based on their total U.S. sales in 2016, the 10 companies included in the Index are Coca-Cola, ConAgra, Dr Pepper Snapple, General Mills, Kellogg, Kraft Heinz, Mars, Nestl&#xE9;, PepsiCo and Unilever. Launch meetings took place November 16, 2018 in Washington D.C.; &#x2022; Breakfast meeting with company representatives (13) from Coca-Cola, Conagra, Mars, Nestl&#xE9;, PepsiCo, RB/MJN, and Unilever. The main points of discussion were on (1) the role of food and beverage manufacturers in driving accessibility and affordability of healthy products, (2) future planning of the Index and reducing complexity, (3) the overlap between the Global Index and U.S. Index and (4) plans to venture into the Out-of-Home sector to capture a larger part of relevant business. &#x2022; Multi-stakeholder meeting with representatives from companies, CSOs, and experts present (at-tendance: 51). The U.S. Index was well received from various stakeholder perspectives, with a constructive dialogue between company and CSO representatives. Additionally, the investor per-spective was addressed. &#x2022; BMS roundtable (on invitation only) with representatives from BMS-related CSOs (attendance: 17). Main points of discussion were (1) interest in lobbying assessment focusing on BMS and in-dustry association roles, (2) lack of information on U.S. BMS marketing practices, and (3) the role for ATNF in engaging with FDA to address regulation. Additionally, an investors meeting took place on November 19, 2018 in New York. The meeting was hosted by Bernstein and attracted attendance from Arisaig Partners, UBS Asset Management, Ra-bobank, Tourbillon Capital, MEAG Munich Ergo Asset Management, Trinity Health and ICCR. Attendees were very engaged and a lively Q&amp;A took place. The publication of the Index was covered both in traditional media as well as on social media: &#x2022; The publication was covered in Hagstrom Report, Bevnet.com, Food Navigator, Food and Drink International, Food Dive, Cision, Baking Business, and Marion Nestl&#xE9; also made reference to the Index in Food Politics. Forbes ran a story on the Index which featured an interview with Inge and Vice President of Nutrition, Health and Wellness at Nestl&#xE9;. &#x2022; The #USNutritionIndex hashtag was used in 239 tweets by 95 contributors, including Partner-ship of Healthier America, American Heart Association, 1,000 Days, Rudd Centre, GAIN, Healthy Eating Research, ARCH Nutrition, Voices of Healthy Kids. ATNF and the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation have started discussions on a renewal of the grant for this work, to allow for a second US Spotlight Index to be made. Following the publication, companies ranked were invited to have a follow-up call with the ATNF to discuss the findings of the U.S. Index 2018 and the potential next steps. On request a call with Unile-ver was organised directly after they received the report under embargo -like all companies in the In-dex- a day before the launch events. A follow-up with Kellogg took place in Q4 of 2018. Calls are planned for the first quarter of 2019 with Conagra, Dr Pepper Snapple, KraftHeinz, Mars, Nestl&#xE9; and Pepsico. Nigeria Spotlight Index ATNF is exploring the feasibility of conducting a Nigeria Spotlight Index, potentially in 2019/2020. Additional objective 3: Further development of verifica-tion-type activities Additional Objective 3 focuses on further development of complementary verification-type activi-ties, such as the Product Profile assessments. &#x2022; A project proposal submitted for funding to BMGF to explore options for an improved Nutrient Pro-filing System with a micronutrient component and to incorporate it in future iterations of our In-dexes was approved in November. This project aims to objectively assess how company products can contribute to addressing undernutrition, focusing specifically on micronutrient deficiencies. Contact with project partners was started up in Q4 of 2018. &#x2022; Dialogue continued with GAIN on a cooperation to develop a self-assessment tool in Sun Business Network countries for small and medium scale enterprises. (the contract is expected to be signed early 2019). &#x2022; Funding for a UK Product Profile and UK pilot retail-sector Access to Nutrition Index (both to be published in 2019) was included within a proposal made by Share Action (UK NGO that works with investors to address ESG issues among companies) to Guys &amp; St Thomas&#x2019;s Foundation &#x2013; ATNF is reviewing a contract for a subgrant (50,000 GBP) expected to be signed January 2019. &#x2022; WHO Global monitoring mechanism; ATNF is asked by the World Health Organization as one of the initiators to develop a mechanism to follow-up on industry commitments on product (re)formulation (IFBA, CGF) &#x2022; Nutrition for Growth N4G summit 2020 Tokyo; The Japanese government has approached ATNF to advice and contribute to the preparations for this summit.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; As follow up to the publication of the Global Index 2018, published in May 2018, all companies scored and ranked in the Index were invited to have one-on-one meetings to discuss questions they might have on their scores and ranking, the methodology and the recommendations. Meet-ings have been planned and confirmed with Abbot, Ajinomoto, Danone, FrieslandCampina, Meiji, Nestl&#xE9;, RB/Mead Johnson Nutrition and Unilever. Planning of meetings with the other companies continues.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; As follow up to the publication of the Global Index 2018, published in May 2018, in the first quarter of 2019 ATNF staff met with Nestl&#xE9; in their office in Vevey, and had teleconferences with others including MARS, PepsiCo, Conagra, Kraft Heinz and Keurig Dr Pepper (partly combined with follow up of the 2018 US Index). A full day of meetings with subject matter specialists of Nestl&#xE9; in-creased understanding of ATNI&#x2019;s methodology among Nestl&#xE9; staff who indicated, inspired by AT-NI&#x2019;s Product Profile, considering the use of Health Star Rating as an independent nutrient profiling system besides their internal system. The ATNI team also spoke to two members of Nestl&#xE9;&#x2019;s ex-ecutive board who indicated ATNI has been on the board agenda several times and is influencing their strategy discussions (not just on BMS). MARS staff were very specifically commending ATNI as a useful tool driving internal thinking and contributing to a portfolio with more &#x2018;nutrition posi-tive&#x2019; products. Kraft Heinz and Keurig Dr Pepper who did not engage during the Global- and/or US Index 2018 research were eager to hear about specific reasons for their scores and inclined to en-gage in the next iterations. Pepsico indicated being impressed by ATNF outreach at international fora and conferences. &#x2022; A review of the methodology of the Global Index has led to a plan to reduce complexity, perceived duplication &amp; other changes and improvements. While ATNF reviews and revises the methodology after each Index iteration, the current revision is more extensive as it aims to integrate two major aspects of our current methodology: The Corporate Profile and the Product Profile, to come to one overall Index score and ranking. The first draft of a revised methodology and set of indicators was presented to and discussed in a ATNF board meeting 27-28 March. The revision of the methodolo-gy is done in parallel to updating the India Index methodology and will run well into 2019, offering experts, companies and other stakeholders to provide input in the process. Additional objective 1: Developing indexes that assess the performance of other key segments of the F&amp;B industry, e.g. retailers, food service companies, fast food chains. ATNF was awarded a subgrant (50,000 GBP) by Share Action (a UK NGO that works to press investors to be more active in their engagement with companies in addressing critical environmental and societal is-sues). Share Action received a three-year grant from the Guys &amp; St Thomas&#x2019;s Charity to develop and launch a campaign to tackle childhood obesity in the UK. The campaign is to be called Too Sweet. ATNI&#x2019;s sub-grant will fund the publication of our UK Product Profile for manufacturers, and the develop-ment of a small-scale UK retail-sector benchmark focused on sugar. The UK Product Profile for manufacturers will be published April/May 2019; a methodology the benchmark for UK retailers will be developed during the course of the year. The pilot retailer benchmark will be pub-lished in early 2020. In addition, ATNI and Share Action will work up plans for further benchmarks and related activities across the food value chain in the UK, i.e. beyond ATNI&#x2019;s current focus on manufactur-ers. It will be an important pilot to lay the groundwork towards ATNI doing the same at the global level or in other Spotlight countries.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; June-August: The ATNF analyst team conducted the pre-population of the on-line data-gathering platform with publicly available data about companies&#x2019; nutrition commitments and performance. ATNF also visited Japan to engage with the Japanese companies in the 2018 Global Access to Nutrition Index: Tingyi, Meiji Holdings and Ajinomoto. &#x2022; August: ATNF organized webinars for the selected companies in the Global and US Index to share final methodologies and training in using the platform. 16 Out of the 22 companies participated and Q&amp;A were developed/distributed. &#x2022; September: The data-gathering platform was opened for the Global and US Index companies. 16 Out of the 22 companies actively engaged in the research for the Global Index and submitted non-public data on the data-gathering platform, partly under NDA (12). The platform was closed on 01/10/2017.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">371700</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">123526</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATNF</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-09-30">161538</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">215267</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-31">90006</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-30">110774</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">276846</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">126670</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">109247</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">238529</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">145582</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.accesstonutrition.org/sites/in16.atnindex.org/files/resources/activity_report_2017_jan-july-final.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity report January - July 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
