<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/H/NGO/20847</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving services in Idleb governorate - Northwest Syria: Support Ar Rahma (Darkoush) Hospital</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented through Space of Pease as an implementing partner and UOSSM France (DHO as registered in Turkey) as a sub-implementing partner to ensure service provision continuity at Al Rahma (Darkoush) Hospital: HeRAMS code: &#x201C;G0704003!Arrahma Surgical Hospital&#x201D;. The hospital is located in Darkosh community/subdistrict, Jisr-Ash-Shughur District, Idleb governorate. The hospital is one of the leading referral hospitals (besides Bab Al Hawa Hospital) in Idleb governorate. While UOSSM France will be responsible for the direct management of the project implementation in the field, SoP will be responsible for the supervision of the implementation plan and reporting and communication with the donors. However, UOSSM France (DHO) will play the role of communication with all the stakeholders, including donors, regarding the technical aspects of the project and the facility.

The hospital has been supported by an international NGO for the past two years. However, during a health cluster meeting, the NGO has recently announced that the hospital&apos;s support will be suspended by the end of November 2021 due to the lack of funds. Closing this hospital, as one of the biggest hospitals in NWS in terms of capacity, will significantly impact the collapsed health system in the region.

UOSSM France has communicated with the hospital&apos;s management to coordinate a future plan, including capacity and needs assessment and fund obtaining. UOSSM France has signed an authorization letter with the hospital to get better access to donors, partners, and stakeholders. UOSSM France planned to seek funds for the hospital through the 2nd SCHF 2021 allocation in partnership with Space of Peace as a registered organization and active member in the health cluster. The project will last for seven months, starting from the 1st of February 2022 until the 31st of August 2022.

Through this project SoP and UOSSM France (DHO) will support Al Rahma Hospital to continue the provision of surgical procedures and interventions of the following specialties: 
&#xF0FC;	Surgical procedures
&#xF0FC;	ENT, 
&#xF0FC;	General Surgery, including caesarian, 
&#xF0FC;	Neurosurgery, 
&#xF0FC;	Thoracic surgery, 
&#xF0FC;	Orthopedic surgery, 
&#xF0FC;	Urosurgery and the internal medicine department: 
&#xF0FC;	internal Thoracic, 
&#xF0FC;	cardiology, 
&#xF0FC;	gastrologic.

In addition, the hospital includes a medical laboratory, radiology department, a blood bank unit, and an Intensive Care Unit ICU for children and adults. Furthermore, beneficiaries have access to medicines. While SoP and UOSSM France are proposing to support the secondary healthcare services in this hospital, UOSSM France managed to obtain funds from (Gift of Givers) of 420,000 for 12 months to support the primary healthcare services and part of the operational and running costs.

It is worth mentioning that the BEmONC package of services in the hospital is supported by Shafak Organization. Therefore, the project will not include relevant budget and indicators to avoid any duplication in reporting to the donors and health cluster 4Ws.

Responding to the COVID-19 outbreak in NWS, an international partner established a COVID-19 Community Treatment Center CCTC for the suspected cases that visit the hospital to avoid any potential infection in the facility. Suspected cases will be referred immediately to the nearby CCTC and the required care will be delivered inside the CCTC when applicable.

All services will be provided through a well-skilled team consisting of 106 medical staff members, out of which 10 surgeons and 13 resident doctors, and 44 non-medical staff.

Through this project, SoP and UOSSM France / DHO will improve their capacity in the health sector by receiving and administering capacity building and training sessions to the staff of both organizations and their teams inside Syria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-24">772725.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20847">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-24">772725.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
