<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/FS/NGO/18434</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scale-up efforts to sustain minimum food consumption needs of the most vulnerable IDPs through daily bread distribution for 18964 IDPs in camps in high and medium priority in Harim and Salqin areas for 7 months.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Without adequate resources and due to the general economic deterioration in northwest Syria, people in need have continued to resort. 
The proposed project aims to Scale-up efforts to sustain the most vulnerable IDPs&apos; minimum food consumption needs through Supply flour or bread directly to bakeries and provide free bread distribution in areas with limited access to subsidized bread in sub-districts in NW Syria. 

The proposed project will serve a total population of 18964. IDPs ( 4659 Men, 5191 women, 4760 Boys, and 4354 girls) in Harim (4.3 high priority area) and Salqin ( 3.9 Medium priority area) according to the 2021 1st allocation paper in 21 IDPs camps and settlements. 
The proposed project is a continuation of last year&apos;s SKT project in the same locations. SKT has access to IDPs&apos; information and needs. Thus, the proposed project will be a continuation of the cluster plan to support the food security of the most vulnerable groups in NWs. 
The target locations have not received any food assistance from the distributed free bread during the last 2 years. The proposed free bread distribution project is the only project that partially covers the daily 2100 calories needs of the target IDPs. Suspending these services will create a huge gap and will harm the food security of these IDPs. 

According to the needs assessment results and the coordination that SKT has implemented with the other key organizations in the same target area, and as addressing to 3PM recommendation, SKT will start increasing the weight of the bread bundles to 0.9 KG. The coordination has been made with NWS FSL cluster coordination, Goal organization, and Hand in Hand to improve the technical aspects of bread distribution activities. Further coordination was done with Insan, IHH, and Mercy without limits to ensure no duplication or overlapping in targeting IDPs.

 
SKT will conduct a procurement process for flour from inside Syria - as cluster and HF recommendation-  SKT team to be transferred to the bakery. SKT will provide the operational cost for the bakery for the flour to be baked. It will provide the nylon bags, each ton of flour will provide 1277 bread bundles with  900gr for each with criteria (900gr for each family with members of 5 and less and 1.8kg for each family with members of 6 and more daily). SKT will monitor transferring the bread from the bakery to the distribution points (5 distribution points) through special cars prepared for bread transferring to save the quality of the bread (the distance between the bakery and the distribution points will not be more than 7 km maximum and the distance between each distribution point and the targeted beneficiaries will not be more than 1 km maximum), the volunteer will monitor and supervise the distribution process, a monitoring process will be conducted for the number of bread bundles baked, the weight of bread bundles, the quality of the bread bundles through three levels (the first one in the bakery by the bakery officer, the project officer, and the project assistant and through the volunteers in each distribution point daily, an external monitor from each camp will attend the distribution process, and s/he will monitor the quality and quantity of the bread distributed. Each level of the monitoring process, including the external monitor, will be reported daily, contained signed papers, and reported to the Turkey-based project manager to match all it together. 
A card with a serial number that matches with the SKT database received by hand with the same beneficiary will be distributed for each family monthly.

COVID-19 prevention measures recommended by the FSL cluster will be taken into consideration while implementing the project activities. 

SKT has developed an integrated MEAL and Risk Management plans. PSEA reporting and BNF feedback system are active and functional.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">278359.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">22493.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18434">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">300853.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
