<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/WASH/NGO/18406</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-Saving Assistance to Increase and Sustain Access to Critical WASH Supplies and Services in Underserved Areas with High Severity of Needs.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action will provide life-saving assistance to increase and sustain access to critical WASH supplies and services in underserved areas of Maaret Tamsrin and Atareb sub-district. These areas are considered high priority for this allocation and classified as high severity of need by the WASH cluster. In line with allocation and WASH cluster priorities, the action will immediately increase access to critical WASH services while also ensuring the long-term sustainability of service provision through establishing renewable energy modalities in targeted station and informed tariff systems to support operation and maintenance cost recovery in all targeted areas. COVID-19 prevention measures have been incorporated across the program design. 

The project will benefit a total of 34,844 conflict-affected people, of which 12,857 Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) and 22,027 host community members in Hazano and Zardana town, Maaret Tamsrin sub-district, and Sahara town, Atareb sub-district. Geographic targeting and program design has been informed by WASH Severity Scale rankings, the geographic priorities of this allocation and through close coordination with the WASH cluster and bilaterally with other members. 

The action will immediately address critical gaps in access to safe water through completion of essential electrical and maintenance works during early June to ensure stations are operational. The project will then provide essential operational and maintenance costs for a four-month period from June to September to Zardana and Sahara stations. Operations and Maintenance (OampM) support to Hazano will be provided by Shafaq during this period. During this four-month period, hybrid solar power systems will be installed in Hazano and Zardana stations. Detailed, recent solar assessments have been completed to inform the design of this action (see Documents). These have found solar to be a viable renewable energy source for both systems. This component of the action will also be informed by Big Hearts recent experience providing technical support for the installation of hybrid, solar power systems for the Jeineh water network in Atareb sub-district under SCHF WASH project 16296. From June through to August, Big Heart will complete detailed service-user mapping across targeted areas to inform the design of tariff systems for cost recovery. Mapping will be completed at household level and with all public and private users to assess WASH service needs, ability to pay and particularly vulnerable service users, including female- and child-headed households, People with Disabilities (PWDs) and IDPs living in inadequate shelter conditions. Building on successful experience with the design and roll-out of Cost Recovery Mechanisms, Big Heart will work with Local Councils (LCs), Water Stations, community leaders and members to design tariff systems during September 2021. These will be rolled out across all targeted areas from October 2021. While not included in the scope of this action, planned solar installation in the two Maaret Tamsrin stations will allow for further works to connect the six surrounding camps to these networks with operational costs reduced due to the installation of renewable energy modalities for the central stations. Support for operational materials for the Sahara station will be gradually reduced as the tariff system is rolled out, as detailed under activity 1.1.6. To maximize the impact of CRMs and willingness to pay, essential rehabilitation and improvement works will be completed to all water networks during the first four months of the action to ensure all residents are connected to the network. Network rehabilitation and improvements will be informed by the service user mapping to ensure the most vulnerable residents &#x2013; including IDPs living in protracted displacement and PWDs &#x2013; are connected to the network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">492072.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">158646.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18406">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">650718.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
