<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/ER-L/UN/18369</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rehabilitation of flood affected roads and associated flood drainage systems around prioritized IDP campsites in Maaret Tamsrin and provision of emergency infrastructure restoration service around all IDP campsites in Idleb during rainy winter season.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recurrent flooding in North West Syria (NWS) in winter severely impacts physical access to IDP sites by rendering roads completely or partially impassable. Heavy winter rains trigger flooding, primarily affecting self-settled IDP sites which do not have the appropriate infrastructure to withstand this elemental onslaught. Flood damaged roads and drainage networks negatively impact the physical access for IDPs as well as the safety and dignity of residents. This further limits access to markets, livelihood opportunities, health, and other critical services. According to the SNFI cluster, 60% of flood affected HHs were in Maaret Tamsrin (MT).
The project will provide critical improvements to road and associated flood drainage infrastructure through the following key activities: 
1.Rehabilitating critical flood-affected roads and drainage systems which connect IDP sites to host communities in MT.
2.Creating short-term work opportunities to involve local community members to directly contribute to and benefit from preventative rehabilitation works in MT. 
3.Training the local communities on asset management to improve the sustainability of infrastructure and increase social cohesion in MT.
4.Establishing a ready-to-be-deployed Rapid Response Team to provide emergency infrastructure restoration service around IDP sites throughout Idleb Governorate during winter. 
The interlinked ERL and Logistics activities have been developed in coordination with the ERL, SNFI, CCCM and Logistics Clusters as well as with NGOs and UN agencies, including UNHCR, to ensure the project is integrated with ongoing and planned works to alleviate the effects of flooding and prepare for winter in IDP sites. First, the project will rehabilitate 30.5kms of roads and 8 drainage systems in immediate proximity to 26 IDP sites in in MT where flooding has previously reduced physical access to sites and surrounding communities. Second, the project will engage 314 people in CFW to rehabilitate roads and drainage systems.  Third, the project will train 140 key stakeholders on asset management to ensure that the infrastructure will be maintained beyond the project. Fourth, the project will establish a Rapid Response Team to provide 250 emergency infrastructure restorations to flood-affected roads near IDP sites during winter throughout Idleb Governorate. These activities aim to provide preventative and emergency infrastructure restoration for flood affected IDP communities, simultaneously creating short term livelihood opportunities. 
Overall the project will directly benefit 510603 people (84063 HHs).  Specifically, ERL activities will directly benefit 232228 people in MT (37711HHs). Emergency infrastructure restorative service for logistics will directly benefit 278375 people throughout the Idleb Governorate (46352HHs).
UNDP brings in the value addition of its expertise in infrastructure projects around the world and in NWS specifically. UNDP&#x2019;s early recovery team, who are highly experienced in infrastructure projects, will provide technical guidance and expertise to ensure the quality and appropriateness of infrastructure works and livelihoods activities as well as better outcomes for beneficiaries. UNDP will work in partnership with BINAA, a Syrian national NGO which has experience with proven track record in the rehabilitation and reparation of roads and drainage systems, as well as in the creation of livelihood opportunities. Overall, UNDP will be responsible for the management of the project and its oversight against programmatic and fiduciary risks through efficient contractual arrangements and administrative support from teams in Gaziantep, Damascus and its regional bureau. This will strengthen overall risk management and ensure timely implementation of the project along with the high quality of activities and the deliverables. The added value of BINAA is anchored around their extensive experience in ERL and rehabilitation activities in Idleb go</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-ERY-179032-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="78" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="22" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Logistics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-15">2075299.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-15">1100537.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18369">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-15">3175837.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305079717">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-25">3175837.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
