<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/ER-WASH/NGO/20611</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(Envelope 1 and 2), Rehabilitation of basic infrastructures in prioritized IDP sites and nearby host communities in NW Syria through an integrated multi-sectoral response including ERL and WASH interventions in Idleb Governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the needs in targeted areas, BRD, in partnership with (IMAAR)&quot; proposes a 8-month project that uses a flexible integrated programming approach that includes a multi-sectoral response (ERL,WASH) with a focus on appropriate preventive measures to alleviate the effects of flooding and prepare for winter in prioritized IDPs sites and nearby HCs affected by poor weather conditions in Idleb Governorate, NWS.

The project design and development has been based on needs identified by ER, WASH, and Logistic clusters, supported with rapid needs assessments conducted by IMAAR and BRD in Nov 2021 and firsthand consultations with camps management and local authorities/stakeholders and aims to rehabilitate and maintenance of basic infrastructures, including long-term road heavy rehabilitation, related drainage systems, and sewage systems, to ensure safe and dignified living conditions for 84,650 most vulnerable IDP people (33,016 W, 22,002 M, 17,777 G, and 11,855 B), currently living in 79 IDP sites/camps and 5 nearby HCs in the sub-districts of Salqin and Darkosh (Idleb), which affected by poor weather conditions to alleviate the effects of flooding and improve the livelihoods infrastructure through integrated multi-sectoral response.

The project aims to achieve the following outcomes:
ERL Component: Rehabilitation and maintenance of 5.5 km access long-term road heavy rehabilitation during the road building season from April to October, this roads connect the targeted IDP sites/camps with Abu Talha and Kafr Hind communities (Salqin sub-district), Saidiyeh &#x2013; Bsentiya, Talamar and Azmarin communities (Salqin sub-district), Al Ramadya community (Darkosh sub-district) as well.
The Proposed targeted roads have been completely damaged and affected by floods in most of their parts in recent years. This intervention will lead to timely, safer, and uninterrupted access for humanitarian aid and humanitarian workers to more than 79 IDP sites/camps in 2 sub-districts (Salqin, and Darkosh) in addition to prevention of access issues and disruption of linkages with HCs affecting local economic recovery as well as improve movement and mobility for livelihoods opportunities.
According to ERL GAP Analysis in NWS (Jan &#x2013; Aug 21), Salqin sub-district came in grade four in terms of PIN early recovery and livelihood and graded 3.6 in the severity scale of ERL cluster.

WASH Component: Provision of WASH supplies and services in 10 prioritized IDP sites/camps in the sub-districts of Salqin (9), Darkosh (1), through construction of sewerage sub and main networks to ensure adequate latrines, showers, and handwashing facilities are in place following a ratio of 20-25 person per latrine in addition to sewage management services as needed.

Both components (ERL and WASH) will be guided by the Basic Guiding Requirements guidance to Reduce Flood Incidents in IDP Sites and Communities in NWS shared by ERL and other clusters and ensuring that HLP documentations are well carried out in parallel through field coordination with the relevant LCs.

Additionally, IDPs sites and nearby HCs around project locations will get access to short-term livelihoods and work opportunities in the form of unskilled labor (CFW). This component will be guided by the CFW Recommended Minimum Actions in NWS guidance shared by the ERL cluster/CWG.
Fifteen employment opportunities will be created in this intervention for a temporary period of three months through hiring 15 CFW unskilled labors with daily wages.
This project will be implemented jointly by BRD and the sub-IP, IMAAR. BRD will carry out WASH component while IMAAR will carry out the ERL component.

In the context of this highly strategic intervention which has to be delivered within a period of eight months, both organizations, BRD and IMAAR bring in the value addition of their local expertise in infrastructure projects throughout NW Syria, which is there since the conception of this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-ERY-178594-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-WSH-178643-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-26">626369.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20611">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-26">626369.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
