<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/RA3/WASH/NGO/18983</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH Response to IDPs in Idleb Camps</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project supports IDPs in the camps of Dana and Maret Tamsrin sub-districts by extension and construction of water infrastructure (water network, sewage network)  and connecting them to nearby borehole and water station, in addition to providing other WASH services in these camps based on their needs  in ordet to provide  comprehensive emergency life-saving package. In camps where it is not possible to be connected to water sources, there will be water trucking with FRC 0.2 - 0.5 so these people get lifesaving humaintarian assistance. sanitation facilities and mitigation measures against Covid-19. It aims to ensure that IDPs in the targeted camps can maintain or improve their hygiene behaviours, particularly for those who have settled in the camps as their last resort and are more vulnerable to the risks of Covid-19 pandemic. In total, 24,190 individuals (5,806 men, 6,047women, 6,533 boys, 5,804 girls) will benefit from the activities of this project. 


The project consists of five main activities:
1 - Providing chlorinated water and water storage tanks (average of 35 l/p/d, FRC 0.2 - 0.5)
2 - Expanding water network, and water drainage and sewage networks in camps.
3 - Providing and installing sanitation facilities (latrines and septic tanks) in addition to regular desludging.
4 - Solid waste management and hygiene sessions in all targeted camps
5 - Hygiene promotion activities.

The interventions are designed based on the needs that were reported through WASH cluster gap list in addition to confirming the needs by assessments conducted by HIHFAD. Throughout the project, COVID-19 mitigation procedures will be observed. Gender, age and disability inclusion will be taken into consideration. The latrine blocks are gender segregated and will be equipped with ramps and handrail to make them accessible to all people including people with disability. In addition, adults diapers will be distributed to the elderly or persons with disabilities who have a difficulty to access common latrines. male and female cleaners for the latrines and maintenance workers will be selected among the IDPs in the target camps in order to ensure involvement of IDPs during implementation as they were also involved during the design of the project through the needs assessment. In Damaet Nazeh and Sanabil Alkheir , desludging will be for 3 months, during this period the sewage network will be ready and all sewage lines are connected to it ( rain drainage will be constructed in these two camps. While in Al Faraj camp, sewage network will be expanded to cover all HHs, and the already existing water network will be expanded so no water trucking will be needed in this camp. Om Jaran and Alsalihyah camps will be targeted with lifesaving activities. before the beginning of winter all septic tanks will be desludged and regularly monitored to prevent any overflow(more details in detailed needs attached excel sheet).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">526305.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">276383.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18983">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">802689.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
