<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/H/NGO/18374</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Access to Trauma, Secondary, and primary Healthcare Assistance for Conflict-affected Syrians in Northern west Syria.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Expatriates Medical Association (SEMA) aims to increase access of affected population in North West Syria to primary, secondary, and trauma services in Idlib governorate, the project&#x2019;s objectives will be attained through supporting Waseem Hsaino hospital in Idleb, which provides integrated life-saving health, nutrition, and protection services to all age and sex groups boys, girls, women, and men, with attention to people with special needs physical disability, elderly, people with chronic diseases and psychosocial problems without any discrimination, among IDPs and host communities in NW Syria in general and in Kafar takharim area in particular.
SEMA-targeted HF will receive support in the form of payment of salaries for HF staff (medical and non-medical), monthly operational costs, professional training and monitoring, provision of pharmaceuticals, and other medical and non-medical commodities (including equipment, medicines, and consumables). SEMA support will ensure the provision and continuation of integrated health, nutrition, and protection package services.
In recognition of the risks and urgent needs associated outbreak of COVID-19 in NW Syria, SEMA will provide coordinated assistance to conflict-affected communities, alongside focusing on infection prevention and control through different measures taken for health staff and patients in the health facilities. Triage spaces are already established in front of the identified health facilities. Trained staff will screen persons for COVID-19 and detect and refer suspected COVID-19 cases according to the WHO and Taskforce guidelines. Moreover, awareness raising messages will be distributed to the patients and care givers to ensure risk communication and community engagement. 
SEMA will collect health data from the HFs monthly and share it accordingly. All SEMA - targeted HFs are part of the EWARN network and report weekly bulletin to EWARN regularly. 
SEMA will provide the capacity building, and ongoing medical supervision to ensure the target HFs are staffed with qualified medical personnel and enhance compliance with standard treatment protocols. SEMA will continue to provide training to the HFs on various health topics, either by conducting training or securing training opportunities through inter-agency opportunities. Including management of communicable and non-communicable diseases, pharmaceutical supply management, patient data management, and gender-sensitivity and protection.
The hospital is one of the largest hospitals in northern Idleb, and provides its services through ER, OPD, IPD and operations departments. The hospital has a capacity of 23 beds in the various departments, in addition to the pharmacy and laboratory. 
The hospital is fully accessible for people with disabilities and older people, as the building of the hospital is prepared with all the measures to facilitate the reception of these beneficiaries (Ramps, chair wheels..), the stairs have a hand-rail, in addition that the water closets are also equipped with flip up grab bar to address PwDs needs.
As the hospital was supported through SEMA private fund after the end of the previous support, from SCHF on 22nd of November 2020, and the hospital was supported with the minimum, so the beneficiaries&#x2019; number were estimated as when the project was supported by SCHF as an average of three months were taken into consideration, where the total number of beneficiaries was about 4847 (1879 men, 1478 women, 920 boys and 570 girls) 2948 hosts and 1899 IDPs.
During the first quarter of 2021, Waseem Hsaino hospital provided the following consultations as follows:
- Waseem Hasino: # of consultation (11458), # of IDPs (3895), # of females (5039) and # of children under 5 (2020).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-HEA-179234-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">464557.13</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">13465.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18374">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">478022.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305067667">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-18">286813.53</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
