<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/RA3/P/INGO/18981</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delivery of life-saving protection services to the most at-risk and marginalized women, girls and boys residing in IDP camps and host communities in Azaz Sub-district, with particular focus on widows and persons with disabilities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project, RI and its partner SEMA aim to provide prevention and response to GBV and CP services as well as empowerment activities for women and children living in 10 camps Alharamean, Alshohda, Talgeben, Ewaa shamareen, Altawheed, Alarmota, Alandane, Alresala, Ahl-alsham, Alresala/random in Azaz subdistrict, Aleppo governorate, with particular attention to widows living there as they are numerous and exposed to multiple protection risks. In Alshohda camp, moreover, there is a dedicated and separated section for only widows&#x2019; and their children (widow camp), situation which creates marginalization, additional protection concerns and vulnerabilities for this particular group.
Ensuring participation of individuals from the general population will ensure acceptance of services, avoid stigmatization of widows and the development of social networks with women and girls living in the general population sections. These locations were selected based on a recent needs&#x2019; assessment conducted by SEMA, which identified great vulnerabilities and gaps in service provision in the target locations. The population living in these camps are particularly at risk of various forms of GBV including emotional abuse, physical assault, sexual harassment, early forced marriage, and child labour is widespread. 
While SEMA will be responsible for the direct implementation of the proposed activities, RI will provide supervision and capacity building covering the sectors of intervention though its existing technical capacity. After an inception phase where safety audits will be implemented to select the most appropriate, safe and accessible locations in the selected camps, SEMA will establish two women and girls safe spaces (WGSS) in Alshohda and Altawheed  camps and one child friendly space (CFS) in Alshoda camp. SEMA will also continue supporting one existing CFS in Azaz community (Amal Centers), which is located close to the camps. During the inception phase RI will train SEMA project staff to ensure quality delivery of services. Moreover, extensive outreach activities will be conducted throughout the project to ensure the population in the camps are aware of services and activities being implemented. 
The GBV services that will be provided are case management, community based and focus psychosocial support (PSS) services as well as awareness raising and empowerment activities. Moreover, in order to strengthen the community approach RI and SEMA will support the establishment of 10 women&#x2019;s committees to foster participation of women in decision making structures as well as build on community protective mechanisms already in place. Under CP, the project will provide CP case management, community- PSS, parenting skills training, awareness raising and recreational activities, identification and referral of cases, as well as child protection monitoring. SEMA will facilitate the establishment of a community committee in the camps and ensure appropriate training. This community Committee will be responsible for raising awareness on CP concerns in the camps as well as identification and referral of children at risks to response services provided at the CFS. Moreover, SEMA will provide 80 children with disabilities with special needs rehabilitation (SNR) in the Azzaz CFS and conduct dedicated, tailored parenting sessions for their caregivers.
All activities will be implemented while adhering to strict COVID 19 prevention measures such as reduced numbers of participants in group activities, social distancing and the provision of PPE for both staff and beneficiaries.
Throughout the project cycle RI will provide organizational support to SEMA as well as technical capacity building, covering GBV, CP and PSS, to ensure quality delivery of services and compliance with international standards and best practices. 
The overall target of the proposal is 12,280 individuals: 2,500 males (500 men and 2000 boys) and 9,600 females (4,640 girls and 4,960 women).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">321792.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">332579.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18981">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">654372.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
