<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/H/NGO/18328</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving healthcare services by supporting Two key health facilities in Idlib district.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will reflect the SDH&apos;s strategy to ensure the adequate coverage of the essential healthcare package to the targeted people in need of humanitarian assistance in Northern West Syria within the SDH&apos;s plan coverage area in 2021, which the number of total people in need has increased from 2.8 to 3.4 million people in this year, where the humanitarian needs in northwest Syria continue to be driven by the impacts of over a decade of hostilities exacerbated by economic deterioration and multiple displacements. 
on the other hand, the COVID-19 pandemic impact has further complicated the lives of people in humanitarian settings in northwest Syria. while considering the health system in NWS is still fragile with an urgent need for continuous support.
regarding these settings, and in order to Maintain the essential healthcare services, where the currently supported health facilities, are providing the essential required medical consultations, examinations amp diagnosis, along with prophylactic amp therapeutic medications. 
So, according to SDH plan insight of its HRP 2021, SDH is proposing to continue supporting the health sector in Idlib district, by this project which aims to support the current health system by keeping the flow of medical supervision to the most vulnerable people through supporting three health facilities (2 PHCs) to be able to continue providing the essential healthcare services to the targeted populations as follows:

1- Muhambel PHC (G0705035) In Idleb, Ariha, Mhambal (Average score: 3.2 /Priority ranking: Med): providing approximately 5500 consultations monthly, covering more than 50,000 Ind (host), with more than 12,000 Indv(IDPs + returnees). providing essential OPD services as well as dentistry, lab tests, and medications. with 355,055.21 USD for 1-year full support (54% of total budget).

2- Bab El-Hawa PHC (G0703148) In Idleb, Harim, Dana (Average score: 5.0 /Priority ranking: High): providing approximately 2000 consultations monthly, covering more than 31,000 Ind (IDPs). from Bab El-Hawa camps, providing the essential OPD services as well as medications through its pharmacy. with 302,454.44 USD for 1-year full support (46% of total budget D.C).
  
SDH will also support the staff&#x2019;s capacity-building through training especially for the health staff such as continuous on-job coaching as well as the NCD last approved protocols, and encouraging the empowering of women&apos;s role in this project.
SDH&apos;s aims to Sustaining and expanding essential, quality health services at community and primary care levels by the efforts of CHWs components in this intervention. Likewise, availability and accessibility of essential, emergency, and specialized health services to meet the needs of the most vulnerable groups.
this intervention from the SDH organization is well designed based on recent Needs assessments done by the SDH field team, to fill the gaps of supporting the current healthcare services in the targeted areas, with close coordination with local authorities and Idlib health directorate as well as the health cluster and technical respective WGs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">368494.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">289015.23</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18328">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-08">657509.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
