<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/RA4/H/UN/20201</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Immediate support provision to existing designated COVID-19 health facilities through procurement of medical supplies and health service provision, while introducing RCCE activities aiming to enhance COVID-19 response in northwest Syria.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to maintain and restore access to COVID-19 secondary and tertiary care services filling the gap of services for highly suspected/confirmed COVID-19 patients with severe and/or critical symptoms and with underlying chronic conditions (lung, heart, renal failure, or an immunocompromising condition). 
Based on the conducted need&#x2019;s assessment and coordination within the health cluster, the project will mainly focus on: 
1. Maintaining and restoring COVID-19 SHC services.
2. Supporting operations of 6 CCTCs (selection of CCTC was done by the COVID-19 Task Force Case Management sub-technical working group).
3. Enhance COVID-19 awareness within communities and promotion of vaccination through RCCE activities. 
Through its IP AHF, WHO will support the existing Al-Sham COVID-19 designated hospital (HeRAMS Code G0703007), which is considered as the only COVID-19 designated hospital located in El Karameh community (Dana sub-district, Harem district, Idlib governorate), with a catchment population of 1,400,000 inhabitants in which 78% are IDPs. Support to Al-Sham hospital will be focusing on operations with a capacity of 30 beds including 30 ICU beds equipped with 21 ventilators, 30 monitors, 10 CPAPs and all the beds were connect with a central oxygen supplies line through two central oxygen generators (18 m3 per hour), and backup of 10 oxygen concentrators. 
The hospital will maintain and restore 24/7 COVID-19 specialized care services through designated health professionals (7 doctors, 3 resident doctors, 24 ICU technicians, 9 Nurses, 15 IPC workers, 3 lab technicians, 3 x-ray technicians working 8-hours shifts per day (3 doctors per shift). Based on the need&#x2019;s assessment and available space, the hospital capacity will be an upgrade over procurement of an additional 1 oxygen generator 54 m3/hour, 2 ventilators, 20 CPAP, X-Ray, portable echocardiography, and 15 ICU beds, and 4,500 refilling oxygen Cylinders, electric generator, and medicines and renewal medical supplies. 
In addition to that through IP SAMS, WHO will support the upgrading of Al Zira&#x2019;a hospital (Code G0700139) located in the Idlib governorate with a 605,000 catchment population, and Al Amal COVID-19 hospital (Code B0200097), which is located in Daret Azza community in Aleppo governorate. The current capacity of each hospital is 30 ICU beds 40 intermediate and 70 medical ward beds and equipped with19 (Al Zira) and 13 (Al Amal) 0xygen concentrators, and 2 oxygen generators each
It is planned to include the procurement of one Oxygen generator 54 m3/hour with refilling oxygen Cylinders, 22 BiPAP 22 syringe pump, 22 ICU beds 22 monitors, 22 suction devices and 4 air conditions and other related supported equipment&#x2019;s, while for Al Amal hospital required procurement of one Oxygen generators 54 m3/hour with refilling oxygen Cylinders, 30 BiPAP, 30 syringe pump, 30 beds 30 monitors, 30 suction devices and 4 air conditions. 
CCTCs of Hazzano, Armanaz, Maaret Tamsrin (2 CCTCs), Sarmada, Dana are identified as the top priority and will be supported by AHF, SDH, WATAN, and OUSSM. 
Through the IP AFAQ, WHO will ensure implementation of the RCCE plan aiming to increase the promotion of COVID vaccination by engagement of community leaders and influencers to reduce the hesitancy rate in vaccinations. The awareness campaign will be conducted according to the SIG vaccination strategy targeting different groups in the community in a timely manner using IEC materials, Digital engagement, videos, and other products that will be developed and disseminated during this project. Support (7/24) hotline will be secure to disseminate updated information about the vaccine process and where and how people can receive vaccines to protect themselves and their families from being infected with COVID-19. 
WHO will explore the possibility to organize direct procurement via Global Market and WHO Global Emergency Stock in Dubai as well as through local suppliers in Turkey.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-HEA-178795-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-24" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">779760.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">965971.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20201">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-20">1745731.55</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
