<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/H/UN/18421</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing urgent health needs for the most vulnerable IDPs and host communities in NWS by sustaining access to primary care services through the integrated implementation of EHSP and life-saving secondary and specialized health care services.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will strengthen access to lifesaving and life-sustaining essential health services within COVID-19 response through providing access to integrated primary and secondary health care services to the vulnerable population of northwestern Syria prioritizing the most critical health services. 
This project is designed as a continuation of previously implemented activities for the most vulnerable IDPs and host communities by sustaining access to existing PHC services and COVID-19 secondary (SHC) and critical care services for highly suspected/confirm COVID-19 patients, especially to those with underlying chronic conditions: lung, heart, renal failure, or an immunocompromising condition.
Objective 1: WHO will cover the provision of essential components of the standardized package of Essential Health Service Package (EHSP) through integrated service delivery modality covering preventive and curative health services, psycho-social and mental trauma effects of the crisis providing health care services by continuing of supporting Qah Kidney dialysis center.
Proposed integrated service delivery modality will reduce the fragmentation caused by the vertical programs and will include integration of community health workers (CHWs) into the PHCs level service delivery aiming to ensure continuity of care by maintaining the functionality of the referral network in North Aleppo and providing COVID-19 related activities within the referral service provision within COVID response (supported by IP/Sham Humanitarian Foundation (AHF)) under the pillar #4 based on the health cluster and COVID-19 task force recommendations.
The implementation of EHSP will be supported through implementing partners UDER and AFAQ that already manages operations of selected HFs. Thus, under the technical guidance of WHO IP/UDER will support 4 PHCs located in Sarmada (G0703011), Termini (G0703028), Zarzur (G0704018), and Daret Azza (B0200006), while IP/AFAQ will support 2 PHCs located in Alsahhara (B0200052), Halazon (B0200216), and mobile team in Maaret Tamsrin area (G0700153). 
Regarding integration of most critical health services, WHO will support hemodialysis by covering logistic of supply chain management for securing 4800 dialysis sessions, 3 Hemodialysis machines, and other vital running costs through its IP/AFAQ. As well integration of mental health and psycho-social support will be implemented via introducing educational and informational activities to reach host communities and IDPs by supporting provision of EHSP through early diagnosis of communicable and non-communicable diseases, including breast screening, information for dialysis patients TB treatment COVID-19 vaccination roll out and other IEC on demand.
Objective 2 will cover the critical gap in the provision of SHC services and supporting the operation of Dana hospital (HeRAMS Code G0703007) which is the only COVID-19 designated hospital located in Tal Elkarame community of Harem district at Idlib governorate. Moreover, during the low caseload of COVID-19, the hospital will provide services to patients with a pulmonary disease requiring intensive care. According to the project design, SHC services will be supported through WHO implementing partner - IP/Sham Humanitarian Foundation (AHF).
The hospital will maintain 24/7 COVID-19 specialized care through the operational capacity of 30 beds including 30 ICU beds equipped with 21 ventilators, 30 monitors, 10 CPAPs having a connection to the central oxygen supplies line through 2 central oxygen generators (18 m3 per hour), and backup of 10 oxygen concentrators. Moreover, the 30-hospital ward bed including 20 medical ward beds and beds with monitors, backup oxygen supplier as intermediate care unit to provide care for patient required lower than ICU care but higher the wards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-HEA-178905-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">1003482.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">992515.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18421">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">1995997.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305116035">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-02">1995997.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
