<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/NFI-WASH/NGO/20832</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelope 1: Improvement of Living Conditions of IDPs in Northwest Syria through Provision of Dignified Shelter Associated with Infrastructure and WASH Services.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action aims at addressing the immediate Shelter and WASH needs and improve the living conditions of affected displaced population in A&#x2019;rima sub-district, Al-Bab district (Aleppo governorate), through an integrated Shelter and WASH intervention that ensures a better living conditions for the IDPs, a dignified and weather-resistant shelters and access to a comprehensive package of WASH services to reach 3,141 people (544 men, 706 women, 947 girls and 944 boys). The intervention consists of two components: 

1- Shelter:

The shelter component aims to provide 270 IDP households (1350 individuals) with access to better dignified shelters with associated infrastructure and WASH services. The targeted HHs are living in substandard shelters and spontaneous/torn tents  in self-settled sites including mainly Arab Wiran informal camp, and in other surrounding informal gatherings (in A&apos;rima sub-district, Al-Bab district). Shafak seeks, through this project, to install 270 transitional and dignified shelter units (29 of them are adapted for PWDs) that will meet the needs of the displaced households, and mitigate the risk of floods that the IDPs face during winter. The selection of the location has been based on the deteriorated situation of the spontaneous tents in Arab Wiran camp and the neighboring gatherings, the severity scale of the targeted area, availability of public property land, and the local council consent.
Since the surrounding gatherings of Arab Wiran community include almost 966 IDP households, while the project target is 270 HHs, Shafak will select the targeted beneficiaries from the existing gatherings in a collective manner, based set of criteria( ensuring equity) and proximity to the selected site. Shafak will install the units in an organized method to avoid displacing existing IDP households during work. 

Shelter activities will be mainly: 
Upgrading the selected site through levelling and graveling the ground, installation of fence  and lighting poles to ensure mitigating GBV and protection risks. 
Installing the transitional shelter units (270units) meeting the SPHERE standards with an area of 30 m2 per unit (total area: approx. 5 hectares). The units will be made from the available materials like metal frames, bricks (not exceeding 40 cm from the ground), and sandwich panels. cement will only be added to the basement of the unit. Hygiene and cooking facilities (kitchen, toilet, and bathrooms) will be constructed, using bricks, and attached to the shelter unit (as per the attached photos and modified drawings). 
Movement of the IDP households to the installed shelter units and completion of handover process and documentation to the representatives of the camp and local council. 

2- WASH:

Comprehensive Emergency WASH services will be provided to the targeted IDPs who benefited from the installed dignified shelters in Arab Wiran camp along with its host community. The following WASH services will be provided:

Supporting water supply systems for the installed 270 dignified units through constructing a water network to ensure providing 40 L of potable water per capita per day. 
Providing water trucking for four months for the installed dignified units during the drought season (35 L per capita per day).
Monitoring the quality of trucked and\or pumped water.
Rehabilitating one borehole and supporting the running cost (fuel, engine oil, chlorine and incentives for workers)  for four months to supply water for the installed units.  
Constructing a sewage network for the installed shelter units. 
Constructing a central septic tank connected to the sewage network.
Providing septic tank desludging services for four months. 
Distributing garbage bins (one garbage bin/10 HHs) for the installed shelters.
Supporting the Arab Wiran municipality with the running costs for six months to cover the Solid Waste Management (SWM) for both IDP installed shelter units and the Arab Wiran community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-SHL-178554-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-WSH-178562-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-11">1068099.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20832">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-11">1068099.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
