<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/ER-P/NGO/20730</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Envelop 2: Support the resilience and access to early recovery opportunities to vulnerable women including Women with Disabilities in Idleb</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project was designed to complement and benefit from another project with the code proposed by Emissa TUR-21/3559/SA2/ER/NGO/20846 to provide Apprenticeship Socio-Economic Recovery opportunities to the affected individuals and families in Idleb. 
WSA will focus on including PWDs and with the aim of creating a supportive environment for vulnerable groups including women and PWDs in Idleb (Kafr Takahrim, Dana) through the provision of ERL.
From the implementation of the first phase of Emissa&#x2019;s apprenticeship Socio-Economic recovery program, it was clear the gap in the participation of women and people with PWDs as participants of this type of project was. At the same time as protection and GBV specialized service providers, WSA has always received case where beneficiaries (women and PWDs) had the need of economic empowerment and where not always able to find a relevant actor to refer to provide this service in a protection-sensitive approach. 
Project activities will : 
Provision of vocational training based on market needs assessment conducted by Emissa, FGDs, and community participation. The topics covered in those training will avoid the traditional types of vocational training provided by different protection/GBV and ER actors and will include for examples training on soft skills like accounting, project management, photography, and online marketing. PWDs vocational direction intervention to link the PWDs with the appropriate training and this activity will be conducted in WSA&#x2019;s WGSS. This activity will target 200 women with a minimum of 10% of women with disabilities. 
 Provision of small grants and inclusive livelihood opportunities for women including women with disabilities in WGSS with high priority for GBV survivors and women at risk to achieve economic independence in a total of 80 from the BNFs who participated in vocational training in previous projects including referrals from other GBV case management service providers in the project locations to receive a grant of (800 &#x2013; 1200 USD) per. The other 120 beneficiaries will still have the opportunity to be referred to Emissa to receive their support in accessing the market based on the knowledge and skills they gained from the vocational training and based on the selection criteria of Emissa&#x2019;s project that gives the priority for women referred from this project.
 Safe referrals for female GBV survivors who might disclose issues of GBV and women and adolescent girls at risk to WSA WGSS in Kafr Takharim and Dana through case workers be supported with prevention and response services ongoing in these locations, in addition, to receive referrals from Emissa and other organizations. 
 Provision of response services to GBV survivors referred by protection mobile teams to WSA&#x2019;s WGSS Kafr Takharim, and Dana including case management, focused PSS , and Referral.
 Providing Explosive Ordnance Risk Education (EORE) sessions to IDPs, returnees, Kafr Takharim, and Dana through mobile teams reaching BNFs of ER intervention and their families to support the protective environment in BNFs work location 
The delivered sessions will be based on the MASC guidelines along with providing the targeted locations with leaflets and banners related to EORE topics reaching a total of 770 BNFs including PWDs referred. 

 Provision of vocational counseling for PWD to include them into the vocational training in line with their needs, capabilities, and their type of disability
To minimize the social barriers that face PWDs to access the market WSA will conduct awareness-raising sessions on working with PWDs and their rights for their families and other stakeholders like work own</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-27">247067</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-27">11359.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20730">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-27">258426.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305417802">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-09">103370.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
