<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/P/NGO/18416</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continuation the enhancement of the protective environment and access to comprehensive protection support (GBV, CP, and Legal consultation) and empowerment of vulnerable affected population including women and girls in widows&#x2019; camps in NWS.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Starting from the priorities identified by the protection cluster and sub-clusters, and as per the findings of the need&#x2019;s assessments conducted in the last period, SEMA, and its partners HRO and SANAD, under SCHF, seek to provide life-saving protection prevention and response services. SEMA and SANAD through the existing two CFSs in Afrin and Al-Bab communities (Amal Centers) under SCHF until 14 July 2021, will continue the provision of CP prevention and response services. Activities include CP case management, structured PSS, parenting skills, awareness, identification and referral through static and mobile teams, SANAD team will provide Special need rehabilitation program (SNR) for CwDs, and parenting skill for their caregivers. 4 CP outreach teams will provide awareness raising sessions, recreational activities and identification and referral for at risk CP cases, 3 Case specialists in each CFS will continue providing a comprehensive CP case management. 1CM supervisor in each CFS will continue to supervise the quality of case management and PSS Structured services. Already existed 2 community committees in Albab and Sharran, will continue their roles in raising awareness of affected communities on CP concerns, contagion risks of COVID-19 and precautionary measures. Total number of beneficiaries 16481 (M :1131 ,W:1431 , B:6960, G:6959)
HRO, under SCHF, will continue running the already existing two community centers in (Afrin, Aleppo, and Darkoush, Idleb), to support vulnerable host communities and IDPs prioritizing targeting two Widows&#x2019;s Camps in Darkoush (Aytam Al-Sham, Ommahat Almoamineen) with high quality life-saving GBV, CP, and legal consultation on CSD and HLP including case fund with more emphasis on cases identified by case management to be under child labour and/or exposed to be separated of their mothers in widows camps, in addition to micro-grant to ensure income-generating and economic independence for most vulnerable women including widows in widows camp. 2 GBV case manager, and 2 CP case manager in Syria and technical team in Turkey will ensure quality CM and PSS services. 8 outreach workers will conduct structured PSS, and the establishment of women committees in widows&#x2019; camps to support women&apos;s affairs and engagement in decision-making and addressing women and children concerns, women committees and camps manager will be trained on GBV and CP basic prevention and response, communication skills, and suicide prevention. At-risk women will be supported with micro-grant to promote their self-independence and mitigation of any potential GBV risks. Community awareness is raised on essential topics of GBV, CP, Legal information especially on CSD and HLP, in addition to COVID-19 and PSEA. Total number of beneficiaries 9197 (M:1994, W:3471, B:1436, and G:2296).
SEMA and HRO will continue reporting to CPMT, PMTF, GBV SC (safety audit in widows camps). SEMA, under other grants, continues complementing Health, Nutrition, Physiotherapy, and MHPSS strengthening internal and external referral pathways. Same for HRO who provides MHPSS under private fund along with the protection services. HRO MHPSS team will provide suicide prevention, selfcare and PFA-COVID-19 training for project field team (SEMA, SANAD, and HRO). Activities will be adapted according to COVID-19 consequent restriction of movements, and in line with (Guidance Note on GBV and CP Service Provision during the time of COVID-19) and (Ethical Closure Matrix), COVID-19 precautionary measures in line with WHO standards will be applied in face-to-face activities.
Women and girls benefited from GBV services, and caregivers of children benefited from CP services who are in need for legal awareness and consultation will be referred internally to GP/ qualified and experienced lawyers.
Findings of PM reports on protection needs and gaps, will strengthen the advocacy efforts on GBV, CP, and legal awareness, and during PM interviews cases will be referred accordingly</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-PRO-179183-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-PRO-179202-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">363263.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">299741.87</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18416">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">663005.19</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305112415">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-28">397803.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305478546">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-22">265202.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
