<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/RA3/FS/INGO/18978</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security Assistance to flood and winter affected people. 3RA 2021/22</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Flooding and winter conditions are disrupting lives across northwest Syria, particularly at IDP sites. Due to the lack of shelter space, a considerable number of these displaced people have been living in tents or in unfinished buildings, where they are vulnerable to the hard weather conditions. Heavy rainfall each year causes severe flash flooding in North West Syria. This area has a high proportion of displaced people and concentration of camps and sites, making it a region with a notably large vulnerable population. Tents have been destroyed in the affected camps. As a result of the flooding, thousands of people are typically impacted.
During the first quarter of 2021, heavy rainfall across the Idleb area and northern Aleppo governorate reportedly caused damage to at least 310 IDP sites, with many roads leading to camps reportedly cut off or damaged. According to the CCCM Cluster, over 22,000 tents were either destroyed or damaged. The harsh weather conditions have exacerbated the already dire needs of the IDP population, including food, shelter, and non-food items (NFIs). Thousands of people temporarily relocated, many requiring shelter, food, and NFI support immediately and in the long term. The majority of the damaged shelters are in informal sites where IDPs spontaneously settled. These sites are more prone to floods and water drainage remains challenging.
GOAL carried out a response to this flooding in Q1 2021, where MPCA was the default modality for flood response GOAL was able to reach 13,868 Unique HHs/65,023 Unique individuals through MPCA and In-Kind assistance (Food, Hygiene, RTE, NFI Kits and Tents). In winter 2020/21 in responding to seasonal and natural hazards needs, GOAL was successful, funded in part by OCHA, in reaching 45,674 Unique HHs/226,677 Unique individuals with MPCA in a value of USD 5,204,460.
Looking forward to winter 2021/22, GOAL will respond to sites affected by flooding and harsh winter conditions through both MPCA and In-Kind response modalities, according to needs assessment findings and available resources. The response will target IDPs living in flood-prone camps/informal settlements

Under the proposed action GOAL is planning to target 969 unique HHs/ 4,845 unique individuals approx. affected by flood and harsh winter conditions in Armanaz sub-district with RTE kits (funded by BHA), followed with 4 rounds of OCHA-funded MPCA of 100 USD per round/HH (100 USD is the harmonized CWG value). GOAL will explore the opportunities to transition these affected people to the BHA-funded RESTORE project for longer term food (8 rounds) and NFI (6 rounds) assistance.
In cases where a beneficiary is unable to attend the distribution points, door-to-door distributions &#x201C;home delivery&#x201D; will be organized for specific vulnerability cases such as new widows, persons with disabilities or the elderly with movements restrictions. These will be captured in the home delivery tracker.
As multi-purpose cash assistance is the main response modality under this action, GOAL will keep a closely monitor the functionality of the markets in Armanaz sub-district by monitoring items availability and prices as well as stock/supply and currency information.  GOAL has a Market monitoring team in place who collects markets functionality and monitoring  data on a monthly basis,  which also contributes to REACH/CWG&#x2019;s monthly joint market monitoring exercise and the monthly SMEB value. 
GOAL&#x2019;s accountability and protection mechanisms will be applied, and planned activities will be closely coordinated with the cluster.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">322071.13</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">180359.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18978">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">502430.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305116041">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-02">301458.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
