<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/H/UN/20632</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening primary and secondary healthcare along with COVID-19 response in northwest Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Project is the continuum of preexisting activities, aiming to maintain lifesaving health response by enhancing access to integrated primary and secondary healthcare services to alleviate human suffering of affected communities inside northwest Syria, emphasizing areas with high severity of needs and COVID-19 burden through:
Outcome 1: Improved access to life-sustaining integrated PHC through maintaining the functionality of mobile and fixed PHCs activities in the most affected areas of Idlib and Western Aleppo countryside.
The WHE will implement the Essential Health Service Package (EHSP) covering curative health services through integrated health service delivery to reduce the system fragmentation caused by the nature of the crisis. At the same time, partners will ensure COVID-19 preparedness and response through maintaining crucial service delivery (in coordination with the HC), implementing triage for screening, and referring suspected cases for treatment (Pillar 4, 6 amp 11). The implementation of EHSP will be supported through IP/ AFAQ, UOSSM France, and SEMA that already manage the operations at selected HFs providing reproductive services, including ANC, PNC, family planning, and referrals pediatrics and IMCI consultations, NCD and CD services CHWs identifying illness cases and refer to PHCs, mobile clinic, and SHC hospitals.
Under the technical guidance of the WHO, IP/AFAQ will support 2 PHCs located in Alsahhara (B0200052), Halazon (B0200216), and 1 mobile team covering IDP camps in the Dana area (G0700153) IP/UOSSM France will support 1 PHC located in Barisha (G0703043) and 2 mobile teams in Ehsem, and Jisr-Ash-Shugur (G0705069 amp G0704048) IP/SEMA will support 2 PHCs located in Al Dana and Armanaz (G0703076 amp G0703001). 
Aiming to ensure integration of tuberculosis services on community-level WHO will support operations of TB center in Idlib city - the only center, which receives referrals of TB suspected cases from other PHCs in Idlib governorate and is playing a complementary role with PHCs to provide holistic integrated primary health services. It will be designed under the supervision of the WHO in accordance with the international TB protocols aiming to ensure the provision of diagnostic (clinical, imaging by X-Ray and laboratory) and patient follow-up services and medical supplies. 

Outcome 2: Vulnerable populations, including women and children, have enhanced access to critical life-saving secondary care in the Idlib governorate.
Through IP/AFAQ, WHO will continue supporting the functionality of &#x201C;Save the Soul Hospital for Maternity, Newborn and Child Health&#x201D; (Salqin MNCH hospital - G0703109), that provides outpatient and inpatients maternity care, including antenatal care (ANC), delivery, and post-natal care services comprehensive Emergency Obstetric and Newborn care (CEmONC), gynecological interventions: hysterectomy, ovarian cystectomy, vaginal abscess drainage, etc. 

Outcome 3: Provision of integrated PHC and SHC services within COVID-19 response to vulnerable population inside NWS, through procurement of essential medicine/medical supplies and implementation of PSEA capacity-building activities, while ensuring effective PSEA mechanisms at the health facility level.

In addition, to mention above, the project will support continuous capacity building of previous success on PSEA training in 2020, where IP/HIHFAD reached 300 focal points working in HFs. The project will continue capacity building for PSEA Focal Points so they can develop their NGOs&#x2019; plans, prevent and mitigate the risks of sexual exploitation and abuse. IP/HIHFAD under the support of WHO will coordinate with the Health Cluster to ensure that the 300 PSEA Field Focal Points from health facilities will attend the refresher training.
To ensure the provision of essential medical supplies WHO will procure (Annex 5) and preposition emergency stock inside NWS aiming to support health service even after the end of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-HEA-178770-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-HEA-178795-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-25" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">2500109.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">58826.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20632">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">2558936.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305497048">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-01">2558936.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
