<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/ER/UN/18368</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing socio-economic resilience of communities affected by protracted civil war, the COVID-19 pandemic, floods, and economic deterioration through diverse livelihood opportunities for the most vulnerable groups in Dana sub-district</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project delivers a strategic and integrated set of interventions to restore local economy in Dana, Idleb in the aftermath of protracted conflict further aggravated by the impact of the COVID19 pandemic, and deteriorated economic situation. Its main objective is to create income generating opportunities for the most vulnerable IDPs, and host community members in the targeted locations. The project proposes an integrated protection and livelihood intervention where the most vulnerable households (HHs) (those being referred from child protection case management actors and GBV case management actors, as well as PwDs) will be directly targeted to enhance their resilience and promote their access to employment and entrepreneurship opportunities. The project formulation has been based in needs as identified in multi-cluster RNA/REACH/HNAP data. Besides, firsthand consultations, conducted specifically for this project with local stakeholders, have also informed the design of this proposal. By pursuing the referred main objective, the project aims to achieve the following outcomes:
1. Essential socioeconomic services are revived and restored through the creation of short-term work opportunities 
2. Access to inclusive livelihoods and entrepreneurship support is enhanced through vocational training (VT)
3. Local small businesses and entrepreneurs are supported
4. Social cohesion among IDPs and host communities is enhanced
For this purpose, a set of interlinked activities will be conducted in coordination with FSL, WASH, Shelter and Protection clusters. Firstly, 10 essential socioeconomic infrastructures will be rehabilitated in Dana, through the creation of 240 short-term work opportunities for the most vulnerable HHs, in coordination with the FSL partners to ensure that the intervention is synergistic with food assistance. Secondly, the project foresees the identification of 450 HHs with a specific focus on severe economic vulnerability to provide them with VT linked to either CfW opportunities or small business support. These opportunities will be directly aiming to address Protection concerns, targeting PwDs, GBV survivors and HHs where cases of child labor have been identified.Thirdly, the project will identify and provide business support to 120 small businesses affected by floods, economic recession and COVID19 in the targeted location, to boost economic recovery. Moreover, the project is specifically designed to foster social cohesion among IDPs and host communities through the establishment of a Socio-Economic Empowerment Community Committee (SEECC) for advising the design and implementation of the project activities, fostering local ownership and ensuring sustainability of the achievements of the project upon its completion. 
This project will directly benefit 373,320 individuals living in 9 communities and 18 camps in Dana (M:132980, F:94450, B:64410, G:81480, PWD: 5690). 
UNDP is the global lead agency in Early Recovery and Livelihoods Restoration with extensive experience in ERL projects, including inside NWS.UNDP will work in partnership with SARD, a national NGO which has experience in both ERL and Protection projects. UNDP will be responsible for overall management of the project and oversight against programmatic and fiduciary risks through efficient contractual arrangements and administrative support. This will ensure timely implementation of the project, and high quality of activities and program deliverables. Moreover, UNDP&#x2019;s ERL team will provide technical guidance and expertise to ensure the quality and appropriateness of livelihood activities, the sustainability of the business support which will improve the effectiveness of the project and better outcomes for BNs. The added value of SARD is anchored around their experience in both ERL and Protection activities in Idleb, which will be a key to ensure the smooth transitioning between protection activities to livelihood activities for the most vulnerable</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-ERY-179032-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">805562.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">796758.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18368">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-30">1602321.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305101960">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-14">1602321.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
