<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/H/NGO/20699</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Envelope 1&quot;: Maintain Provision of COVID-19 Case Management Services, and Improve the Access to Critical Life-Saving, Life-Sustaining Primary and Secondary Health Care to Highly Vulnerable People in NWS.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to respond to the most urgent needs identified by the cluster and health directorate, where the targeted intervention is built on the dire need of high severity areas in NWS and will provide life-saving and life-sustaining humanitarian assistance to people in need.
The project will apply a facility-based approach in providing quality triage, isolation, and case management services and will contribute to containing the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic and decreasing morbidity and mortality by filling critical gaps in response to the COVID-19 outbreak.
thus, Idleb Isolation Hospital (Known as Carlton), a central hospital for COVID-19 in NWS, located in Idleb City, is considered as one of the biggest referral facilities for COVID-19 in NWS according to Idleb Health Directorate, WHO, and COVID19 Taskforce, with the capacity of (60 ward beds, 13 ICU beds, 10 Ventilators, oxygen generator with 53 m3/hour, Laboratory Dep, X-Ray Dep)
Idleb isolation hospital (Carlton) received from Jan to the end of Oct 2021: 4658 COVID-19 patients: 1050 Ward, 189 ICU,
Al-Carlton hospital is reporting to the COVID19 TF and Idleb health directorate on a daily basis. As NWS is entering the second peak of the epidemic, the hospital currently is considered as a very crucial facility to be supported, as, since 15/08/2021, the percentage of occupations of ICU beds is not lower than 90%, and reached 100% more than two months.
Under this project, SEMA is planning to continue providing the COVID-19 case management activities for the people, especially the most vulnerable people such as children, women, elderly, IDPs, and people suffering from chronic diseases, in both the ICU and the ward departments, in addition, to provide the needed medication, laboratory and X-Ray services.
The project also will raise the capacity of staff in dealing with moderate and severe cases, in addition to activating telemedicine through 11 ICU specialists from SEMA advisors around the world, who will follow up the cases periodically.
Through this project, SEMA will also continue supporting the already existing and functioning Al-Farabi CEmONC facility (HeRAMS code B0202024) located in Al-Bab subdistrict.
Al-Farabi hospital is considered the main hospital in Al-bab city, and it is the main referral hospital in Albab.
The main services to be introduced in Al-Farabi hospital will be as follows:
1.	Operate emergency and comprehensive obstetric and neonatal care unit and services.
2.	Provide reproductive health care to women and adolescences in the form of antenatal, prenatal, natal, postnatal care, family planning services, and STIs management.
3.	Provide normal, assisted deliveries and C-section deliveries.
4.	Provide gynecologic, pediatric, inpatient, and outpatient services for women and children.
5.	Provide safe abortion and post-abortion care, including emergency treatment of abortion complications.
6.	Provide life-saving services to GBV survivors, services including clinical management of rape, taking into consideration ensuring privacy, confidentiality, and preservation of information.
7.	Support the provision of essential medicines, medical supplies, and equipment to direct bene&#xFB01;ciaries and the provision of reproductive health and safe delivery kits.
8.	Implement capacity building program including (CMR, RH protocols, ANCampPNC, STIs management) to service providers.
The project will provide health services for 29,190 beneficiaries (1740 men, 11700 women, 8442 boys, and 7308 girls) (17688 IDPs and 11502 HCs) including all age groups children, adolescences, young adults, and middle-aged adults, elderly and people with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-HEA-179234-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-07">1098534.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20699">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-07">1098534.29</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
