<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA2/WASH/INGO/20576</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced access to basic WASH services for IDP and host community in underserved and frontline areas in Northwest Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the Syrian conflict verging on its eleventh year, the humanitarian situation in Northwest Syria continues to deteriorate, impacting all life aspects of the Syrian families and further increasing their struggles to meet their basic needs. Through the proposed action, PIN strives to provide Humanitarian assistance to the most vulnerable in front-line and SCHF-underfunded locations, and IDP camps/sites that are in particularly poor condition.
As indicated in the 2022 HNO, WASH systems have suffered from damages owing to hostilities, years of functioning at high capacity, limited or no maintenance, continuous drain of technical staff and poor water resources management, exaggerated by cascade effects of climate change, economic downturn, and power and fuel supply crisis.
Reliability and efficiency of water systems have sharply decreased for the first time since 2016, up to 47% of the population is relying on alternatives to piped water and unsafe water supply modalities to meet or complement their water needs. Investment in sanitation infrastructure also becomes critical, as at least 70% of sewage is discharged, untreated and at least half of the sewerage systems are not functional. Over 30% of garbage is inappropriately disposed or collected with low frequency. 24% of IDPs in sites couldn&#x2019;t access one or multiple hygiene items, 23% faced barriers to effective handwashing. 35% of HHs reported issues with toilets functionality or wastewater disposal. Disruptions and poor quality of services in IDP sites have also direct negative physical and mental well-being and protection consequences, notably on women and girls. Moreover, The Lack of operational costs is the reason for suspension for 20.38% of suspended water stations according to the water station database 2021 Week 39-40 (attached).
Therefore, based on WASH need assessment conducted between October and November 2021, PIN plans through the proposed project to enhance the access to WASH services for 56673individuals (29824IDPs, 26849host communities members, including 1041people with disabilities, which aligns with the strategic objective 1 that emphasizes on providing lifesaving humanitarian assistance in underserved and frontline areas. 

PIN has developed a comprehensive package addressing the core needs emerging from the assessment in line with the prioritized activities articulated in the allocation paper through the following activities:

1. Installation of solar power systems for 4 water stations, connection of one water station to the electricity grid, rehabilitation of 3 water stations and water networks in 4 villages. This will ensure long-term sustainable and environmentally friendly solutions to the provision of water in the 4 villages. 
2. Extension of existing networks from those water stations to three nearby camps. Additionally PIN will connect exsited water tanks to the estended water netwroks in the targeted camps. 
3. In three villages the sanitation network will be rehabilitated and extended to connect 3 Nearby camps which will provide improved access to sanitation services and minimize flood risks during winter months
4. In line with meaningful complementarity distribution of Hygiene CVA and hygiene promotion for public and with tailored targeting toward people with disabilities will be organized in 3 camps. 
5. In all targeted location operational support for the water stations will be provided and sustainable fee collection system will be established.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-07">1027000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-20576">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-07">1027000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
