<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/SA1/WASH/NGO/18387</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote the resilience of the most vulnerable people in Jarablus and IDP camps affected by the Syrian crisis through live-saving activities in the WASH sector.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In general, 60% of the population in affected communities relying on alternatives to piped water and often unsafe water supply modalities to meet their water needs, the WASH infrastructure and service provision in many parts of Syria require significant repair and operational support. With the anticipation of continued community transmission of COVID-19, mainstreaming COVID-19 response throughout all regular WASH activities is crucial to mitigate risks. The project aims to assist 96,909 individuals ( Host and IDP) living in Jarablus city and IDP camps ( Al Jabal, Al Malab, Abo Shehab, Jubanat, Al Malaab, Al Masref, Khalawy, Bakres, Al koureieh, Maskaneh) the existing water system depends on two water boreholes receive the water from the Euphrates river connected to the main water network through vertical pumps pumping the water to the city and rural sides. The power source is electricity from the national grid supported by a private Turkish company, the yielding water from these two boreholes is very low and un efficient, the local council has to run the water pumps 20 hours per day to cover 50% of the needs in the city only (20 liter at max), the other 50% of the houses and the IDPs in the surrounding camps depend on the water trucking which consider unsafe and expensive based on the families&apos; income. The operating cost covered from the local council&apos;s income, zero water reaches to the IDPs camps because of the low boreholes efficiency, this is due to the expired life of the filtering boreholes (these boreholes established since 20 years ago), the high cost paid by the local council to provide water to the city only push the local council to neglect the other services such as rehabilitation of the sanitation lines, and solid waste management in the city and camps. IYD, by establishing a drinking water treatment plant on the Euphrates River and connect it to the existing water stations in Jarablus, and support the operation cost for Jarablus water stations and Al Jabel camp water station aims to improve humanitarian response in the WASH sector based on priority humanitarian needs by focusing on the most urgent needs which lead to cover the gaps and deliver WASH supplies and services to improve the hygienic and daily practices for the most vulnerable people In Jarablus city and surrounding IDPs camps, the project links to the SCHF first objective and to the 2nd objective of WASH cluster this plant will withdraw the water from the river and pass it through two filtration units ( two lines of filtration units each line consists of one sedimentation block and four sand filters with 35 m3 flow per filter the total flow of the line is 4 X 35 m3 ), the filtration units will be connected to the chlorination unit, the outlet of the chlorination unit will connect to the main groundwater tank 250 m3, IYD will connect this main water tank to the main water network through three horizontal water pumps, the total flow 3 x 180 m3/h. By operating the water treatment plant, the clean water will reach the city and IDP camps and the operation cost will be decreased by about 50% based on the required operating hours. The functioning of the water stations and the flow of the water through the water network will provide good conditions to operate the sanitation system in the city which will make the need to rehab all damaged lines is critical and required, IYD will rehabilitate the sanitation systems by repairing the damaged lines and clean the blocked lines and reconstructs the inspection pits in Jarablus city and AL Jabel camp. The project focus will ensure appropriate water, sanitation, and handwashing standards in IDP sites setting, hand hygiene promotion. IYD will establish water units in the supported water stations and provide them with OampM training, and work closely with the local council to establish the tariff system for sustain.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSYR21-WSH-179019-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-16">452742.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-16">343384.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18387">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-16">796126.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305079720">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-25">318450.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305552025">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-06">238838.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
