<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-21/3559/RA3/NFI/INGO/18969</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency assistance to conflict-affected communities&apos; needs and flood-prone informal settlements in Northwest Syria to cover winter needs through Multipurpose Cash Assistance (MPCA) and graveling and infrastructure improvements in IDP camps. 3RA 2021/22</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The conflict in Syria is now entering its second decade, and the number of people relying on humanitarian aid for survival continues to grow. These people are facing high need and significant challenges to accessing essential services, especially areas in N.W Syria, who face damaged infrastructure, high prices, and lack of economic opportunities compounded by years of conflict and subsequent displacement. Conflict and economic push factors are causing incidents of displacement in NWS. According to the REACH Emergency Needs Tracking (ENT) dataset, in March 2021 there were 565 reported displacements in NWS. The ENT also recorded 27 natural hazard events, including storms and floods affecting households (HHs) in March, displacing people and damaging shelters and infrastructure. 
Winter season with the harsh weather conditions creates further burdens on these people, especially in areas with a high proportion of IDPs, a concentration of camps and informal settlements, making NW Syria a region with a notably large vulnerable population.
GOAL has a commitment to respond to the vulnerable people in winter season using MPCA as the primary response modality. In winter 2020/21 in responding to seasonal and natural hazards needs, GOAL was successful in reaching 45,674 Unique HHs/226,677 Unique individuals with MPCA valued at USD 5,204,460.
Under the proposed activities of IDP site improvement and Winter Response, GOAL will target 7,695 unique HHs/38,475 unique individuals located in communities under Maaret Tamsrin, Kafr Takharim and A&#x2019;zaz sub-districts. 

Under output 1 &#x201C;Output 1 Camps have roads gravelling, tents gravel padding, and installation of solar lights to improve access&#x201D;  GOAL will target IDP camps within Maaret Tamsrin sub-district that are flood-prone, located on flood streams, or receive heavy rainfall and do not have the requisite infrastructure to cope. This activity will focus on the gravelling of roads to facilitate access within the camps, installation of gravel tent padding, and solar lights for communal facilities. These activities will be implemented in two camps hosting 1,870 individuals which will be also targeted under the proposed winter response to ensure integration and complementarity. 
An overall 1,800 meter of roads will be constructed and rehabilitated in the camps. The works will be carried out through contractors selected through GOAL competitive bidding process. Annex 2 provides details of the target locations and the scope of proposed infrastructure work under this project.
Under Output 2 &#x201C;MPCA for seasonal and supplementary NFIs&#x201D; GOAL aims to provide additional support to its food security beneficiaries, newly displaced people, and returnees into GOAL AoO in and off camps to ensure that the most vulnerable HHs receive winterization MPCA with a value of 150 USD per HH, informed by the SNFI winterization guidance, during cold winter months to avoid relying on negative coping strategies in order to meet their winter needs, particularly the cost of heating fuel. 
In this project, GOAL will target the most vulnerable people in extreme need to receive winter assistance, especially those who meet vulnerability criteria, including but limited to: female/widow headed HHs, child-headed HH (head of HH must be less than 18 years of age), HH headed by someone with a disability, elderly-headed HH, HH includes two or more members with a disability, IDP HHs living in camps or informal settlements where their shelter does not provide the sufficient protection to cope with the harsh winter conditions. Part of these informal settlement/camps are also considered under the IDP site improvement component.
In cases where a beneficiary is unable to attend the distribution points, door-to-door distributions, &#x201C;home delivery&#x201D;, will be organized for specific vulnerability cases such as new widows, disabled people or elderly with movements restrictions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">1276744.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">223255.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-18969">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-22">1499999.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305116041">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-08-02">899999.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
