<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12748A0105-ALB-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to AWEN 2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Women rights and organising</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att skydda och fr&#xE4;mja kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter i Albanien och genomf&#xF6;rs av AWEN. Programmet omfattar en 4-&#xE5;rsperiod. Interventionen fokuserar p&#xE5; tre komponenter: 1) F&#xF6;respr&#xE5;kande och lobbyverksamhet p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att skydda och fr&#xE4;mja kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter; 2) Institutionell utveckling och organisationsf&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning av AWEN och dess medlemmar; 3) St&#xF6;d till AWEN-medlemmar f&#xF6;r att erbjuda specialiserade st&#xF6;dtj&#xE4;nster, p&#xE5;verkans&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder, medvetenhets- och kapacitetsbyggande relaterade &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention aims at protecting and promoting women rights in Albania and is implemented by AWEN. The programme covers a 4 year period. The intervention focuses on three components: 1) Advocacy and lobbing at national and international level to protect and promote women rights; 2) Institutional Development and organisations strengthening of AWEN and its members; 3) Support to AWEN members to offer specialised support services, advocacy actions, awareness and capacity building related action to enhance women rights at the local level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the programme is:&#xA0;Increased role and contribution of women civil society organizations for the protection, promotion and respect of women human rights in Albania.
The specific objectives of the programme are the following:
1. Improved and implemented policies and legal framework for protection and promotion of women human rights.2. Strengthening of institutional/ organizational capacities of AWEN and its members in becoming more democratic, accountable, independent, sustainable and capable to promote and protect women human rights.3. Protection and empowerment of vulnerable groups of girls and women, with a special focus on gender based violence and trafficking survivors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEN/Albanian Women Empowerment Network/Rrjeti i Fuqizimit te Gruas ne Shqiperi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEN/Albanian Women Empowerment Network/Rrjeti i Fuqizimit te Gruas ne Shqiperi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">466368.967808882</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-31">423016.317854</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">466368.967808882</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/albania/12748_12748_Agreementandtwoamendments.PDF">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement and amendments 12748</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme during 2019-2021 has contributed to:

- Improvement and implementation of policies and legal framework from duty bearers for protection and promotion of women human rights through advocacy and lobbying initiatives at local, national and international level focused on national policies and legislation that needed to be in place and implemented, central and local public institutions that increasingly fulfilled their obligations as per national and international legislation, and increased accountability and functioning monitoring systems. Some examples:  Inputs on the Protocol of operation of public and non-public residential centers that provide housing service (shelters) for victims of domestic violence and trafficking in the COVID-19 pandemic situation; Acceptance of the request by the CEC for the draft law regarding the public register of sexual abusers, after the collection of more than 22,000 signatures from citizens, an initiative led by AWEN and members.

- AWEN and members becoming more democratic, accountable, independent, sustainable, and capable to promote and protect women human rights, thanks to institutional development and organizational strengthening capacity building efforts, like mentoring and technical assistance to AWEN members in further organizational development, besides ongoing professional capacity building interventions for AWEN and its members.

- Offering of specialized support services and carrying out sensitizing, advocacy, and capacity building initiatives to protect and enhance women human rights at local level, resulting in approximately 4000 girls and women and their children benefiting from the package of services, increasingly more capable local stakeholders in addressing women human right issues and a community that is more supportive and reactive towards women human rights - through the support to AWEN members. Besides, 28 small scale emergent advocacy interventions have been implemented by non-member organizations, inter-sectionally focusing on women economic empowerment, fighting gender stereotypes in media, property rights, information dissemination and awareness raising on GBV and other GE related topics. 

- As part of the post-earthquake resilience building and recovery interventions supported by Sida, three AWEN member organizations have implemented projects, with the aim to ensure protection of earthquake survivors/ right-holders and to make duty-bearers increasingly supportive and reactive towards their rights, prioritizing vulnerable women and their families. As a result, hundreds of damaged citizens have been assisted through different means such as local level advocacy and lobbying, legal aid, and psychological support.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12748" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150104" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="5425000000" strategy-end-date="2027-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with the Western Balkans and Turkey 2021-2027</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2021-2027</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
