<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12749A0101-ALB-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Palme Center Programme in Albania  2019-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palme Center Programme in Albania 2019-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olof Palme International Center/OPC has applied for a new phase of its programme in Albania 2018-2021 with a budget of 15,6 MSEK out of which 61% is forwarded to Albanian partner organisations.  The main objective of the programme is to strengthen the capacity and legitimacy of civil society organisations and support activities that ensure the participatory nature of political and social processes and accountability of duty bearers. The intervention focuses on two thematic areas: 1) Citizens participation and 2) Socio/economic/labour rights. The number of partners in the first area is reduced compared to previous programmes and priority is given to joint actions by partners targeting primarily youth and women. The second area- labour rights-  is expanded compared to the previous programme and the assessment is that that OPC has made strategic choices in terms of what sectors to prioritise (Fashion industry, extracting industry and Call centres) and what would be the approaches for enhancing the cooperation between trade unions and civil society organisations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Olof Pame International Center/OPC har ans&#xF6;kt om nytt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r deras Albanienprogram 2018-2021 med en budget p&#xE5; 15.6 MSEK d&#xE4;r 61% av medlen &#xE4;r t&#xE4;nkt att f&#xF6;rmedlas vidare till albanska partnerorganisationer. St&#xF6;det syftar till att st&#xE4;rka civilsamh&#xE4;llsorganisationers kapacitet och legitimitet samt att st&#xF6;dja partners aktiviteter f&#xF6;r deltagande i olika sociala och politiska processer och att bl a fr&#xE4;mja ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. Insatsen har tv&#xE5; tematiska omr&#xE5;den: 1) Medborgardeltagande och 2) Sociala och ekonomiska r&#xE4;ttigheter samt arbetstagares r&#xE4;ttigheter. Antalet partners inom det f&#xF6;rsta omr&#xE5;det har minskats ned och prioritet ges till partners som s&#xE4;rskilt arbetar med unga och kvinnor. Det andra omr&#xE5;det har utvidgats j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;rt med tidigare st&#xF6;d och Sida bed&#xF6;mer att OPC har gjort strategiska val avseende vilka sektorer som ska f&#xE5; st&#xF6;d (mode- och utvinningsindustrierna samt Call centres) och den valda ansatsen och metodiken f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka samarbetet mellan fackliga organisationer och civilsamh&#xE4;llet.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention is strengthening the role of civil society focusing on two main thematic areas: 1. citizen participation in decision-making and 2. socio-economic and labour rights. 
The expected results of the intervention are: 1) Partner organisations expand the popular base, create networks for joint actions and have capacities to monitor the implementation of political decisions and influence policy agenda. 2) Citizens and citizens groups are empowered, organised, participate and influence in decision making and demand transparency and accountability from duty bearers. 3) Strengthened capacity of employees, trade unions and other CSOs working for increased access to decent work and the rights of workers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olof Palme International Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">972937.5310652609</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">407179.386950715</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">347459.7435312768</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">972937.5310652608</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">407179.386950715</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">347459.7435312768</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1707928.383337</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">126904.8953563384</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">407179.386950715</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 was the first year of this programme period and the Palme Center supported nine civil society organisations/networks to make changes in two thematic areas: 1. citizens participation for good governance 2. ensuring respect for socio-economic/labour rights. Involving citizens in decision-making process has been challenging due to the lack of trust in the democratic electoral process and in public institutions. This required the adoption of new approaches. Through their interventions, partners have made efforts to create a sustained engagement and interactions of citizens with duty bearers, among which POP 2019 - Social Contract initiative was the most prominent one, providing a platform of interaction between citizens and politicians at local level, orienting the decision-making towards citizen&#x2019;s needs. Holding governmental institutions into account remains of utmost important for the development and consolidation of democracy and welfare of citizens, therefore, partners and their citizens groups will continue to be a critical independent voice and exercise pressure to make changes happen. The implementation of national and international labour standards in Albania is still far from satisfactory according to OPC reports. But in the last two years there is a&#xA0; merge and establishment of new labour unions which are gradually filling the need for better organisation and more active role of the unions in general.This provides hope for change. Positive tendencies of collective organising were noted in the oil and gas sector, telecommunication, health and these might be considered the seeds of a rejuvenated labour movement. Collective organising in garment and shoes industry remains a challenge. OPC partners are regularly monitoring and reporting on labour rights violations and increasingly take advocacy actions to improve the working conditions. One interesting example of results in this area from OPC reporting 2019:&#xA0; Union of SPTT-AL represents individuals working in one of the biggest company in telecommunication &#x2018;Albtelecom&#x2019; and its subcontractor company &#x2018;Makhes Albania&#x2019; as well as in the BTC/UNIT call-center company and has the ambition to become a sectoral trade union in the telecommunication sector. The number of members increased to 678, from 595 in 2018, with 71 members from the call center sector. 47% of members are girls/women and the board has 34% women representation. The Palme Center has supported the union in ensuring organisational sustainability and being able to perform its functions by having its own office and having the trade union registered in Tax Office. SPTT-AL is gaining more trust from its members through the negotiation process of the collective agreements. The Palme Center has continued strengthening the capacity of civil society partners network meetings, study visits and capacity building trainings. The recognition and visibility of partners has continued to be progressively increased and partners acknowledged as key actors amongst the civil society evolving environment. A significant positive change relates to the enhanced partnership and networking between Albanian and Swedish organisations. The POP network (consists of 9 active Civil Society organizations) supported by the OPC programme has been very active the first half of 2020 following the situation created by the pandemics in Albania. The main activities of the network remain monitoring and lobbying and advocacy activities for the fulfilment of citizen&apos;s priorities presented in the Social Contracts drafted during the 2019 election campaign for 9 municipalities. With the situation created by COVID-19, the members of the POP network monitored the responses of the central and local government as well as the community problems that the organizations represent by publishing and discussing findings with the respective municipalities. Another partner of OPC, Civic Resistance Center has monitored the quality of online learning in universities following the closing of schools and universities and has been very active in monitoring the elections in universities in July, an election process that was criticized by activists for University Reform.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="12749" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
