<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11986A0101-ALB-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to BIRN Albania</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to BIRN Albania</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albanian society upholds democratic values allowing citizens equal opportunities to make informed choices and hold public institutions accountable.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen inneb&#xE4;r ett st&#xF6;d till BIRN Albania f&#xF6;r implementering av deras halvtidsstrategi f&#xF6;r 2018-2020. BIRN Albaniens huvuduppdrag &#xE4;r att uppr&#xE4;tth&#xE5;lla demokratiska v&#xE4;rderingar, vilket till&#xE5;ter albanska medborgare att erh&#xE5;lla lika m&#xF6;jligheter till medvetna val och lika m&#xF6;jligheter att st&#xE4;lla regeringen till svars.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution is core support to BIRN Albania for implementing the mid-term strategy 2018-2020. The main objective of BIRN&apos;s work in Albania is &quot;Albanian society uphold democratic values allowing citiznes equal opportunities to make informed choices and hold the goverment accountable&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BIRN Albania/Balkan Investigative Reporting Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">126576.452177115</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">232658.9748199537</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">22802.04566924</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">126576.452177115</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">232658.9748199537</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">22802.04566924</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-33320.6293364605</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-12">403893.951946</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">69041.7011875173</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-28">57534.7509895977</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">105754.0794636153</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-28">21150.8158927231</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">105754.0794636153</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">22802.04566924</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-28">-33320.6695114933</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/albania/beslut-om-insats-11986.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats 11986</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During 2018, BIRN Albania has prioritised the monitoring of the justice reform but this has not impeded the implementation of the planned activities in line with the three strategic direction of the organisation. BIRN Albania has produced a considerable number of investigative stories, news pieces and articles. The impact of the investigative stories has been significant. Below are presented selected results from the work during 2019 and also quantitaive data from the annual report.&#xA0; - The investigation published in November 12th, by BIRN Albania editor Besar Likmeta &#x201C;Nj&#xEB; biznes familjar: Farmacit&#xEB; e lidhura me drejtuesit e Fondit p&#xEB;rfituan miliona euro nga ila&#xE7;et&#x201D; (A family Affair; Pharmacies Linked with Fund Employees Rank Millions). The investigation produced after a six months research reveals how a handful of pharmacies owned by the family members of the employees of the Health Insurance Fund, which have been investigated for fraud, ranked tens of millions of euros in drug reimbursements from 2010 to 2018, despite worries over conflicts of interests and illegal gains. In January 2019, the Tirana Prosecutor&#x2019;s Office issued arrest warrants for two of the pharmacists who benefited from the fraudulent practices, underlining the role played by the BIRN investigation in the case.- A BIRN Albania data driven deep dive investigation published on June 26th on how the public utility company OSHEE, has inflated costs and doubled its in order to keep the price of electricity high, while the public watchdog, the Energy Regulatory Agency, ERE, has turned a blind eye -&#xA0; 5 formal trainings were org ionised for journalists. In order to increase the capacities of local journalists in investigative and specialized reporting, BIRN Albania has provided continuous on-the-job training and mentoring for 20 local journalists awarded with reporting grants for covering cases of corruption and lack of transparency in several fields. T - In order to promote the decade-long grassroots struggle of local communities, activists and civil society organisations against hydro power plant projects that threaten the environment, the water supplies of local communities and their livelihoods that are based on sustainable tourism, BIRN Albania has produced a 45 minutes long documentary. &#x201C;Free Flow&quot; chronicles the efforts of local communities, environmental organisations and activists in Albania to halt the destruction of the precious Valbona and Vjosa rivers, protected areas now under threat by the Albanian government attempting to build numerous hydro power plants. This timely documentary presents a resistance movement led by local residents and environmental activists who are standing up against the devastating wave of hydro power plants in Albania over the last decade. &#xA0;-During 2018, BIRN Albania has continuously covered protests of different marginalized groups, with a special focus on the activists protesting against the demolishing of National Theatre to make space for real estate development; the students&#x2019; protests over the university reform; and the protests of communities at risk of eviction due to the construction of the ring road in Tirana. The continues coverage of such protests and grass roots resistance efforts, as well as specific in-depth stories on under-reported groups (such as Intersex community, chronic patients and refugees) has helped amplify their voices and bring them to the mainstream. BIRN Albania&#x2019;s objective and fact-based coverage has also helped inform public debate on these issues, leading to a more informed citizenry. - Also, during 2018, BIRN Albania was actively involved in lobbying against two government sponsored initiatives which posed a serious threat to media freedom in the country. The first attack against the independent media was undertaken by AKEP (Electronic and Postal Communications Authority), which in October 2018 issued a public &#x2018;black&#x2019; list of 44 websites - including BIRN Albania&#x2019;s Reporter.al outlet &#x2013; giving a 72-hour deadline to register with tax officials or be shut down. BIRN reacted immediately to this initiative by several articles and contacts with AKEP, different partners and human rights organizations. Few days later, OSCE and CRD condemned the initiative, which was stopped due to lack of regulatory framework in support of such procedures.  The second initiative considered concerning in regards to media freedom in the country was initiated by the office of Albania&#x2019;s Prime Minister which proposed changes in two laws foreseeing the registration of online media and the policing of news content for a variety of reasons, including &#x201C;biased&#x201D; news, news that &#x201C;damages public morals&#x201D; and &#x201C;publications that can incite penal offences&#x201D;. Failure to uphold the law would result in fines of up to 8,000 euros&#xA0; and even closure of websites.BIRN Albania representatives were part of the three public consultation meetings organized by the authorities, as well as reporting over the threats that such changes pose not only to media freedom, but to freedom of expression in general, as long as the new regulation is attempting to regulate every online website, including blogs and pages of non-governmental and educational institutions.&#xA0; Quantitative data, 2018:&#xA0; 53 investigations published at Reporter.al by BIRN Albania staff215 analysis/features/interviews published at Reporter.al717 news pieces published at Reporter.al by BIRN Albania staff189 photo rich and video stories published at Reporter.al by BIRN Albania staff617 articles translated form BI/Project Syndicate and published at Reporter.al9199 republications of articles produced for Reporter.al by BIRN Albania staff3147 republications of articles produced for BI and translated from BIRN Albania</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11986" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
