<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12749A0101-ALB-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Palme Center Programme in Albania  2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palme Center Programme in Albania 2019-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olof Palme International Center/OPC has applied for a new phase of its programme in Albania 2018-2021 with a budget of 15,6 MSEK out of which 61% is forwarded to Albanian partner organisations.  The main objective of the programme is to strengthen the capacity and legitimacy of civil society organisations and support activities that ensure the participatory nature of political and social processes and accountability of duty bearers. The intervention focuses on two thematic areas: 1) Citizens participation and 2) Socio/economic/labour rights. The number of partners in the first area is reduced compared to previous programmes and priority is given to joint actions by partners targeting primarily youth and women. The second area- labour rights-  is expanded compared to the previous programme and the assessment is that that OPC has made strategic choices in terms of what sectors to prioritise (Fashion industry, extracting industry and Call centres) and what would be the approaches for enhancing the cooperation between trade unions and civil society organisations.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Olof Pame International Center/OPC har ans&#xF6;kt om nytt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r deras Albanienprogram 2018-2021 med en budget p&#xE5; 15.6 MSEK d&#xE4;r 61% av medlen &#xE4;r t&#xE4;nkt att f&#xF6;rmedlas vidare till albanska partnerorganisationer. St&#xF6;det syftar till att st&#xE4;rka civilsamh&#xE4;llsorganisationers kapacitet och legitimitet samt att st&#xF6;dja partners aktiviteter f&#xF6;r deltagande i olika sociala och politiska processer och att bl a fr&#xE4;mja ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. Insatsen har tv&#xE5; tematiska omr&#xE5;den: 1) Medborgardeltagande och 2) Sociala och ekonomiska r&#xE4;ttigheter samt arbetstagares r&#xE4;ttigheter. Antalet partners inom det f&#xF6;rsta omr&#xE5;det har minskats ned och prioritet ges till partners som s&#xE4;rskilt arbetar med unga och kvinnor. Det andra omr&#xE5;det har utvidgats j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;rt med tidigare st&#xF6;d och Sida bed&#xF6;mer att OPC har gjort strategiska val avseende vilka sektorer som ska f&#xE5; st&#xF6;d (mode- och utvinningsindustrierna samt Call centres) och den valda ansatsen och metodiken f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka samarbetet mellan fackliga organisationer och civilsamh&#xE4;llet.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the intervention is strengthening the role of civil society focusing on two main thematic areas: 1. citizen participation in decision-making and 2. socio-economic and labour rights. 
The expected results of the intervention are: 1) Partner organisations expand the popular base, create networks for joint actions and have capacities to monitor the implementation of political decisions and influence policy agenda. 2) Citizens and citizens groups are empowered, organised, participate and influence in decision making and demand transparency and accountability from duty bearers. 3) Strengthened capacity of employees, trade unions and other CSOs working for increased access to decent work and the rights of workers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olof Palme International Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Olof Palme International Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">972937.5310652609</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">407179.386950715</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">373095.1742471056</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">972937.5310652608</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">407179.3869507151</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">373095.1742471057</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-30">1707928.383337</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">126904.8953563384</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">423016.3178544613</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">407179.386950715</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">373095.1742471056</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sccio economic/Labour rights 
The labour movement in Albania is weak and old trade unions are seen as undemocratic structures and unrepresentative of workers&#x2019; interest. During the last four years, the Palme Center is contributing to building a future strong labour movement, through promoting and supporting representative, legitimate and independent trade unions who act as collective voices for the workers&#x2019; rights. During 2020, contribution was provided through the Palme Center programme in organizing workers and strengthening of&#xA0; new unions in different sectors, including call centres, oil extract and refinery industry, health sectors and textile and shoe sector (examples below):&#xA0;
- The new union in the health sector SPSHSH (Sindikata e Punonjesve te Sherbimit Shendetesor) that was established in late 2019, has reached to 600 members as of January 2021. It has as well gained recognition among the public health institutions. During 2020 the union has been active in voicing their demands through official letters to the relevant public institutions. 
- Another specific example in 2020, includes the establishment and strengthening of &#x201D;The National Trade Union of Call Operators&#x201D; &#x2013; SKOT, accounting for around 150 members.&#xA0; The union is acting as voice for workers in call centers and has successfully addressed during 2020 a collective dispute with the company B-Connect regarding the unpaid payment of the official holidays for 2019.&#xA0;
Through the Palme Center Programme, Sida is supporting civil society organisations and trade unions create awareness on the labour rights and mobilise workers strengthen their capacity to claim these rights. Violation of labour rights was more evident during the pandemic, with people losing jobs or unable to make a living due to reduced working hours, risking health due to lack of the protection measures. The year saw an increased number of workers and unions asking for support.&#xA0;
- Assistance, counselling, and legal support has been provided to workers in different sectors. With the support of the Center for Labour Rights, the New Albanian Oil Workers&apos; Union- SRNSH won against the largest employer oil company in the country &quot;Albpetrol&quot; sha. The SRNSH acted with an number of actions in response to the decision of the Albepetrol&#xA0; Company to reduce the salary at 60% during the pandemic in April-May 2020. The negotiation with the management were successful only after the actions escalated in a protest in front of the company and gathering of signatures as a petition for the Prime Minister office. 90% of the workers were able to receive the full salary. For about 10% of employees, involving senior administration, the negotiations have not been successful although still ongoing. 
- Through the LRER organization in Elbasan, was made possible that self-employed informal workers, particularly from Roma community, benefit from the assistance package of the government. The LERE addressed the lack of support for this group of workers to the&#xA0; State Commissioner for Protection against Discrimination who issued a recommendation regarding the inclusion in the Decision of the Council of Ministers of some groups of informal workers as beneficiaries. As a result, the Council of Ministers decided that the category of informal workers receive an amount of 6000 ALL during the period of the civil emergency of Covid-19.
Citizen&#x2019;s participation for good governance
The year 2020 has witnessed an unprecedented crisis with the outbreak of the Covid-19 pandemic that hit the country in March 2020 and affected the health, economic and social development, as well as the quality of democracy. The government imposed severe restrictions on core civic freedoms as a means to contain the COVID-19 pandemic, including the freedom of assembly and movement.&#xA0; The space left to organizations to operate as well as the opportunities to engage with citizens and decision/makers were increasingly narrowed.
The role of the Palme Center and OPC partners during this period has been important particularly in monitoring the measures and decisions taken by the government in response to the situation Corona Virus and draw attention and advocating for citizens&#x2019; concerns (examples below).
- The POP platform, an initiative of 10 local organisations has provided spaces and opportunities for citizens, mainly through digital mode, to question the governance and demand transparency and accountability at nine municipalities in Albania. It was the first initiative to publish 9 monitoring reports on how the measures of the local government were affecting the vulnerable groups of society and discuss the finding with the respective municipalities&#x2019; representatives. The initiative established a channel of communication between citizens and local government during Covid times and led to an improved understanding of the citizen&#x2019;s needs, better transparency and accountability of municipalities and adaptation of several measures responding better to concerns of the citizens.&#xA0; 
- The Palme Center partner, &#x2018;Civic Resistance&#x2019; has been at the centre of public debate through periodic assessment of the higher education system under the effects of Covid-19 and implementation of the Pact for University. It has become an articulator of the problems of students in the field of education at the institutional and public level&#xA0; and has significantly increased responsiveness of the government. The platform provided through Civic Resistance&#xA0;&#xA0; has improved the democratic accountability of the duty bearers and has made the voice of the students be heard. The efforts have led to several tangible changes, including for instance the reduction of the tuition fees for students in the Agricultural University of Tirana by 15 %.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12749" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
