<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5502004301-ALB-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">One UN Albanien</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to One UN Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the cooperation programme 2012-2016 is to promote sustainable and equitable development, social inclusion and adherence to international norms and fulfilment of international obligations, in support of the integration of Albania into the EU. The four outcomes in the updated RAF are:1) Human Rights and gender equality consideration guide interactions between citizens and institutions (Human rights) 2) The rights of individuals and groups are ensured through equitable, inclusive and evidence based sectorial policies (Inclusive and Social Policies) 3) The Albanian State executes major governance processes following internationally agreed democratic principles and practises, while upholding the rule of law and eliminating key factors of exclusion of women (Governance and Rule of Law). 4) Government of Albania implements policies that advance democratic, equitable and sustainable regional and local development (Regional and Local Development) The original pillars of the programme agreed are the following:  1) Governance and Rule of Law 2) Economy and Environment 3) Regional and local development and 4) Inclusive social policy. As noticed from the updated RAF, Human Rights are highlighted as a new pillar and Economy and Environment theme is integrated under the Governance and Rule of Law pillar.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sida, f&#xF6;retr&#xE4;dd av ambassaden i Tirana, undertecknade 2011 ett avtal om st&#xF6;d via One UN Coherence Fund f&#xF6;r FNs och Albaniens samarbetsprogram 2012-2016 (Programme of Cooperation, PoC). St&#xF6;det &#xE4;r en mjuk &#xF6;ronm&#xE4;rkning till programmets genderrelaterade prestationer (gender outputs).  Sida har gjort tv&#xE5; utbetalningar om 10 MSEK enligt avtal. Avtalspartnern som f&#xF6;retr&#xE4;ds av FNs f&#xE4;ltchef (Resident Coordinator) och UNDP i Albanien har beg&#xE4;rt ytterligare medel f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra programmets genderprestationer, utifr&#xE5;n resultat och erfarenheter fr&#xE5;n en halvtids&#xF6;versyn 2014 och det reviderade resultatramverket och budgeten 2015-2016. Det nya resultatramverket har 4 effektm&#xE5;l (outcomes), 6 s&#xE4;rskilda genderrelaterade prestationer (gender outputs) och &#xE4;ven de &#xF6;vriga 9 prestationerna har tydliga genderdimensioner.  

Sida bed&#xF6;mer att fortsatt st&#xF6;d till genderrelaterade prestationer (gender outputs) i samarbetsprogrammet skulle konsolidera och ytterligare p&#xE5;skynda de positiva och strategiska resultat som uppn&#xE5;tts under perioden 2012-2014.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To support Albania&#x2019;s international commitments for the implementation of international human rights standards, gender equality, environmental sustainability, and development of national capacities, the Government of Albania and the United Nations signed in 2011 the Programme of Cooperation 2012-2016. The Programme of Cooperation (PoC) was organised in inter-related outcomes and outputs and represented a foundation for combined work and joint programming of several UN agencies in support of Albania&#x2019;s development priorities. The joint planning and programming work happens primarily at Programme, Outcome and Output level, with the participation of government representatives, UN staff and sometimes donors. While UN agencies are all required to mainstream gender in all aspects of planning and implementation of this Programme of Cooperation, in keeping with the dual nature of gender mainstreaming, the Programme also envisages interventions focused entirely or considerably on gender equality issues. The proposed intervention is a continuation of Sida&apos;s contribution to the One UN Coherence Fund for GoA-UN programme of Cooperation Programme 2012- 2016. Swedish support is a softearmarking to the gender outputs of the programme. Sida has disbursed the two installments planned in the agreement, each MSEK 10. The Embassy believes that additional funding in the amount of 20 MSEK to the gender outputs would consolidate and advance further the positive and strategic results achieved during  2012-2014.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1541022.0057942427</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1477344.9157174726</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1895071.3567253167</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">474535.2520375358</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">923274.7034418278</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1541022.0057942427</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1477344.9157174726</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1895071.3567253167</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">474535.2520375358</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">923274.7034418279</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-01">6919188.806016</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-28">1541022.0057942427</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-12-28">1477344.9157174726</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-11-28">1895071.3567253167</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-28">474535.2520375358</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-28">350610.6468766435</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">572664.0565651844</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Support has been critical in the development of key national policies, action plans and laws on gender equality and women&apos;s rights, alignment with international treaties and development of capacities and tools for gender mainstreaming. Examples of results are the following:
1) The regulatory, systemic change has led to adoption of new or amended policies, laws and regulations for implementation and their alignment with international standards - Develop the National Strategy and Action Plan on GE and against Gender Based and Domestic Violence 2016-2020; National Action Plan for Women Entrepreneurs 2014-2020; National Action Plan on Involvement of Men and Boys as Partners to Women and Girls in Challenging Stereotypes and Combating Gender Based Violence- Amend the Albanian Penal Code with comprehensive provisions on the rights of victims of crimes including victims of GBV. Provisions on rights of victims of crimes and GBV and a specific provision provides for special guarantees to victims of sexual violence/human trafficking included in Albanian Code of Criminal Procedure amendments. Amend the Law on Measures against Violence in Family Relations - Integration of sex-disaggregated, gender-sensitive governance targets in the NSDI 2015-2020.
2) Central and local level capacity development to implement GM and GRB - Gender is mainstreamed in MTBP 2018-2020 in 24 medium-term budget programmes that include gender related objectives, targets, and financial resources of 11-line ministries totaling to 90 million USD or 2.3 % of the budgets of these ministries. For the first-time budget funds for the housing of one-parent families are foreseen in the MTPB as well as budget funds envisaged for strengthening the role of women in the integration process, the country&apos;s cultural life and the development of science;
3) Strengthened institutional capacities, mechanisms and structures to respond to GBV at central/local level
- 60.6% of municipalities (two thirds supported by UN) have established Coordinated Community Response (CCR) mechanism that provide multi-disciplinary services with real-case management at the local level with varying level of functionality and responsiveness;- online tracking system of domestic violence cases established and operational at former Ministry of Social Welfare and Youth / current Ministry of Health and Social Protection (MHSP) since 2014 - 718 GB-DV cases were recorded and handled by CCR in 2017 compared to 545 in 2015; credited to increased awareness, 4,537 cases of GBV reported to the state police in 2017 compared to 94 cases in 2005; - state-run National Shelter for DV victims adopted rehabilitation and reintegration programmes with both state and non-state service providers. As a result, rehabilitation and reintegration programmes for GBV&amp;DV survivors have contributed to their social integration: nearly 58% of sheltered GB&#x2013;DV survivors in national center are integrated through employment, social housing and legal empowerment in 2017 compared to 38% in 2014; 4) Strengthened institutional capacity of public oversight bodies to monitor, report and redress violations of rights, especially of vulnerable groups such as women and children deriving from main human rights conventions- Central Election Commission strengthened its capacity to implement and enforce the gender quota in the national elections (2013, 2017) and local election (2015) as well as to monitor women&#x2019;s participation in election and report gender-disaggregated statistics on participation in elections.- A National Index on women&#x2019;s representation and participation in elections is established, which will serve as a baseline to monitor upcoming elections. - Following GREVIO&#x2019;s recommendations, the Government has increased efforts to address other forms of violence against women, including sexual violence and harassment. - The Parliament has increased its oversight role with regards to gender equality and violence against women.
5) Mechanisms established to support women&#x2019;s political and economic rights at central and local level:&#xA0;- Women MP&#x2019;s Alliance established in Parliament in 2013 advocated for legal amendments on gender equality by increasing the gender quota on candidate lists for local councils to 50 per cent, with the gender of candidates alternating at every second name (zipper/zebra lists). The approval of this recommendation yielded increased results in women representation at local level. - Two new public funding mechanisms established targeting women owned enterprises in urban and rural areas (a dedicated subsidy scheme for women engaged in agro-processing at Ministry of Agriculture and a Competitive Fund for Women Entrepreneurs in Tirana Municipality with a budget in 2016 of 60,000 USD which doubled in 2017). 18 viable businesses were supported by the fund.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55020043" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
