<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5513000501-ALB-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heritage for people</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Heritage for people</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cultural Heritage without Borders Albania has applied to Sida for funding 15,36 MSEK to carry out the project &quot;Heritage for People - An integrated approach to development and education&quot; in Albania.

It will be the continuation to Cultural Heritage without Borders, contributing to cultural heritage and linkage to education, including a better understanding of history, a feeling of pride and belonging..

The main objectives of the contribution are: 1: The cooperation between the State and civil society is strengthened, 2: Cultural heritage is valued and utilized as a social, economic, cultural and environmental resource for local communities, 3: Regional cooperation serves as the platform for building peaceful relations for responsible preservation and interpretation of cultural heritage in the Western Balkans, with effects felt beyond the region.

The proposal outlines 3 main components: 
Component 1 outlines the achievements and activities planned, while focusing on the case studies of two historical cities, Gjirokastra and Berat (both on the UNESCO World Heritage list).
Component 2 outlines the approach to direct engagement with a large array of stakeholders coming from local communities and marginalized groups, building successful models, so as to provide incentive for dynamic and sustainable responses.
Component 3 outlines the regional approach through two separate but interrelated programs: the Regional Restoration Camps (RRC) and the Balkan Museum Network (BMN). 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 20 281 420 SEK, out of which the Organisation&#x2019;s funds are 15,36 million SEK and the remaining 4,42 MSEK is contributed by other donors and 500 000 Sek are allocated to an external evaluation, to be commissioned by the Embassy.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kulturarv utan Gr&#xE4;nser Albanien har ans&#xF6;kt hos Sida om ett finansiellt st&#xF6;d p&#xE5; 15,36 MSEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &quot;Kulturarv &#x2013; ett integrerat angreppss&#xE4;tt f&#xF6;r utveckling och utbildning&quot; i Albanien.
Det &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning till Kulturarv utan Gr&#xE4;nser och bidrar till ett kulturellt arv och kopplar till utbildning, inkluderar en b&#xE4;ttre f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else av historien, en k&#xE4;nsla av stolthet och tillh&#xF6;righet.

De viktigaste m&#xE5;len f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r att: 1: St&#xE4;rka samarbetet mellan staten och det civila samh&#xE4;llet, 2: Kulturarvet v&#xE4;rderas och anv&#xE4;nds som en social, ekonomisk, kulturell och milj&#xF6; resurs f&#xF6;r lokalsamh&#xE4;llet, 3: Bidra till ett regionalt samarbete som plattform f&#xF6;r att bygga fredliga f&#xF6;rbindelser f&#xF6;r ansvarsfullt bevarande och tolkning av kulturarvet p&#xE5; v&#xE4;stra Balkan, med p&#xE5;verkan utanf&#xF6;r regionen.

F&#xF6;rslaget inneh&#xE5;ller 3 huvudkomponenter:

Komponent 1 beskriver resultaten och planerade aktiviteter, med fokus p&#xE5; fallstudier av tv&#xE5; historiska st&#xE4;der, Gjirokastra och Berat (b&#xE5;da p&#xE5; UNESCO: s v&#xE4;rldsarvslista ).

Komponent 2 beskriver tillv&#xE4;gag&#xE5;ngss&#xE4;ttet f&#xF6;r medverkan av ett stort antal intressenter fr&#xE5;n lokalsamh&#xE4;llet och marginaliserade grupper, med syftet att bygga framg&#xE5;ngsrika modeller, f&#xF6;r dynamiska och h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar.

Komponent 3 beskriver den regionala strategin genom tv&#xE5; separata men inb&#xF6;rdes program:
Regional Restoration Camps (RRC) och Balkan Museum Network (BMN).

Insatsens totala budget &#xE4;r 20 281 420 SEK, varav 15,36 MSEK &#xE4;r organisationens medel och resterande 4,42 MSEK &#xE4;r bidrag fr&#xE5;n andra givare och 500 000 SEK f&#xF6;r en extern utv&#xE4;rdering, som kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras av Ambassad.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Right based approach in cultural heritage coupled with sustainable development leads to equitable growth resulting in cultural heritage being valued and utilized both by state and civil society at large.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHWB/Cultural Heritage without Borders</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHWB/Cultural Heritage without Borders</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">463974.7560334249</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">531521.0015210016</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">596569.7781460001</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">145207.6481350268</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">463974.7560334249</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">531477.2434772436</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">596569.7781460002</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">145622.838651001</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-01">1761281.949395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">231987.3780167124</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">231987.3780167124</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-28">270416.5204165204</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">270416.5204165204</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">-9312.0393120393</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-28">221508.7913099512</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">221508.7913099512</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">-14305.4404860536</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">167857.6360121513</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">-9061.1322031747</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-28">154268.7634175488</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/albania/55130005-grant-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/albania/beslut-om-insats-55130005.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats 55130005</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Culture Heritage without Borders has integrated the cooperation between state and civil society at another level. Aside from continuous technical training on raising capacities to the local government a tourism strategic approach has been adopted by CHwB to prologue tourism stay in the Gjirokastra region. The value chain analysis identifies the weakness of the system but also shows a good example on how to make long term strategies for the local government, which is missing in Albania. For Gjirokastra to be developed into a full managed tourism destination, a focused intervention and care is needed.&#xA0;
Based on history and social development the best way to be a key driver for social change is to show more practical results than theoretical ones. CHwB has made a very good case with 5 Pilot projects realizing Gjirokastra&apos;s economic potential. It is important to highlight the cooperation with the Public institutions to implement these projects, which are interconnected with each other and foster the holistic development of the old town. The 5 projects have introduced innovation into old Town, with new ways to use monument houses, use renewable resources for management of historic cities etc.
A need identified was the lack of entrepreneurial capacities for monument owners. A hand on and continuous capacity building which should have an important social impact. CHwB has/will increased their capacities to provide face to face consultations. This shows the capacity and willingness of the organisation to develop and adapt on the needs of the target group.
The panels designed were based on international guidelines and standards due to lack of national guidelines. CHwB is providing a good example for the quality that products and services should have. This will influence the service providers to increase their quality and always interlink with EU standards.
CHwB though &#x2018;E ka kush e Ka&#x2019; methodology, increased awareness of the values of historical environment though work with young population. The methodology was inserted in the framework of the pilot national programe &apos;&apos;Doing homework&apos;&apos; and was well accepted by the Ministry, students and parents. A strong will and desire from children to absorbed this knowledge by playing was identified. This is also an innovative way of teaching/learning for the Albanian system. A transfer from theoretical knowledge to learn by doing/playing.
Besides restoring of monuments sites (taken by the regional list of Culture Heritage), CHwB has laid the foundation of the successful inclusion of these monuments in the cultural life of the cities and developed the monument owners mindset towards a more local economic development. Further CHwB has signed a few contracts of usage for some of these sites, which is a very good result achieved. This will not only increase the request from monument owners to restore their sites but also to transform them into an economic situation.&#xA0;
On the VET component beside training 131 people and certified 115 assistant craftspeople and 16 master crafts people, CHwB has lobbied with the Ministry of Culture to make adoption in the bylaws related to the licensing conditions for conservation companies within the new law on &apos;&apos; Culture Heritage and Museums&apos;&apos;. A further improvement is foreseen with the law of self-employment for master crafts-people. This is the biggest intervention in the craft people law made in 30 years. As a reaction 3 companies have sent their staff for training in order to get certificates.
There is an attemption for the conversion of the training certificate into a national certification standard. This will allow the VET to adopt and fully implement this training nationwide.&#xA0;
Regarding SPAc CHwB produced two documents to further develop Spac which contained 1) Creating a safe space for Dialogue and 2) Turning memory into Action.
There was a huge interest from Donors to contribute into this action. The Ministry of Culture has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CHwB but a clear commitment is need from the government in order for donors to join in with additional funds. The Albanian Governement should design a long-term perspective for Spac and also allocate budget means.
Regional restoration Camps is the historical component of CHwB. The camps have created an inclusive environment where participants do not only learn topics on conservation but also economic impact of culture heritage, encourage youth to embrace the value of Ch, create international bonds in the community and exchange know-how. Representing more than 22 000 Hr of trainings, the RRC did not limit their impact only to education but they provided real support of local communities through the completion of more than 14 intervention on important monuments in Gjirokastra and 16 intervention in Berat. Some of the participant the RRC have opened an entrepreneurial potential to become self-employed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55130005" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
