<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13827A0101-ALB-15112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Territorial Administrative Reform STAR 3</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to Territorial Administrative Reform STAR 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Denna insats st&#xF6;der, via en f&#xF6;rvaltningsfond med flera bidragsgivare, implementeringen av den territoriella administrativa reformen i Albanien genom f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttring av tillhandah&#xE5;llande av tj&#xE4;nster och insyn i kommunala beslut och utg&#xF6;r den tredje fasen av programmet &#x201C;St&#xF6;d till administrativa och territoriella reformer&#x201D;. Fonden administreras och implementeras av FN:s utvecklingsprogram (&#x201C;UNDP&#x201D;) i Albanien, i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med Albaniens regering. I denna tredje fas kommer projektet att anta en modul&#xE4;r strategi d&#xE4;r fokus och prioritet kommer att l&#xE4;ggas p&#xE5; de nyckelaktiviteter som f&#xF6;ljer av STAR2: n&#xE4;mligen att utvidga OSSIS-n&#xE4;tverket till att omfatta administrativa enheter; fr&#xE4;mja deltagarstyrning och utvidga antagande av integritetsplanering; &#xF6;ka statlig och lokal f&#xF6;rvaltningskapacitet avseende standardisering och insamling av lokala data genom utbyggnad av det nationella integrerade planeringssystemet f&#xF6;r informationssystem (&#x201D;IPSIS-systemet&#x201D;) p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5; f&#xF6;r att kunna planera och &#xF6;vervaka resultat; och genomf&#xF6;ra samarbete med den albanska skolan f&#xF6;r offentlig f&#xF6;rvaltning f&#xF6;r tillhandah&#xE5;llande av standardkursplaner f&#xF6;r lokala myndigheters personal.
I enlighet med dess till&#xE4;mpningsomr&#xE5;de kommer STAR3 att arbeta i partnerskap och n&#xE4;ra samarbete med flera offentliga kontor och byr&#xE5;er. Inrikesministeriet kommer att utg&#xF6;ra den h&#xF6;gsta niv&#xE5;n av partnerskap, eftersom denna institution har det &#xF6;vergripande mandatet och en tillsynsroll n&#xE4;r det g&#xE4;ller de strategiska, operativa och &#xF6;vervakande ramar inom vilka de lokala myndigheterna verkar. Programmet kommer att ha ett n&#xE4;ra samarbete med specialiserade statliga organ t.ex. Albaniens myndighet f&#xF6;r leverans av integrerad service (&#x201C;ADISA&#x201D;) avseende antagande av nationella standarder och gemensamma kontor f&#xF6;r tillhandah&#xE5;llande av tj&#xE4;nster. Andra framst&#xE5;ende offentliga institutionspartners inkluderar Albaniens nationella myndighet f&#xF6;r informationssamh&#xE4;llet (&#x201C;the National Agency for Information Society&#x201D;), justitiedepartementet, avdelningen f&#xF6;r allm&#xE4;n f&#xF6;rvaltning och kommission&#xE4;ren f&#xF6;r &#xF6;versyn enligt f&#xF6;rvaltningslagen, och den nationella myndigheten f&#xF6;r bost&#xE4;der och fastighetsregistrering (&#x201C;the National Cadaster Agency&#x201D;). Inom projektet kommer man ocks&#xE5; att samarbeta med lokala civila organisationer f&#xF6;r att unders&#xF6;ka om framsteg g&#xF6;rs och fr&#xE4;mja en debatt om lokala f&#xF6;rvaltningsfr&#xE5;gor genom &#xF6;kat medborgarengagemang och f&#xF6;r att unders&#xF6;ka vilken efterfr&#xE5;gan som finns p&#xE5; gr&#xE4;srotsniv&#xE5; p&#xE5; lokala &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder. Projektet kommer att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att de lokala organisationer som engageras representerar specifika m&#xE5;lgrupper, s&#xE4;rskilt kvinnor, s&#xE5;rbara och marginaliserade. Projektet kommer att skapa utrymme f&#xF6;r och bjuda in lokala myndigheter och f&#xF6;rvaltningar f&#xF6;r att utnyttja deras kapaciteter och n&#xE4;tverk i syfte att ytterligare st&#xE4;rka dessa funktioner.
Den modul&#xE4;ra strategi som byggts upp under utformningen av programmet kommer att g&#xF6;ra det m&#xF6;jligt att snabbt genomf&#xF6;ra andra specifika aktiviteter om ytterligare resurser erh&#xE5;lls.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This  intervention supports the implementation of the territorial administrative reform in Albania through service delivery improvement and transparency of municipal decisions, being the third phase of the Support to Administrative and Territorial Reform programme, designed as a multiple/donor trust fund, administered and implemented by UNDP Albania, in close cooperation with the Government of Albania. .
In this third phase, the project will adopt a modular approach, keeping into the focus as priority interventions only the key activities to be followed from STAR2, namely, expanding the OSSIS network to administrative units, promoting participatory governance and expanding the adoption of integrity planning, increasing central and local government capacities on standardization and collection of local data through the expansion of IPSIS system at local level to plan and monitor the performance, and collaborating with Albanian School of Public Administration  for the provision of standard curricula for local government staff. 
In accordance with its scope, STAR3 will work in partnership and close collaboration with several public offices and agencies. The Ministry of Interior will be the highest-level partnership and project counterpart, as this institution has the overall mandate and oversight role on the strategic, operational, and monitoring frameworks where local governments operate. The programme will collaborate closely with specialized state agencies (like ADISA) on adopting national standards and joint single offices for service delivery. Other prominent public institution partners include National Agency Information Society, the Commissioner on Freedom to Information and Data Protection, the Ministry of Justice, Department of Public Administration and the Commissioner for Oversight of the Law on Civil Service, and National Cadaster Agency. The project will also engage with local civil society organizations in reviewing progress and promoting debate on local governance matters, promoting civic engagement and bottom up demand for responsive local action. The project will ensure that engaged CSOs represent specific target groups, especially women, vulnerable and marginalized ones. The project will make space and invite the engagement of the Local Government Associations, making use of their capacities and networks and aiming to strengthen these capacities further.
The modular approach built in the design of the programme will enable  other specific activities to be triggered in case of additional resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-11-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and support to subnational government</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.5095605719</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-02">325743.50956</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">325743.509560572</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONCLUSION ON PERFORMANCE
1.1 Objectives of the intervention
STAR3&apos;s overall objective is to strengthen local government effectiveness and efficiency
through enhancing the supporting framework, consolidating systems, standards, and
organizational capacities in place, expanding, and sustaining service delivery innovation
and best practices, and institutionalizing local government accountability to women and
men for enhanced participatory governance.
The overall objective is supported by the following specific objectives:
1. Local government participatory governance practices are in place and functional and
encourage civic engagement.
2. Municipal systems and standards are enhanced, expanded, and consolidated for
improved service delivery and overall municipal performance.
3. Government institutions, responsible for decentralization and local government, are
capacitated to effectively drive policy development, coordination, and monitoring.
1.2 Examples of results achieved
The expected results of the intervention are the following:
1. Methodology for public consultation and participation adopted and implemented in
six municipalities and endorsed as a municipal standard.
2. 1/3 of Albanian municipalities supported to adopt integrity planning as a tool for the
management of corruption risks.
3. The one stop shop system functionality is improved overall and extended to up to 240
municipal administrative units.
4. A local government data hub, inclusive of local level IPSIS module requirements is in
place.
5. Central level government structures in charge of Decentralization and Local
Government are capacitated to monitor the implementation of the National Crosscutting Strategy on Decentralization and Local Governance and its Action Plan.
When it comes to the implementation on the ground, the early part of the 2021, has
been spent to secure the funding of the most important activities, especially those that
belonged to the category of those requiring consolidation like the OSS (One Stop Shop);
and to build upon the results of the bridging phase between STAR 2 and STAR 3 for a
well-targeting and resource-matched Work Plan.
Also, the project needed to establish its implementation team. The essential expert
project staff has been retained from the Preparatory Phase and moved to the STAR3
project. Nevertheless, during the early bridging phase, the project replaced the OSS
expert, as the former one left, and had also to replace the Communication and the
Administrative Assistant. Between January  March 2021, the project re-hired ten
regional coordinators. The staff vacuums were mainly caused by the time gap between
the phases of the project.
The insecurity of funding and the efforts required for the reestablishment of the project
staff team, have contributed to a rather slow start of activities.
During the first year of implementation the project has:
-developed Terms of Reference for Public Consultation and Participation at local
municipality level.
 - prepared Terms of Reference for expansion of Integrity Planning pilot experience in
the selected municipalities. The Activity is about consolidation and expansion of the
integrity instrument to at least an additional 14 municipalities, that is making integrity
planning a standard and integral part of the overall management of the local
administrations in a total of 20 municipalities (1/3 of all Albanian Municipalities). The
practice will also be disseminated to other municipalities and the objective is to trigger a
positive reaction from additional municipalities by the end of the project. Also, UNDP
has engaged a short-term consultancy for the development of various alternatives of an
Integrity Index, a quantification measure of the municipal integrity performance, a
novelty that the Project envisages to introduce.
-an IT needs assessment for OSS expansion in the administrative units has been carried
out by the project staff, instead of hired consultantsand as suggested by Sida/Embassy.
The assessment has identified approximate needs in consultation with respective Mayors
or municipal managerial staff. This exercise was followed up by accurate specifications
and formalization of the commitment of each municipality through the signing of MoU-s
with the respective Mayors. Larger municipalities have tended to accept and adopt the
system in order to increase their performance and service delivery quality. Small and
medium municipalities have been more resistant to change, believing that they could
serve better and faster to citizens without the system due to their size and service
procedures they have followed by years. Differences also vary from one individual to
another due to the mentality, experience, and ability to use new technologies. Since the
use of OSS has had fluctuations caused by internal leadership issues and outer
environment, the project has responded by restoring the OSS Information System
maintenance and support services for 48 municipalities until end 2021, improve the
connection with the central data systems and refresh the training for the personnel using
the system. Public awareness on the benefits of using the OSS has been prepared and
conducted. The project has also advanced in the preparations for the rolling out of the
OSS in the administrative unit of the target municipalities.
-When it comes to Integrated platform for municipal performance /IPSIS, the project
has followed and supported the relevant actors (Municipalities and Ministry of Interior)
to take a final decision with regards to the approach to be applied in building the system.
The options are two: 1) the development of a publicly or semi-publicly accessible
integrated platform for local data and indicators, including data and indicators developed
by the existing data collection platforms built by existing assistance programmes (Swiss in
particular). This would become a centrally run system for data collection on municipal
level to be used for statistics and monitoring of performance. The option 2) is about
developing and rolling out the IPSIS on local /municipal level. The decision will direct
the types of activities to be carried out by the project in this particular area.
- with regards to Central level monitoring and reporting capacity building, the project
has helped the Ministry of Interior&apos;s Local Affairs Directorate to carry out the first round
of monitoring of the implementation of the its Action Plan for 2020.
1.3 Assessment of the likelihood that the objectives will be achieved by the end of
the intervention given the overall risk
Even though initially under-resourced compared to the ambitions, the project has
developed realistic plans by adjusting to the changing circumstances at both local and
central level. Now that the main bulk of the funds is disbursed from EU and there are
promising signs a that USAID might reengage with support to STAR 3, it is expected
that the implementation will get a boost in 2022. Especially, if COVID related
restrictions will be reduced, it is expected that the effectiveness of the intervention will
also increase visibly.
 One new emerging issue is the ongoing discussion between the two main political parties
for a remaking of the territorial division between the municipalities of the country. In
case that is going to happen, there might be effects on the STAR 3, as attention will go to
the new territorial division.
 However, since the current phase of the project has been very focused, it is still likely
that the results expected can be achieved at the end of the implementation period.
1.4 It is likley that the objectives of the intervention will be achieved
No risks have been identified that require monitoring or mitigation by Sida

1.6 Current dialogue issues
The possibility for a renewed territorial division needs to be considered during the
dialogue with the Ministry of Interior, municipalities targeted by STAR 3, and on
political level from the Embassy in the meetings with the leaders of the main political
parties. Any new division should ideally lead to better administration of land and human
resources at local level and should not compromise the move towards further
strengthening of the municipalities.
1.7 Follow-up of dialogue issues
The dialogue with the implementing partner and main beneficiary has led to a more
vitalized implementation of the intervention, has brought important discussions in the
Project Steering Committee and has generated a more coordinated donor feed-back to
UNDP and GoA.
1.8 Follow-up plan for the coming period
During 2022 the possibility of a revised Territorial and Administrative Reform and its
effects on the planned activities of the STAR 3 project needs to be followed up
rigorously.
 Also, important will be to follow up the pending decision about how to approach the
data collection system for the local governments. This is a decision that has multiple
interests and actors involved and needs to be taken in a way that serves at the same time
to the local municipalities and the central government.
 Also, the use of possible additional funding to the project by rejoining partners like
USAID, needs to be connected to the highest next priorities and discussed widely in the
PSC meetings.
 A coupling at least with the Swiss cooperation team for assessments and dialogue about
STAR 3 performance and strategic orientation is considered important and useful to the
project and will be conducted whenever possible, with the view to achieve a broader
donor harmonization in the framework of the intervention.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13827" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
