<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-IN-F16AP00744</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen the protection measures in Kaziranga and Manas National Park through advanced patrolling as a part of the program &#x2018;Indian Rhino Vision 2020 Phase-II&#x2019;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. Programs in this element should be integrated with the Agriculture Area under Economic Growth and Conflict Mitigation and Reconciliation Area under the Peace and Security Category, when applicable and appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. This includes The purpose of this project is to help better manage the Protected Areas of Assam. Project objectives are as follows: (1) Establish best practice systems that can improve the effective use of information for conservation and monitoring; (2) The development and use of standardized processes together with flexibility to meet the different needs of the protected areas guidelines for data collection, analysis, and presentation that will promote meaningful assessment and enable comparability of conservation data across information management systems; (3) Develop suitable forms of spatial monitoring and recording tools to meet the management needs of protected area of Assam; and (4) Improve security in Kaziranga NP and Manas NP through improvised patrolling and monitoring, and continue support to run the existing Spatial Monitoring And Reporting Tool (SMART) patrolling in both the parks..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-DUNS-918630005" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WILDLIFE AREAS DEVELOPMENT AND</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>918630005</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-30" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="IN">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">India is the anchor of South Asia, one of the United States&apos; most important bilateral partners, and a rising global power with a multi-billion dollar economy. In the last several years the relationship has risen to a new level of cooperation, where the United States and India are working positively across a multitude of sectors to advance shared national interests. One common area of interest is the pursuit of sustainable development, and the United States and India are now working jointly to achieve their shared development goals for India, the Asia Pacific Region, and global progress. New commitments include initiatives to mitigate the impact of climate change, achieve global health and food security objectives, and ensure continued regional integration and stability. U.S. assistance in India is used to advance this shared agenda by engaging a range of stakeholders to end extreme poverty - which affects 21.3 percent of India&apos;s population, according to the World Bank - and increase citizens&apos; access to quality health care, education, water and sanitation, and energy. Through this assistance, the United States also helps to support and protect vulnerable women, girls, and minority groups. With assistance, the United States is piloting a new model of development, whereby partnerships and platforms created jointly with the Government of India (GOI), private sector stakeholders, and civil society organizations are used to scale proven solutions locally and globally.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-01">26954</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-30">26954</value>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">26954</value>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2016-08-30"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
