<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="13" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/21887" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-3997-21887</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Nutrition Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malnutrition and hunger-related diseases are the largest preventable causes of mortality amongst children under the age of 5 in the developing world. Proper nutrition, safe feeding practices, quality care and interaction are all critical to ensuring that children&#x2019;s brains and bodies have, and are able to utilize, all the nutrients that they need to grow and develop to their full potential.

Holt International&apos;s Child Nutrition Program (CNP) addresses the critical nutrition, health and development issues facing orphaned and vulnerable children around the world. CNP focuses on addressing the unique nutrition and feeding needs of children who are most at risk of malnutrition. This program uses a Training of Trainers (ToT) approach to empower sites to provide optimal care to children.  CNP&#x2019;s training, tools, resources and support provides sites with targeted interventions to help address and prevent the causes of malnutrition, especially in children ages 0-5 and children with disabilities. 

CNP provides partnering sites individualized resources and tools to support behavioral and organizational change through a variety of methods consisting of training and hands on practicum. This program&#x2019;s training covers a range of topics and health interventions including: nutrition basics, nutrition by age, hygiene and sanitation, growth tracking, health monitoring, nutrition interventions to address malnutrition and other common illnesses, feeding and positioning, food texture modification, and child development. CNP also provides sites with Holt&#x2019;s online Nutrition Screening System Database. This database is an essential tool that enables sites to track and evaluate the health and growth of children and also address any health related issues early and effectively. 

Through CNP&#x2019;s standardized training, long term supported implementation and rigorous evaluation, the program is able to implement a sustainable and scalable model. Local trained trainers are successfully able to scale the program to additional sites and provide ongoing support.

Since the beginning of the program in 2013, the Child Nutrition Program has:
&#x2022;	Conducted more than 20,000 health and nutrition screenings, impacting more than 4,700 children while allowing for optimal health monitoring and intervention. More than 30% of the children impacted by the program have a disability or special need. 70.2% of the children start the program with one or more malnutrition indicators (stunting, wasting, underweight, anemia)
&#x2022;	Trained more than 1,000 people on key principles of the Child Nutrition Program.
&#x2022;	Expanded to 7 different countries and 41 sites including institutional care, day care, and foster care programs. 
&#x2022;	Conducted, and continuing, research and statistical analysis to provide evidence of program impact and areas to improve practices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Holt International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3997-21887" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Holt International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emily DeLacey</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>emilyd@holtinternational.org</email>
   <website>http://holtinternational.org/nutrition</website>
   <website>http://www.holtinternational.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="14.285714285714286"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="14.285714285714286"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="14.285714285714286"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="14.285714285714278"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="14.285714285714286"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="14.285714285714286"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="14.285714285714286"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://holtinternational.org/nutrition">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
