<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-45865</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VLP Dry Port</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project outcomes
Stakeholder effects: IFC anticipates that the Project will support improvement in transport logistics by introducing the first international standard dry port in Laos. Laos is a landlocked country with an underdeveloped logistics services industry and with transport prices twice as high as in other Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) member states. Prior to the operation of the Project, the cross-border trade in Vientiane was served by the First Friendship Bridge Checkpoint, which suffered from severe capacity constraints and with limited ability to process the increased traffic from the Laos  China Railway. The Project is expected to offer access to advanced logistics services including multimodality, trans-shipment and value-added services with potential cost and time savings. 
Market Creation Integration: The Project is expected to improve integration by establishing a strategic node for trade in the region, as well as setting a precedent for the remaining seven dry ports (Pursuant to art. 8 of Decree No. 513/GOL on Dry Port dated 4 August 2021, there will be a total of 9 dry ports to be constructed including Thanaleng Dry Port in Laos) to be constructed. The lack of strategic inland nodes (dry ports) to facilitate trade between Laos and its neighbors have led to sub-optimal solutions where trade not always moves through the most direct route. The Project will improve integration by helping Laos to transform from a land-locked to a land-linked country, leveraging its strategic location and provide a range of services to help improve connectivity within Laos and the ASEAN member countries, and thereby facilitating efficient and cost-effective bilateral and transit trade.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project involves the financing of development, construction and equipment costs of a dry port in Vientiane, Laos (the Project). The Project is being developed by Sitthi Logistic Lao Co. Ltd. (Sitthi Logistics or Sponsor), part of the Phongsavanh Group, a diversified Laotian business conglomerate. In July 2020, the government of Lao awarded a 50-year concession to Vientiane Logistics Park Co. Ltd (VLP), a special purpose subsidiary established by the Sponsor to develop an integrated logistics park in Vientiane, which includes development of a brownfield dry port and a multi-service logistics park. IFC&apos;s financing will be used for financing of the dry port only through Thanaleng Dry Port Sole Co. Ltd (Project Company), a subsidiary of VLP. The Project has been partially operational since December 2021 and is expected to be fully operational by second quarter of 2022.Once fully operational, the Project is expected to offer access to advanced logistics services including multimodality, trans-shipment and value-added services with potential cost and time savings. IFC is the mandated lead arranger for the entire debt package and also will invest quasi equity in the Project Company.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THANALENG DRY PORT SOLE CO.,LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-45865" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  T  he ESRS and ESAP documents   will be a  vailable at the following address  ;   Kamphengmeuang   Road,     &#xA0;  Phonthan   Village,   Saysettha   District, Vientiane Capital, Lao PDR  .</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Petroleum Trading Lao Public Company  Mr. Mark Luvant  Project Finance Director  +856 (0) 20-5555-4034  mark.lv@petrotradelaos.com  Kamphengmeuang Rd  Phonthan Village, Saysettha District Vientiane Capital  Lao PDR  www.petrotradelaos.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lao People&apos;s Democratic Republic</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="LA-Lao People&apos;s Democratic Republic">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is located in the Hadxayfong and Saysettha Districts in Vientiane, Laos. It is located 1 kilometer from the First Friendship Bridge and connected to the bridge by a bonded road, which is a cross-border trade point between Laos and Thailand. The Project is also next to the terminus of the Laos-China Railway.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.0000000000 105.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="4883" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-BB - Port and Harbor Operations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/45865">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/45865">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
