<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="KES" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-NCB-KE-NCB-2180519317899-AVT09/BZ95937B</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P051098561L" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kituo Cha Sheria-Legal Advice Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROMOTING ACCESS TO JUSTICE FOR THE POOR AND MARGINALIZED</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To promote access to justice for the poor and marginalized communities  


EXECUTIVE SUMMARY
The year 2020 was riddled with challenges caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. Indeed, these challenges affected Kituo Cha Sheria&#x2019;s (hereinafter &#x201C;KITUO&#x201D;) work towards enhancing access to justice for the poor and marginalized. However, KITUO&#x2019;s commitment to its vision and mission withstood the test of time. The COVID-19 pandemic marked a paradigm shift in KITUO&#x2019;s programmes, procedures and processes; the change was necessary to remain relevant, responsive and useful to beneficiaries during a pandemic.
In the period under review, KITUO conducted 10 outreach activities. An approximate total of 1,836,769 people were reached directly and indirectly through the various interventions conducted across the country. Further, 200 M-Haki platform users expressed satisfaction in their matters being adequately resolved. Additionally, 20 volunteer advocates were recruited through the legal aid clinics and radio shows done. KITUO continued to mentor and provide technical support to the existing seven community and seven prison justice centres. Whilst access to prisons justice centres during the height of the pandemic was restricted, the prison paralegals continued to provide services. In the same vein, community justice centres never downscaled their operations. They became key human rights monitors and response agents on the ground.
KITUO&#x2019;s development and use of the M-Haki sms platform was of utmost importance at a time when legal services had to be provided remotely due to the COVID-19 health protocols. There was an increase in use of the M-Haki platform in 2020 as compared to the year 2019. In 2019, the platform received a total number of 1029 smses as compared to 1649 smses received in 2020. This translated to a 60 percent increased use of the M-Haki platform.  The increased use of the platform is attributed to increased interaction with the platform, advertisement and media engagements that were conducted during the period under review. The increased use of the M-Haki platform also meant increased legal awareness amongst indigent clients. Furthermore, with the increase in sexual and gender-based violence cases in the country resulting from the stay-at-home directives, clients were able to receive legal assistance through the platform. As such, outcome one of the project was achieved. Kenyans who accessed the M-Haki platform received legal services and enhanced their legal knowledge. The increased legal awareness in turn results in improved access to justice for the indigent and marginalized communities. 
Despite the challenges, KITUO continued to promote and advocate for human rights during the pandemic. The 16 days of activism and the International Human Rights Day were critical events in the global human rights calendar. KITUO commemorated the 16 days of activism by highlighting the unique legal challenges of the most vulnerable groups in society and advocating for better inclusivity amidst the pandemic. The online public discourses touched on persons with disabilities and persons living with HIV/AIDS and the impact the COVID-19 pandemic had on their lived realities.  
KITUO acknowledges the importance of building the capacity of community and prison paralegals. In pursuance of enhancement of capacities of community and prison paralegals, KITUO continued to provide technical and administrative support. For appropriate cases, the referral mechanism between the justice centres and KITUO continued to be utilized. 
The period under review also witnessed the first annual paralegal learning forum and KITUO Annual Paralegal Awards (KAPA). The learning forum presented a platform for the widespread network of KITUO&#x2019;s community justice centres to share experiences and build each other&#x2019;s capacities. The paralegals were also informed about the ongoing reforms on paralegalism. There was increased learning and sharing through the platform. The acknowledgment of the good work implemented by our community justice centres was a good motivation.
Lastly, KITUO is indebted to the Kingdom of the Netherlands for its unwavering support, especially during the COVID-19 pandemic. The partnership with the Netherlands Embassy has enhanced access to justice for vulnerable and marginalized Kenyans during this state of fragility.

PROGRESS TOWARDS OUTCOME 1: INCREASED LEGAL AWARENESS OF THE INDIGENT THROUGH THE M-HAKI PLATFORM
KITUO has employed the use of M-Haki, an SMS and digital convergence platform to provide free legal aid services to the poor and marginalized. Through the support of the Netherlands Embassy, we have dedicated the mobile number 0700777333 to provide this service. Members of the public send text messages with legal questions, which are then answered by our in-house lawyers and pro bono advocates within 48 hours.  The site has undergone several improvements from version 1 to now version 4. 
KITUO intends to continue creating awareness of the platform by engaging stakeholders who have interacted with the site; sharing the progress and; the workings of the platform. It is through such engagements that KITUO gets feedback on how to further improve the site, and to better serve the poor and marginalized in society.
Our target for the year 2020 was to have 80 volunteer advocates trained on the use of M-Haki, 50 paralegals trained and using M-Haki and 20 staff trained and using the M-Haki platform.
Following from the above, KITUO conducted training for it&#x2019;s in- house lawyers and staff achieving a total number of 45 participants (14 males and 31 females) attending the virtual training conducted by our M-Haki team. With the onset of COVID -19 in the country, online engagements became the new normal and this gave the platform a big boost as will be seen in the report hereunder.
Our lawyers and volunteer advocates log in to the back-end of the system through the website-www.m-haki.co.ke to access the questions and send answers back to clients. Legal questions handled on M-Haki are categorized into land rights, succession issues, labour rights, refugee rights and forced migration, housing and forced evictions, in line with KITUO&#x2019;s core mandate areas. An additional category of General Legal Inquiries catering for all other legal areas outside the scope of KITUO&#x2019;s core mandate areas is incorporated into the platform.
In the period under review, the M-Haki platform received 1649 matters from groups and persons of both genders. 

There was a peak in the number of messages received in the last quarter of 2020. This can be attributed to the COVID-19 pandemic. During the lockdown period, clients were no longer attended to at KITUO&#x2019;s physical location in adherence to the covid-19 health protocol hence M-Haki became the main platform where all KITUO advocates attended to clients remotely. The increase in numbers could also be explained by the vigorous advertising conducted by the team and its community paralegals during this period.

Through the primary data source-SMS, 55% of the users of the platform were males while 45% were females. Moreover, there was a high number of labour rights cases recorded in 2020 followed by land right cases. Majority of users sought for legal redress on labour rights as a result of losing jobs owing to the COVID-19 pandemic.  
During the reporting period, questions were relayed onto the M-Haki platform from different regions of Kenya; including Nairobi, Mombasa, Kilifi, ElgeyoMarakwet, Thika, Narok, Kisumu, Migori, Eldoret, Chuka and Homa Bay. A majority of SMS sent were from Nairobi, Kisumu, Nakuru, Turkana and Mombasa counties. 
2.0	PROGRESS TOWARDS OUTCOME 2: ENHANCED COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT TO FACILITATE ACCESS TO JUSTICE
2.1	Radio talk shows
We conducted radio shows at Ghetto FM, Radio Nam Lolwe and Pwani FM. During this period, we benefited from the good relationship with partners to discuss issues such as mental health, COVID-19 and its impact on access to justice justice for the poor and marginalized. Each show was held during peak hours, giving KITUO, M-Haki and our community justice centers visibility. 
2.2	Networking meetings 
During the period under review, KITUO participated and also hosted some stakeholders&#x2019; meetings. The meetings were conducted virtually due to the restrictions presented on social gatherings. As a member of the governing committee of the Paralegal Society of Kenya, KITUO participated in the coordination meetings. 
We also participated in the East and Horn of Africa Paralegal Network meeting that focused on collecting reviews and presenting a report on the state of legal aid in the member countries. Through this network we were also able to prepare and present a report to the African Commission on Human and People&#x2019;s Rights.
KITUO joined the Missing Voices network that deals with torture and advocacy on extrajudicial killings by law enforcement agencies. In 2020, the network assisted KITUO in collecting evidence on the PIL case filed challenging excessive force by the police on individuals while enforcing the COVID-19 directives.
2.3 Community awareness around key human rights days
KITUO joined the world in marking and celebrating the 16 days of activism that runs every year from 25th November to 10th December.  In 2020, KITUO conducted the following activities on different days to mark each of the 16 days. 


&#x25CF;	Mood board &amp;selfie booth- the team organized a white board/ wall with a canvas white sheet at the entrance of the Kituo offices where staff, clients and survivors wrote short messages on the fight against Sexual gender-based violence marking the 16 days of activism. We had students from the University also making notes on the mood board through art or simple messaging through the 16 days. The selfie Booth was a social media plan targeting the youth especially during the Youth day. We had a total of 20 participants writing on the mood board and 15 clients participating in the selfie booth.

&#x25CF;	Social media gender polls &amp; facts- KITUO embarked on a daily fact messaging using our Facebook, Twitter and Instagram pages to share facts about the 16 days. These facts were then followed by polls creating awareness on Gender based violence issues. The polls indicated the low levels of understanding of what GBV entails and the redress mechanisms available. The 16 days of activism campaign posts reached a total of 10,600 people and 6, 800 engagements (clicks, likes, comments, shares and messages) on Facebook. Twitter had a post reach of 7,900 and 3,044 engagements (clicks, retweets, likes, comments, and messages). A total of 2304 people participated by voting on twitter and Facebook gender polls.

&#x25CF;	GBV videos- We documented short messages speaking against GBV from staff, clients and the general public on Gender based violence in Kenya. These also included experiences of GBV.
&#x25CF;	Webinars on HIV and AIDS day, and PLWDS day- These were online conversations organized by the team to discuss and create awareness on human rights issues surrounding persons living with HIV and disabilities especially during the COVID-19 pandemic. We had a total of 190 views from Facebook live and 63participants on zoom. 15 questions were raised on the HIV and AID&#x2019;S webinar. These questions were indicative of a lack of awareness on the legal redresses for violations available for persons living with HIV/AIDS.KITUO also had 235 views on Facebook live and 70 participants on zoom and 21 questions asked during the Persons living with Disabilities webinar. The questions indicated that there is an information gap on inclusivity of PWDs in employment and in government initiatives.

&#x2022;	Marking the International Human Rights Day
A legal aid clinic was held to mark the International Human Rights Day. The culmination of the 16 days of activism is the International Human Rights Day. KITUOconducted the free legal aid clinic on KITUO&#x2019;s grounds together with law students from the University of Nairobi, Volunteer advocates and community paralegalsfrom Kamukunji, Kibera and Korogocho Justice Centres. . The Legal Aid Clinic attended a total of 70 beneficiaries consisting of 29 being women and 41 being men. The legal issues ranged from labour, housing, land and succession, constitutional and criminal matters.

2.4	Communication and IEC materials and creative HAKI blog-vlogs and production/dissemination of interactive creative Haki blogs-vlogs on access to justice and other human rights.
Our target for the year was to have 300 reference materials and booklets disseminated 
In the period under review, we managed to produce M-HAKI fliers and stickers to be used during the legal aid clinics and paralegal summits.  The following items were equally produced in 2020 that contributed to the number of questions and clients received in 2020.  The booklets will be produced in 2021 and disseminated during the in-person activities. The remaining materials used for education and information would however be produced to be used for implementation in 2021.

PROGRESS TOWARDS OUTCOME 3: CAPACITY OF PRISON AND COMMUNITY PARALEGALS TO PROVIDE LEGAL AID STRENGTHENED. 
3.1	Monthly monitoring and administrative support of prisons and community paralegal justice centres
KITUO continued to give administrative and technical support to the Justice Centres thereby strengthening their capacities to attend to clients. This was done through:
&#x2022;	Phone calls with the paralegals; 
&#x2022;	One on one meetings; 
&#x2022;	Holding joint community legal aid clinics and; 
&#x2022;	Regular visits to the justice centres to discuss and advise on various cases.
Community Justice Centres documented cases on the impact of COVID 19 in informal settlements. Issues predominantly attended to by the community justice centres were land, labour, housing and succession matters. These matters were unique because they were a result of the COVID 19 restrictions, which caused loss of employment and evictions rom rental houses. Other matters covered include assault and damage, defilement, arbitraryarrest, child maintenance, disturbance, child custody, loan repayment, health, SGBV, Identity card issues, domestic disputes, threats , petty theft ,  fraud ,  debt and  robbery with violence were successfully handled at the centrres
A total of 890 (384 Male, 460 Female, 46 children) clients were attended to by the individual justice centres as follows: 

Studying the data, it was interesting to note that the gap between female and male clients reporting cases continues to close. There were no records of persons with disabilities being attended to. To remedy this, Kituo will work with the justice centres and support them to capture data on PWDs seeking justice.
3.2	Successful matters resolved at the Community Justice Centres
Of the 890 cases brought to the attention of the community justice centres, 277 matters were conclusively resolved through ADR with the help of the paralegals. The matters resolved through ADR included family disputes andchild maintenance disputes. The paralegals handle matters most civil cases and draft documents for filing in court. Those outside their capacity were referred to various institutions such as the courts, chiefs, lands office, police, KITUO volunteer advocates, KITUO Head Office and Mombasa Regional Office, district registrar, children&#x2019;s office and other NGOs for further legal assistance. In conclusion, the use of ADR, referrals and free legal services has been a success at the community justice centres. 
The high number of cases addressed by way of mediation is a positive outcome. It is indicative that conflicting parties were satisfied with the quality of legal and ADR services and have adhered to the mediation agreements. 
Furthermore, there was an improved relationship between the Community centres and the local authorities. Some of these cases were referred to the centres by police officers, the chief and the other community-based organizations. For example:
&#x25CF;	The Kibera community justice centre is a focal point on SGBV and domestic issues within the informal settlement of Kibera.
&#x25CF;	Additionally, the Kitui community justice centre is the only referral centre used by the children&#x2019;s department to channel children&#x2019;s issues for further legal advice or intervention. Kibera Community Justice Centre uses the local administration offices to deliver the summons to the respondent/ as a result of the good work of the centre and an established working relationship with local administration. 
We have annexed some cases that have been concluded and satisfactorily dealt with at the centres using ADR. 
3.3	Prison Justice Centres Report
Due to the Government restrictions that were in place in 2020, we were unable to train and launch the new prison and community centres. However, the prison interventions have been planned for 2021. KITUO continued to maintain contact with the prisons justice centres, the paralegals and liaison officers. The review of sentences due to theFrancis Karioko Muruatetu &amp; another v Republic 2017case resulted in a number of the prison paralegals being released. With their release, the number of trained paralegals reduced e.g. in Meru Prison Justice Centre there are only 5 prison paralegals left while in Kodiaga Prison Justice Centre there are only 3. 
Moving forward, there is a need for regular training in order to meet the demand of paralegals within correctional facilities. The prison justice centers&#x2019; computers and printers require upgrading. There is a need for new materials especially in the wake of the digitization of the judiciary in Kenya. Matters are now handled virtually and applications are filed online. It is therefore important to supply good quality computers for the enhancement of justice within these centres.

3.4	Annual Paralegal Learning Forum 
KITUO conducted the first annual paralegal learning forum at Pelican Lodge in Naivasha on 10th to 12th December 2020. The forum sought to &#x201C;bring together paralegals trained and supported by KITUO to begin a conversation on legal empowerment, and how they can build commonalities and realize collective aspirations in achieving access to justice for all. This was done through   learning and team building sessions for the paralegals as a means of rejuvenating team spirit in paralegalism.&#x201D;


A keynote address from activist and human rights defender, Okiya Omtatah, was received warmly as he encouraged the community paralegals to teach communities about the law since this was a key tool in the fight against human rights violations. He advised the participants to always use avenues that are likely to deliver results. Moreover, he asked them to choose their fights, be diplomatic and create connections. Lastly, he motivated the community paralegals to equip themselves with knowledge. The outcome of this event was that the paralegals were further encouraged to create awareness on various legal matters in their communities. Furthermore, increased capacity building on new laws was requested as well as the content of the building bridges initiative report. 

The highlight of the Paralegal learning forum was the Kituo Annual Paralegal Awards (KAPA) which was the first ever event of such a nature. It consisted of a gala dinner where community justice centres and the best paralegal of the year were acknowledged and rewarded for their exemplary work.
At the end of the ceremony, all community justice centres received an award for their good work and resiliency during this challenging year. The paralegal of the year award went to Ms. Jamia Rahim from Kibra Community Justice Centre. Ms. Rahim was recognized for her work in improving rights consciousness by educating her community members, referring clients to Kituo Cha Sheria, offering legal advice, dispute resolution, accompanying clients in accessing justice and most importantly documenting cases of abuses and human rights violations and reporting the same to KITUO. She was very instrumental in assisting Kituo with the filing of the PIL case on police brutality during the enforcement of the curfew order in Kenya. This case profiled KITUO as the centre for Human rights protection.

The award ceremony was graced by the KITUO Executive Director Dr. Annette Mbogoh, KITUO Board member, Ms. Mercy Wambua, Dr. Dan Juma from UNDPand KITUO Chairman Mr. Justus Munyithya. The summit was attended by a total of 48 participants, 30 male and 18 females. This is against the planned 65 participants. We could not have the intended numbers due to the Government regulations on gatherings capped at 50 participants. During the KAPA gala dinner, we had additional 45 participants attending the awards via the online platforms Facebook live and zoom.

4.0	PROGRESS TOWARDS OUTCOME 4: MONITORING AND EVALUATION
4.1	KITUO policy reviews (HR manual, finance manual, procurement policy, Board Chatter, Asset and disposal policy, costs policy and sexual harassment policy)
During the year 2020, KITUO developed new policies that would strengthen systems and governance within the organization. The policies were drafted and reviewed by the Board of Directors and Secretariat. The Secretariat was granted an opportunity to suggest revisions. As is provided in the KITUO Constitution, the Members of the General Assembly discussed the policies in a Special General Meeting that was held virtually in May 2020. The inputs by members were adopted and the following policies were passed: 
&#x2022;	The Board Charter
&#x2022;	The Procurement and Asset Disposal Policy (a stand-alone policy on procurement; KITUO also did not have an asset disposal policy)
&#x2022;	Sexual Harassment Policy (a stand-alone policy on sexual harassment separate from the Human Resources Manual)
&#x2022;	Fraud and Anti-corruption Policy
&#x2022;	Costs Policy (organizational policy on court costs)

The policies are now ready for full implementation having been adopted by the General Assembly. The Human Resources Manual and the Finance Manual will be reviewed in 2021 with the assistance of an external consultant.
The organization adopted a new strategic plan for the period 2020-2024. The theme of the Strategic Plan is &#x201C;Realizing Sustainable Development: Strengthening Access to Justice and Promoting Human Rights&#x201D;. The current project falls squarely within the following strategic objectives of the Strategic Plan:
&#x2022;	To strengthen and ensure implementation of quality programs and services that promote and protect the rights of the poor and marginalized.
&#x2022;	Strengthen the voices of the poor and marginalized to represent themselves in accessing justice to realize and enjoy their rights. 
&#x2022;	Advocate to ensure that the rights of the poor and marginalized are recognized and realized in all relevant legal frameworks leading to the promotion of the rule of law and equal access to justice by all. 
A performance monitoring, evaluation and learning plan has also been developed to support the implementation of the Strategic Plan 2020-2024. 



5.0	CHALLENGES
1.	We received an increased number of security threats on our community-based paralegals especially from the Police causing insecurity both at the individual paralegals&#x2019; homes and at the community centres. 
2.	Paralegals have had bribes solicited from them when handling cases. In criminal cases, some witnesses have demanded payments in exchange for information making the paralegals&#x2019; work difficult.
3.	The community has interfered with evidence in defilement cases and early/ teenage pregnancy cases. This has led to young girls dropping out of school at an early age and the young boys forced to seek employment to care for the young family.
4.	Facilitation of Transportation for paralegals has been a challenge especially where emergency action is needed. Some sub- counties are very remote and use of vehicles is impossible. While in some cases, our paralegals are forced to spend the night at their costs while conducting field work. Poor infrastructure within the counties which made it difficult for the paralegals to navigate as they collected cases/stories.
5.	The justice centres&#x2019; office rent has continued to rise and maintenance has become a great challenge. 
6.	Need for new equipment in the CJCs as the ones provided are now past their shelf life. 
6.0	PROPOSED WAY FORWARD 
1.	There is a need for a sustainable solution to the rent/ office space for the centres. KITUO should explore the suggestion on getting a container or free office space donation from the county government and well-wishers to enable continuous monitoring and support of Community Justice centres.
2.	There is a need for continuous partnership with both state and non-state actors to expand the list of referral avenues.
3.	Bearing in mind the COVID-19 pandemic, community paralegals should be equipped with protective kits (Face Masks, hand sanitizer and hand wash containers for the walk-in clients)
4.	As we head towards the 2022 general elections, there is need to start monitoring election related conflicts. This is because political activities have already been heightened across the country from the launch of BBI. 
5.	It will be crucial to conduct capacity building training sessions on resource mobilization and reporting to improve reporting capacity and accountability of the justice centres. For the KAPA annual awards, there is a need to include both community and prison paralegals through their officers and recognize the work of Paralegal Society of Kenya (PSK) and its relevance to the annual summit. It will be important to include PSK as a crucial stakeholder in paralegal work in Kenya. 
6.	We have also noted how popular our legal aid clinics have become. To increase KITUO&#x2019;s reach, community paralegals will be encouraged to conduct outreach activities following the legal aid clinics so as to reach clients with special needs. 
7.	M-Haki has also received a number of questions in the period under review, there is a need to improve it further and begin the process of owning and hosting the application and the website itself. Improvements should be focused on a more personalized way for clients and advocates to interact. Notably, it is increasingly difficult to follow up on client&#x2019;s cases with the increase of cases. Some suggestions for improvement include allowance for sharing of documents, allocation of clients to specific advocates on the interface for easy follow up and inclusion of a mechanism to allow advocates to view new messages from clients whose questions had already been responded to.
8.	There is a need to conduct capacity building sessions for the existing centres including resource mobilization, financial reporting and mediation. This will empower the teams to become self-reliant as we explore solutions for sustainability.

ANNEX
1.	Gender Violence
Miriam (not her real name) reported that she was beaten by her husband, had lost 2 teeth on the lower jaw and sustained bruises on the upper right side of her lip.
How It All Started.
The incident had occurred on 29/12/2020 at around 4.pm. Mariam had asked the husband whether to prepare ugali with the remaining flour. The husband barked at her saying that was Miriam&apos;s problem. He followed Miriam into the house. He kicked her as she shielded herself with her arms falling to the ground.  He turned to the daughter who was pleading with him not to beat her mother and slapped her too then locked all three children in a separate room.
The husband then returned saying he was going to destroy her face. Miriam later passed out and when she regained consciousness about one and half hours later, the man was washing his stained T-shirt. She looked at her dress (dera) she had worn. It was wet with blood. She had lost two teeth in her lower jaw and felt weak and dizzy.
After having obtained a p3 form, she pleaded with police not to take her Husband to court. She needed him to take care of her children together. Miriam was then referred to the Lamukani CBO in Msambweni for resolution of the domestic abuse and other matters. The paralegal, Mwabatarealized that the husband was suffering from depression. The husband was confronted and was remorseful, the couple is now attending counselling sessions together and individually for the husband once a week. There have been no incidents since.
Documented by Paralegal Ali Mwabata.
2. Land 
Philip KisiaraOruko a 75 years old, from Mibasi in Muhoroni Sub county; reported to Nyandocentre that he had given his two sons David and Michael two different parcels of land that were registered in his names to use for agricultural purposes but instead the sons decided to lease the said parcels of land to one Charles Obong&#x2019;oGwara without his consent in a bid to raise money to empower their younger brother David to start up a business.  The land was leased for a period of five years, the five years had elapsed. 
Philip Kisiara the registered land owner approached Charles early January 2020 asking for his land parcels but was shocked to be informed by Charles that the two land parcels had been sold to him by his sons and now the land belonged to Karisa. Charles refused to surrender the land parcels to Philip and continued cultivating the land.  Philip reported the issue to our office where he was screened by our paralegal Judith Ochanda; a demand letter was drafted, invited both parties for alternative dispute resolution meeting on 22nd April 2020, fortunately both parties came and we managed to listen to their side of the story where we also realized that Philip and Charles were lso relatives which helped to ease the conflict. The alternative dispute resolution team (Paralegals) Francis Opande, Booker Kadundo and Judith Ochanda managed to take both of them through land laws and as well as on the process of acquiring land /land ownership.  
After a lengthy discussion the paralegals sent them back to discuss the issue at family level since the perpetrator claimed that he had been paying Phillip&#x2019;s sons money with an intention of buying the land from them additional to the money he had paid during lease period. We postponed the discussions pending the resolution from the family. 

                     The photo below is Philip Kisiara aged 72 years old, who&#x2019;s two 
                     Sons leased his parcels of land for a period six years without her 
                     Consent / knowledge came to the office to give feedback of the outcome 
                     Of the family meeting concerning land dispute. 


On 22nd July 2020, Philip came to give us feedback from the family meeting concerning the land dispute between him and Charles; he told us that Charles had surrendered the land back to him after getting the knowledge on land laws that we had taken them through during the alternative dispute meeting that we had with them in the office.

He is already making use of it, he has tilled it and planted maize and sugar cane in it. He was so happy and very grateful for the work that we do as a paralegal adding that the matter was solved amicably within a short period of time unlike when taken to court where cases drag and take like forever to be concluded.  
Documented by the alternative dispute resolution team (Paralegals) Francis Opande, Booker Kadundo and Judith Ochanda from Nyando Community Justice Centre</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="KE-NCB-KE-NCB-2180519317899" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kituo Cha Sheria-Legal Advice Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

The year 2020 was riddled with challenges caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. Indeed, these challenges affected Kituo Cha Sheria&#x2019;s (hereinafter &#x201C;KITUO&#x201D;) work towards enhancing access to justice for the poor and marginalized. However, KITUO&#x2019;s commitment to its vision and mission withstood the test of time. The COVID-19 pandemic marked a paradigm shift in KITUO&#x2019;s programmes, procedures and processes; the change was necessary to remain relevant, responsive and useful to beneficiaries during a pandemic.
In the period under review, KITUO conducted 10 outreach activities. An approximate total of 1,836,769 people were reached directly and indirectly through the various interventions conducted across the country. Further, 200 M-Haki platform users expressed satisfaction in their matters being adequately resolved. Additionally, 20 volunteer advocates were recruited through the legal aid clinics and radio shows done. KITUO continued to mentor and provide technical support to the existing seven community and seven prison justice centres. Whilst access to prisons justice centres during the height of the pandemic was restricted, the prison paralegals continued to provide services. In the same vein, community justice centres never downscaled their operations. They became key human rights monitors and response agents on the ground.
KITUO&#x2019;s development and use of the M-Haki sms platform was of utmost importance at a time when legal services had to be provided remotely due to the COVID-19 health protocols. There was an increase in use of the M-Haki platform in 2020 as compared to the year 2019. In 2019, the platform received a total number of 1029 smses as compared to 1649 smses received in 2020. This translated to a 60 percent increased use of the M-Haki platform.  The increased use of the platform is attributed to increased interaction with the platform, advertisement and media engagements that were conducted during the period under review. The increased use of the M-Haki platform also meant increased legal awareness amongst indigent clients. Furthermore, with the increase in sexual and gender-based violence cases in the country resulting from the stay-at-home directives, clients were able to receive legal assistance through the platform. As such, outcome one of the project was achieved. Kenyans who accessed the M-Haki platform received legal services and enhanced their legal knowledge. The increased legal awareness in turn results in improved access to justice for the indigent and marginalized communities. 
Despite the challenges, KITUO continued to promote and advocate for human rights during the pandemic. The 16 days of activism and the International Human Rights Day were critical events in the global human rights calendar. KITUO commemorated the 16 days of activism by highlighting the unique legal challenges of the most vulnerable groups in society and advocating for better inclusivity amidst the pandemic. The online public discourses touched on persons with disabilities and persons living with HIV/AIDS and the impact the COVID-19 pandemic had on their lived realities.  
KITUO acknowledges the importance of building the capacity of community and prison paralegals. In pursuance of enhancement of capacities of community and prison paralegals, KITUO continued to provide technical and administrative support. For appropriate cases, the referral mechanism between the justice centres and KITUO continued to be utilized. 
The period under review also witnessed the first annual paralegal learning forum and KITUO Annual Paralegal Awards (KAPA). The learning forum presented a platform for the widespread network of KITUO&#x2019;s community justice centres to share experiences and build each other&#x2019;s capacities. The paralegals were also informed about the ongoing reforms on paralegalism. There was increased learning and sharing through the platform. The acknowledgment of the good work implemented by our community justice centres was a good motivation.
Lastly, KITUO is indebted to the Kingdom of the Netherlands for its unwavering support, especially during the COVID-19 pandemic. The partnership with the Netherlands Embassy has enhanced access to justice for vulnerable and marginalized Kenyans during this state of fragility.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-31">310822</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
