<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7103</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkiye Sise ve Cam Fabrikalari A.S.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Name            Turkey-Sisecam Glass Works and Cogeneration Project                           Region                  Europe    Sector                  Manufacturing    Project No              007103    Projected Board Date    March 21, 1996    Company Name            Sisecam Group    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders                         The project sponsor is the Sisecam Group, Turkey&apos;&apos;s    largest glass producer.  The Sisecam Group controls all five operating    companies.  Sisecam&apos;&apos;s major shareholder is Turkiye Is Bankasi A.S., one    of Turkey&apos;&apos;s largest commercial banks, with about 70% ownership of the    Group.     Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment                         The total project cost including all five sub-   projects is $334 million.  The projected IFC funding will be a $70    million loan of which about $35 million on IFC&apos;&apos;s account and $35 million    on the account of participants.    Location of project and Description of site                         The float glass line is located at a new site    within an existing industrial park, about 20 km from the port of Mersin    in South East Anatolia.  The glassware factory and glass container    factory will be located adjacent to one of Sisecam&apos;&apos;s existing glass    container factories near Mersin, about 7 km from the float glass    project.  The glass fiber project is located at its existing site near    the town of Gebze, 40 km south east of Istanbul.  The cogeneration    project will be located adjacent to Sisecam&apos;&apos;s existing float glass lines    near Kirklareli in the Thrace region of Turkey.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project                         The Sisecam Group is implementing a major    modernization and expansion program from 1994 through 1997, to alleviate    production capacity constraints caused by growing demand for glass    products. The five sub-projects are as follows:  (i) a float glass line    of 215,000 tonnes capacity to be operated by Trakya, Sisecam&apos;&apos;s float    glass producer;  (ii) a glassware factory with a capacity of 35,000    tonnes of soda lime mechanical glassware, to be operated by Kirklareli;    (iii) a glass container factory with a capacity of 95,000 tonnes, to be    operated by ACS; (iv) a glass fiber factory with a capacity of 30,000    tonnes, to be operated by Cam Elyaf; and (v) a 27 MW cogeneration plant    supplying electricity and steam to Trakya and Kirklareli, to be operated    by Camis Elektrik, a new Sisecam company.  The cogeneration project is    motivated principally by forecasts of power shortages in Turkey    beginning in 1997.    Environmental Category and Issues                         This is an environmental review category B project;     principal issues include air emissions, liquid effluent, waste    management and occupational health and safety.  Sisecam is investing in    environmental protection measures to mitigate the environmental impacts    of the projects and meet local requirements and World Bank guidelines.     For its Trakya float glass line, the company will install a flue gas    desulfurization unit and an electrostatic precipitator to treat waste    gases from the float furnace.  Because centralized wastewater treatment    facilities will not be installed by the industrial park until a future    date, biological wastewater treatment facilities for the Trakya plant    will be constructed as part of the project.  At the ACS and Kirklareli    plants, Sisecam will use the locally available No. 6 fuel oil in the    expansions, but by December 31, 1999, will either switch to natural gas    which is expected to arrive in the area by that time, or bring the    plants into compliance with European Union requirements by that time.     The new glass fiber production line at Cam Elyaf will include bag    filters to control particulates.  Sisecam&apos;&apos;s cogeneration plant will be    fueled by natural gas and employ low NOx burners to reduce emissions.     Solid wastes from Sisecam&apos;&apos;s plants are used internally in other    operations, disposed of in accordance with local practice, or recycled.    Noise abatement procedures are included in designs, while filters and    ventilation measures will be used to reduce particulate matter and    vapors.     The Environmental Review Summary is available from the Public    Information Center.    Date SPI sent to PIC February 21, 1996    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TURKIYE SISE VE CAM FABRIKALARI ANONIM SIRKETI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7103" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1996-10-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1996-11-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TR-Turkey">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>39.0000000000 35.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CA - Glass and Glass Products (Including Glass and Mineral Wool)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1996-10-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1997-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1996-10-18">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1996-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1996-10-18">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TURKIYE SISE VE CAM FABRIKALARI ANONIM SIRKETI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7103/turkiye-sise-ve-cam-fabrikalari-a-s">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
