<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8425</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Modern Karton</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Turkey-Modern Karton Sanayii ve  Ticaret              Region    Europe 1        Sector       Project No008425   Projected Board DateFebruary 15, 1998   Company NameModern Karton Sanayii ve Ticaret   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The project sponsor is the Eren Group, a diversified medium sized second-tier Turkish group with investments in eleven companies in the textiles, cement and paper sectors.  The shareholding structure of Modern Karton as of December 31, 1996 was as follows: the Eren Group (75%); Dentas, another Turkish paper producer, (20%) and others (5%).    Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	The project cost is estimated at US$89.3 million.  The proposed IFC investment is a loan of US$30 million, of which US$10 million will be for the account of participants.     Location of Project and Description of Site    	Modern Kartons two existing paperboard lines are located in Corlu, an industrial area, about 100 km west of Istanbul.  The new production line will also be installed at the same site.  The plant is well connected to the road network in Turkey.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project   (include IFCs Role and Development Impact)    	Modern Karton is the largest private sector producer of corrugating packaging materials in Turkey.  The Companys expansion and modernization program has many components, the most important of which is the expansion of the Companys capacity from 90,000 tpy to 290,000 tpy by installing a new, complete production line for white-top liner, test liner and fluting.  This is in line with Modern Kartons strategy of removing capacity constraints on existing equipment and improving quality to meet competition particularly from imports from the EU. The additional production will primarily be sold on the domestic market.  IFCs role in the project will include providing long-term financing to the Company, assisting a second-tier Turkish company access international financial markets through the syndication and providing technical assistance through its review and suggestions in evaluating the project design and the cost structure of the project.  The project is also expected to have a positive development impact: it will create  40 new direct jobs in Turkey and 400 more indirect jobs; it will impact the environment positively since waste paper collection and recycling will be stimulated due to the substantially larger waste paper needs of the Company; it will raise skill levels in Turkey since no other production facility in Turkey uses the modern technology that the Company intends to use; it will benefit customers from improved product quality and new and more sophisticated products; and it will assist a good company in its transition to becoming an internationally competitive company.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure. The expansion and modernization project will take place on the existing facility and no additional land will be acquired.  The project does not therefore involve any relocation or resettlement.  The Sponsor will buy all electricity and steam needed for the project from Modern Enerji which means that MK will not have air emissions.  The industrial liquid effluents from the plant will be treated in a biological wastewater treatment plant.  MK will therefore comply with local governmental standards and World Bank guidelines for liquid effluents.  Modern Karton will establish Safety and Occupational Health programs to comply with governmental standards and World Bank guidelines.  Based on its review of available information regarding potential environmental impacts and proposed mitigation measures, IFC has concluded that the proposed project is being designed to meet Government of Turkey requirements and World Bank policies and environmental, health and safety guidelines.  IFC will monitor MKs ongoing compliance with World Bank policies and guidelines during the life of the project by evaluating the environmental performance reports submitted annually to IFC by the Sponsor, in conjunction with the annual financial report, and by conducting periodic site reviews during project supervision.     The  is  from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to InfoShop     January 15, 1998      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MODERN KARTON SANAYI VE TICARET ANONIM SIRKETI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8425" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-07-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TR-Turkey">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>39.0000000000 35.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AG - Paper Packaging Products (Including Boxes, Cartons, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1998-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-03-31">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-03-31">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MODERN KARTON SANAYI VE TICARET ANONIM SIRKETI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8425/modern-karton">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
