<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-11144</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atilim University</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atilim  University, founded in July 1997, has about 1,186 students in its three faculties (arts and sciences, management, and engineering). It also provides graduate degrees to 74 students in engineering and management. Atilim wants to become a top-ranked research institution helping students develop market-needed competencies in engineering and business.  Upon completion of its long-term investment program by the year 2010, the university expects to have three additional faculties: law, fine arts, and communications, a broader science faculty with five additional departments in the faculty of arts and sciences, and two new engineering departments. The engineering faculty will be the largest, followed by the faculty of management. Eventually, about 10% of the total 10,500 students will be enrolled in graduate programs. The project will increase enrollment in Atilim by about 1,300 students. It will add 15,000 m2 of indoor space dedicated to classrooms and laboratories for the faculties of management and engineering. In addition, this phase will include the construction of a waste water treatment facility and a power generation and distribution facility.       Development impact:    The project will help augment the delivery of quality tertiary education in Turkey and alleviate the shortage of slots in Turkish universities. With the expansion, Atilim University will begin to achieve sufficient scale to increase its research activities. The successful implementation of the project will encourage other private initiatives in tertiary education and diffuse best management and academic practices to the public and private education system.       IFC&apos;&apos;s role   :   Turkeys financial sector has been unable to provide adequate local currency financing to support long-term investments, especially for not-for-profit institutions such as Atilim.  Financing for these institutions is limited to short-term loans at high spreads or leasing, because they are considered frontier sectors and risk assessment is complicated by their not-for-profit status.  Yet they provide important social services that are directly linked to improving the social capital of the country.  Consequently, the role of IFC is especially important, as it is the only major source of long-term project financing for these clients.  With this investment in a young private university in Turkey, IFC would demonstrate the financial viability of these institutions, structuring innovate ways for securing its loan, while applying some governance measures commonly found in well-managed private institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATILIM UNIVERSITESI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-11144" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2002-06-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2002-07-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr Yalcin Zaim, Chairman of the Board of Trustees   Atilim University   Kusilcasar Koyu,    06836 Incek, Ankara   Phone: (90) 312 499-1276, Fax: (90) 312-499-1278</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TR-Turkey">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is located in the outskirts of the city of Ankara, Golbasi location, at Kisilcasar Village and is close to the Ankara-Konya highway. Out of 24 ha, 10 ha are already in use by a private school (kindergarten to college) and by Atilim University. The remaining 14 ha still remain to be built. The project will add two buildings and 15,000 m2 of indoor space.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>39.0000000000 35.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Colleges, Universities, and Professional Schools</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $6.50 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2002-06-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2002-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2002-06-14">6500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2002-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2002-06-14">6500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ATILIM UNIVERSITESI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/11144/atilim-university">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
