<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26016</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enerjisa Enerji Uretim A.S.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed IFC investment will extend corporate loans to EnerjiSA Enerji &#xDC;retim A.S. (EnerjiSA or the company), secured with its underlying portfolio of energy assets and contracts, to finance the first phase of EnerjiSAs capital investment program for the 2008 to 2012 period.  IFCs proposed investment will be in parallel with financing arranged by the Turkish commercial bank Akbank and the European commercial bank WestLB headquartered in Germany.  The project consists of the construction of a portfolio of one natural gas-fired thermal plant (TPP) and  according to current planning  ten hydroelectric power plants (HPP) in various locations throughout Western and Southern Turkey with total capacity of approximately 1.9 GW with an estimated cost of $2.0 billion (EUR1.4 billion) (Phase I), representing the initial phase of Enerjisas overall capital investment aimed at developing 5.0 GW in generation capacity by 2015.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey is facing a serious electricity shortage, expected as early as 2009, due to a combination of sustained economic growth and lack of adequate investments in the energy sector in recent years. To address the critical situation, the Government of Turkey (GOT) has embarked on implementing an on-going liberalization program of the Turkish electricity sector, including the preparation for the privatization of state-owned electricity distribution and generation assets. Consequently, several of the local private groups, many of which are already auto generators for their own industries, have begun expanding their power generating capacity, either independently or by the means of partnerships with experienced international power operators.   Despite the growing risk appetite from commercial lenders to finance power generation assets, the sector exhibits significant commercial risks and regulatory uncertainties during the transition period, impeding the availability of long-term financing for the merchant power projects, in the absence of long-term power purchase agreements (PPA).  The project will have a high development impact as it will:     - contribute to the development of a merchant power operator in Turkey where ongoing structural and regulatory changes have introduced additional uncertainty for prospective investors;     - finance the construction of power generation capacity of approximately 1.9 GW and meet incremental power demand in Turkey given the expected supply shortage in 2009;     - support the power sector reforms in Turkey as the plants built within the scope of the project will not benefit from any government guarantees contrary to the existing independent power producers. Moreover, the project is expected to demonstrate the viability of a liberalized power sector to other potential private entrants to the sector.  Due to its reliance on hydro and natural gas as energy sources, the project will contribute to reducing Turkeys reliance on coal, thereby reducing carbon intensity and improving security of supply.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENERJISA ENERJI URETIM ANONIM SIRKETI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26016" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-06-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-12-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerhard Wedam (CEO) Enerjisa Enerji Uretim A.S.  Sabanci Center Tower 2, Floor 5, 4. Levent 34330 Istanbul    E-mail:    gwedam@enerjisa.com.tr    Telephone:+90 212 385 88 50 Fax:&#xA0; +90 212 385 88 55   Website:    http://www.enerjisa.com.tr/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TR-Turkey">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project envisions the construction of the Bandirma natural gas fired thermal power plant in western Turkey adjacent to the Marmara Sea, and  according to current planning  ten hydroelectric power plants, including Cambasi in the Solakli River basin in northern Turkey; Kusakli, Kavsakbendi, Yamanli II, Kopru, and Menge, located in the Seyhan River basin in the south of Turkey; and Dagdelen, Kandil, Hacininoglu, and Sariguzel, located in the Ceyhan River basin in the south-east of Turkey.  A technical and economic optimization of the individual projects is going on.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>39.0000000000 35.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BA - Large Hydro - Renewable Energy Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $247.70 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-06-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2008-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-06-13">247700000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-06-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-06-13">247700000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENERJISA ENERJI URETIM ANONIM SIRKETI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26016/enerjisa-enerji-uretim-a-s">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
