<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41236410-6340</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dorcas Aid International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Joint Response 5</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">37100 persons affected by the ongoing conflict in South Sudan, with a focus on the most vulnerable populations (women, children, elderly and people with disabilities)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRA Joint Humanitarian Response to the South Sudan Crisis</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific Objective 1: Save lives by providing timely and integrated multisector assistance to reduce acute humanitarian needs amongst the most vulnerable people Specific objective 2: Reinforce protection and promote access to basic services for the displaced and other vulnerable people Specific objective 3: Support at-risk communities to sustain their capacity to cope with significant threats</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dorcas Aid International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dorcas Aid International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41201463-SSJR2019" ref="NL-KVK-41201463" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="South Sudan Joint Response 5" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="6340"></owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and Livelihoods (FSL) Emergency food assistance support is provided in Bagari (Wau County) and Pibor, where JR partners have provided 22,500 individuals with sundry food items, including sorghum/maize flour, cooking oil, salt and pulses/beans. Beneficiaries were selected in collaboration with local authorities, village leaders and target communities so as to address the neediest families and minimize inclusion and exclusion errors. The ration size was determined based on the WFP recommended ration for monthly household food basket. In connection to short-term livelihood support, a total of 49,500 individuals across all five JR locations are provided with resources to protect and start rebuilding livelihood assets. Vulnerable households, including households which are single headed families, pregnant and lactating women, Child headed families, Household without livestock, Households who survive off casual daily labour, Households with chronically ill and disabled family members, HHs caring for UASCs, HHs with cases of child labor, and HHs with SAM/MAM cases. The short-term livelihood support includes the provision of agricultural inputs (crop seeds, vegetable seeds, farming tools) and aquacultural inputs (fishing kits) to vulnerable households. JR partners conducted agriculture inputs availability assessments, and where possible, in order to support local markets and increase relevance and the acceptability of inputs distributed to the community, the project has used a local procurement approach, with items being purchased from were purchased from local vendors. All households receiving inputs were provided with relevant accompanying trainings on the use of the seeds, improved farming practices, mitigation measures against some of the shocks such as flooding, and orientation on the use of the equipment, fish harvesting techniques, and on the effect of overfishing on the local breeds and environment. Monitoring is key in these activities: in all locations, post distribution (at minimum after first and last round) and pre- and post harvesting monitoring for agricultural inputs is conducted. To provide communities with an opportunity to build an income base that can support them when they are subjected to disasters and shocks, a total of 762 individuals have become active participants in Village Saving and Loan Associations (VSLA) groups in Aweil East, Malakal, Wau &amp; Jur River. These groups were provided with trainings on financial management, and are applying the skills they gained in the training during their weekly meetings in which they jointly agree on saving, loaning and repayments.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH The key objective of the WASH component of the JR is to provide timely and equitable access to safe water, sanitation and hygiene for IDPs/host communities and returnees in Aweil East and Wau and Jur River specifically. In order to increase households&#x2019; access to sufficient and safe water for domestic use, a total of 29 non-functional boreholes/handpumps have been rehabilitated and repaired since the start of this year, and an additional 5 new boreholes have been drilled. 22 of the rehabilitated boreholes required major repairs, while the other 7 required minor repair only. Water quality tests were conducted for all boreholes, to ensure the water sources meet the minimum requirements and can be used for human consumption, and to provide chlorination if necessary. Taking the issue of sustainability into consideration, water management committees (WMC) were formed for each borehole. All 350 WMC members were selected and organized with the guidance of the community and their leaders, and training was provided were trained on the proper management skills of water facilities. To ensure that the support is sustainable, the community were involved in contributing towards the repair of the borehole. In the water user committee training, one of the topics the committee is trained on is how to collect small fee from the community members benefiting from the repaired borehole in order to make funds available for future repair of the borehole in case they break down again. The involvement of women was ensured through their participation during beneficiary selection, community mobilization, capacity building, and committee formation in water management for the boreholes. To improve sanitation and hygiene practices among the target communities, JR partners are applying the Community Led Total Sanitation (CLTS) approach for the construction of household latrines. Following the first step, triggering, which helped the community to analyze and aware their situation including the extent of open defecation and the spread of oral-faecal contamination, the approach encourages households to build their own latrines from local materials to ensure that there is sustainability. JR partners distributed various type of tools to each target location to support the effort. CLTS activities that were planned to be carried out in Aweil East in the early months of the year, before the heavy rainy season, have been successful with 832 households in the targeted ten villages having constructed their pit latrines and another 437 households having started constructing their latrines already. To integrate the hygiene component, a total of 95 hygiene promotors were recruited and trained in Aweil East and Wau &amp; Jur River, who are response to increase hygiene promotion awareness at community and household level in their communities, by sharing relevant hygiene messages.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dorcas Aid International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>+31 (0)228 595900</telephone>
   <email>info@dorcas.org</email>
   <website>https://www.dorcas.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O.Box 12 1619 ZG ANDIJK, the Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="2"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="Western Bahr el Ghazal" vocabulary="A1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and Livelihoods (FSL) The three key objectives of the FSL intervention of the JR are to meet basic food needs, to protect and rebuild vulnerable households&#x2019; livelihood assets and strengthen their resilience. The FSL needs are at the core of the programs designed in all JR locations, with all locations ensuring an increased focus on sustainability and resilience within the lifesaving FSL activities conducted, and all activities work to establish a nexus between humanitarian response and resilience programming. Emergency food assistance support is provided in Bagari (Wau County) and Pibor, where JR partners have provided 22,500 individuals with sundry food items, including sorghum/maize flour, cooking oil, salt and pulses/beans. Beneficiaries were selected in collaboration with local authorities, village leaders and target communities so as to address the neediest families and minimize inclusion and exclusion errors. The ration size was determined based on the WFP recommended ration for monthly household food basket. In connection to short-term livelihood support, a total of 49,500 individuals across all five JR locations are provided with resources to protect and start rebuilding livelihood assets. Vulnerable households, including households which are single headed families, pregnant and lactating women, Child headed families, Household without livestock, Households who survive off casual daily labour, Households with chronically ill and disabled family members, HHs caring for UASCs, HHs with cases of child labor, and HHs with SAM/MAM cases. The short-term livelihood support includes the provision of agricultural inputs (crop seeds, vegetable seeds, farming tools) and aquacultural inputs (fishing kits) to vulnerable households. JR partners conducted agriculture inputs availability assessments, and where possible, in order to support local markets and increase relevance and the acceptability of inputs distributed to the community, the project has used a local procurement approach, with items being purchased from were purchased from local vendors. All households receiving inputs were provided with relevant accompanying trainings on the use of the seeds, improved farming practices, mitigation measures against some of the shocks such as flooding, and orientation on the use of the equipment, fish harvesting techniques, and on the effect of overfishing on the local breeds and environment. Monitoring is key in these activities: in all locations, post distribution (at minimum after first and last round) and pre- and post harvesting monitoring for agricultural inputs is conducted. To provide communities with an opportunity to build an income base that can support them when they are subjected to disasters and shocks, a total of 762 individuals have become active participants in Village Saving and Loan Associations (VSLA) groups in Aweil East, Malakal, Wau &amp; Jur River. These groups were provided with trainings on financial management, and are applying the skills they gained in the training during their weekly meetings in which they jointly agree on saving, loaning and repayments. WASH The key objective of the WASH component of the JR is to provide timely and equitable access to safe water, sanitation and hygiene for IDPs/host communities and returnees in Aweil East and Wau and Jur River specifically. In order to increase households&#x2019; access to sufficient and safe water for domestic use, a total of 29 non-functional boreholes/handpumps have been rehabilitated and repaired since the start of this year, and an additional 5 new boreholes have been drilled. 22 of the rehabilitated boreholes required major repairs, while the other 7 required minor repair only. Water quality tests were conducted for all boreholes, to ensure the water sources meet the minimum requirements and can be used for human consumption, and to provide chlorination if necessary. Taking the issue of sustainability into consideration, water management committees (WMC) were formed for each borehole. All 350 WMC members were selected and organized with the guidance of the community and their leaders, and training was provided were trained on the proper management skills of water facilities. To ensure that the support is sustainable, the community were involved in contributing towards the repair of the borehole. In the water user committee training, one of the topics the committee is trained on is how to collect small fee from the community members benefiting from the repaired borehole in order to make funds available for future repair of the borehole in case they break down again. The involvement of women was ensured through their participation during beneficiary selection, community mobilization, capacity building, and committee formation in water management for the boreholes. To improve sanitation and hygiene practices among the target communities, JR partners are applying the Community Led Total Sanitation (CLTS) approach for the construction of household latrines. Following the first step, triggering, which helped the community to analyze and aware their situation including the extent of open defecation and the spread of oral-faecal contamination, the approach encourages households to build their own latrines from local materials to ensure that there is sustainability. JR partners distributed various type of tools to each target location to support the effort. CLTS activities that were planned to be carried out in Aweil East in the early months of the year, before the heavy rainy season, have been successful with 832 households in the targeted ten villages having constructed their pit latrines and another 437 households having started constructing their latrines already. To integrate the hygiene component, a total of 95 hygiene promotors were recruited and trained in Aweil East and Wau &amp; Jur River, who are response to increase hygiene promotion awareness at community and household level in their communities, by sharing relevant hygiene messages. MPC JR partners in Aweil East and Malakal are using cash as a modality to empower beneficiaries and increase efficiency, adding to restoring dignity and freedom of choice in humanitarian assistance. The key objective of the JR MPC activities is to provide unconditional/conditional but unrestricted cash support to those most vulnerable households. In Aweil East, members from 1500 households (6.328 individuals) participated in the constructions of community access roads. Upon completion, each HH received $41 USD per month in two rounds for the month of May and June. Beneficiaries were selected based on combination agreed criteria with the community which include poor HHs with limited or no food and income sources, able to engage in labour works. 700 households not able to participate in the labour works in Aweil East, received unconditional cash transfer for two months in May and June, with each HH receiving $41 USD per month. The selection criteria which include household&#x2019;s heads who are constrained in participating labour works or with disability as the main criteria combined with limited or no food and incomes, with children; elders and PLWs with malnutrition cases and few cases of referral related to protection.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Note: &#x201C;Affected persons&#x201D; have often been described in past donor reporting templates as requiring the number of &#x201C;beneficiaries.&#x201D; In consideration of ongoing discussions about greater accountability toward and inclusion of the affected population, the term &#x201C;beneficiaries&#x201D; is instead framed here as &#x201C;affected persons,&#x201D; but implies the same level of reporting as in past &#x201C;beneficiary&#x201D; reporting. This section should also include a reflection on how complementary programming impacted the affected persons. The SSJR 2019 program targets the most vulnerable groups, which includes IDPs, host communities and returnees, as all groups remain extremely vulnerable in South Sudan. A specific focus of all JR activities is on those categories of most vulnerable persons: female headed households, child-headed households, Pregnant and Lactating Women (PLW), vulnerable youth, elderly, households with children facing SAM/MAM, and people with disabilities. For the comprehensive case management activities, the identification and registration of children with heightened risks of abuse, exploitation, neglect and separation from families was guided by the established inter agency vulnerability criteria. JR partners used these vulnerability criteria and established referral pathway to support extremely vulnerable boys and girls with complex cases. In addition to staff, communities are also sensitized on the Interagency vulnerability criteria for children in need of case management services. This way, communities are able to support the identification of children with heightened protection risks, and refer the cases to CBCPN, CP help desk and focal persons, who could then ensure that case workers assessed all the referred cases which all met the registration criteria and ensure that care plans were developed to address individual vulnerabilities. In all JR locations, JR project teams have jointly rolled out the project at various levels mainly to the local authorities at county, payam and boma level, and JR partners used a community-based approach to identify and select the most vulnerable HHs. The targeting and selection of affected persons was conducted through active participation of community representatives that involve Boma chiefs, women, elderly, and religious leaders. Specific vulnerability criteria for JR activities were discussed with community leaders/committees during the planning meetings and consensus was reached on the criteria to be used for beneficiary identification. Communities and JR staff jointly carried out the verification of project beneficiaries. Through project information sharing meetings that were held in targeted villages prior to the registration of the beneficiaries, the communities were informed on the beneficiary selection criteria and the entitlement of those who were to be selected to benefit from the project. These joint and transparent beneficiary mobilization exercises are extremely important to mitigate the main challenge encountered by partners with regard to beneficiary selection processes: the high number of needy households, exceeding the total amount of assistance available. This emphasizes the importance of carefully and jointly deciding selection criteria together with community chiefs, Payam Administrators, and target communities to avoid conflict. Community representatives and project staff together can clarify the eligibility criteria to target community member prior to the process of identification and registration of beneficiaries. Additionally, they are able to respond to any questions and complaints coming from village communities without delay following the procedure set. The JR partners implementing protection reach the beneficiaries at the WGFs and the CFSs through conducting awareness raising on GBV/CP, its effects and service availability and ensure that beneficiaries know their right to access the WGFS/CFS, and where/how to obtain it. Rights awareness sessions are provided in sufficient quantity in local languages so that the communities understand the content of messages during the sensitization. In addition, posters/banners are printed with use of pictograms instead of text due to variation in the literacy levels.</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="WESTERN BAHR EL GHAZAL" level="1" vocabulary="A1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.696855351422755 27.988357543945312</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="PPLS"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="43" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="57" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">775292</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="Food distribution">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">67011.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food distribution by local NGO</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="Mary Help Association" ref="Mary Help Association" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Q1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-30">37280.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q1</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Q2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">304295.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSAA">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">775292</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SSAA</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41201463-SSJR2019" ref="NL-KVK-41201463" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="localization">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-25">67011.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">food distribution through local partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="Mary Help Association" type="22"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="first instalment">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-29">465175</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41201463-SSJR2019" ref="NL-KVK-41201463" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41236410-6340" ref="NL-KVK-41236410" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://www.dorcas.org/about-dorcas/annual-report/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual Reports</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hygiene promotion, Excreta disposal, Water supply, Hygiene promotion (Awareness)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people reached with hygiene promotion/awareness raising activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hygiene promotion awareness in communities.Train 15 Hygiene promotors per location to reach 250HH per location (5)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-03-22" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7500"></target>
     <actual value="13488"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people having access to dignified, safe, clean and functional excreta disposal facilities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Construction of latrines for Child friendly Spaces (2*165 Children from HaC program) and CLTS triggering for communities to dig own pit latrines at household level.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3030"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people having access to sufficient and safe water for domestic use</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Drilling of 5 Boreholes (icl. Handpumps) and rehabilitation and /0r repair of 23 broken handpumps</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="14000"></target>
     <actual value="12500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q1+Q2 The activity was undertaken in four locations and it was possible to manage five major rehabilitations and 18 repairs. The water facilities were maintained together with government line ministry experts of Wau and the target communities were also participated by providing labour. &#x2022; Furthermore, water quality test was conducted for all boreholes. The result of the test shows that all sources meet the minimum requirements and can be used for human consumption. Only three were required chlorination. The intervention has enabled to serve around 11,500 people with clean water. &#x2022; To contribute to similar objective, new borehole drilling activities have been undertaken after the completion of geophysical survey which is important to ensure sustainable use of the facilities and measure level of the water table. The project has a plan to develop five new boreholes and until this reporting period the drilling of four of the five boreholes has been completed .</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people having regular access to soap to meet hygienic needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of dignitiy /sanitary kits and installation of sanitation kits for hand washing in 4 schools</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Short-term livelihood support Availability of, access to and consumption of food</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people enabled to meet their basic food needs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food relief distribution in three locations in Bagari area</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15600"></target>
     <actual value="14028"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people provided with resources to protect and start rebuilding livelihood assets</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seeds and tools distribution and trainings, conditional cash grants for goats/chickens, trainings of community animal health workers, cash grants for income generating activities and trainings</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11700"></target>
     <actual value="8940"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
