<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC732</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisectoral emergency assistance to the people affected by storms in PuniaTerritory</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of 6pm on 9th December 2021, the population of Punia and its surroundings experienced an unusualyl violent wind accompanied by torrential rain. The wind which blew for more than 3 hours damaged several family dwellings houses, health facilities, schools, churches. Several houses have completely collapsed, others have had their roofs blown away and others have sustained severe damage to their structure, with collapsed walls. After the wind, a heavy rain fell causing enormous damage to the affected population by means of a loss of means of subsistence (shelter, essential household items, stock of food, children&apos;s school supplies, etc.). Several fields were also reported which were devastated, family fish ponds whose dikes gave way, people who were injured by collapsing walls: 
At present: 
- 703 households (3,515 people) are directly affected, 576 host families, 53 households have moved into the houses whose owners are in the mining sites and in the surrounding churches while waiting for their houses to be repaired, others are living currently in the public spaces (churches, schools, etc.), and other are spend the night under the stars. 
- I032 houses have lost their roofs and collapsed walls, 
- Latrines washed away and filled with water with the risk of disease; 
- 10 schools including 7 Primary schools were destroyed; 
- 6 health centers including drugs and equipment were destroyed

This crisis comes when the attention of both the national and provincial government as well as the entire population of Maniema is focused on preventing and combating the new wave of the COVID-19 pandemic. Victims and the host families live in overcrowding. There are also reports of some families living under the stars. This poses a huge risk for the rapid spread of the COVID-19 virus as preventive barrier measures against this pandemic require observing social distancing of at least 1m between people. In addition, this disaster occurs during the period when the harvest of the crop season A 2021 is expected in this area (In the DRC there are two growing seasons per year. The first season called season B which is the smaller of two, which starts from February in April and the second season called season A which is the larger of the two and starts from September in January of the following year). Several fields being devastated, causing an immediate shortage of harvested products in the households and consequently, at market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC732" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC732" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC732" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-19">143372.856</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55581">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-22">143372.856</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
