<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC733</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multipurpose cash assistance for the displaced people due to conflict in Mangina health zone.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expected impact of this intervention is the reduction of suffering by improving the living conditions of the beneficiaries as they will access food, NFIs, shelter, education, health, etc, through multipurpose cash. In total, this project will reach 10812 individuals: 10812 will receive COVID sensitization messages through radio and other means. 1555 households (1133 direct affected households and 422 host households, 7775 people) will be assisted by cash. Each household will receive &#xA3;103.55. This amount has been recommended by the Cash Working Group as Minimum Expenditure Basket standard (2021). After beneficiary identification, in conjunction with the affected communities and a survey check for reliability conducted by SOCOAC, the list will be shared with the Micro finance agency who will provide the bank books which will allow the beneficiaries to receive their money at the mobile counter which will be installed in the villages targeted by the project, or at pre-existing microfinance offices even if they are not previous Microfinance account holders. Priority will be given to the most vulnerable households affected by the current attack, including widowed women, children heads of households, elderly people, people with disabilities, chronically ill, and / or other people who are unable to buy goods of their choice that meet the need of their households. The targeting criteria will be included within the sensitisation to ensure the do no harm principle is adhered to. CAFOD and SOCOAC will ensure that protection mainstreaming principles (security and dignity, equity, accountability, participation, and empowerment) are applied in all the project cycle. Sensitive protection issues will be referred to specialized service providers and advocacy around protection issues will be carried out where it is required. This will also consider the security situation in this region. CAFOD and SOCOAC will ensure that every beneficiary is withing a 5km radius of one of the mobile counters/microfinance offices and that the sites are chosen in collaboration with beneficiary&#x2019;s committees to facilitate beneficiaries who may have feedback and concerns to easily access the partner and microfinance supplier&apos;s agents. During the distribution days, the bank books will be distributed to the beneficiaries and they will be free to take back their money when and where they want. The bank counter be placed in the villages to facilitate easy access to all beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC733" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC733" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9; Coop&#xE9;rative Agricole du Congo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC733" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-24">215107.2727</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55582">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-23">215107.2727</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70422">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-12-23">215107.27</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Solidarit&#xE9; Coop&#xE9;rative Agricole du Congo</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
