<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC706</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clean Water supply to households affected by the Nyiragongo volcano eruption</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On May 22, the Nyiragongo volcano near the city of Goma in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo erupted.  Report produced by OCHA states that electricity line from Virunga national park and water supplies were damaged leaving thousands of Nyiragongo, Goma and Karisimbi communes unserved.  
Three villages and a district of the city of Goma were destroyed by lava on the north eastern side. Thirteen civilians lost their lives on the night of May 22 due to incidences related to the evacuation. The Civil society in Nyiragongo health zone confirms that 24 people, including 10 women, were burnt by lava, and 40 adults are still missing. The report produced by Caritas Goma indicates that more than 3,629 houses were ravaged by lava, 23 house roofs were washed away, the Goma-Rutshuru road is cut (about 2 km invaded by lava), 3 health structures and 12 primary and secondary schools were destroyed.
People have lost their belongings either in the haste of displacement, or burnt by the lava flow, or even looted in some cases. UNICEF reported that 2 of the 3 water towers serving the villages were burnt down. The only one still operational has piping problems and is in Bushara, more than 150 children have been separated from their families and it is feared that more than 170 children have gone missing as the population fled the city of Goma as a result of the volcano eruption.
In the city of Goma and its outskirts, earthquakes are felt intermittently. These tremors have caused cracks in buildings and more stress for an already traumatized population. Authorities have warned the population to remain vigilant and not to approach the red zone as mapped by the local government. There is also an outstanding risk related to ash from the eruption that could cause respiratory problems.
An assessment carried out by the Wash cluster on May 25, 2021 highlighted limited capacity to intervene in emergency to supply the affected households on WASH components and this particularly on clean water servicing. Through this project, Caritas Goma intends to supply drinking water to the 100m3 reservoir belonging to REGIDESO to serve affected and displaced sites by gravitation the households coming to Munigi center, Kihisi and part of Buhene thanks to 3 public fountains of at least 6 taps each.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC706" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas DR Congo Goma Diocese</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC706" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC706" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-01">49303.0985</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55088">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-01">49303.0985</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69687">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-01">49303.1</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas DR Congo Goma Diocese</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
