<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC744</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interfaith Peace Project in North Kivu</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This multi-faith project was designed to make a lasting contribution to conflict reduction and promote peaceful cohabitation between ethnic groups in the province of North Kivu. The religious denominations have recognised that the populations of this province need not only support for material rehabilitation but also, and above all, support for social, cultural and moral transformation through educational actions for peace and reconciliation through an ideal framework of dialogue for peaceful cohabitation and sustainable development for all. This project is being implemented in Goma, then in the territories of Masisi and Nyiragongo in the next phases. Among the peace-building actions envisaged are the awareness-raising campaign on peace and non-conflictual cohabitation through inter-community meetings, capacity-building sessions for conflict mediators and the promotion of human rights, cultural activities (games, competitions, choirs singing and playing about peace and reconciliation), the organisation of a two-part carnival for actors, and educational talks, which are one of the most important elements in promoting peace and respect for human rights. The project also plans to ensure a rapprochement of trends and inter-ethnic dialogue between the communities and the public and customary authorities (Hutu, Tutsi, Nande, Kumu, Nyanga, Hunde, Tembo, Bashi and Twa) through the creation of a consultation framework that would bring together the leaders of the ethnic and social groups living in the city on the one hand, and the representatives of the public administration and the customary chief on the other. In this framework of permanent consultation, we will call it a peace hut. The Anglican Diocese of Goma, through PEAC, is responsible for coordinating and steering this project.  The project itself will be executed in collaboration with the Catholic Diocese of Goma, the 3rd CEBCA North Kivu and the Evangelical Lutheran Church-North Kivu.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC744" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC744" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province de l&apos;Eglise Anglicane du Congo (PEAC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC744" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-05-03">9600</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="56035">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-05-16">9600</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70961">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-05-16">9600</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province de l&apos;Eglise Anglicane du Congo (PEAC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
