<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC702</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting CENCO&apos;s commitment to protect the Congo Basin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to strengthen the bishops&apos; capacities in the field of the environment and natural resources in order to facilitate their advocacy for protecting the common home. This capacity strengthening will provide the bishop members of CENCO with the tools to mobilise their different diocesan structures for responsible citizen actions with regard to the environment and natural resources, and will also enable the bishops to consolidate their advocacy role for securing the Congo Basin and the Common House. 
The commitment of the Church, especially of CENCO, in the field of the environment and natural resources is based on the social doctrine of the Church and the Magisterium, on the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, on international agreements, and on the DRC constitution and laws. The Church, constituted by citizens, has the full right and the imperious duty to contribute. This can only be done in a relevant way by sharpening the individual and collective conscience through knowledge of faith, law, science, technology, realities and shared experience. This is the reason for this special Plenary Assembly to be held at the top of the DRC church and which is in line with the Paris Agreement affirming the importance of education, training, awareness raising, public participation, public access to information and cooperation at all levels on the issues discussed in the Agreement.
This project will be held in Kinshasa and will target all the Bishops members of CENCO, the General Secretaries of CENCO and ACEAC, the Executive Secretaries of the Episcopal Commissions, the Director of the OPM, the members of USUMA-ASUMA and UCC-IPCM, the Director of the Liaison Office with the Parliament, the Secretaries of the Provincial Episcopal Assemblies, the focal points of the CDRNs at the level of the Ecclesiastical Provinces as well as the support team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC702" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC702" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commission Episcopale Ad Hoc pour les ressources naturelles</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC702" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32210" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-05-07">7553.9568</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55021">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-05-12">7553.9568</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
