<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC668</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the Role of Faith Leaders to respond to COVID19 pandemic</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a context like the DRC, there is plenty of misinformation that is moving around, leaving the communities in confusion and thus increasing the risks of propagation. For instance, some people continue to believe up to this date that Africans cannot be infected by Covid19; others say that Covid19 is not real and so forth. 
Congolese are a very spiritual people. Up to 70 percent of the Congolese population are Christians with half of these being Catholic. The rest are from other beliefs such as Islam and local sects. All have a lot of faith in their religious leaders.
Thus, in the midst of all this the people are eager to hear from the religious leaders they trust.
Even with churches closed, faith leaders still have ways to raise their voices and reach out to their believers to articulate and give their followers the correct information, strengthen sensitisation and consequently limit the propagation.
It is in this sense that this project aims to strengthen the capacity of the religious leaders so that they can meaningfully play their role and pass on the right information to their followers. The Project will also target other local influencers such as journalists (especially from the faith-based radios) whose capacity will be strengthened so that they pass on the right message and limit the misinformation and consequently have the right information to the community. 
In addition to the above, since some of our key services do not have access to the protection masks, our local partners will also get involved in this effort: In the effort to comply with the government regulations and strengthen the protection measures, the project will also supply some protection masks to the communities.

CAFOD partners&#x2019; intervention will certainly contribute to strengthening INRB measures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC668" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC668" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province de l&apos;Eglise Anglicane du Congo (PEAC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC668" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-27">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54065">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-26">15000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="68485">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-26">15000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Province de l&apos;Eglise Anglicane du Congo (PEAC)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
