<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC654</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Learning Grant: Collaborative Approach to Targeting</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To be most effective, targeting should engage communities throughout the targeting cycle, ensuring the views of affected communities &#x2013; and particularly those of potentially marginalized and most vulnerable groups &#x2013; can influence the targeting process . Often, vulnerable groups or those with special needs are overlooked in society, and in the community committees (for example, internally displaced committee) it is not often, for example, you would find a person living with disabilities as part of this committee &#x2013; which means that those with specific needs do not always get a voice and are not always seen. When committees are being organized, it is important that targeting also takes place at this stage, incorporating members who are marginalized or are people with specific needs.   

Because of diversity of needs of different communities, targeting ensures that the specific needs, vulnerabilities and capacities of communities and people affected by crisis are identified and assistance is provided accordingly, taking account of the diversity within communities including those who may be marginalized or disadvantaged. However, after consulting and going through the literature of targeting guidelines from different START Network Members in DRC it is clear that they are using different frameworks and thus there is an interest in harmonization and standardizing this approach so that all agencies are collecting consistent data. Agencies who respond to an alert together could also be using different means of targeting which then raises issues of consistency in implementation and reporting for the same project.
As agencies use different targeting approaches and data collection methods, there could potentially be gaps in targeting and some people who need support, may be missed. With a standardized framework, all agencies in DRC could use the same methods for data collection and targeting, this would ensure a better approach and would significantly lessen the opportunity for people who should be targeted to be missed. It will also make sure that the Start Fund&#x2019;s statistics for DRC are more accurate, as all members will be working from the same framework.
CAFOD will work with other Start member agencies based in Goma to try to build a framework to enable consistent targeting, data collection and beneficiary identification, including people with specific needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC654" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC654" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC654" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="80" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-01">7657.16</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="53807">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-24">7657.16</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
