<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC680</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting &#x201C;Rien Sans Les Femmes&#x201D; (RSLF) mouvement initiatives in DRC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD is implementing the Tufaulu pamoja (succeding toghether) project funded by SIDA. Project aims to empower women and young people to have greater involvement in civic and political life and to stand up for their rights.  The project will undertake a human rights-based and gender-responsive approach that places paramount priority on promoting, protecting and fulfilling the human rights of women and girls, as well as strengthening institutional capacities at local and national levels to eliminate all forms of violence against women and girls. This projet plans to work directly with and through the Rien Sans Les Femmes (RSLF) movement and youth platforms. The RSLF movement provides female political aspirants with the encouragement, training, coaching, mentoring and networking opportunities that they need - and would not get otherwise through predominantly male political networks-in order to advance in a political career.
Currently, the national headquarters of the Rien Sans Les Femmes (RSLF) movement is being established at the periphery of Kinshasa, which is difficult to access and has an impact on the visibility of its actions and limits the interaction among various members as well as carrying out the advocacy work required by this movement. During discussions with CAFOD, the need to have a headquarters close to decision-makers and to enable the movement to work in the best conditions for greater efficiency and visibility was raised. Given that SIDA has neither allowed for full payment of the rent, it appears hard for the RSLF movement to secure in-house funds for this purpose. This project therefore aims to cover the rent for RSLF&apos;s offices for a period of 6 months, covering the period during which the project is being launched, while waiting to find a definitive solution for its long-term takeover. It is part of institutional support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC680" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC680" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC680" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-29">5645.1612</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54253">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-30">5645.1612</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
