<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-DRC639</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory governance and civic education for peace in DRC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will mainly target the youth in Bukavu and Goma Dioceses that are easily manipulated and therefore vulnerable to fall into different kinds of violence. Now that the election has been carried out and the results have been published, it is time for the population to be engaged in the participatory governance process. The youth need to be equipped with the right knowledge to be able to participate meaningfully in the management of the public affairs, to exercise their civic rights, to demand what rightfully belongs to the people and meaningfully participate in the consolidation and construction of a stronger state.

However, it has been noticed that the results that have been published do not reflect the reality and the wishes of the people. Currently majority of the people are in some sort of suspense and observing whether the newly elected president will indeed challenge the Congolese people and fully rise to the expectations of the people to promote better governance and accountability in the management of the public affairs.
Otherwise there is the fear that there might be a sparkle of violence and the youth remain the main target for this. It is in this sense that this project will principally target the youth not to run into violence but to use their power to peaceful channel their expressions.
The use of new information and communication technologies will still be crucial component of this project as an effective tool to facilitate the collection and management of information on cases of abuses, monitoring human rights violations, as well as for advocacy purposes in preventing such cases. This project is implemented in Goma diocese by the Justice and Peace Commission.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC639" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="DRC639" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DRC639" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-17">16991.1504</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="52451">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-18">16991.1504</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
