<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-7300067404-ASO-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gov Mozambique, 071001-171030Pungwe River Integrated Water Resources Managem II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Gov Mozambique; 071001-171030 Pungwefloden vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltning+utveckling II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">M&#xE5;let med st&#xF6;det &#xE4;r att fr&#xE4;mja samarbete mellan Mozambique och        Zimbabwe f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad vattenresursf&#xF6;rvaltning i Pungwe-flodens      avrinningsomr&#xE5;de. St&#xF6;d ges f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka institutioner och system    samt f&#xF6;r att ta fram underlag f&#xF6;r utvecklingsorienterade              investeringar som ska minska fattigdom.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of PP2 is to strengthen relevant institutions,  stakeholders and systems at all appropriate levels for the joint,     integrated and sustainable management of water resources in the       Pungwe River Basin, and to stimulate and support appropriate          development-oriented investments in the basin that contribute to      poverty reduction and environmental sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x201C;To strengthen relevant institutions, stakeholders and systems at all appropriate levels for the joint, integrated and sustainable management of water resources in the Pungwe River Basin, and to stimulate and support appropriate development-oriented investments in the basin that contribute to poverty reduction and environmental sustainability.&#x201D;.The extension phase 2014-2016 is structured into four main components:?	Institutional development (with focus on Human resources and sustainability of institutions);?	Poverty reduction;?	Protection of the environment; and,?	Regional Cooperation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="12000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of Mozambique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="12000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mottagarlandets regering</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">601042.1317127331</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">601042.1317127331</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2007-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2007-10-01">761053.200147</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">223959.8235259744</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-28">198868.7535791504</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">178213.5475953953</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A completion memo was finalised 2018-07-26. There are no changes to this memo in terms of assessment of results but this updated memo include new information as regards the financial closing of the contribution. The updates are included in the sections on lessons-learned below (in italics).
The Pungwe Basin Transboundary Integrated Water Resources Management and Development Programme (PP2) has had as an overall objective to strengthen relevant institutions, stakeholders and systems for joint, integrated and sustainable management of water resources in the Pungwe River Basin. Aside from&#xA0;general institutional strengthening, focus was on the one hand on a set of&#xA0;activities to reduce poverty in the basin and on the other a line of work to promote&#xA0;environmental protection.
The specific objectives were:
To strengthen the capacity of key basin IWRM institutions to efficiently, effectively and sustainably fulfil their defined roles and responsibilities.
To strengthen and expand stakeholder participation in Integrated Water Resources Management and Development (IWRM&amp;D) in the Pungwe Basin.
To ensure appropriate, efficient, effective and sustainable technical systems and capacities for the collection, monitoring, management and communication of water resources data, and to improve information systems more generally in the Pungwe Basin.
To mobilise resources for sustainable, poverty-oriented, water-related development investments in the Pungwe Basin through establishment of a Pungwe Basin Pre-Investment Facility and launching of the Pungwe Basin Initiative.
In addition, seven Critical Development Projects with their own specific objectives were included in the programme.
The programme has been largely successful in producing its intended outputs. The major concrete results of PP2 in that regard have included:
- Extensive training and other capacity building programmes; In Zimbabwe, 615 individuals received training during 2012-2016. Out of these, 63% were Zinwa staff, 29% catchment stakeholders and 8% SGF beneficiaries. Out of the total number of participants, 23% were women. In addition, 32 SGF beneficiary households were trained. No consolidated data is available for Mozambique but it can be assumed that the figure is substantially higher than that for Zimbabwe.
&#xA0;- Enhanced bilateral cooperation on water resources management between Zimbabwe and Mozambique, manifested most clearly through the adoption of a bilateral agreement for the Pungwe Basin.
- Establishment of stakeholder forums in the respective catchment areas of Pungwe River in Mozambique and Zimbabwe.
- Improved information and communication systems.
- Improvement of capacity for IWRM, including monitoring, forecasting flood and drought management; A total of 32 hydrometric stations are operating in Pungwe, of which 28 in Mozambique and 4 in Zimbabwe. In Buzi there are 27 hydrometric stations and in Save 22. Transboundary and national flood risk management routines are in place. Key hydrometric stations supply real-time data, but there is a risk that they will stop functioning if O&amp;M budgets are not available.
- The implementation of a large number of small-scale water projects with poverty alleviation focus in the two countries; PP2 has implemented 32 community projects, of which 22 in Mozambique and 10 in Zimbabwe. The projects have&#xA0;benefited 543 families and 1,922 school children in Mozambique and 274 families and 2,469 school children in Zimbabwe.
Results at the outcome level include:
- Strengthened institutional capacity of the key water resources management institutions: ARA Centro in Mozambique and ZINWA Save Catchment Agency in Zimbabwe. An institutional assessment carried out in 2016 has confirmed hat the capacity of ARA-Centro to conduct its mandated functions has significantly improved following the PP2 capacity building programme. The revenue for ZINWA Save has increased by 10 % since 2008 and for ARA-Centro by 3.8 %.
- Improved flood risk management; Flood management strategy and flood forecasting model prepared.
- Improved livelihoods in some areas where small-scale water projects have been implemented
Results at impact level are less evident.
The programme has been less successful in ascertaining the sustainability of its results and of the institutions as such. This is to some extent compensated by the partners having been able to secure funding for a project of two years duration under which it is intended to continue to develop the cooperation between the two countries and create a facility for financing water investments. The new project will include the establishment of a secretariat for the implementation of bilateral agreements on the Pungwe, Buzi and Save rivers.
Some of the original components of PP2 were dropped by agreement with all parties, including the establishment of the Pungwe Basin Pre-Investment Facility and launching of the Pungwe Basin Initiative, the main reason being that the time was considered not ripe for such an initiative.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="73000674" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
