<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5100011502-ASO-14010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKACOM 2014-2017; OKACOM 5-year plan institutional and organizational capacity</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">OKACOM 2014-2017; OKACOM 5-&#xE5;rs plan f&#xF6;r institutionell kapacitetsutveckling</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d till Okavango Basin Commission (OKACOM) f&#xF6;r en del av            fem&#xE5;rsplanen &amp; kapacitetsst&#xF6;d till sekretariatet. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade          resultat:i)st&#xE4;rkt sekretariat inom administration,                    kunskaps-hantering,policy &amp; prgramkoordinering,samt ii) ett gemensamt besluts- &amp; f&#xF6;rvaltningsramverk har etablerats inom                    f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjnings-m&#xF6;jligheter, vatten- och markf&#xF6;rvaltning,</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Okavanago Basin Commission (OKACOM) for part of their five year plan and capacity support to the secretariat. Expected results:  i)strengthened secretariat in administration, knowledge management,   policy analysis and programme coordination, and ii)a joint            decision-making and management framework established within           livelihoods, water and land management, environment, biodiversity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKACOM/Permanent Okavango River Basin Water Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47000" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKACOM/Permanent Okavango River Basin Water Commission</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water sector policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.5 - By 2030, implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.5 - Senast 2030 genomf&#xF6;ra en integrerad f&#xF6;rvaltning av vattenresurser p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, n&#xE4;r s&#xE5; &#xE4;r l&#xE4;mpligt genom gr&#xE4;ns&#xF6;verskridande samarbete.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">702000.7020007019</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">526500.5265005265</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-132980.7844837615</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-02-01">874648.318488</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">351000.351000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">175500.1755001755</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-28">-132980.7400670481</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida has been supporting OKACOM in two phases over a period of almost a decade. The first phase 2009-2012 served to&#xA0;strengthen the OKACOM work program and the Secretariat&#xA0;and contributed to the creation of the Strategic Action Program (SAP). The present phase (2014-2017) is for the&#xA0;implementation of the SAP&#xA0;and has focused, on the one hand, on the institutional and organizational capacity of OKACOM and its secretariat&#xA0; and on the other hand it has supported the implementation of key priorities of the SAP in relation to the basin Development and Management Framework. The support has been instrumental in providing OKACOM with the capacity to agree on a joint vision for the basin&apos;s development,&#xA0;identify and commission&#xA0;knowledge products&#xA0;and further analysis (Basin Vision, SWA, MSIOA, TWC Benefits assessment) to achieve the vision and to become a first point of entry for cooperation partners to increasingly coordinate projects and support around&#xA0;OKACOM&apos;s own defined priorities. OKACOM itself is convinced&#xA0;that the Swedish support has been instrumental in that it has supported OKACOMs organizational development, whereas other donors have&#xA0;preferred to support selected parts and programs under SAP.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Several of the knowledge products that have been commissioned using Sida funding are instrumental in creating political will for cooperation among the member States&#xA0;and supporting the commission to take the step from dialogue and information sharing to really begin to implement cooperation on the ground.
The&#xA0;Water Allocation Strategy&#xA0;was finished&#xA0;during the last year of the Sida support. The initial analysis shows that there is room for all existing uses in the basin within the conservative boundaries determined by the member states. However,&#xA0;the analysis also&#xA0;shows that there is a general lack of data on availability and abstractions, and a great need to improve monitoring capacity. The recently approved UNDP/GEF project will be supporting these aspects. The strategy has been&#xA0;developed in a participatory manner through basin wide stakeholder consultations and was approved at the mid year meeting in November 2017. The&#xA0;next step is now for OKACOM to start applying the strategy, allocating water and&#xA0;carefully monitoring effects with an aim to adjust allocations as needed.&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;
The MSIOA identified that there&#xA0;is room for development in the basin while still respecting the Acceptable Development Space. It also identified that the option of doing nothing (i.e. no development)&#xA0;was not viable, because maintaining status quo would&#xA0;allow currently ongoing&#xA0;degradation of the basin to continue. The MSIOA identified a few possible options for joint development in the areas of livelihood enhancement, tourism and water infrastructure which are now being analyzed by OKACOM. Understanding that there&#xA0;are real&#xA0;opportunities for regional benefits from&#xA0;cooperative development projects has a positive impact on TWC in the basin, as the countries begin to realize that the gains from cooperation substantially outweigh the costs associated therewith. &#xA0;
The Assessment of Benefits of Transboundary Water Cooperation has allowed MS to realize that the investment they have made in OKACOM/SEC is paying back manifold. It is&#xA0;conservatively estimated that&#xA0;cooperation in the basin to date has leveraged in excess of USD 35 Million&#xA0;in regional resources that would not otherwise be&#xA0;available at the national level.&#xA0;The seed funding that makes this possible is the MS contributions&#xA0;that provide the core&#xA0;operating costs for the Commission.&#xA0;&#xA0;Realizing the return on investment on the resources spent on membership&#xA0;fees has&#xA0;encouraged the countries to make more timely contributions and settle arrears. &#xA0;
Sweden phasing out its support has forced OKACOM to start thinking about sustainability. Analysis of different options is being undertaken and has resulted in an agreed action plan that combines cutting costs where possible in the short term, raising membership contributions in the longer term, and exploring alternative mechanisms for financing (such as charging for projects). &#xA0;MS contributions are at present covering core staff such as Executive Secretary, Program officer, and&#xA0;administrative officer an can continue to do so,&#xA0;but MS&#xA0;contributions alone&#xA0;will not be&#xA0;sufficient for OKACOM to make the transition from coordination to cooperation as described above. Two large projects of over 10 MUSD in total have been signed with UNDP/GEF and the EU. Both projects will provide additional staff to be housed at the OKASEC and thereby temporarily increase Secretariat capacity.&#xA0;There is also a number of smaller projects&#xA0;supporting specific components of OKACOM work. The important&#xA0;success factor here is that these projects are&#xA0;articulated around OKACOM&apos;s own agenda, and not purely donor driven.
There is a general feeling of cautious confidence (from Member States, donors and experts) that OKACOM/SEC will be able to step up&#xA0;collaboration and&#xA0;move on to the implementation of joint projects. There is a clear political will from all countries to do so, the main challenge will be to ensure that this commitment extend also beyond the water sector to include key actors like finance ministries, ministries for development planning etc.
Even though Sida now ends its&#xA0;bilateral contribution to OKACOM, it will still maintain some support through the CIWA multi-donor trustfund managed by the World Bank. CIWA has already provided&#xA0;support to the&#xA0;MSIOA analysis and&#xA0;has tentatively allocated resources to set up the Endowment Fund, one of the joint development projects suggested by the MSIOA to deal with livelihoods enhancement and environmental protection in the basin.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51000115" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061603" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4725000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional Africa 2016-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt Afrika 2016-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
