<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-21-UY-UR-187</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GRANTS. Street Football: A sport and educational tool for youth and adolescents values. N/A</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve the quality, contributions and accessibility of higher education. Higher education includes but is not limited to: teaching; training; curricula; degree programs; pedagogy; research; policy analysis and participation in policy development; workforce development; second-chance learning opportunities; skills certification programs; community service; extension; applied technology; professional development; exchange programs; institutional linkages; program linkages; institutional governance; financial planning; administration; management; and policy that is developed, conducted, and/or implemented by universities, colleges, community colleges, upper secondary schools, public and private technical and vocational training institutions, public and privately led skills development programs, teacher-training colleges and institutes, research institutes, and/or relevant ministries. This program area places a special emphasis on ensuring equitable access to tertiary education and workforce development programs, especially for youth from lower income and marginalized groups including girls and young women and students with disabilities. As such, activities reported against this program area should also contribute to the Youth Development Key Issue, and be reported as such.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to improve the quality, contributions and accessibility of higher education. This award places a special emphasis on ensuring equitable access to tertiary education and workforce development programs, especially for youth from lower income and marginalized groups including girls and young women and students with disabilities.This includes Centro de Estudios e Investigaciones Afro- Mundo Afro Organizaciones. Mundo Afro and its partners, including former IAF grantee Fundaci&#xF3;n Defensores del Chaco of Argentina, will use sports leagues and educational and cultural activities to further civic participation and tolerance among marginalized young Afro-Uruguayans in larger cities of Uruguay. The program includes outdoor events and performances by neighborhood musicians, dancers and actors. The work will benefit 2,500 young Afro-Uruguayans directly and another 8,000 indirectly.. Centro de Estudios e Investigaciones Afro- Mundo Afro Organizaciones (Mundo Afro) and its partners, including former IAF grantee Fundaci&#xF3;n Defensores del Chaco of Argentina, will use sports leagues and educational and cultural activities to further civic participation and tolerance among marginalized young Afro-Uruguayans in larger cities of Uruguay. The program includes outdoor events and performances by neighborhood musicians, dancers and actors. The work will benefit 2,500 young Afro-Uruguayans directly and another 8,000 indirectly.. Centro de Estudios e Investigaciones Afro-Mundo Afro Organizaciones and its partners, including former IAF grantee Fundaci&#xF3;n Defensores del Chaco of Argentina, will use sports leagues and educational and cultural activities to further civic participation and tolerance among marginalized young Afro-Uruguayans in larger cities of Uruguay. The program includes outdoor events and performances by neighborhood musicians, dancers and actors. The work will benefit 2,500 young Afro-Uruguayans directly and another 8,000 indirectly..</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To help nations achieve sustainable improvements in the well-being and productivity of their populations through effective and accountable investments in education and other social services. Promote equitable, effective, accountable, and sustainable formal and non-formal education systems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centro de Estudios e Investigaciones Afro-Mundo Afro Organizaciones</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Inter-American Foundation</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-18" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-18" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using transaction date.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-18" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-18" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lesley Duncan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-360-4530</telephone>
   <email>lduncan@iaf.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.iaf.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1331 Pennsylvania Ave. NW, Suite 1200 North&#xC2;&#xA0;Washington, DC 20004</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UY">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uruguay</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The primary goal of U.S. assistance is to bolster Uruguayan engagement in international affairs, advance Uruguay&apos;s security sector reform, support military professionalization, and prepare the armed forces to counter emerging threats at home and abroad. Uruguay&apos;s commitment to international engagement makes it an important U.S. partner in global efforts to foster democracy, prosperity, and rule of law. Uruguay has a remarkable record as a contributor to peacekeeping operations and remains one of the top per capita police and troop contributors to United Nations peacekeeping missions. Military education and training is a key component of the U.S. government&apos;s commitment to enhancing security cooperation and strengthening Uruguay&apos;s national defense capabilities. This training also helps strengthen and maintain Uruguay&apos;s peacekeeping and disaster response capabilities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-10">27300</value>
   <sector code="11230" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth and adults</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4000" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education and Social Services - General</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2016" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-18">49000</value>
   <sector code="4002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher Education</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="11420" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher education</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2015" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-19">21700</value>
   <sector code="4000" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education and Social Services - General</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2015" end="2017"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
