<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WASTE TRMT</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan - EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY project: Jordan; EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY: The As-Samra Wastewater Treatment Plant was constructed in 2008 with support from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to replace the highly polluting waste stabilization pond system outside Amman, and is the primary facility for treating wastewater from Jordan?s Amman and Zarqa Governorates. However, the demands of a growing population had pushed the capacity of the plant to its limits. Without an expansion to properly handle the region?s growing volume of wastewater, the plant would be overloaded, its ability to treat wastewater would deteriorate, and downstream agricultural areas that rely on treated water for irrigation would face serious food safety risks and the loss of markets for agricultural products. The objectives of the As-Samra Expansion Project were to (i) increase the capacity to treat wastewater from Amman and Zarqa Governorates, (ii) increase the volume of treated wastewater that is available as a substitute for freshwater for non-domestic use, and (iii) protect existing agriculture from the potential consequences of pollution from untreated wastewater.

Under a project finance public-private partnership, with help and a funding commitment from MCC, the plant underwent an expansion and technological upgrades, which allowed the Government to treat 70 percent of the country?s wastewater and meet the region?s wastewater treatment needs through 2025.The plant has improved the long-term sludge management and disposal practices and helped preserve Jordan?s scarce water resources. The expanded plant provides 133 million cubic meters of high-quality treated water per year ? equivalent to over 10 percent of Jordan?s entire annual water resources ? for irrigation in the Jordan Valley.

At the end of the compact, approximately 375,000 households (2,023,000 individuals) in the Zarqa Governorate and neighboring Amman benefitted from the project through additional supplies of freshwater transferred to these areas as larger volumes of treated wastewater were made available for substitution in agricultural applications in the Jordan Valley. This included approximately 8,500 households in the Jordan Valley (46,000 individuals) that receive consistent supplies of high-quality treated wastewater that can be used for irrigation. The As-Samra plant also provides bio-solids for potential reuse in fertilizer and fuel, and produces nearly 13 megawatts of energy, or 80 percent of its own energy needs, from biogas and hydropower, making it one of the most modern and energy efficient treatment plants in the Middle East.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Jordan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-M&amp;E COLG" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WASTE TRMT-0360" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WASTE TRMT-0364" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WASTE TRMT-0374" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WASTE TRMT-0477" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WASTECLLCT" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-JOR-2750BXCOMD-WATERREHAB" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(a) Prior to the initial Disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, any funding for the As Samra Project: (i) The Government will have delivered an ESIA, in form and substance acceptable to MCC, that includes among other things (A) an analysis of sludge disposal and sludge reuse options, and (B) an ESMP that addresses potential environmental and social impacts during the construction of the As-Samra Expansion Project and the operation of the expanded plant.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(b) Prior to any Disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, any funding for the As-Samra Expansion Project, MWI will have certified that it has met its obligations to prepare, update and adopt a sludge management plan in accordance with Article 9.5.3 of the Restated Project Agreement (including where that responsibility is a joint obligation with the Project Company) and otherwise is in material compliance with its responsibilities under the sludge management plan then in effect.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(c) Prior to the first Disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, any funding for the As-Samra Expansion Project after June 30, 2013, the Government will have delivered to MCC a duly signed contract, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, for the feasibility study of a facility or facilities, as the case may be, for the permanent disposal of sludge from the plant.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(d) Prior to the first Disbursement of Program Funding that includes, in whole or in part, any funding for the As-Samra Expansion Project after December 31, 2014, the Government will have provided evidence, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, that the Government has committed sufficient funds for the construction of the facility or facilities referenced in Section 4(c) of this Schedule 2.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(ii) The Government will have delivered a Restated Project Agreement, in form and substance acceptable to MCC, that among other things (A) provides that the plant operator has the responsibility to produce, temporarily store and maintain treated sludge in accordance with applicable Jordanian laws, regulations and standards, the MCC Environmental Guidelines, and the ESIA, (B) provides that MWI has responsibility for the permanent disposal of sludge produced prior to, during and after the As Samra Expansion Project in accordance with applicable Jordanian laws, regulations and standards, international best practice, and the MCC Environmental Guidelines, and (C) includes an initial sludge management plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(iii)?The closing, with a syndicate of lenders acceptable to MCC and on terms satisfactory to MCC, will have occurred with respect to the debt financing for the As-Samra Expansion Project in an amount sufficient to finance the As-Samra Expansion Project.  The As-Samra Transaction Documents and all other agreements and documents related to such closing shall be in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(iv) MCA-Jordan and MWI will have duly signed the As-Samra Implementation Agreement, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, and such agreement will be in full force and effect without modification, alteration, rescission, or suspension of any kind, unless otherwise agreed to in writing by MCC, and no material default will have occurred or be continuing thereunder.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">(v) MWI?s authority engineer for the management and supervision of the construction, satisfactory to MCC, will have been mobilized on terms satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Treated wastewater used in agriculture</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of - This indicator is calculated based on treated wastewater used for irrigation in Northern and Middle ghors relative to the total irrigation water used in Northern and Middle ghors. - M&amp;amp;amp;E started using JVA Water Management System data as of Q5/2013 ,</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="61" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">- This indicator is calculated based on treated wastewater used for irrigation in Northern and Middle ghors relative to the total irrigation water used in Northern and Middle ghors. - M&amp;amp;E started using JVA Water Management System data as of Q5/2013 ,  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-12-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="70.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">- This indicator is calculated based on treated wastewater used for irrigation in Northern and Middle ghors relative to the total irrigation water used in Northern and Middle ghors. - M&amp;amp;E started using JVA Water Management System data as of Q5/2013 ,  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">- This indicator is calculated based on treated wastewater used for irrigation in Northern and Middle ghors relative to the total irrigation water used in Northern and Middle ghors. - M&amp;amp;E started using JVA Water Management System data as of Q5/2013 ,  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value disbursed of water and sanitation construction contracts</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of -Yearly Targets need to be revised in the M&amp;amp;amp;E Plan revision2, as actual values of contracts are in hand. Figure is updated as of May 31, 2016.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-Yearly Targets need to be revised in the M&amp;amp;E Plan revision2, as actual values of contracts are in hand. Figure is updated as of May 31, 2016. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-12-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="93375000.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-Yearly Targets need to be revised in the M&amp;amp;E Plan revision2, as actual values of contracts are in hand. Figure is updated as of May 31, 2016. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="25747264">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-Yearly Targets need to be revised in the M&amp;amp;E Plan revision2, as actual values of contracts are in hand. Figure is updated as of May 31, 2016. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cost of As-Samra expansion; Engineering, Procurement, and Construction (EPC) contract</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of Indicator for EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2011">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2011-12-13"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-13"></period-end>
     <target value="184350000.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="184350000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator for EXPANSION OF WASTEWATER TREATMENT CAPACITY Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
