<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1071659-PROJDRC045</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">START Fund: Protection Emergency Response for Children and Families Surviving the Volcanic Eruption in Goma</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed action aims at ensuring that vulnerable children are protected against additional risks of violence, abuse, exploitation and emotional distress provoked by the sudden displacement and family separations in the aftermath of the volcanic eruption. The consortium (War Child and its national partner MIDEFEHOPS) proposes to cover the needs in child protection, housing, FTR and information on protection issues. We propose to strengthen community-led prevention through community-based awareness-raising activities and the provision of FTR services and PSS to the most vulnerable. The key activities we will implement during the 45-day project duration are the following:

- Strengthen child protection networks in the targeted areas for appropriate and safe support. Network members will receive training on the main threats faced by children during massive displacement, and they will be supported to update the referral pathways and coordination in the targeted areas.

- Welcome and support children in need of protection in three housing centers during massive displacement (services include shelter, food and psychosocial activities). Initial rapid assessments will identify gaps in terms of safety for children in the centers and a quick improvement plan for safer services.

- Family tracing and reunification will be strengthened with more qualified resources in order to make sure that children are reunified as quickly as possible with their family members. This activity will be done with authorized ressources from DIVAS and based on SOPs validated by the Child Protection Working Group.

- Mass sensitization on protection issues with a focus on child protection and SGBV.

- Referral and access to protection services. Protection issues will be continuously monitored during displacement, in IDPs centres and in host communities. Financial resources will be made available to support and refer children who might face more critical protection issues such as exploitation and abuse, physical violence, sudden health issues etc. Critical situations within households that might put children at higher risk of protection issues will be take into consideration as well.

- Distribution of dignity kits to women in need. As a result of awareness-raising activities on protection and SGBV, the project is expected to support women and young girl victims of violence or feeling who might need additional support in term of NFIs and financial assistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-05-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-05-30">71459.49</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">71459.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">12201.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
