<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1071659-PROJYEM010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clifford Chance - ECCD in Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">*** The implementation of this project was too difficult. The funds are relocated to Iraq. The donor paid for the expenses occurred in the start of the project. *** This project aims to improve young children&#x2019;s learning outcomes and their caregivers&#x2019; ability to support the education of their children. Activities include: i) provision of Early Childhood Care and Development (ECCD) classes to 1,050 Children between the ages of 4 and 6 aimed at enhancing cognitive and social development, improving long-term learning outcomes, and facilitating their entry into formal schooling; ii) Training 52 community teachers who will be trained on ECCD learning techniques including how to encourage cognitive development through play, participatory and active learning as well working with children in conflict settings; iii) basic nutrition support for young children attending ECCD activities; iv) provision of awareness sessions for parents and caregivers to improve their parenting skills and their attitudes towards the importance of education as well as improve the psychosocial wellbeing and parenting skills of caregivers; v) community members will be involved through community-based education committees which will conduct outreach activities to identify beneficiaries and plan awareness sessions that are centred around key education and child protection issues; vi) Finally, the project will also include an ECCD research study which will be used to inform both the ECCD curriculum in Yemen and global ECCD policy discussions*.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="5"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11240" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-30">101696</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-30">4727.11</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-30">6839.69</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
