<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1071659-PROJYEM017</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Crowdfunding</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce food insecurity and increase access to basic necessities for the most vulnerable IDPs and host communities households in Attawahi and Al Boraiq districts in Aden governorate (COVID-19).

Emergency Food Assistance: Multi-Purpose Cash Assistance (100 HHs). Multi-Purpose cash assistance will be provided to 100 HHs beneficiaries in Attawahi district (at least 700 individuals). WCUK will carry out six rounds of multi-purpose cash assistance on a monthly basis in order to support families in meeting their food and other essential household needs. Households will receive approximately YER 117,495 per month as per the last guidance provided by FSAC. During cash distributions beneficiaries will be sensitized on Covid-19 prevention measures, as well as food and water safety and, healthy nutritional practices.

Emergency Livelihood assistance: Distribution of Cash and Fishery kits (100 HHs): The second component of the project will target 100 HHs (reaching at least 700 individual beneficiaries). Since Al Boraiqa district is a coastline district where the majority are involved in fishery activities, fishermen in the area will be targeted as part of our livelihoods component. The combination of cash and livelihood inputs distribution will increase HHs&#x2019; income available for food consumption and to cover basic needs and at the same time livelihoods tools will enable them to better engage in productive activities. Finally families will be better able to protect their assets as a result of the assistance provided by the project as it will allow them to avoid selling their possessions as a copying strategy to survive. Target households will receive four rounds of cash (50 USD per HH) on monthly basis and Fishery kits. The cash will be distributed in Yemeni Riyals and during cash distributions beneficiaries will be sensitized on Covid-19 prevention measures as well as food and water safety and on healthy nutritional practices. Fishery kits should be distributed during the fishing season, and first round of cash should be distributed together with fishery kit. The fishery kit consists of fishing nets (Rope+ Floater+ Sinker+ Net), Coolers (Ice) boxes and Life jackets (one life jacket to be distributed for each individual fisherman). Fishery kit composition is defined by FSAC cluster but it is also recommended to consult with target beneficiaries during baseline and with the local Ministry of Fish Wealth (MoFW) before start of implementation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1071659" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-02-01">201000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">38541.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 2021</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">201000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
