<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/3485/R/Ed/INGO/3777</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To ensure IDP children (girls and boys) benefit from safe primary education in emergencies inside K7-K15 IDP camps in Mogadishu.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this project is to provide access to primary education in emergencies for 1,646 IDP children (823m, 823f) in Banadir (K7-K15) through conditional and restricted vouchers for school fees and for learning materials each for the second and third term in the school year 2016/2017 which can be redeemed at Temporary Learning Spaces (TLS) and in contracted shops. The vouchers will be handed out to the parents/guardians (P/G), mostly single mothers, of the learners. The eligible shops have a framework agreement with the Somali partner of Diakonie Katastrophenhilfe (DKH), Daryeel Bulsho Guud (DBG), for the distribution of relief items against vouchers including learning materials. The vendors are assessed for their capacity to supply the items listed on the voucher for the number of beneficiaries in the area.

This project will compliment two other projects currently been implemented DKH and its local partner DBG in the K7-K15 IDP camps and one in planning.

In the first component, through funding from the German Bureau of Foreign Affairs (AA), DKH is implementing a 15 months&#x2019; (start 01/04/2016) multi-sectoral project in the K7-K15 IDP Camps in Mogadishu. The AA-project plans, amongst objectives in other sectors, the construction of 30 TLS which comply with International Network for Education in Emergencies (INEE) standards in the camps along Afgooye Road. Each TLS shall be composed by 4 classrooms. The camp community shall make an active contribution to the identification of the construction site. Important aspects are the safety of the place and the negotiation of the communities with the land owners to ensure temporary land tenure for the TLS. The classrooms with the measurements of 5 by 8 meters shall host 24 students and 1 teacher each. The AA project will also mobilize 150 teachers from the IDP community to form 30 Teacher Associations (TA), one for each TLS, and train them in Education in Emergencies (EIE). The TLS will be handed over to the TA after construction. Exit strategy for comp. 1 is that the TA will be the owners of the TLS already during a part of the project period.

Component 2 concerns the training of TA in Management and Operation. DKH through means from the German Federal Ministry for Economy and Cooperation (BMZ) supports income generating activities (IGA) for IDPs in the same camps. A TA shall operate one TLS as an IGA thus generating teachers&#x2019; incentives and operational costs for the TLS through education fees. The BMZ-project will train the TA in business management and the operation of the TLS as private sector institutions and follow-up on the application of the learned stuff. The TA will continue to run the TLS as learning institutions after the end of the project as their own IGA. 

Components 1 and 2 are a boost to setup the infrastructure that is capable to enrol 3000 children and that can continue self-sustained as IGA.

Component 3 and the overall objective of DKH&#x2019;s education programme is to enrol 2880 IDP children (1440f) in gender parity from the IDP camps along Afgooye road. The present proposal will take on one part of this objective. The target group are children in the age between 5 and 12 years of single female headed households (SFHH) with complex vulnerability that is often gender based and that limit the capacity to earn money. The number of beneficiaries that is not covered through this project will be covered through an anticipated funding provided by Caritas Germany combined with DKH own funds. This will be a project on its own and it will apply the same approach as the presently proposed SHF project. 

The poorest and most vulnerable IDP households, especially SFHH, may remain in need of external aid for school fees as long as their livelihood situation would not change. Therefore, as an exit strategy, DKH will continue to raise funding for vouchers for education for their children. The BMZ project also targets the same group for gender based IGAs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daryeel Bulsho Guud (DBG)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonie Katastrophen Hilfe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonie Katastrophen Hilfe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juergen Feldmann</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 788888292</telephone>
   <email>juergen.feldmann@diakonie-katastrophenhilfe.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-05">21978.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-05">178021.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-3777">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-05">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonie Katastrophen Hilfe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302480736">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-02">160000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonie Katastrophen Hilfe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303198672">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-26">23325.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diakonie Katastrophen Hilfe</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
