<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/3485/R/Shelter/INGO/2534</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of transitional shelter and NFIs to the most vulnerable IDPs in Dalxiiska, Kismayo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARC proposes to respond to the complex shelter needs in Dalxiiska IDP Camp/Dalxiiska area in Kismayo, designated in 2014 by the Jubaland interim administration for settlement of evictees, returnees, IDPs and other persons in need. The proposed project has strong linkages with health, education, protection and livelihood activities. The proposed project has two major components:
1.	ARC will use an area-based approach targeting the 202HH(1212 Individuals) most vulnerable households within Dalxiska IDP camp with transitional (Charish) shelter. ARC will ensure quality implementation through owner-driven approaches and community engagement focusing on local building culture as well as on building back safer. Capacity building on the local building culture and how to build back safer form essential pillars of the project while addressing the much needed lack of livelihood opportunities at the same, time. 
Settlement components/modules  in Dalxiiska, as well as shelter locations and set up will be developed through a three-stage participatory process,  including formation and training of the planning rehabilitation committee in Dalxiiska consultations with key stakeholders including community leaders and authorities, beneficiaries represented by the planning and rehabilitation committee, and land owners, and final  selection of locations and beneficiaries based on the parameters set through the consultative process above and based on owner-driven initiatives.  
IDPs will live in transitional shelters that meet international standards, that were constructed with full participation of owners from the shelter in the DRR planning stage, and that were built by a combination of the owners and skilled paid labor, including participation of home owners in rehabilitation and maintenance of the communal infrastructure. Transitional shelter designs will be finalized under the auspices of the community planning and rehabilitation committees with participation of 50% of women. The consultative process will determine the size, layout, types of materials and Bills of Quantities of materials and labor of the Carish shelter. Besides the community consultative process, ARC will follow the technical recommendations and best practices of the Shelter Cluster. 

2.	ARC proposes to target 3,000 vulnerable newly arrived IDP Households(18,000 Individuals) with emergency shelter NFI kits.  ARC will conduct a material assistance needs assessment in Dalxiska to identify households with multiple dimensions of vulnerability according to standard UNHCR guidance and assess materials needs. Assessment will include consultation with local authorities and IDP settlement representatives to determine process for equitable distribution and secure locations for distribution events to mitigate risk of a security incident against staff. Strategic planning in consultation with local authorities, security personnel and IDP representatives represents a critical best practice employed by ARC to consider and incorporate safety procedures for staff and beneficiaries, as well as to build community support which ultimately allows for timely access to conflict or natural disaster affected target populations. Registration will be conducted, with beneficiary ID cards or chips (depending on locally available materials) will be distributed at time of registration.

Both components will enable ARC to respond to the most urgent shelter needs in Dalxiska thereby contribution to shelter cluster strategic objective 1 Contribute to the protection of newly displaced  people and those affected by natural hazards. And 2 Improve the living conditions of protracted IDPs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rebekka Bernholt</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 717 163782</telephone>
   <email>rebekkab@arcrelief.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">80553.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">161773.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-2534">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">242326.82</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302183517">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-05">145396.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303537946">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-10">84013.59</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ALIGHT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
