<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/3485/R/Prot/INGO/3948</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening protective environment for displacement affected populations in Daynille and Kaxda through Housing, Land and Property (HLP) interventions.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This program response is a strategic innovation that is framed around three central pillars, or outputs, with inextricable thematic linkages: i) Eviction prevention and response initiatives are identified and implemented to address tenure insecurity issues faced by beneficiaries ii) Beneficiaries receive information and specialized legal assistance and counselling services and are able to competently identify, claim and exercise their Housing, Land and Property rights and iii) Improved local capacity among beneficiary communities to resolve HLP and other disputes through non-adversarial approaches. It is designed to consolidate ongoing humanitarian efforts by expanding critically essential protection services and introducing additional activities that would otherwise render the protective environment more complete but are either absent or noticeably inadequate. Parallel to expanding coverage, upgrading eviction data management system, and establishing functional synergies with other organizations that are involved in eviction monitoring, the project seeks to strengthen the prevention and response facets of NRC&#x2019;s ongoing work on forced eviction, and to diversify the Information, Counselling and Legal Assistance Program&#x2019;s current institutional capacity building approach.

The project will be implemented by NRC&#x2019;s Information, Counselling and Legal Assistance program department that specializes in the application of legal concepts to promote and protect the rights of persons affected by displacement. In the case of this intervention, contextually appropriate legal methods will be employed to provide effective and quality lifesaving protection response designed to address Housing, Land and Property rights violations and to promote peaceful co-existence in Daynille and Kaxda districts. While NRC will provide direct implementation in order to guarantee quality, local capacity development has been mainstreamed into the project&#x2019;s design: Banaadir Regional Administration, Public Property Commission, the district courts of Daynille and Kaxda, and a local organization are the main institutions that are targeted for partnership cooperation. The combination of direct implementation and support to local capacity development will result not only to an incremental effect in terms of project coverage, but also the sustainability of the action.

The overall desired outcome envisaged through this three-prong response will be achieved through the following set of actions: monitoring, documentation and reporting of forced evictions identification and mapping of potential eviction sites for preventive engagements facilitation of lawful eviction processes capacity building on IDP protection and lawful eviction institutional capacity building for local administration and district offices with statutory competence on eviction occupancy agreement and access to land negotiations information services operations of legal clinics for case management capacity building on Housing, Land and Property rights advocacy on HLP rights and forced evictions HLP sub-cluster capacity enhancement and visibility Supplementary technical assistance through post-training follow-ups dispute resolution through socially legitimized community structures capacity building on Collaborative Dispute Resolution and promoting peaceful co-existence through community dialogues. Through these modalities, which are further elaborated in the logical framework, IDPs in Dayniile and Kaxda will be protected against forced evictions or supported to cope with the aftermath thereof and assisted to claim and exercise their HLP rights by overcoming legal obstacles, to pursue and attain durable solutions through the prevention of further secondary displacements, and to co-exist peacefully. As the community based protection systems often discriminate against women due to male dominance, concrete steps will be taken to ensure women have equitable access to project services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdelgadir Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 618454597</telephone>
   <email>abdelgadir.ahmed@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Barnabas Asora</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 790 205708</telephone>
   <email>barnabas.Asora@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">250000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-3948">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">250000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302413662">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-09">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303264278">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-09">49999.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
