<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/2470/R/Nut/INGO/2560</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition project aimed at reducing morbidity and mortality related to malnutrition through a KAP study to provide IYCF information and strengthening of community programs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recently released FSNAU 2015/2016 post Deyr assessment results show deterioration in the nutrition status of Kismayo IDPs, from 12.5 Global acute malnutrition (GAM) in  Gu 2015 to 12.9 in Deyr 2015/16.SAM levels went up to 2.8 from 2.9 in post Deyr 2015.Stunting levels, indicator of chronic malnutrition, are the highest in the country at 43.8, while underweight also showing critical rates of 30.1. The same assessment shows GAM rate of 8.8 and SAM rate of 1.6 among the urban population. Stunting and underweight are equally high among the urban population at 27 and 18.4 respectively. In January 2016 ,SAF-UK initiated a project for treatment of uncomplicated SAM among IDPs in Kismayo in , and the project has by passed the target SAM caseload by 500%. The SC at the district hospital also reported an overwhelming number of complicated SAM cases,with more than 300 children with complicated SAM by end of May (Kismayo district hospital report, May 2016). Currently there are approximately 74893 IDPs in Kismayo. 22140 in Farjano, 20135 in Fanole, 13302 in Cananley and 19316 in  Shaqalaha.Health and nutrition services are also some of the much needed services among the IDPs. The only hospital that can be accessed by the population is the Kismayo district hospital. There are however three Maternal and child health (MCH) facilities in the area, most often experience supply stock out and are not able to consistently offer Out Patient Department (OPD) services (Health cluster 4W, May 2016). Most of these IDPs therefore resort to private clinics and pharmacies for treatment, which often lack competent personnel and appropriate medication (SAF UK January 2016). Stunting among the IDPs is visibly high at  47% stunting rate among the IDPs (FSNAU, 2016). It was also noted that teenage pregnancy and marriage is at a very high rate with very few programs that address adolescent nutrition, early marriage and family planning, as a means to addressing malnutrition among PLWs and children lt 6 months (SAF UK ,2016). This coupled with poor IYCF practices. IYCF information on knowledge, attitudes,practice and perception to new initiatives has not yet been conducted in Kismayo leaving a huge knowledge gap. Partners working among IDPs, struggling to meet  various needs of IDPs, do not have scientific evidence to guide their programing, thus very little impact is felt , especially in improving child health and nutrition indicators. Preventive and promotional IYCF is one of the key programs that have shown evidence of reducing malnutrition considerably, especially in emergency settings where food insecurity is usually high. Scientific information generated from this study, just like other IYCF Knowledge attitude and practice (KAP), will aid humanitarian actors formulate programs and policies that will positively contribute to reduction on malnutrition among children 6-59 months in this population.
SAF UK is currently running a program treating uncomplicated SAM, covering the whole of Kismayo town including IDPs, through 2 fixed sites and 5 mobile Outpatient therapeutic feeding program (OTP sites). The beneficiaries have been generated from our interaction with the community and baseline data collection conducted by the organization in January 2016. Needs assessment was conducted by the organization following critical observation and lessons learned from the Infant Young Child Feeding (IYCF) interventions.This was coupled by key informant interviews of program staff and Community Health Workers (CHWs) working for other partners in the health and nutrition clusters.
The organization proposed to carry out the survey in a period of 45 days using a consultant , 5 groups each with 1 supervisor and 2 enumerators. The survey proposes to use household questionnaire, Key informant interviews and Focused group discussions. It will cover all IDPs in Kismayo town.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdi Hashi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chairman</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254725449441</telephone>
   <email>info@safuk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-18">37146.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-2560">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-18">37146.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302085498">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-25">22287.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303027703">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-29">12162.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
