<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/3485/R/Nut/NGO/2556</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life saving nutrition interventions to boys and girls Under 5 years through integrated nutritional treatment services for SAM and preventive services such as IYCF and micronutrient supplementation to Internal Displaced Person ( IDPs) in Marino, Bulla Fatura, Camp Dhudu, Barawe, Badar IDP settlement in Kismayo district.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To address malnutrition among internally displaced people in Kismayo Internally Displaced Persons (IDP) settlements and ensure  provision of life saving nutrition services for acutely malnourished children (girls and boys), women of child baring age, Somali Aid will implement two stationary Out patient programs and One stabilization center where there will be preventive and promotive services such as infant young child feeding promotion and counseling as well as awareness creation and nutrition messaging within the community. 
Treatment of severely malnourished children under 5 years without medical complication will be done through the out patient therapeutic program targeting to treat at least 761 under fives.  At least 180 children under fives will be treated through the stabilization center for severe acute malnutrition with medical complications. 
Nutrition and health promotion sessions will be conducted at the nutrition sites as well as within the community through community health workers assigned to house individual camps. Nutrition sessions will include sessions on infant and young child feeding, hygiene and health promotion as well as food and nutrients education. 
Mothers of children under five who are visiting the nutrition treatment centers will be targeted for nutrition session and IYCF counselling at the nutrition center while community health workers will continue with nutrition messaging at the community level targeting men and women in the camps.
Generating community demand for improved maternal and child nutrition calls for a more integrated approach and building of capacities within communities to understand the nutrition services and ensure that women and children under five survive and remain healthy during pregnancy and through out the first five years of life amidst the presented climatic, political and geographical complexities. Creating awareness and demand in the communities will equip them with necessary knowledge to effectively participate in sustainable improvement of nutrition status among the Internally displaced  hence the program will work with community health workers and community key leaders to establish well supportive and effective social environment within the community for the nutrition program.  

Technical nutrition team and the community health workers will be trained to build their capacity in management of acute malnutrition through a 5 day training on Integrated management of malnutrition for the technical team and a 3 day training for community health workers which will include training on identification and referral of malnourished children under five and screening skills,  reporting,  peer health education and conducting community meetings and sessions. 
mobilization sessions will be done through the community key influential people and the camp leaders to create awareness of the program and also to ensure program ownership and utilization. at least 5 key leaders per camp shall be targeted for community program conception meetings and awareness.

Somali Aid through the nutrition program is committed to ensure community systems are equally strengthened for community nutrition service delivery.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nasra Muktar</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254722608833</telephone>
   <email>nasra@somali-aid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9668">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Juba</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.05100000 41.59600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">66483.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">133516.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-2556">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-20">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302172025">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">120000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
