<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/3485/R/Ed/INGO/3168</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expanded Access to Inclusive Quality Basic Education for the displacement affected Children in Mudug and Middle Shabelle regions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expanded Access to Inclusive  Quality Basic Education for the displacement affected Children in Mudug and Middle Shabelle regions  is 12 months project designed to contribute to the fulfillment of the rights of displaced children in Mudug region of Puntland and Middle Shabelle regions of Southern Somalia to quality basic education services.  

The objective  of the project is  that children affected by emergencies and crisis including IDPs, returnees, refugees and vulnerable host communities have access to inclusive and quality  basic education in protective learning environment that promote well being of children.

The project will be implemented in Mudug region of Puntland and Middle Shabelle region of South Central Somalia where large numbers of displacement affected communities are living. The project will be implemented in collaboration with the education authorities in these regions to ensure its success, ownership and sustainability.

The main purpose of the project is to retain and support 8,102 students in 39 schools in  Galkacayo and Balcad districts, supported by NRC and Intersos in collaboration with local NGO called Aid Vision, with CHF funding which are now closed or on the verge of closure due to lack of funding. In Balcad district, CHF funded project implemented by INTERSOS in collaboration with local NGO called Aid Vision in 16 schools has ended in June 2015 leading to the closure of the schools and dropout of learners due to lack of support while CHF funded project implemented by NRC in 23 schools in Galkcayo IDP has ended in June 2016. The end of these 2 project has affected the target schools&apos; capacity to operate, pay its teachers to provide education service for the enrolled and new students.  Extremely high rates of poverty in communities across these IDP settlements make it difficult for parents to afford school
fees forcing these students to dropout of schools worsening the already low enrollment rate in the IDP settlements. Apart from the retention of these 8,102 students, the project will enroll new 4,898 out of school-children in the IDP settlements of Galkacayo and Balcad in order to expand access to basic education in these IDP settlement. 
The project will also support 434 teachers, head teachers and CEC members and local education authorities. Special consideration will be given to the enrollment of the girls, children with disabilities and those from minority clans.

In order to achieve its objective and contribute to the cluster objective, the project will conduct community mobilization, enrollment and back to school campaigns in order to retain and bring back the current students to the schools and enrol new students, provide learning materials, recreational materials, sanitary kits for the students. The project will train and provide incentive for the teachers and head teachers. Child to Child clubs in the target schools will be strengthened and Child club facilitators will be trained to support the student clubs. The project will also train CEC members, head teachers and local education authorities on education in emergencies, child rights, Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR), teachers code of conducts etc. The Local education supervisors will be supported to regularly visit the schools, supervise and provide on-job training for teachers  to ensure the quality of education. The project will also put special emphasis on community mobilizations in order to change the IDPs&#x2019; attitude toward education, increase their participation and involvement in the project, school management and send their children to school instead of sending them for work or keeping them at home.

 In Balcad district, NRC will engage with local NGO called Aid Vision to regularly supervise the schools and support the CECs and the local communities in organizing community sensitization campaigns in the IDP settlements. Aid Vision will not be an implementing partners but will carry out regular school supervision.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-02" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Barnabas Asora</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 61 7219993</telephone>
   <email>Barnabas.asora@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdelgadir Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 618454597</telephone>
   <email>abdelgadir.ahmed@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9672">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mudug</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.49100000 48.01000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-02">56434.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-02">342366.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-02">115689.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">0.34</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-3168">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-02">514490.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302287267">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-15">308694.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303377832">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-07">205796.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
