<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-16/3485/R/WASH/NGO/3789</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH Support Project for  IDP Camps in Kaxda District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project targets to provide WASH needs for 10,344 (4655 Women, 1552 Girls, 1034 Boys and 3103 Men) Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) who have sought refuge within Kaxda District along the Afgooye corridor.  The Internal Displacement Profiling in Mogadishu Report-(April 2016) indicated that Kaxda District hosts 76,739 IDPs, which is about 20% of the total enumerated IDPs living in the entire Mogadishu. Other waves of IDPs include those displaced from conflicts and severe drought in 2010-2011 in Lower Shabelle, Middle Shabelle and Bay region. The IDPs residing in Kaxda District are currently residing in periphery areas of Mogadishu defined by lack of basic services infrastructure which helps define their current situation noted for poor welfare indicators in access to clean water, health services, education, nutrition, protection, livelihood and shelter among others.  The situation ahead for the IDPs looks even more bleak when considering the prediction of drought in the latter part of 2016 and continuing in 2017 (the La Nina effect as predicted in SWALIM and FSNAU Updates for June 2016) which will only aggravate an already precarious situation.
This project is anchored on rehabilitation of 1 borehole located in Kaxda (GPS, N02003.804 E045014.954) which will be a source of water for the planned 10,344 IDPs, 3 schools and 2 Health and Nutrition centres also located in Kaxda. The borehole, which had been drilled and managed by CPD, currently has a 10 metres- high elevated water tank with a 40m&#xB3; storage capacity. The project&apos;s initiative will undertake the following activities in providing water, sanitation facilities and hygiene promotion activities to address noted critical gaps existing in the three WASH components-: 1). Rehabilitation of 1 existing borehole by converting the existing gen-set run system into a solar system for sustainability and energy efficiency, 2) Installation of a 1.2 km water supply piping system to connect water to 3 Water Storage Bladders (each with a capacity of 10m&#xB3;) to provide clean water to 1,724 IDP Households (10,344 IDPs) in IDP camps in Kaxda District and connect the water to nearby schools, health and nutrition centers, 3).  Purchasing of 3 water bladders (10 Cum) and installation into the IDP camps 4). Undertake daily chlorination of water at the borehole water storage tank (Holding capacity 40m&#xB3;) and daily testing of the water for residual chlorine before supply, 5). Carry out chlorination of 10 strategic water sources/storage facilities while involving women,  6). Carry out a 3-day Safe Water collection, storage, treatment, and testing training for 30 water committee members, 7). Carry out 3 days training in operation and maintenance, water treatment and testing for 20 borehole owners and operators.
Equally the project will support the construction and rehabilitation of sanitation facilities for the 1,724 IDP HHs within the IDP Camps in Kaxdo District to ensure the IDPs have sufficient gender-friendly latrines with hand-washing facilities. These will be achieved through-: 1) Construction of 87 gender segregated emergency latrines with hand washing facility for the IDP households and urban poor communities 2). Construction of 5 gender segregated twin pit latrines to DDR standards, with hand washing facility to 3 school and 2 MCH in the targeted areas and 3). Distribution of 50 sanitation tools and 50 latrine cleaning kits, all the structures will meet DDR standards as required.
The project shall undertake hygiene promotion activities targeting the 10,344 IDPs which will include-: 1). Undertake 2 Days Hygiene promotion training for 30 hygiene promoters (60% women and 40% men) selected from the IDP camps to disseminate hygiene messages in the IDP Camps and at the health/nutrition centers schools within, 2). Dissemination of health and hygiene promotion messages to 10,344 IDPs and lastly, 3). Purchase and distribute 500 hygiene kits (Bathing and washing soaps, Aqua tabs).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Yarrow Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>252618137983</telephone>
   <email>mohamed.yarrow@cpd-africa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muktar Abdille</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252618900109</telephone>
   <email>muktar.abdille@cpd-africa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9662">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banadir</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.11500000 45.46700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-14">20591.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-14">229254.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-3789">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-14">249845.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302400295">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-29">199876.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303379865">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-08">49969.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Peace and Democracy</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
