<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="RWF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>RW-RGB-101-RGB-NGO-2014-UWEZO_JOA_WASH_2018</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="RW-RGB-101-RGB-NGO-2014" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UWEZO Youth Empowerment</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To improve girls with disabilities access to education and learning through safe water, sanitation and hygiene in Rwanda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Female YwD mentors have increased capacity to advocate for the inclusion of disability inclusive WASH policies and programmes in education. 2. GwD have better understanding and skills to access WASH in schools and good hygiene practice (including menstrual) through peer to peer mentoring. 3. Schools become more accessible and a healthier learning environment for GwD in schools in Rwanda through improved accessibility and promotion of good WASH. 4. Informed and empowered communities have increased capacity to demand improved supply and use of WASH services to support GwD to access education.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girls with disabilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Project supports &#x201C;Inclusive education: WASH as a way to empower girls with disabilities&#x2019; to access education in Rwanda&#x201D;, which aims to contribute to the government&#x2019;s commitment to &#x2018;leave no one behind&#x2019; through the advocacy for disability inclusive WASH policies and programmes for GwD in education.
This multifaceted and youth-led project will identify out of school GwD and train female youth with disability (YwD) mentors to design and implement a twofold peer to peer mentoring programme using child-friendly resources that they develop. This programme will consist of individual mentoring at GwD homes and inclusive group mentoring sessions in schools, made up of both girls with and without disabilities, to promote inclusion and break down stigma. Teacher training, school modifications, the provision of hygiene kits, community awareness, a media campaign and parent group meetings will also be central to achieving project outcomes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AbleChildAfrica</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UWEZO Youth Empowerment</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="RWF" value-date="2018-05-30">48106000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="RWF" value-date="2018-05-30">47519500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="RWF" value-date="2018-05-30">42242275</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
