<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10266A0101-GGG-25040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Call to Action (BCtA) 2018-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Business Call to Action (BCtA) 2018-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Call to Action (BCtA) is a global platform that works to support companies to develop and adapt their business according to the principles of inclusive business (IB) and thereby contribute to poverty reduction and sustainable development. BCtA aims to increase the visibility, credibility, scope and efficiency of companies that work with IB in an effort to contribute to achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Since its launch in 2008, BCtA has gradually refined its strategy to accelerate the progress made in meeting the SDGs. This is done by challenging and encouraging companies to develop business models for inclusive business that engage the people at the base of the economic pyramid (BoP) as consumers, producers, suppliers, distributors and employers. The effort has three overall objectives:

1. Inclusive business is recognised as an efficient solution to achieve the global Sustainable Development Goals by benefitting people in BoP.

2. Improved credibility and integrity for results from inclusive business.

3. Increased efficiency within, and upscaling of inclusive businesses.

The objective of BCtA is to, by promoting inclusive business, ensure that those in BoP become part of the value chain, as suppliers, distributors, customers, employees, shareholders or a combination of these. Models for inclusive business benefit those who are in BoP through, for example, increased access to necessary and affordable goods and services as well as improved productivity, employment and / or business opportunities, which can lead to new or increased income, improved living standards and increased autonomy. The companies that implement models for IB can in turn benefit from increased profits, innovation, market expansion, improved operations and risk reduction, competitive advantages and long-term growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From its genesis in 2008, the Business Call to Action (BCtA) has sought to demonstrate that profitable business activities can achieve development results (e.g. improved livelihood opportunities for poor people and expanded access to affordable goods and services) and inspire other companies to develop their own IB initiatives. BCtA also supports knowledge exchange on inclusive business at the international level through knowledge exchange events, publications and other international activities. BCtA is now helping companies to directly measure the social results of their activities on the ground through a mobile enabled impact data collection programme. 

The programme has promoted and expanded the impact of inclusive business by showcasing and measuring the results of successful company initiatives. These initiatives, while keeping their &#x2018;for-profit&#x2019; nature, contribute to achieving the SDGs through the inclusion of low-income populations in their value chains. 
Sida&apos;s assessment that the continued support to BCtA is relevant and remains a strategic partner both in terms of the implementation of the 2030 Agenda, but also related to the role of inclusive business and the private sector in its achievement.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sidas st&#xF6;d avser fortsatt finansiering av ett globalt n&#xE4;tverk &quot;Business Call to Action&quot; som fokuserar p&#xE5; f&#xF6;retags arbete med inkluderande f&#xF6;retagande (Inclusive Business). Utg&#xE5;ngspunkten &#xE4;r att utmana f&#xF6;retag att genom konkreta initiativ utveckla och anpassa sin aff&#xE4;rsverksamhet enligt principer om inkluderande f&#xF6;retagande, d.v.s f&#xF6;retagande d&#xE4;r f&#xF6;retags k&#xE4;rnverksamheter bidrar till minskad fattigdom och h&#xE5;llbar utveckling. Alla initiativen &#xE4;r f&#xF6;rankrade i f&#xF6;retagens k&#xE4;rnverksamhet.

Interventionslogiken bygger p&#xE5; antaganden att f&#xF6;retag har m&#xF6;jlighet att bidra till utvecklingseffekter men med bibeh&#xE5;llet krav p&#xE5; l&#xF6;nsamhet, d&#xE5; f&#xF6;retags etablering och potential att kunna v&#xE4;xa p&#xE5; de nya marknaderna (s.k. emerging markets) f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;tter bl.a. utbildad arbetskraft och tillg&#xE5;ng till naturresurser. Fokus f&#xF6;r resultatuppf&#xF6;ljning &#xE4;r value added avseende BCtAs olika erbjudanden och st&#xF6;d till de f&#xF6;retag som ing&#xE5;r som medlemmar i detta globala n&#xE4;tverk. 

Sida kommer att skriva avtal med UNDP men genomf&#xF6;randet &#xE4;r delegerat till BCtA Sekretariatet. Sida bed&#xF6;mer att UNDPs &#xF6;vergripande regler och rutiner v&#xE4;l lever upp till Sidas olika krav. Vidare g&#xF6;rs bed&#xF6;mningen att BCtA Sekretariatet har god kapacitet liksom- teknisk kompetens f&#xF6;r att tillse implementering och att uppsatta m&#xE5;l uppn&#xE5;s. Governance struktur och beslutsprocess finns etablerad inom styrgruppen (donor steering committee), d&#xE4;r samtliga givare finns representerade. &#xD6;vergripande riskbed&#xF6;mning anger att f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningarna &#xE4;r goda f&#xF6;r att leverera resultat och samtidigt tillse efterlevnad avseende Sidas krav avseende finansiell styrning och kontroll. 

Sidas st&#xF6;d str&#xE4;cker sig till 2020 och mid-term review och utv&#xE4;rdering kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras, vilken &#xE4;ven kommer att inkludera aspekter relaterat till olika scenarier f&#xF6;r post 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing countries, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="25040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Responsible Business Conduct</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/globec/10266_10266-AvtalmellanSidaochUNDP,third-partycost-sharingagreement,BusinessCalltoAction.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement between Sida and UNDP, third-party cost-sharing agreement, Business Call to Action</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/globec/10266_10266-Amendmentofthethird-partycost-sharingagreementbetweenSidaandUNDP.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment of the third-party cost-sharing agreement between Sida and UNDP for BCtA</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/globec/10266_10266-Beslutominsats,BusinessCalltoAction(BCtA)2018-2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats, Business Call to Action (BCtA) 2018-2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite COVID-19 pandemic affecting the overall business sector &#x2013; including Inclusive Business (IB) &#x2013; negatively, BCtA has managed to be flexible to meet member companies&apos; needs and have done a successful transition to online and digital delivery of activities. BCtA has reached most targets for 2020 (targets were revised during the first six months of 2020 in recognition of the limitations placed on planned activities). BCtA is mainly contributing to GLOBEC&apos;s ToC through production of knowledge materials and contributes to driving a normative change [GLOB/NORM].&#xA0;
Highlighted results
&#x2022;&#xA0;Growing the Membership Base:&#xA0;In 2020, BCtA reached a total of 280 member companies and 294 commitments, adding 31 new member companies and 5 recommitments, which met the target exactly. During the current phase, BCtA has increased its activities and influence in Impact Measurement and Management (IMM) which is now a core element of BCtA&apos;s offering. During the reporting period, a total of 277 companies have received IMM training using BCtA tools (compared against target of 155 companies) and 270 companies have adjusted IMM practices through BCtA tools and guidance (compared against target of 155 companies). Overall, BCtA&#xA0;meets its set targets with regards to engagement and commitments&#xA0;from private sector actors as members of BCtA. [ACT/TARGET]
The impact reported from member companies is at risk of being inconsistent and biased as reporting is done on a voluntary basis, which may cause fluctuation over the years. Moreover, the aggregated results reported by member companies are inflated as they cannot be attributed solely to the companies&apos; support&#xA0;from&#xA0;BCtA. Nonetheless, 90 companies reported their impact achieved in 2019, representing 72% of total number of companies requested to submit reports. Given the uncertainty&#xA0;and ambiguity&#xA0;in these results&apos; attribution to BCtA, these specific results are not that relevant.&#xA0;
&#x2022;&#xA0;Scaling BCtA&#x2019;s Tools and Methodologies through Strategic Partnerships: The Arab Gulf Programme for Development (AGFUND) became a new donor to BCtA. BCtA established and successfully implemented a new revenue model in which services are delivered through fee-for-service and/or development services agreements with private sector actors, CSOs and UNDP country offices and regional bureaux. This is intended to help ensure and sustain BCtA&apos;s offering longterm.&#xA0;
&#x2022;&#xA0;Providing Quality Services to the Inclusive Business Ecosystem: BCtA has produced a guidance note, knowledge management and peer-to-peer information sharing services that have adopted a COVID-19 lens to help member companies and IB sector generally cope with new challenges following the pandemic. [GLOB/NORM] BCtA has continued to provide both in-person and online training programmes to member companies (including 12 webinars and 10 IMM training sessions), many in collaboration with strategic partners (e.g. IFC, Oxfam). [ACT/TARGET]
&#x2022;&#xA0;Advocating for Member Companies and&#xA0;Inclusive Business:&#xA0;67 pieces of BCtA-produced content (articles, case studies and thought-leadership pieces on inclusive business) have been disseminated. BCtA has arranged 40 opportunities for member companies to share their experiences of implementing IB models. [GLOB/NORM]
&#x2022;&#xA0;BCtA in Focus Countries: BCtA has been working in Colombia as a focus country, to carry out capacity building activities, deploy BCtA tools and services, increase quality in private sector engagement in SDGs and strengthen engagement in IB through knowledge products and advocacy. 2020 marked the end of Colombia&apos;s time as focus country. The emphasis has been to integrate responsibility for activities within UNDP Country Office, and BCtA&apos;s activities have been integrated into the Country Office&apos;s private sector strategy.&#xA0;
BCtA&apos;s SDG Corporate Tracker was launched first in Colombia, after collaboratively developed by BCtA and Colombian National Planning Department (NPD), following standards developed by Global Reporting Initiative (GRI). The SDG Corporate Tracker is a multi-stakeholder platform that measures the contribution of the private sector to the SDGs, enabling mapping and analysing the private sector&apos;s influence. BCtA trained seven regional implementing partners to become allies in disseminating the initiative, generate publicity, onboard companies into reporting processes and accompany them in the use of the platform. In total, currently 323 companies are using the SDG Corporate Tracker to report their SDG contributions through individual profiles. 400 companies have been trained on the tool. [GLOB/NORM]
&#x2022;&#xA0;Impact Measurement and Management: In 2020 BCtA added more services delivered through its updated platform Impact Lab 2.0, reaching additional target actors when transitioning to online training and new projects to facilitate provision and scaling up of IMM services. There are a total of 428 active users on the platform, of which 194 have reached Module 2 or beyond. BCtA also established new service lines around IMM and the development of a structured training program on IMM, tailored for different company sizes. [GLOB/NORM]
New services and approaches
&#x2022;&#xA0;Communities of Practice (CoP): BCtA has arranged CoPs in the themes of gender and health-tech. The purpose of the CoPs is to&#xA0;build a peer-to-peer learning network that can co-create solutions and share insights into how to use innovative models, including responding to COVID-19. 13 companies have joined the Gender CoP, bringing together women-led member businesses in its network and 9 companies have joined the health-tech CoP. [ACT/TARGET]
&#x2022;&#xA0;Gender: BCtA has a strong commitment to position gender equality. In 2020, BCtA added six women-led businesses to the network, raising the total to 38.&#xA0;BCtA has&#xA0;introduced a requirement for all new member companies to include details of gendered approaches to inclusion within their applications and report progress against KPIs by reference to six gender-disaggregated frameworks. In 2020, all 31 new commitments included gender-disaggregated targets. [ACT/TARGET]
&#x2022;&#xA0;Due Diligence Facilitation Process: BCtA has been working to address the challenges associated with due diligence and approval procedures for new companies by developing more efficient and standardised structures for conducting risk assessments and pre-approval background checks. It is reported that the UNDP Development Effectiveness Team recognised BCtA as having the best practices on due diligence and risk management, selecting BCtA as a reference on risk assessment for UNDP colleagues around the world. [NAT/INST]</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="10266" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
