<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>BE-GTCF-0453475391-4000000619</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0453975341" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Engaging Youth as Actors of Peace in Central Mali and Northern Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although the signing of the Algiers Agreement in 2015 by prominent warring parties showed a promising opportunity for peace in Mali, two years later, international observers and national stakeholders are still concerned about the lack of progress in the implementation of the Accord and the ongoing deterioration of the security situation. However, unlike the 2012 crisis that unravelled in the North, this time the central Mali serves as the epicenter of instability. Neighboring Burkinabe regions have experienced similar trends since 2015 in a worrying spillover effect, and is increasingly affected by violent extremist attacks targeting police and military stations as well as schools, intimidating the civilian population and threatening teachers and local leaders. For this reason, Search for Common Ground (SFCG) is implementing a 12-month pilot project to strengthen youth engagement in key communities across Central Mali and Northern Burkina Faso and leverage youth participation towards sustainable peace and stability. Overall, this this youth-led initiative will seek to tackle key issues impeding constructive youth engagement in Mali and Burkina Faso by strengthening leadership capacities of young people to engage constructively around the grievances in their communities and enabling young people to be recognized as agents of positive change for peace, security and resilience. The action proposed under this initiative will equip Malian and Burkinabe youth with critical conflict prevention and transformation skills, as well as social communication tools, and allow them to undertake action in their communities. More specifically, selected youths will be trained in leadership, Common Ground approach and conflict transformation to provide them with the skills to set-up community fora and collaborative actions in targeted communities. SFCG&#x2019;s teams will also train youths in participatory theatre and assist them in organizing performances, and develop a youth-led fictional radio soap opera. We estimate that at least 9600 people will be indirectly targeted through the community outreach activities and media programs. Thanks to this project, we will contribute to positively shift local dynamics and increase community resilience in a continuously deteriorating context.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kingdom of the Netherlands&apos; Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Search for Common Ground</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Victor Gauthier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Associate</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+223 78 57 97 54</telephone>
   <email>vgauthier@sfcg.org</email>
   <website>http://www.sfcg.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="12.5">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project takes place in Northern Burkina Faso, in the departments of Djibo and Ouahigouya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="37.5">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project takes place in the Mopti region, and more specifically in the communes of: - Koro - Dougoutene I - Dougoutene II - Bondo - Madougou - Bankass</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="50" vocabulary="99"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-09-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-09-15">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/Quarterly-Report-Jan-2018-SFCG-Minubuza-20180122030139.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">QUARTERLY REPORT: Engaging Youth as Actors of Peace in Central Mali and Northern Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-01-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage increased in knowledge of young leaders on Common Ground Approach and conflict transformation tools and techniques in Koro</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project team was to administer pre and post tests during the Youth trainings in Koro to measure the percentage increased in knoweldge on Common Ground Approach and conflict transformation tools and techniques</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pre and post-tests Tests have been given before and after each training session and compiled by SFCG&#x2019;s DME Officer in Mali. Disaggregated by gender and locality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="BE-GTCF-0453475391" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="21.5" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-12-10"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-23"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="96.77"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target Zones Mapping</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project team was to idenfity 8 target zones within the region of Mopti in Central Mali and of Djibo and Ouahigouya in Northern Burkina Faso</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of target zones identified</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="BE-GTCF-0453475391" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target zone had been identified before the mapping activity</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-11-18"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
     <actual value="8"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth identification in Central Mali</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project team was to identify 160 young leaders within the target zones of intervention for a total of 20 young leaders per target commune</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of young leaders identified</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="BE-GTCF-0453475391" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-09-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-11-24"></period-end>
     <target value="160"></target>
     <actual value="120">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">So far, 120 young leaders have been identified in Central Mali to take part in the project&apos;s activities, including 31 women. The remaining 40 young leaders will be identified in Northern Burkina Faso over the next reporting period.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
