<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peaceful, just and inclusive societies: Promoting national action</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicative project objectives: 1. Map national stakeholders and key implementation institutions; 2. Identify change-agents who can become Goal 16 champions; 3. Contextualise Goal 16 through prioritisation and alignment; 4. Promote innovative and collective approaches; 5. Support monitoring processes; 6. Track implementation of Goal 16 in pilot countries; 7. Support follow-up and review processes; 8. Advise international actors on effective engagement; 9. Examine evidence, learn and promote best practices. Country-specific strategies, objectives and outputs designed after initial assessments and consultations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to support stakeholders in the Horn of Africa region to make use of the 2030 Agenda to contribute to peaceful, just and inclusive societies at the national level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29040" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Silke Nebenfuehr</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>snebenfuehr@saferworld.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GB" percentage="0"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-27">61162</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-27">191557</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-27">195685</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-04-01">448404</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29040" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">149612</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29040" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">154531</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29040" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">22539</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">20483</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">18139</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">33466</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-NetherlandsMFA_F017_29040" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="GB-CHC-1043843-SwedishMFA_E006" type="4"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline assessments in focus countries have been conducted to both inform Saferworld&apos;s project strategies and help track the implementation of Goal 16</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Given the complex political and insecurity context in the focus countries it was important to prepare the ground carefully for any engagement with national stakeholders on the 2030 Agenda, and especially on sensitive topics related to conflict, justice and governance. Therefore during the inception period, initial baseline assessments (based on desk research and consultations) will be conducted in the focus countries to inform Saferworld&apos;s project strategies as well as enable the tracking of the implementation of Goal 16.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of baseline assessments conducted</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on desk-research and consultations in the region, Saferworld conduct these assessments, which can be periodically updated, of relevant aspects of the national context.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No baseline assessments had been conducted previously.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of country-focused project strategies developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">No baseline assessments had been conducted previously.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In addition to two national country-focused strategies, also one regional-focused strategy was developed. These tailored approaches respond to the particular needs, capacities and operating contexts in each of the two countries. This is critical as both countries present significantly different operating environments, and political and security contexts. The strategies also outline the regional component of the project, which will focus on enabling civil society representatives in the Horn of Africa to learn from the experiences of other stakeholders in the region who are mobilising around the PJIS agenda.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National stakeholders and key implementation institutions mapped and relationships with stakeholders established and strenghtened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identify and build relationships with the broad set of stakeholders and national institutions that will be instrumental for helping deliver changed policies and approaches to achieving the PJIS agenda.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Initial mapping of stakeholders conducted and Goal 16 Champions identified</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld will identify the broad set of stakeholders and national institutions which will be instrumental for helping deliver changed policies and approaches to meeting Goal 16, including government officials, civil society, media etc.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld has consulted with national civil society actors, government officials and international partners about how they view the relevance and utility of the global commitments to peaceful societies, and how it can be used to leverage action at the national level. For instance, Saferworld took part in consultations on the implementation of the 2030 Agenda in Uganda. We attended a High-Level Breakfast meeting organised by the Uganda National NGO Forum which focused on Uganda&#x2019;s role in implementing the Nairobi Outcome Document, which seeks to shape how existing and new development actors implement the 2030 Agenda. As a result of this engagement, we identified a number of civil society stakeholders that work on the SDGs in Uganda, and who could contribute to the regional engagement aspect of the project. Saferworld also initiated engagement on the PJIS agenda in Somaliland with both government officials and the Somaliland Non State Actor Forum (SONSAF).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation of Goal 16 tracked in focus countries</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld has developed a methodology to assess whether and how national stakeholders are using the framework and integrating the SDGs, especially Goal 16, into their plans and actions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of 2-year national tracking studies published</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Starting from the baseline assessments conducted in Year 1, progress in the implementation of Goal 16 in each focus country will be tracked and reviewed.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guidance provided to international partners and other relevant bodies on how they can support Goal 16 change agents, context-relevant processes and priorities and innovative approaches.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld was able to participate in and influence policy events and initiatives organised by stakeholders involved in global partnerships for Goal 16. Saferworld has contributed to these initiatives in several ways. We have held numerous bilateral meetings with and produced communications for those coordinating or involved in these new initiatives. In addition, we were invited to play a central role in workshops that aimed to refine and elaborate these initiatives.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policy analyses and briefings on support for Goal 16 disseminated to international partners</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">This includes briefings, policy analyses, inputs into consultations etc.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld published and disseminated a range of outputs during this reporting period. These were designed to raise awareness of the importance of implementing the PJIS agenda, and to offer practical guidance and policy recommendations about how to realise this ambition.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of advocacy interventions at workshops, meetings and other events targeted at international partners for support for Goal 16</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld&#x2019;s efforts to help translate the peace-related elements of the SDGs into action have already yielded positive results. Saferworld&#x2019;s close engagement with key officials within a number of Member States has enabled us to feed into discussions on how to take the implementation process forward. A number of Member States have expressed their appreciation of Saferworld&#x2019;s work on Goal 16 and have requested meetings with Saferworld to hear and discuss our analysis and technical advice. We have been able to feed into member states&#x2019; thinking through various channels such as bilateral meetings, key policy forums, workshops and submissions to official review processes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">More cohesive and cross-sector engagement by stakeholders working for peace, justice and inclusion under the SDG framing</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output aims to bring together a diverse set of stakeholders to develop joint strategies to promote specific peace-related issues using the 2030 Agenda&apos;s holistic vision of peaceful, just and inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national strategy options papers developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased awareness among stakeholders (both non-state actors and government) engaging on peace-related issues regarding the 2030 Agenda and SDG16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will continue to build relationships and confidence with civil society stakeholders, hold consultations and explore partnership options with relevant civil society actors.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of consultations held with stakeholders to strengthen their understanding and capacities regarding the 2030 Agenda and SDG16+</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stakeholders include civil society, government officials and international stakeholders.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="12"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global processes and events related to SDG16+ are informed by the perspectives, experiences and analysis of stakeholders from the Horn of Africa region</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will support change agents, such as civil society activists, politicians, businesspersons and youth leaders who can become Goal 16 champions, to participate in international follow-up and review processes and connect them with allies internationally.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Goal 16 champions supported to participate and feed into global processes and debates related to the 2030 Agenda.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Their participation helped ensure that international policy debates did not ignore practical questions about how to support implementation of the agenda at the national level and they were able to connect with relevant policy actors at the global level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning and best practices collected and promoted</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working with national partners we will develop an evidence-base of what approaches have been effective in particular contexts.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional and global learning events held.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Report and policy brief produced on what works and why and disseminated to national and international stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society representatives contribute to and learn from the experiences of other stakeholders in the Horn of Africa region who are mobilising around the 2030 Agenda and SDG16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants at the regional CSO meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by gender</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of regional meetings of CSOs held</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional meetings will be held to exchange knowledge and experiences regarding engagement with national authorities on Goal 16 issues and how the SDG agenda can be utilised to build more peaceful, just and inclusive societies.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National multi-stakeholder consultations/dialogue regarding the 2030 Agenda&apos;s commitment to peaceful, just and inclusive societies organised by key stakeholders with Saferworld support</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national multi-stakeholder consultations/dialogues held</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output is part of the Annual Plan 2017/18.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Experiences from focus countries in implementation of Goal 16 feed into national, regional and international follow-up and review processes to shape narratives of progress and ensure they reflect reality and a broad spectrum of voices</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national review dialogue meetings held</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output will only be reported on in Year 3.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
