<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Sustainable Pastoralism through Improved Rangeland Management Governance in Samburu County, Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project intends to address the problem of weak natural resource management systems primarily in Samburu and Baringo counties, and overlapping into other counties that constitute the larger northern Kenya region, thereby contributing to sustainable natural resource utilisation, improved livelihoods and reduced conflict over scarce resources. The project will also engage with other frontier counties through their regional platforms, the Frontier Counties Development Council and the Amaya Triangle Initiative.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-GOV-1-G019" ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAFERWORLD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding Department</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">James Wangombe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding, Grant Management and Programme Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>254202733250</telephone>
   <email>jwangombe@saferworld.org.uk</email>
   <website>http://www.saferworld.org.uk</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 21484-00505, Nairobi, Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samburu and Frontier Counties of Northern Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project takes place in Kenya - Samburu and Northern Frontier countries</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-16">450000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-12">477065</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-01">241230</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-03">98400</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q1 Disbursement for the Project under the DFID Direct Grant</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-1-G019" ref="Organisational identifier code: GB-GOV-1" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-14">89078</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 payment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-1-G019" ref="GB-GOV-1" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">222455</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3 Payment</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-1-G019" ref="GB-GOV-1" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-30">53066</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relates to Q1 expenditure (July - Sept 2018)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-31">78615</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relates to Q2 expenditure (Oct - Dec 2018)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-31">155272</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Relates to Q3 expenditure (Jan - March 2019)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-16">927065</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-1-G019" ref="GB-GOV-1" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-17">67556</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-1-G019" ref="GB-GOV-1" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="GB-CHC-1043843-DFIDKenya_DAI_A014_G019" ref="GB-CHC-1043843" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saferworld</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1: Pastoralist communities in Samburu and Baringo counties are empowered to individually and collectively engage county authorities on legislation and practices that support improved rangeland management.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.2: Number of instances of appropriate use of social accountability tools by WCAGs, CAPs and local CSO as part of engagement with county government on CCG</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-06" value="0" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Few avenues exist to bring together all the stakeholders&#x2019;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3-To be reported in the next reporting period. Q4-1. Members of the CAP had an interface meeting with MCAs and county executives on 4 key issues related to rangeland management (water, pasture forest and conflict). 2. In Waso and Wamba East, WCAGs held meetings with their MCAs to seek for implementation of priority rangeland management concerns in Samburu County. 3. In Waso, Loosuk ward, the WCAGs held a meeting with Land Committee where they discussed land issues and boundary. Q5 -One interface meeting held on August 27, 2019 between the County officials from Department of Environment, Energy and Natural resources to discuss the community policy related issues and how they should be included in the policy Q6:-Not done this quarter. This is planned for January - December 2020 during inter agency policy engagement.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.1: Number of Ward Community Action Groups(WCAGs) and County Action Platform(CAP) formed, trained and facilitated to develop the advocacy plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">5 WCAGs and 1 CAP have the capacity to engage the county government representation of women, youths, minority and marginalised groups formed and their capacity built.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2-Instead of the intended 6,5 ward based community action groups (WCAGS) were formed, trained and facilitated to undertake various actions plans, including resource mapping.This is because ChildFund, who are being funded by the same donor,took up one of the target wards, which was a measure aimed at avoiding duplication of effort and enhancing efficiency in the utilization of donor funds. Q3: 3 ward based action groups were formed in Baringo county. Q4-1 count Action Platform(CAP) was formed in Samburu county; with 30 members-23 male and 7 female. Q5 - 3 action plans supported during this reporting period. They include: a meeting held at Samburu Guest house by CAP member on 26th August 2019 to consolidate community issues on rangeland management; and a meeting held on 27th August 2019 between County officials from Department of environment, energy and Natural resources and CAP members on rangeland management policy on among communities that borders themselves in Laikipia, Samburu and Baringo counties. In Baringo county, a meeting was Tangulbei WCAGs to assess and support traditional grazing structure involved in conflict resolution was held. They participants agree to form a grazing committee to regulate the access to grazing areas.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 1.3: Number of collective actions initiated by citizens to engage county government as part of climate change mitigation climate change.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4 -In Wamba East WCAG led to the formation of water resource management committees for Mnanda Pump and Omo Sordo dam on the 20th May 2019 during the planning meeting held on 20th May 2019 at Wamba Catholic Parish. 2. In Baringo, Pokot community formed grazing committees in the Silale, Tangulbei and Churo wards to regulate access to grazing areas. Q5 - 1. In Suguta Marmar ward, the water management committee formed has effectively managed conflict that always arise from access to water resources by livestock herders and those fetching water for domestic use. 2. Formed inter county platform Known as SABALA (Samburu, Baringo and Laikipia) to manage access to water and pasture hence managing cross border conflict 3. Conflict was solved between Rendile herdsmen from Marsabit and Samburu youth in Suguta due to former intruding into Samburu grazing areas. Q6:-Not done this reporting period. Planned for next reporting period</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact: Inclusive and accountable governance of natural resources (such as land, pasture and water) thereby contributing to sustainable peace, security and community resilience in northern Kenya</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="NA" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Indicator 1: Number of significant improvements in implementation of NRM practices, policies and legislation by communities and county governments in Northern Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-06" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Includes bi-annual small scale perception ranking, County rangeland and development policies, ATI and FCDC secretariat and Participatory Assessments.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="1"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3: 0. No improvement observed this reporting period. The policy engagement process with the County officials is still at the nascent stages. This will gain momentum after the completion of the policy review process Q5: 1. At the community level, formation of various management committees on water and grazing areas has made different communities groups access water and grazing reducing conflicts among them. 2. Formation of SABALA as inter county platform by three communities (Samburu, Baringo and Laikipia counties) will enhance cross border relations and further reduce resource-based conflicts. 3. At FCDC level, members of Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum embarked on lobbying for policies and budgets to be allocated to Peace and security directorate to support Peace and Cohesion activities at county levels</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="1"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4:0.The initial engagement with Member of County Assembly (MCAs) and County Executive (CE) started in May 2019. From their participation in county official training in May and follow up conversations, noticeable commitment has been observed from MCAs to support the Rangeland management policy formulation process. Rangeland management and planned grazing policy was identified during technical review and confirmed during training as a priority focus for the county. The process of review and finalisation will be supported by the project in the next quarter.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q5: 3 1. At the community level, formation of various management committees on water and grazing areas has made different communities groups access water and grazing reducing conflicts among them. 2. Formation of SABALA as inter county platform by three communities (Samburu, Baringo and Laikipia counties) will enhance cross border relations and further reduce resource-based conflicts. 3. At FCDC level, members of Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum embarked on lobbying for policies and budgets to be allocated to Peace and security directorate to support Peace and Cohesion activities at county levels</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q6: 5 1. In November 2019, the director of environment and natural resources, shared the draft Rangeland Management and Grazing policy with other heads of departments, National Government officials and other stakeholders at the county level to review the policy. The feedback will be submitted during the interface workshop scheduled for February 2020. 2. During Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum (PCSF) workshop in Lamu town, on 14th and 15th December 2019, the FCDC member counties came up with an action plan for this year 2020 on how they are going to implement the recommendations from the analysis of institutions, legal and policy frameworks report.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 3: FCDC and ATI member counties sets up a Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum (PCSF) that will lead on the development of strategies to address resource based conflict in the Amaya Triangle and the FCDC counties</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 3.1: Number of individual or joint strategic documents developed to coordinate and guide peace processes by FCDC and ATI county governments</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-06" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q5: one strategic document around on the Peace and Cohesion Sector exists. The signing of the MoU by FCDC member counties on 15th August 2019 at Weston Hotel in Nairobi. In Addition, an analysis report for Institutional, legal and policy framework for peacebuilding and social cohesion with FCDC and CPD has been completed and final report has been submitted with key policy recommendations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q6:- 1.From the PCSF workshop held in Lamu, an action plan was developed drawn from the recommendations contained in the analysis report for institutional, legal and policy framework for peacebuilding in the FCDC counties 2. Using the findings from the analysis report, DLCI developed a peace and cohesion policy brief titled &#x201C;Every life has equal value: renewing the institutional, policy and legal framework for Peacebuilding and social cohesion in Kenya&#x201D;. It contains issues such as natural resource management, cross-border dynamics, livestock theft, anti-terrorism, and the control of drugs and small arms. The recommendations in this policy brief are aimed at transforming the framework within which all these highlighted issues can be addressed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 3.2: Number of FCDC and ATI county governments signed up to the peace and cohesion sector forum, with clear terms of reference</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-02-03" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4-12 counties(10 FCDC+2 non FCDC (Laikipia and Baringo ) .The 12 counties initiated processes towards the formation of Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum. Q5: The county governments include 10 members of FCDC, which include Lamu, Tana River, Garissa, Wajir, Mandera, Marsabit, Isiolo, Turkana, Samburu and West Pokot and additional 2 counties (Laikipia and Baringo Counties) which have applied to be members and are now part of Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q5:-The county governments include 10 members of FCDC, which include Lamu, Tana River, Garissa, Wajir, Mandera, Marsabit, Isiolo, Turkana, Samburu and West Pokot and additional 2 counties (Laikipia and Baringo Counties) which have applied to be members and are now part of Peace and Cohesion Sector Forum.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 4: Natural resource management stakeholders systematically access and uptake knowledge generated through learning and evidence to inform their collective advocacy influence on relevant policies and legislation at county and national levels.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ouput Indicator 4.1: Number of stakeholders committed to the learning agenda</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="32">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3: 25 stakeholders committed to the learning agenda. Q4: 7 stakeholders committed to the learning agenda. Q5: The representatives of the 32 stakeholders identified last quarter (April - June 2019) during Technical review of policies in Samburu county have been mobilised to participate in the earning event schedule for October 30 and 31, 2019. Q6:-Completed in Quarter 5. These stakeholders participated in the Learning event held on 29th to 31st October 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 4.2: No. of case studies documented based on implementation of recommendations generated during learning events/forums</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4- A case study has been developed on WCAGs and CAP engagements in Samburu county. The case study describes the formation, ward level engagement and their performance by end of this quarter. This case will be further developed in the next quarter. Q5 - This case study will be developed in the next quarter (October - December 2019). The case study will be around the support and strengthening of CPD secretariat and engagement among the member counties. Q6:-CPD engagement has faced a lot of challenges. A lot of effort is required to have CPD in its intended course. This case study will be developed in the next quarter.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 2: Samburu County government and the ATI Secretariat develop legislation / policies and frameworks on natural resources management that are in line with climate change governance and responsive to needs of the pastoralists communities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.2: Number of policy briefs or legislative recommendations identifying citizen priorities in climate change governance submitted to county governments by WCAGs, CAPS or CSOs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-06" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q3: 1 expert paper with recommendations has already been produced from the policy review process. Q4-1.Policy recommendations from Technical policy review of Samburu county, 2. Recommendation from the county officials training report and; 3. Recommendations from Cooperation for Peace and Development (CPD) engagement . Q5- Facilitated by policy experts/ consultants, a policy issues document detailing community policy concerns and policy gaps in the zero draft rangeland management and planned grazing policy was done. Policy issues and gaps informed the revision of the zero draft to initial draft of the rangeland management and planned grazing policy Q6:-During November - December 2019, there was no policy related document produced by the WCAGs/CAP. This is planned for next quarter when communities through WCAGs will engage other county government and other agencies as the Draft policy is being reviewed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.3: Number of draft inclusive rangeland management policies, plans, legislation, regulations developed or revised by county governments.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-06" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q5: A draft rangelands management and planned grazing policy was developed by the Samburu county department of environment. The policy includes priority areas/issues identified by communities through the WCAGs and the CAP. Q6:-A draft Rangeland management and planned grazing policy has been produced awaiting the inter agency review.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output Indicator 2.1: Number of county government officials trained on policy development in rangeland management and pastoral resource management.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NA" indicator-uri="https://www.saferworld.org.uk/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">30 county officials from Samuru county trained</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="36">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4-36 participants (21M: 14F) County officials that included 26 MCAs, 9 County Assembly officials (a Speaker, deputy speaker, 4 staff from Clerk office, Legal counsel, Hansard and Sergeant. Only 1 Chief officer of special programme participated . Q5- The project will continue to engage with the 36 trained in the last quarter for further policy development engagement in the next quarter. Q6:-This was completed in Quarter 4</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome: County governments in northern Kenya individually and collectively formulate and/or adopt responsive and coherent policies, legislation and practices on natural resource management that address communities&#x2019; priorities, enhances peace and resilience to climate change.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.2: Level of institutional knowledge of climate change issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2019-02-06" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Includes media/press statements, Rangeland management policy/framework</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4-Both Samburu and Baringo counties have embarked on policy formulation (Rangeland management and planned grazing policy - Samburu county and Climate change policy - Baringo County). It has been observed that county projects on rangeland have been recorded in the annual county progress reports and County officials (MCA and County Executives) have been trained on Climate change with support from project and other organisations such Food and Agriculture Organisation and Child Fund. Q5: For this quarter, the score of 2 relate to Samburu county development of rangeland management policy. It is now at draft stage after consultations with communities Q6:The score remains at 2 during this reporting period. The community policy issues on rangeland management were incorporated in the draft policy, section 2.4 and 2.5 awaiting interagency review at the county to be done next quarter before being submitted to County government for deliberations, review and ratification</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.3: Number of instances of state responsiveness to citizen engagement or institutional strengthening (in climate change governance, service delivery or Oversight)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Includes media/press statements, Rangeland management policy/framework</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-30"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q5: Willingness of the county officials to have a meeting with CAP members to receive the community issues related to rangeland management policy is an indicator of Samburu county government being responsive to community concerns that they face as pastoralist communities. The issues were incorporated into policy Q6:As stated in indicator 1.1., community policy issues related to rangeland management have been captured in section 2.4 and 2.5. The fact that the county officials took considerations of these issues into the policy shows the county government responsiveness in citizen engagement.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome Indicator 1.1 : Level of integration of climate change in planning</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-17"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Includes County Intergrated Development Plans, Annual Development plans, County Budget and Review and outlook paper, County Fiscal paper, Estimates of revenue and expenditure, Annual contingency Coordination Framework</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q4-Some climate change related initiatives were included in Samburu County Fiscal Strategy Paper (CFSP), February 2019. They include improving irrigation schemes, planting of drought resistant crops and management of water resources such as water catchment areas. From the Samburu Website -http://www.samburu.go.ke, the Ministry of Water, Environment, Natural Resources &amp; Energy has stated that in the year 2019/2020 its promoting sustainable land management approaches, undertaking natural resource inventory and conduct establishment, training and strengthening of natural resource management institutions such as Water Resource User Associations (WRUAs), Sand harvesting groups, Charcoal Producers Associations (CPA&#x2019;s), and Community Forest Associations (CFA&#x2019;s) in the county. A zero draft of climate change policy and County Environment action plans (CEAPS). Q5: Currently the Department of Environment, Energy and Natural resources is in the process of developing a policy on rangeland management. In the Policy, 2.6 has been dedicated to climate change, effects and coping strategies in Samburu county. Q6:The Samburu Rangeland Management and grazing draft policy has section 2.6 that addresses matters on climate change. It has information on change, effects and coping strategies in Samburu county.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
