<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-20/DDA-3379/SA2/NFI/ES/INGO/17465</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter Repair and ESNFI kits assistance to Conflict and Flood Affected IDPs  and Returnees in Fafan and Nogob Zones of Somali Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia has not yet fully recovered from the consecutive drought that resulted in massive livestock loss in pastoral regions and crop failure in the ago-pastoral areas. The past three years have seen major changes in Ethiopia&#x2019;s governance landscape. At the peak of the displacement crisis between January and April 2019, conflict and climate shocks left some 3.2 million people displaced. Internally displaced persons (IDPs) have been experiencing deplorable conditions and limited access to basic services, lack of opportunities to rebuild their livelihoods, protection risks, and wider security concerns. According to HNO 2020, 8.4 million people nationwide are projected to have humanitarian needs in 2020, and in the Somali region, 2.4 million or 39% of the population are in need of humanitarian assistance. Based on the recent  Displacement Tracking Matrix (DTM) round 22, there are 43,785 HHs of (262,710 individuals) IDPs in 159 sites, mainly in the Somali region of Liben, Afder, and Dawa Zones. The crisis has placed a significant strain on existing Shelter infrastructure and practices, particularly in remote areas where returned IDPs and returnees have integrated into communities with already limited access to basic services. The safety and well-being of returned IDPs depend on effective and timely humanitarian intervention while meeting urgent needs. ZOA and OWDA (Organization Welfare and Development in Action) designed this project in response to the tremendous Shelter Repair and reconstruction and Emergency Shelter and Non-food Item (ES/NFI) response needs of IDPs and returned IDP communities of Garbo and Tuliguled district of Nogob and Fafan zone respectively. The proposed areas are the most affected areas with the limited services available for IDPs and returnees. Hence, the proposed intervention will support 920 HHs (5060 Individuals ) returned IDPs (1,113 Girls, 911 Boys, 1,670 Women, and 1,366 Men) households with life-saving humanitarian assistance through the provision of cluster approved in-kind ESNFI kits (V1). 40% ES/NFI kits and ERK will be procured and transported by ZOA and OWDA that will be directly distributed during implementation. Partial ESNFI (V1) Kits and labor cost for the ERK will be distributed in cash to the beneficiaries using AWASH Bank and or Somali Micro Finance. A total of 550 IDP households living in Garbo will receive 550 ESNFI (V1) kits, while 370 IDP households living in Tuliguled will receive ERK. ZOA will select 10% of the total beneficiaries from host communities living around the IDP sites. Cash-based assistance will be considered in areas where the market is functional and offers items needed by IDPs and where IDPs have a preference for cash. The ES/NFI intervention will be a combination of cash 40% and 60% in-kind while implementing activities including facilitation of Protection mainstreaming, market assessment, and post-distribution monitoring of ESNFI kits and post-construction monitoring. Therefore, the project will be implemented through a coordinated response of ZOA and OWDA considering geographic coverage, cost-effectiveness, and past partnership history with ESNFI Cluster members. Using the vast experience of ZOA on shelter construction, ZOA will be provided with job training and other training materials including IEC materials to OWDA. ZOA will regularly monitor the project delivery to ensure the project is delivered in a quality manner and extend support in the procurement of ERK items.  In addition to this ZOA will support the local partner to conduct post-distribution monitoring in a quality manner using ZOA MampE staff.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Welfare and Development in Action</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chris MacLullich</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 911-207 908</telephone>
   <email>c.maclullich@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mahlet Tekalegne</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager of Programme Quality</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251 920 80 82 08</telephone>
   <email>m.tekalegne@zoa.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET05">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.92946999 43.32903576</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-08">26098.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-08">211401.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-17465">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-08">237500.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304828156">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-10">237500.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400365447">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-13">9339</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZOA Refugee Care</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
