<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11113A0201-MOZ-15230</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Women Participation in Peace Process</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fr&#xE4;mjande av kvinnligt deltagande i fredsprocesser</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Participation of Women in Peace Processes and in Social Cohesion in Mozambique seeks to widen and increase the space, opportunities and the capacities of women in Mozambique to engage in the current dialogue processes, in political processes, in trust building and in social cohesion.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att bredda utrymmet, m&#xF6;jligheterna och kapaciteten hos kvinnor i Mo&#xE7;ambique att engagera sig i den p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende fredsprocessen och i det &#xF6;vergripande politiska beslutsfattandet, samt f&#xF6;rtroendeskapande &#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder som fr&#xE4;mjar social sammanh&#xE5;llning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participation in international peacekeeping operations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">13808.3402375035</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">9556.0618613643</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-08">13808.340237</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">2435.1284175642</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">3739.2916321458</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">3381.6625241646</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The below provides an overview of both results and activities, given the nature of the intervention being quite focused on consultations and dialogue and where results and outputs to a large extent go hand in hand.

Activities and results

During the baseline study, consultations were held with women  but also men and youth  from across the country with different backgrounds (socio-economic) and beliefs (religious, political), reinforcing the project aim of building social cohesion through dialogue and peaceful handling of conflicts, whilst at the same time developing an understanding of underlying barriers to women&apos;s participation and key messages. Of interest is the findings from the round table discussions held with over 660 individuals (whereof which 547 were women) was that the majority indicated that gender issues, such as low schooling, gender-based violence and socio-cultural barriers were the main barriers to women&apos;s participation and influence in peace and reconciliation in Mozambique. Furthermore, the study concluded that weak engagement of women in initiatives to build peace and existence of opportunities and local experiences that can be capitalized, were two other main aspects affecting women&apos;s participation in peace and reconciliation processes.

However, despite many hindrances (not least cultural, financial and socio-economic), the study revealed that women at community level either already were involved, or had the potential to become, involved in peace building and conflict resolution processes (mainly as equal members of a community or district committees, but also as e.g., mediators, advisors and trainers).

Apart from having uncovered obstacles, gaps and opportunities for women&apos;s participation, the baseline study also served to mobilise women and raise their awareness of their potential and influence in peace processes, and one quite concrete result was that some women groups took it from the baseline discussion to promote community dialogues and reflection workshops based on the gap in terms of space for women&apos;s participation.

For the project team, the baseline study also served to reveal the gap in terms of space for women&apos;s participation, as well as a lack of triggers for change and social transformation.

Apart from various regional and local dialogues covering 53 districts and including more than 2100 women and men (in their turn representing the voices of 125 000 women from different walks of life), outreach activities were performed, such as airing radio debates on peace and reconciliation, targeting 84 000 of Radio Mozambique&apos;s listeners.

Furthermore, a national conference was held in Beria 21-23 August 2018, with representation from the Vice-Minister of State Administration and Civil Service, a high-level mission from FBA represented by the Swedish Women Mediation Network Ambassador Lena Sundh, the Ambassador of Sweden in Mozambique Marie Anderson de Frutos, two representatives from the Colombian women&apos;s movement, and Mrs. Gra&#xE7;a Machel, founder and chair of FDC. The purpose was partly to share experiences from the regional consultations, but also to develop a women&apos;s agenda for peace and reconciliation and launch the movement and its roadmap towards its affirmation and consolidation. The adopted agenda which included nine priorities connected to women&apos;s participation and inclusion in peace processes, the advocacy for end of all types of violence and sexual harassment against women and children, and promotion of women&apos;s savings and credit groups for greater financial inclusion and economic empowerment, to mention a few.

Following the national conference, a number of initiatives were held and led by the members of the movement, for instance were dialogues held at community and church levels, as well as engagement with media and meetings with other women&apos;s movements involved in peace-building and national reconciliation.

Another great achievement of the movement was a meeting with the President of Mozambique, who had invited the movement to hand over its Final Declaration and Agenda for Peace and Reconciliation with Mozambique. During the meeting, the president recommended the expansion of the movement (albeit warned to keep it focused so that it would contribute to women&apos;s empowerment).

The final report submitted by FDC concludes that the project brought about significant changes at community and institutional levels, especially considering its short time frame and in the complex context in which it was implemented. Some of the successes are attributed the projects low-profile approach, using the strengths of each involved partner (FDC harnessing its community-rooted experience and reputation amongst government institutions, IMD using its influences on political parties and ACCORD through bringing in its expertise in facilitating conflict resolution and peacebuilding processes). The report lists a number of positive changes attributed the project, for instance the emergence of community and religious nuclei for peace and reconciliation, support given women&apos;s movements by district administrators and provincial governments through providing space for community debates, increasing interest by national and provincial media, and joint collaboration among women representing different parties.

It is also Sida&apos;s opinion that the objectives set for the intervention were met, and an assessment for continued support to the consortium has been underway during some time. A new agreement is likely to be signed in Q2 2022 for a three-year period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11113" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060702" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="4150000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>Mozambique 2015-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Mocambique 2015-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
