<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12655A0101-GEO-16062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS)  Georgien</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) Georgia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) is one of the largest international household survey programmes worldwide. It is designed to collect estimates of key indicators that are used to assess the situation on households and especially of children and women. 

Government of Georgia decided to participate in the sixth round of MICS with support of UNICEF to collect comprehensive, nationally and regionally representative data for key indicators of the situation of households, especially children and women, and thus to strengthen its capacities for evidence-based strategic policymaking towards achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG).

The MICS field survey will be conducted during  September - December, 2018, followed by a period of data analysis up until the release of the survey results in March 2019. After the release of the data, the project is planning to conduct a series of trainings and workshops for journalists during 2019, covering  dataintepretation and public awareness of the survey results.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) &#xE4;r en av v&#xE4;rldens st&#xF6;rsta hush&#xE5;llsunders&#xF6;kningar. Den &#xE4;r utformad f&#xF6;r att samla uppskattningar av nyckelindikatorer som beh&#xF6;vs f&#xF6;r att bed&#xF6;ma hush&#xE5;llens situation och s&#xE4;rskilt f&#xF6;r barn och kvinnor. 

Den georgiska regeringen har beslutat att delta i den sj&#xE4;tte omg&#xE5;ngen av MICS med st&#xF6;d av UNICEF f&#xF6;r att samla omfattande, nationellt och regionalt representativa data f&#xF6;r nyckelindikatorer f&#xF6;r hush&#xE5;llens situation, med s&#xE4;rskilt fokus p&#xE5; barn och kvinnor, och p&#xE5; s&#xE5; vis st&#xE4;rka sin kapacitet att genomf&#xF6;ra evidensbaserad strategisk policyutveckling f&#xF6;r att uppn&#xE5; de Globala m&#xE5;len (SDGs).

MICS hush&#xE5;llsunders&#xF6;kninge kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras under september - december 2018, f&#xF6;ljt av en period f&#xF6;r dataanalysering fram till det att resultaten realiseras i mars 2019. Projektet planerar &#xE4;ven att genomf&#xF6;ra en rad utbildningar och workkshops f&#xF6;r journalister under 2019, som kommer att inkludera datainterpretering och medvetandesarbete kring resultaten av MICS.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the MICS 6 will be effectively to address existing data gaps and provide the Government of Georgia and its development partners with accurate, nationally and regionally representative estimates of indicators on the situation of households, especially children and women, in Georgia.
Consequently, the Government of Georgia will be better equipped for evidence-based strategic policymaking towards achieving the SDGs, while the development partners will be better prepared to support this process through appropriate technical assistance.
The MICS 6 will also result in increased capacities of GeoStat to carry out big household surveys and using the new Computer-Assisted Personal Interviewing (CAPI) technology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF/United Nations Children&apos;s Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41122" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Childrens&apos; Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16062" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Statistical capacity building</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">460278.0079167817</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">460278.0079167817</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-01">460278.007916</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">460278.0079167817</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/georgia/unicef-mics-agreement-signed.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF MICS Signed Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/georgia/beslut-om-insats-mics-georgien.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beslut om insats MICS Georgien</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/georgia/12655_DecisiononContributionMICS.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution MICS</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For MICS 6 results to be achieved&#xA0;several important preparatory steps were required. Namely - the establishment of a MICS team, consisting of dedicated staff from all relevant departments of Geostat, as well as relevant staff members and consultants of UNICEF Georgia; procurement of field equipment and materials; design of the survey; customization and translation of all questionnaires; and design of the sampling framework. After those preparatory steps successfully were implemented the field work was conducted and received results processed in the end of 2019.&#xA0; The key findings of the MICS6 offer a variety of significant data on households and children (child functioning and discipline, early childhood development (ECD) and education, health and nutrition etc.), as well as for some SDG baseline indicators. Some of the findings are below: &#x2022; 47 per cent of birth were delivered by Caesarean-section and almost 80 per cent of cases were planned (elective) - decided before onset of labour pains. &#x2022; Only 30 per cent of newborns had skin to skin contact immediately following birth. &#x2022; 80 per cent of children between 0-5 months are not exclusively breastfed. For 64 per cent of infants between 0-5 months, breast milk is not their predominant source of nourishment. &#x2022; 8 per cent of children between 2-17 years have functional difficulties in at least one domain including seeing, hearing, walking, fine motor, communication, learning, playing, and/or controlling behaviour. &#x2022; 22 per cent of children between 3-5 years do not participate in preschool education. Children in rural areas (68 per cent) are less likely to benefit from preschool education than children in urban areas (84 per cent). Children from poor families (39 per cent) are considerably more often out of preschool education than children from rich families (13 per cent). There are disparities among ethnic minorities as well: only 29 per cent of Azeri children are engaged in preschool education compared to 60 per cent Armenian and 80 per cent Georgian. &#x2022; While school attendance rate in primary and lower secondary school is almost universal (98 per cent and 96 per cent), 7 per cent from the poorest do not complete lower secondary school. &#x2022; The upper secondary school completion rates are strongly related to the wealth of the household: 56 per cent of poor children and 96 per cent of rich children complete upper secondary school. &#x2022; Significant differences are observed by ethnicity for out of school children: 10 per cent of Georgian children are out of school compared to 36 per cent of Azeri children and 16 per cent Armenian children. &#x2022; 69 per cent of children experienced violent upbringing and 31 per cent experienced physical punishment. Among the latter group 5 per cent were subject to severe punishment. Children with functional difficulties were more likely to be subject to violent upbringing methods. &#x2022; The share of children aged 6-23 months who receive a minimum acceptable diet (dietary diversity + meal frequency) is 27 per cent; 6 per cent of children under five are overweight and a similar share are stunted. &#x2022; 41 per cent of 2-7 year-old children in Georgia had elevated blood lead levels. While 5 micrograms per decilitre (&#xB5;g/dl) of whole venous blood is the reference level at or above which WHO and the US Centre for Disease Control recommend public health action to be initiated, the survey results showed that in Georgia 41 per cent of all children between 2-7 years have a lead prevalence in blood of = 5 &#xB5;g/dl with 25 per cent of all children having a10lead prevalence in blood between 5 - 10 &#xB5;g/dl, while 16 per cent of all children have a lead prevalence in blood of even = 10 &#xB5;g/dl. &#x2022; 6 per cent of households do not have adequate means to wash their hands because of unavailability of water, soap or detergent. &#x2022; The share of population using an E. coli contaminated source water is 25 per cent (6 per cent in urban and 53 per cent in rural area) while share of population with E. coli contamination in a glass of drinking water is 31 per cent (11 per cent in urban and 60 per cent in rural areas). All those and other findings from MICS6 will help the Georgian Government to elaborate evidence based policies in different fields to address issues highlighted by the MICS6 survey.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12655" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
