<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13385A0104-GEO-15111</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the Financial Management and Control in Georgia</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Strengthening the Financial Management and Control in Georgia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet &quot;Strengthening the Financial Management and Control (FMC)&quot; &#xE4;r ett myndighetssamarbete mellan Central Harmonisation Unit (CHU) inom det georgiska finansministeriet och Ekonomistyrningsverket, ESV.
Projektets m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka kunskap och kapacitet att till&#xE4;mpa ett moderniserat system f&#xF6;r finansiell styrning och kontroll  och d&#xE4;rigenom &#xF6;ka effektiviteten inom den georgiska statsf&#xF6;rvaltningen

Projektet kommer under 26 m&#xE5;nader att fr&#xE4;mja utveckling av a) CHU:s organisatoriska kapacitet, samt inom b) fyra centrala ministerier som har b&#xF6;rjat implementera ett nytt system f&#xF6;r finansiell styrning och kontroll. Insatsen f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rker och kompletterar den p&#xE5;g&#xE5;ende budgetreformen som omfattar etablering av  programbudgetering i Georgien. FMC-insatsen verkar f&#xF6;r etableringen av effektiva managementsystem, vilket utg&#xF6;r en v&#xE4;sentlig byggsten i riktningen mot  ett v&#xE4;l fungerande system f&#xF6;r programbudgetering.

Samarbetet kring intern styrning och kontroll  verkar f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rvaltningen av offentliga medel fr&#xE4;mjar regeringens m&#xE5;l samt sker i enlighet med lag och regelverk. Detta inneb&#xE4;r till exempel att en statstj&#xE4;nsteman som beslutar om nyttjande av  statliga medel ska b&#xE5;de f&#xF6;lja f&#xF6;reskrifterna f&#xF6;r intern kontroll och anv&#xE4;nda medlen &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenligt.

Ett huvudproblem som projektet adresserar g&#xE4;ller brister i f&#xF6;rvaltningssystemet g&#xE4;llande ledningsansvar och ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande. Det georgiska systemet har en kvarvarande stark centralisering med bristande f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande och ansvarstagande hos ledare p&#xE5; olika niv&#xE5;er utvecklat. Projektet riktar sig mot f&#xF6;ljande svagheter: brist p&#xE5; delegering; otillr&#xE4;cklig m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning; svag riskhantering; otydlig informations- och rapporteringssystem samt en otydlig verksamhetsroll  f&#xF6;r finans- och ekonomienheter.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution &quot;Strengthening the Financial Management and Control (FMC) in Georgia&quot;  is an agency-to-agency cooperation between the Central Harmonisation Unit (CHU)  at the Ministry of Finance (MoF) in Georgia and the Swedish National Financial Management Authority (ESV).

The objective of the project is to increase the knowledge and strengthen the ability to apply managerial control and thus increase effectiveness and efficiency of public entities in Georgia.

The project will work over 26 months to support a) CHU&apos;s institutional capacity development and b) four central ministries that have started to implement Financial Management and Control (FMC). FMC is complementary to the ongoing establishment of programme budgeting in Georgia. FMC is concerned with the establishment of effective management systems required to achieve the potential of programme budgeting. 

The aim of the FMC reform in Georgia is to provide assurances that spending of public funds meet the objectives of the Government and are managed in accordance with laws and regulations. This means e.g. that civil servants responsible for the use of public funds both follow the prescribed standards of internal control and are using those funds as efficiently and effectively as possible.

The main problem this project addresses is the lack of managerial accountability. At present the system of accountability and responsibility by managers at different levels is not well developed in Georgia. This project addresses the following causes; lack of delegation; insufficient objective setting; weak risk management; inexplicit information and reporting systems and the vague role of the financial/economic department.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the current contribution is as follows:

Development of managerial control arrangements in Pilots, to explore and improve within the Pilot organisations the managerial accountability and other changes, including information flows, required to ensure that FMC is effectively implemented and that FMC can deliver the benefits expected. Reaching the objective will result strengthening the ability of Georgian authorities to apply managerial control and thus increase effectiveness and efficiency of public entities in Georgia.

Within the main objective, the sub-objectives, related to activities, are as follows:

- Each Pilot ministry should possess an adapted implementation plan for the activities;

- Management structures should be designed to deliver the policy objectives efficiently and effectively to specified standards and within defined timescales;

- All managerial arrangements should include the establishment of appropriate accountability requirements for financial and operational performance;

- Managers should take responsibility for the specification of the internal control systems and for the effectiveness of those systems by introducing risk management;

- The manager should define the specific information (financial and performance) needed to ensure that objectives are being achieved in accordance with the principles of economy, efficiency and effectiveness and in accordance with plans and programmes;

- The managers at different levels should be aware of the budgetary requirements and participate in the budget process;

- The Head of finance should be the expert on FMC and the person within the ministry to turn to when advice is required;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESV/Ekonomistyrningsverket</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESV/Ekonomistyrningsverket</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public finance management (PFM)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">58296.1209761103</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">58296.1209761103</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-01">54290.584926</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-28">14221.2874115356</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/georgia/13385_ESVPreparationGrantAgreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The submitted report covers period from June 1st 2020 to August 31st 2021. The fist two months the project worked in remote format due to worsened the Covid 19 pandemic situation in Georgia. Long Term Adviser (LTA) came to Georgia in September and since then he has been working in Tbilisi.

The project worked and prepared tailor made support to pilot ministries meaning that the project directly approached working groups in each pilot ministries and elaborated and planned different activities with them. Central Harmonisation Unit (CHU) the main counterpart to the ESV and beneficiary of the project introduced benchmarking for pilots.

With the project support was prepared the document &quot;The Rules and Procedures on the Development of Managerial Control&quot; that was shared with stakeholders for comments and feedback and afterwards was sent to the Government for approval.

Another important document towards with the project contributed was Public Internal Financial Control Strategy and Action Plan covering years 2021-2024. The document was endorsed by the Government. 

ESV and CHU elaborated a risk manual that gives risk identification cases, who is doing what in the risk process, etc. The manual was introduced to the pilot ministries through workshops and trainings. As a results the risk management in the pilot ministries have been improved. 

Within the project a comprehensive description of the budget processes has been written.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13385" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150105" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="6400000000" strategy-end-date="2027-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with the Eastern Europe 2021-2027</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa 2021-2027</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
