<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13557A0102-GEO-31120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pre-core support to Georgian Farmers&apos; Association</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Pre-core support to Georgian Farmers&apos; Association</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GFA was founded in 2012 as a non-commercial, non-for-profit legal entity. Currently, the organization unites about 4,000 farmers across Georgia. GFA acts as a facilitator between the government and farmers and its mission is to develop the agricultural sector in Georgia and improve the conditions of Georgian farmers through bringing the farmers together and promoting their voice and visibility.
Throuch the pre-core support, the GFA is expected to have in place the assessment of the organization and be able to follow up and assess how they have evolved since the last organizational assessment conducted in 2016, which served effective for organizational and structural analysis and formation of its mandate. The assessment is a key component in development of the new 5 year strategic plan for 2020-2024, as the previous strategy expired in 2018. Without a strategic document the GFA will face difficulties of continued efficient operations and responding to the needs of its members. Moreover, the Embassy has directly procured a review of internal management and control, which was conducted during July 2019 by KPGM Georgia LLC. The pre-core support will also be aimed to support GFA in compliance and follow up with the recommendations of the abovementioned review.
Overall, at the end of the pre core support, the organization is expected to have:
1. Renewed organizational assessment document, which will serve as a basis for the new strategy development;2. New strategy developed;3. Improved internal and management systems, including financial systems.&#xA0;
The intervention is expected to have positive impact on the GFA staff and its 4 000 members.&#xA0;The pre-core is expected to result in a core support in 2020, aimed at supporting the GFA with the implementation of the new strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Georgian Farmers&apos; Association har ans&#xF6;kt om inledande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n ambassaden med en budget p&#xE5; 1 633 000 SEK f&#xF6;r f&#xF6;ljande verksamhet:

1) Genomf&#xF6;ra en organisations- och kapacitets bed&#xF6;mning;
2) Utveckla en ny strategi f&#xF6;r 2020-2024;
3) F&#xF6;lja upp och uppfylla rekommendationerna fr&#xE5;n granskningen av intern styrning och kontroll, genomf&#xF6;rt av KPMG Georgia LLC i juli 2019.

Insatsen syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra GFA:s organisatoriska kapacitet, st&#xE4;rka systemen f&#xF6;r intern styrning och kontroll och leda till en h&#xE5;llbar strategisk utveckling av organisationen.

Den totala budgeten av det inledande k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;det &#xE4;r 1 633 000 SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 
1 november 2019 - 30 juni 2020, och ska f&#xF6;ljas upp med en dialog om fullt k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r implementeringen av den nya strategin senare under 2020.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Georgian Farmers&#x2019; Association (GFA) has applied to the Embassy of Sweden for pre-core support with the funding of 1 633 000 SEK to implement the following:
 
1) Perform an organizational assessment; 
2) Develop a new 5 year strategic plan for the years 2020 - 2024; 
3) Follow up and implement the recommendations of the review of internal management and control systems conducted by the KPMG Georgia LLC in July 2019. 

The contribution aims at improving the organizational capacity, enhance the internal management and control systems and sustainable strategic development of GFA. 

The total amount of the pre-core support  is 1 633 000 SEK for the period 1 November 2019 - 30 June  2020, followed with a close dialogue on core-support for implementation of the new strategy later in 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GFA/Georgian Farmers Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GFA/Georgian Farmers Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-100.8522892887</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/georgia/13557_GFAPre-coreGrantagreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pre core support grant agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following results have been achieved by the partner:&#xA0;
1) Partner has conducted organizational assessment -&#xA0;During the period of February 15-22, 2020 the experts visited Georgia and conducted the assessment based on GFA strategic plan 2014-2018, with special attention for: Governance Financial Health, Management Capacity Services/business case. The experts conducted a thorough scan and provided detailed conclusions and recommendations for further development and capacity building. The process included discussions/reflections with management and board members, various key stakeholders, field visits, interviewing GFA farmers and GFA staff members.
2) Developed new 5 year Strategy, which serves the bases for core support developed as a result of a pre core support.&#xA0;The methodology of the Strategy development&#xA0;involved a combination of approaches:Review of existing situation and previous assessment/review documents of the organization; Discussions, interviews and meetings with various parties involved in the process; Development of the conclusions and recommendations for further strategy development.
3) Followed up on implementation of the recommendations of the internal management and control review (ISK) by the KPMG. Namely, with the KPMG&apos;s support, the GFA&#xA0;now has&#xA0;reviewed and updated harassment document; Defined roles of GFA Board and top management; developed a formal anti corruption policy. In terms of organizational management, with the support of KPMG, developed financial management software, updated organizational structure and other as recommended by the ISK. Specifically,&#xA0;KPMG&#xA0;delivered the&#xA0;Salary survey report, updated organizational structure, job descriptions, performance evaluation, risk management framework, matrix, action plan. It also uupdated&#xA0;internal policies (Accounting Manual, Financial Manual, Personnel and Administration Manual, Procurement Manual, Travel Policy, IT policy, Grant Manual, Employment Agreement Template, Vendor agreement template; Internal audit and template, annual audit work plan.&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;&#xA0;
During the no cost extension of the contribution, the partner has additionally achieved&#xA0;the following results:&#xA0;
4) Final electronic&#xA0;versions of&#xA0; all GFA manuals and organizational policies have been developed and shared with the Embassy.&#xA0;
2) Training of GFA saff by KPMG took place to train them on the updated and new GFA manuals, as well as organizational policies. Training materials have also been shared with the Embassy.&#xA0;
3) GFA new policies have been translated into Georgian and shared with the Embassy.
The partner has been very adaptive and kept flexible approach together with the Embassy based on the needs and savings during the pre core support implementation. The partner successfully&#xA0;achieved all the results and ticked all pre requisites which the pre core support aimed at in order to continue with the core support. As a result,as of 1st January 2021, the core support agreement has been in force with the GFA&#xA0;fore the period of 2021-2023.&#xA0;
Moreover, as partner has also noted in the narrative reporting, despite the world pandemic and risks, the project team, together with partners and the Embassy, managed to undertake tasks and accomplish project goals in a quality manner. The implementation style during the period (online consultations, meetings, trainings, team work) was a challenge, but a good lesson learned for future similar circumstances.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13557" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
