<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-23-2220051-ide_nep_anukulanxphoto01</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-23-2220051" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development Enterprises</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anukulan-X Photos</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Increasing access to an additional 1000 smallholder farmers to climate smart loans through microfinance services. 2) Ensuring high value crop production through extending crop insurance safety nets to an additional 1000 climate vulnerable farmers 3) Facilitating public private partnership groups at &#x2018;Palika&#x2019; level to prompt investments for MUS and collection centers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building on Anukulan, in which iDE worked to enable the vulnerable poor, especially women and children, to be more resilient to climate extremes and disasters. The worked to increase the annual income for 100,000 households (benefiting over 500,000 people), increase food security, and reduce the proportion of children under five suffering from malnutrition, through climate resilient farming systems and diversification of livelihoods. Anukulan-X builds on this work by further strengthening public-private partnerships by increasing the accessibility of smallholder farmers to micro-finance and crop insurance services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">vulnerable poor, especially women and children</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADRA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DFID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middlesex University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nepali Technical Assistance Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RIMS Nepal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rupantaran</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAPPROS Nepal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iDE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="43072" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/www.ideglobal.org/files/protected/Anukulan-X-Collection-Center-Photo-1.pdf?mtime=20190828173909">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Collection Center Photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In early 2017, Anukulan/BRACED established the Milijulju a collection centre with the objective to increase vegetable production in hill district Surkhet. Collection centres are pillars of the iDE Nepal commercial pocket approach to enable smallholders to become commercial producers and to increase their agricultural productivity. Collection centers also recommend CSA crops/technologies and represent communities in adaptation planning. The collection centre is chaired by Ms. Yasodha Thapa (left) and provides services to 239 households in Malarani, Sahare, and adjoining villages. With a local collection center mostly women farmers save time and can generate crucial income from their small landholdings. In the first year the centre made a running profit of GBP 745.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/www.ideglobal.org/files/protected/Anukulan-X-woman-entrepreneur-as-a-nursery-grower-Photo-2.pdf?mtime=20190828174232">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nursery Grower 02</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ms. Sumitra Sunar lives in Barahtal village of Surkhet. She is managing her farm and a nursery business. She also receives water from Sajpani multiple use water system (MUS) that Anukulan /BRACED established in 2017. The construction of the Sajpani MUS has brought a remarkable change in the life of marginalized women as the MUS has saved their time for collecting water and enabled the nursery business. Sumitra is earning more than GBP 560 per year by selling vegetables in nearby collection center and seedlings of various vegetables to farmers of her village and adjoining villages. Sumitra is using safe IPM facilitated by last mile supply chains developed by Anukulan to produce the seedlings, including use of insect netting to protect from insect damage and the spread of viral diseases by insects.</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="A08"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/www.ideglobal.org/files/protected/Anukulan-X-MPC-Photo-1.JPG?mtime=20190828174006">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MPC Photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/www.ideglobal.org/files/protected/Anukulan-X-Nursery-grower-Photo-2.jpg?mtime=20190828174127">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nursery Grower 01</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
