<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00135</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultation meeting with impacted communities in target states.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Bayelsa state, CEHRD visited 6 impacted communities, Sampou, Kaiama, Swali, Akaba, Igbogene and Onopa communities, while in Rivers state 6 communities were visited namely Mogho, Gio, Kpoghor, Gbe, Biara and Ebubu Ejamah communities respectively.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity was to engage traditional rulers, youths and community stakeholders in both Rivers and Bayelsa State. 12 highly impacted communities were mapped with the structure of creating awareness on climate change and its impacts on the community. It was aimed also at providing mitigation and adaptation measures that can be adopted to reduce the impacts on their environment. 

Niger Delta communities are currently suffering the double impact of climate change and oil spills on their environment and natural resources, this is because Niger Delta communities are mostly coastal communities and as such are situated along coastlines. Climate Change is the increase in temperature of the environment caused by the melting of ice in the arctic regions of the world, resulting in increased volume of water and sea-level rise. However, climate change is a global issue with localized impacts. In the Niger Delta region in Nigeria, climate change has caused the sea-level rise, coastal erosion, coastal subsidence, harsh weather, poor yield of crops, an increase of disease vectors, loss of lives due to increased waves in the rivers and seas, a threat to food security, contamination of freshwater sources, and resettlement of those living in flood-prone areas amongst others.
However, it has been noted that fighting climate change presents a major economic challenge. Substantial economic resources would be required to transcend into a green and low carbon economy. Therefore, appropriate frameworks need to be evolved to encourage citizens to reframe from activities that contribute to climate change; also substantial financial commitment by the government is imperative if a low-carbon economy will be achieved and a design policy needs to be recognized that will curb climate change and protect our environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To adopt climate change mitigation and adaptation measures.To educate local communities and stakeholders on the challenge of climate change and sensitize them on proper waste disposal mechanism.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD Implemented the activity.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-29">1887600</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
