<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advocacy visit to key environmental regulatory agencies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD embarked on advocacy visits to key environmental regulatory agencies in Bayelsa and Rivers states to create awareness on the project activities and solicit for their support and partnership during the activity implementation. Stakeholders outlined by CEHRD team were: 1. Hydrocarbon Pollution Remediation Project (HYPREP), Rivers State 2. National Oil Spills Detection and Response Agency (NOSDRA), Bayelsa and Rivers States. 3. Department of Petroleum Resources (DPR), Bayelsa and Rivers States. 4. Rivers State Ministry of Environment. HYPREP, as part of their mandate to remediate polluted sites in Ogoniland, is meant to sensitize Ogoni communities on the dangers associated with artisanal refining and provide sustainable alternative livelihoods for Ogoni communities. Following this mandate, CEHRD being aware that Ogoniland is one of the spots for artisanal refining in the Niger Delta region, engaged HYPREP to discuss developed frameworks to support their work in achieving sustainable environmental management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00127" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-17" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-17" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-17"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-28">732200</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
