<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00133</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Based Civic and Citizenship Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD embarked on Gender based Voter Education in December 2018 at the 6 Senatorial districts of Rivers and Bayelsa States. At that time, the proximity of the 2019 elections was close. It was imperative to train the women on ethical voting and the processes involved. CEHRD trained 120 women in the target LGA&#x2019;s in Rivers and Bayelsa States on civic and voter&#x2019;s responsibility. The training increased voters&#x2019; turnout during elections, encourage ethical voting thereby empowering them. This becomes was starting point of political activeness, especially for women who have justifiably developed a nonchalant attitude towards their freedom to vote and to be voted for. That training generated the needed outcomes envisaged. However, this time similar training will be done but Nigeria is not close to another elections. It is the appropriate time for coach and groom the women of their constitutional responsibilities. They must not only vote. They could also be voted for. They have the rights to participate in the decisions that overtly and mostly impact on them. It is the reason why CEHRD turned their attention this time towards a Gender based Civic and Citizenship Education. In many countries, access to human rights is disproportionate among sexes and thus the thematic campaign by the United Nations for equal rights in all climes. Equal rights could mean different concepts to different people depending on the context. For example, women in Nigeria are struggling for affirmation action. Women desire and deserve equal political rights with their male counterparts. The Nigerian woman deserves to aspire for political office on the platform of a political party and earn votes that would make her an active participant in politics and governance. However, there are no legal instruments to reduce the overarching dominance of the male folks in the political landscape. Thus, access to political right affects women&#x2019;s inclusion and participation in politics and governance in Nigeria. This activity aims to promote women&#x2019;s inclusion in governance and political participation. The 2019 elections ended with one of the worst ratios of women to men in power in the world. The Gender Based Civic and Citizenship Education is meant to identify their gender barriers and strengthen them towards the paths of achieving equal rights in decision making.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00133" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-20" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-12" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-02"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-03-12">5843700</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
