<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00131</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Entrepreneur Training from Zero-to-low in Rivers and Bayelsa States</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD has prior to this training conducted a baseline study in Bayelsa State on February 5 to April, 2019. While that of Rivers was conducted on April 24th to May, 2019. The survey measures the level of women&#x2019;s involvement in economic activities in their communities, the average income that women earn, factors that exclude them from earning well and their areas of interest if there is existent support system. This baseline was meant to generate findings that will eventually produce the content of an entrepreneur training for women in Rivers and Bayelsa States. Having hired 2 well-knowledge consultants- one from the academics and the other a practising entrepreneur, CEHRD shared the baseline report with them to enable them design a content that will fit the women the training is intended for.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participants are based on Senatorial Districts. In each Senatorial Districts 40 participants were trained. The 3 Senatorial Districts got 120 WIGN members trained in Rivers State and 120 WIGN members are also trained in Bayelsa State. These make a total of 240 WIGN members trained in Rivers and Bayelsa States.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xF0A7; To improve the income of the rural women. &#xF0A7; To provide entrepreneur skills to women in target States</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00131" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-07" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-17" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-07" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-12" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-12-13">6456000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
