<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00109</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signature Campaigns</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this activity is to gather sixty thousand signatures from supporters for engagement towards the domestication of the VAPP Act in Rivers and Bayelsa States. The collation of signatures for the support of the VAPP Act involved people both males and females. It addressed the issue of ignorance with regards to the Act and canvassed resolute support from different people. One method employed was to converge officials from the Ministry of Justice, Ministry of Women Affairs, civil society groups and community heads. This meeting produced strategies for the distribution of signature booklets to all manner of persons. During the activity, it was discovered that prominent personalities who had signed the signature booklet served as an attraction to those who were yet convinced. For instance, the fact that some top-ranking policemen signed the signature booklet was a motivation for persons who were in doubt. The signature campaign is an ongoing process but will come to an end when there are sixty thousand signatures in the booklet or the VAPP Act has been successfully domesticated in Bayelsa State. So far, the numbers and the rate of signing have been very encouraging.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00109" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2019-08-19">1845000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
