<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inauguration of Environment Club Members in Community Secondary School, Biara and Mogho &#x2013; Gokana LGA, Rivers State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger Delta communities are currently suffering the double impact of climate change and oil spills on their environment and natural resources, this is because Niger Delta communities are mostly coastal communities and as such are situated along coastlines. Climate Change is the increase in temperature of the environment caused by the melting of ice in the arctic regions of the world, resulting in increased volume of water and sea level rise. However, climate change is a global issue with localized impacts. In the Niger Delta region in Nigeria, climate change has caused sea level rise, coastal erosion, coastal subsidence, harsh weather, poor yield of crops, increase of disease vectors, loss of lives due to increased waves in the rivers and seas, threat to food security, contamination of fresh water sources, and resettlement of those living in flood prone areas amongst others.
However, it has been noted that fighting climate change presents a major economic challenge. Substantial economic resources would be required to transcend into a green and low carbon economy. Therefore, appropriate frameworks need to be evolved to encourage citizens to reframe from activities that contribute to climate change; also substantial financial commitment by the government is imperative if a low-carbon economy will be achieved and a design policy needs to be recognized that will curb climate change and protect our environment by sensitizing young ones in communities as vanguard for good environmental practice amongst.


Following the consultation visits to selected schools and communities in Rivers and Bayelsa states, CEHRD with the buy-in and support of some communities in Bayelsa and Rivers states established formal and informal environmental clubs in the communities with mission to build community youths&#x2019; capacity in green development and environmental conservation, encouraging them to study, practice, care and advocate for environmental sustainability within their immediate environs and reside vision to engage and promote environmental literacy among youths of all divides.
The essence of establishing community environmental clubs whether in a formal or informal setting, is to push for behavioral change at the rural level amongst youths by engaging them in environmental education directed at forming their minds for a future in the Niger Delta. Also, catching them young will avail us the opportunity to orientate them on prevailing global environmental issues that is directly affecting the Niger Delta because of the region&#x2019;s geographical location and given their natural resource base.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 8 established clubs each had 20 pioneer members. The school and communities include&#x2019;:
1.	Community Environmental Club Mogho, Rivers State (Informal)
2.	Community Secondary School Biara, Rivers State (Formal)
3.	Community Environmental Club Biara, Rivers State (Informal)
4.	Government Girls Secondary School Kaiama, Bayelsa State (Formal)
5.	Community Environmental Club Kaiama, Bayelsa State (Informal)
6.	Sampou Grammar School, Sampou Bayelsa State (Formal)
7.	Community Environmental Club Sampou, Bayelsa State (Informal)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To educate and mainstream mangrove protection and restoration in coastal schools and communities in Rivers and Bayelsa States.

To promote green development and climate change mitigation approaches.

To increase awareness amongst secondary school students on environmental issues.

To advocate for environmental conservation/sustainability.

To promote gender inclusiveness in addressing environmental issues.

To create a platform where students are taught the dynamics of the Environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00135" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD has implemented.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-21" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD has implemented.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-20" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CEHRD</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15162" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implemented by CEHRD</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-01-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-01-29">1524200</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
