<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00129</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training of Trainers for Leaders (TOT) of Women in Governance Network (WIGN) in Rivers State and Bayelsa state on Common Ground Advocacy and Social Networking</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target participants were only the WIGN leaders who are to step down the training to their community women. The one TOT has 20 participants in Bayelsa and 20 participants in Rivers State; making a total of 40 participants in both States. Participants were all women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity, the TOT for WIGN leaders in Rivers and Bayelsa States aims at equipping and re-orienting target women on value priorities amongst women. It was meant for women to begin see themselves as equal partners in development. The training which was practical and interactive exposed women to the cultures and worldviews that have relegated them. Then practical steps were pointed out for adoption for women to think, plan and work as the male folk in the society. The WIGN leaders were meant to step down this training to their members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xF0A7; To change the perception of women with regards to their contribution to societal development &#xF0A7; To instill confidence in women to take up leadership &#xF0A7; To clear misconceptions on cultural values that seem to relegate women &#xF0A7; To empower women on their different potentials.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00129" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-27">379500</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
