<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="NGN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NG-CAC-19258-00132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NG-CAC-19258" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A One-Day Strategic Meeting for Political Mentorship for Women in Governance Network (WIGN) in Rivers and Bayelsa States</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It was a multi-stakeholder meeting. In Rivers State, a total number of 27 participants attended the meeting. There the 3 most active political party women actors. The Peoples&#x2019; Democratic Party (APC) has 4 women political actors. The All Progressive Congress (APC) has 4 women political actors. The Labor Party also has 4 women political actors. The woman who represented Ikwerre constituency in the Rivers State House of Assembly was also present. Also in attendance was the Councilor representing B-Dere Ward 9. Other women came from the Civil Society organizations and representatives from the WIGN in the 3 Senatorial Districts. In Bayelsa, a total number of 25 participants attended the meeting. There the 3 most active political party women actors. The Peoples&#x2019; Democratic Party (APC) has 4 women political actors. The All Progressive Congress (APC) has 4 women political actors. The Labor Party also has 4 women political actors. Top women from the Civil Society including the International Federation of Women Lawyers (FIDA) were also there. Representatives of the WIGN at the 3 Senatorial zones were present.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The low rate of women participation in governance and politics militating from various factors cutting across sexual, economical, psychological, socially and culturally necessitated the need to engage the public on the importance to create a balance in the opportunities of governance and political participation, activeness in Niger Delta and Nigeria at large. In view of the above, a rally to create public awareness on the need to include women in politics and governance was carried out in Rivers State. The rally aims at sensitizing citizens of Rivers state on the importance of women in inclusion in politics and governance thus, increasing the awareness on the status of women in Nigeria politics and culture. This activity A one day Strategic Meeting for Political Mentorship for Women in Governance Network (WIGN) in Rivers State aims to incorporate grassroot women into active political participants in Rivers State. The activity created a mentorship system between already established politicians with the grassroot base women. Active participation will not be possible if the women do not have vital knowledge on how the political system works, the challenges and how to surmount them. Implicatively, women from the grassroots can stand their ground in vying for political positions and achieve success in return.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xF0A7; To create mentorship system between politicians and grassroot women. &#xF0A7; To increase active participation of women in politics and governance &#xF0A7; To Define Strategies for Political Mentorship for Women in Governance Network (WIGN) in Rivers State. &#xF0A7; To Create Mentors for WIGN at the Senatorial Level</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="00132" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="NG-CAC-19258" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Environment, Human Rights and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-20" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-20" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-04" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">None</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="NGN" value-date="2020-02-18">634900</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
