<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RER/11/51/FRG" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-102549-1107-2018-RER902</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating Child Labour in Central Asia. Commitment becomes Action (PROACT CAR Phase III). Award No. 500794 (GLO/10/19/FRG). 2011 and 2012 contribution.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ILO&#x2019;s International Programme on the Elimination of Child Labour (IPEC) has been working in Central Asia since 2005 to provide technical and financial assistance to the ILO constituents in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan in the implementation of the ILO child labour conventions &#x2013; The Minimum Age Convention (1973) No 138 and the Worst Forms of Child Labour Convention (1999) No 182 &#x2013; as well as in the design, implementation, monitoring and evaluation of national child labour strategies, policies and programmes. In spite of important successes with previous projects, urgent action is still required in all the countries of Central Asia. The countries still need further technical assistance in their efforts to prevent and eliminate the Worst Forms of Child Labour by focussing more on policy level interventions, capacity building for social partners and awareness raising on the risks and hazards of child labour at the agriculture sector, with focus on cotton and tobacco. This project builds on the outcomes and achievements of the previous interventions, lessons learned and on the experiences acquired in the sub-region in working with the Government, social partners and other stakeholders in addressing child labour. The main strategy of this project is the combination of policy-related interventions to create a conducive environment with service-oriented activities at the community level. The project consists of two main components: a national and a regional one. At the national level, the project focuses on policy mainstreaming and up-scaling activities through the institutionalization of models of intervention previously tested; building the capacity and stimulating a greater involvement of government, workers&#x2019; and employers&#x2019; organizations, and awareness-raising on the causes and consequences of child labour and possible strategies to address the issue. The project in the three countries is planning to withdraw and to prevent working children from involvement in the worst forms of child labour through provision of a comprehensive package of services. At the regional level, the project facilitates the exchange of information among key stakeholders of the project participating countries. The project seeks to preserve institutional memory and enhance the organizational learning and the multiplier effect of the project.The good practices emerged from the implementation of the previous and the current projects shall be documented and further disseminated to the project partners for possible replication.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DE-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany, Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-region code="619" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: More and better jobs for inclusive growth and improved youth employment prospects</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">537898</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="RER/11/51/FRG-2018-RER902 - TEMP, to link regional TC projects not linked to sub-region or country-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">537898</value>
   <provider-org ref="DE-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Germany, Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="RER/11/51/FRG-2018-RER902 - TEMP, to link regional TC projects not linked to sub-region or country">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">537898</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/idcplg?IdcService=SS_GET_PAGE&amp;ssDocName=WCMS_356030">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Story: Combating Child Labour in Central Asia. Commitment becomes Action (PROACT CAR Phase III). Award No. 500794 (GLO/10/19/FRG). 2011 and 2012 contribution.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=RER/11/51/FRG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Combating Child Labour in Central Asia. Commitment becomes Action (PROACT CAR Phase III). Award No. 500794 (GLO/10/19/FRG). 2011 and 2012 contribution.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A06"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-07"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/ievaldiscovery/#tc_symbol=RER/11/51/FRG&amp;view=list&amp;source=eval">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Evaluation: Combating Child Labour in Central Asia. Commitment becomes Action (PROACT CAR Phase III). Award No. 500794 (GLO/10/19/FRG). 2011 and 2012 contribution.</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
