<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5520001001-GTM-32130</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP -  Cuilco Rural Development Joint Program</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNDP - Cuilco Landsbygdsutveckling Gemensamt Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cuilco Program intends to provide multiple solutions to development in territories, it is focused in small-scale farmers families, farmer organizations and government institutions present in the territory (Municipalities and Ministries).&#xA0; The Program works with public institutions to generate evidence to facilitate right holders greater access to quality public services to improve their lives and strengthens duty bearers to perform their mandates in the territory and to better respond to the citizens demands.The program works in economic, cultural and social rights, including the right to food and the enjoyment of a safe, clean, healthy and sustainable environment. It has been implemented since November 2015 in Tejutla, Comitancillo, Concepci&#xF3;n Tutuapa, Sipacapa and San Miguel Ixtaguac&#xE1;n in San Marcos, Guatemala.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen, som leds av UNDP, bygger p&#xE5; det sammarbete som tre FN organen har haft under f&#xF6;rsta delen av projektet &quot;Joint Program&quot; i San Marcos regionen. D&#xE4;r uppn&#xE5;ddes en v&#xE4;l fungerande interinstitutionell samordning mellan UNDP- FAO -WHO, civilsamh&#xE4;llet, samt lokala och centrala myndigheter. denna insats bygger vidare p&#xE5; detta och har som m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra levnadsvillkoren f&#xF6;r familjer som livn&#xE4;r sig p&#xE5; jordbruk och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra deras tillg&#xE5;ng till sjukv&#xE5;rd samt motsst&#xE5;ndskraft mot naturkatastrofer. Denna fas 2 kommer verka i kommuner som inte inkluderades i FAS 1 n&#xE4;mligen Comitancillo, San Miguel Ixtahuac&#xE1;n, Concepci&#xF3;n Tutuapa, Sipacapa y Tejutla i San Marcos. Initiativet kommer &#xE4;ven att arbeta med att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra kapaciteten bland akt&#xF6;rer fr&#xE5;n civilsamh&#xE4;llet, lokala och centrala myndigheter f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla framtagandet och implementeringen av kommunala utvecklingsplaner, samt fr&#xE4;mja deltagande i lokala utvecklingskommitt&#xE9;er f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja lokala investeringar.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposal aims to replicate inter-institutional coordination between UN Agencies, civil society, local and central government to reproduce successful experience from previous Joint Program in San Marcos Region. The program intents to: improve livelihoods, health and resilience of poor peasant families with productions of subsistence and Infra subsistence in rural poor areas of Comitancillo, San Miguel Ixtahuac&#xE1;n, Concepci&#xF3;n Tutuapa, Sipacapa y Tejutla of San Marcos, Guatemala. The program will also strength capacities of civil society, local and central government with presence in the area to enhance the preparation and implementation of Municipal Development Plan and promote participation on Development Council System as a way to reach investment on the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="321" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Industry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Small and medium-sized enterprises (SME) development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">711802.8780563036</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1402442.5875065739</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">711802.8780563036</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1402442.5875065739</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-01">2135408.634168</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">711802.8780563036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">1402442.5875065739</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/guatemala/55200010-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/guatemala/55200010-decision-on-amendment-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">till&#xE4;ggsbeslut 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/guatemala/55200010-decision-on-amendment-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">till&#xE4;ggsbeslut 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation during 2020 was conditioned by COVID-19 pandemic, the joint program was able to take measures to continue the implementation in a COVID-19 context, such as changes in operations to face the country lock down, design and implementation of a COVID-19 response plan.
The program&apos;s operations changed regarding training sessions, groups were divided in groups of 10, gel alcohol and face masks were provided and physical distance between participants was assured; information about COVID-19 prevention was introduced to support the containment of the pandemic; a response plan was designed and implemented to support the most vulnerable families to go through the lock downs and the economic consequences of the pandemic.&#xA0;
Municipalities:
Municipal governments increased their capacity to plan and promote territorial development processes, introducing watershed management approaches, risk management and promoting gender equality and women empowerment, the municipal offices strengthened were: DMM, UMGAR, OMC, OFM, DMP, UMAIP, OMJNA, OMAS.
5 municipal strategies to strengthen public services were updated, approved, and implemented, including a Covid-19 prevention plan. To achieve this, the Municipal Office of Public Services (OMSP), the office for Water and Sanitation (OMAS), OMESS and OMDEL were strengthened.
Democratic governance was supported through the communitarian development councils COMUDE&apos;s permanent commissions that were strengthened through capacity building to enhance more interaction with the population to reach more participatory and inclusive solutions to citizen demands.
Ministry of Health - MSPAS 
The Comprehensive Center for Maternal and Child Care (CAIMI) of Tejutla was supported&#xA0;with equipment and supplies for water quality&#xA0;monitoring, anthropometric equipment, laboratory supplies and equipment,, ultrasound and electrocardiograph.
Implementation of the Telemedicine Network was developed through the Comprehensive Center for Maternal and Child Care (CAIMI) of Tejutla and the Permanent Care Centers (CAP) of Comitancillo and Concepci&#xF3;n Tutuapa.
Training was provided for health personnel in the five Municipal Health Districts (DMS) for the prevention of COVID-19.
Technical support was provided to update the Municipal Health Plan (PMS).
The planning processes between DMS and the municipalities was supported through training and capacity building for the Municipal Development Councils (COMUDE), the Municipal Food and Nutrition Security Commissions (COMUSAN), the Municipal Water and Sanitation Offices (OMAS), the Municipal Directorate for Women (DMM).
Ministry of Agriculture - MAGA
Ministry of Agriculture received support to train and strengthen local extension services to implement the Family Agriculture Program &#x2013; PAFFEC.
MAGA scaled up the multipurpose rainwater harvesting model, which has been implemented within San Marcos, other departments by several organizations, and families with remittances with technical assistance from MAGA.
With the Joint Program support the Ministry of Agriculture in San Marcos was able to support food systems and food security by: Provision of seeds to families for family gardens; Build and improve productive infrastructure; Implement seedling nurseries; Support the implementation of short circuits of commercialization of the School Feeding Program - PAE Networks; Prepare a protocol for COVID-19 prevention in community markets.
Planning Secretariat - SEGEPLAN
The Joint Program supported SEGEPLAN to develop guides and tools to provide technical assistance in planning to public institutions, local governments, and the System of Development Councils at the departmental, municipal and community levels.
Secretariat for disaster risk reduction - SECONRED
The support provided by the Joint Program allowed SECONRED to improve its instruments and strengthen the mechanisms to guarantee the coordination with the public and private institutions for disaster risk management in San Marcos.
Food Security 
Food insecurity and its consequences is a huge problem in Guatemala, which has increased in 2020 as a consequence of COVID-19 pandemic. Even so, the joint program managed to ensure that 60% of the low-income and subsistence families that participate in the program (1,750) reduced their food insecurity (moderate and severe), which is twice the planned final goal (30%). As well, the program increased the availability and diversity of food with a diet diversity index (DDI) of (9.01) in 2020 compared to DDI (6.96) in 2015.
52 community promoters (29women / 23men) have joined the National Rural Extension System (SNER)exceeding the goal of 45.
Safe, Healthy, and Productive Family Habitat
454 families living in conditions of very high and high vulnerability to natural disasters received training to manage the risks present in their family habitat (home + environment), achieving a dignified, healthy, safe, sustainable, and resilient environment to face extreme events.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55200010" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
