<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-7100450003-GTM-24040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FDLG lokal utveckling II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing and Local Development in Guatemala PhaseII</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribute to poverty alleviation and economic growth for groups that have been excluded from development opportunities. This objective will be reached by increasing access to adequate financial services for poorer segments of the population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det huvudsakliga m&#xE5;let f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra tillg&#xE4;ngligheten f&#xF6;r fattiga befolkningsgrupper att erh&#xE5;lla finansiella tj&#xE4;nster f&#xF6;r   f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttring av bost&#xE4;der och infrastruktur samt mindre krediter f&#xF6;r    generering av inkomster.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the programme is to improve access for poor     population groups to financial services for improvement of housing    and infrastructure as well as small credits for income generation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">L&amp;B Legal and Business Consulting Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEGEPLAN/Presedential Secretariat For Planning And Programming</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="240" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banking &amp; Financial Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="24040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Informal/semi-formal financial intermediaries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="1.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1 - By 2030, eradicate extreme poverty for all people everywhere, currently measured as people living on less than $1.25 a day.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">1.1 - Senast 2030 avskaffa den extrema fattigdomen f&#xF6;r alla m&#xE4;nniskor &#xF6;verallt. Med extrem fattigdom avses f&#xF6;r n&#xE4;rvarande m&#xE4;nniskor som lever p&#xE5; mindre &#xE4;n 1,25 US-dollar per dag.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">645556.2189331037</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2756.0334248817</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-54.2880542881</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">57588.1432385161</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">2756.0334248817</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-54.2880542881</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">21162.086900488</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2005-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2005-09-01">692281.863925</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">2756.066148542</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-28">-54.2728442728</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">21162.0661879775</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 1999 Sida financed the programme &quot;Fideicomiso para el Desarrollo Local en Guatemala FDLG&quot; through a Specific Agreement between Sida and the Secretariat of Planning and Programming of the Presidency- SEGEPLAN-. It was executed through a Trust Fund arrangement managed by a commercial national Bank (at the beginning by Banco del Caf&#xE9;, after that by Banco Industrial).
FDLG was implemented in two phases, the first phase was from 1999 to 2005. In 2006, Phase II began and concluded on December 31, 2017. A Closure plan of the programme was implemented from January to June 2018. The agreement on PLANit system was extended until February 2020 due to the Embassy had to wait for the last transactions correspondent to the sale of the trust fund property (an industrial plant of basic grains that was delivered to FDLG as part of the guarantee of a loan not paid to the program by the organization ADEL-IXCAN), the sale was completed in December 2019.
In order to certify transparency of the Micro-finance programme FDLG closure, the Embassy based on the approved closure plan presented by FDLG decided to conduct an external final audit for the closure plan period (January 1st. to June 30, 2018). The Audit was carried out by the Firm Moore Stephens LPP. The Audit did not report any material findings.
The auditor verified that:
-the financial transactions of the programme closure were carried out in a transparent and appropriate manner, such as: liquidation of the investments and of the credit portfolio, as well as of the real estate guarantees.
-Verified sale and liquidation procedures and results of the Trust fund patrimony. Once a month from April to June the auditor reviewed and certified the process.
-Provided an opinion on the reasonableness of the complementary financial information, in such a way that it permited clarity and integration on the totality of the funds to be refunded to Sida.
-Checked that all formal and essential legal and tax obligations were complied with for an adequate closure of the program and the Trust fund, in order to avoid subsequent contingencies.
-Also the auditor Accompanied as guarantors in the process or specific events such as the liquidation and sale of the assets of the Trust.
Main achieved results:
Through intermediary micro finance institutions which included-Cooperatives, Foundations, Associations, and banks (27 organizations during the total project implementation), FDLG improved access for poor population to financial services for housing improvement and income generation:
(i) Around 197,500 new rural clients obtained micro credits. Gender and ethnic equality were prioritized crosscutting aspects, 71% of borrowers were women and 82% were indigenous people living mainly in rural areas and in poverty conditions, for whom improvements were reflected on their living conditions.
(ii) 331,580 micro credits were operated and provided to the target groups as follows:
-60,440 loans to improve poor housing conditions were provided. Housing improvements provided to the target groups primarily poor families in rural area an affordable housing and a safe space, contributing in this way to their well-being, e.g. improvements in their health and overcrowded conditions. Technical assistance for construction contributed in planning properly the credits investment for family housing building.
(iii) 271,140 loans for income generation activities were provided to develop small-scale businesses specially on agricultural, livestock, small shops and textile activities, which have contributed to the target groups to improve their family economy creating in some cases, employment and self-employment, in this way, the target groups had the opportunity to participate and promote local economy.
(iv) FDLG through technical assistance contributed to strengthen the intermediaries institutional capacities, product development and its organizational structure, in order to provide credit products adapted to the target groups needs and capacities. Before the programme its intermediaries did not operate micro credit for housing, the programme supported these financial institutions to introduce housing loans as well as for micro- and small enterprises development in the country.
(v) As part of the programme&apos;s financial inclusion strategy, in alliance with the intermediaries, micro credits alternative methodologies were created, such as village banking and solidarity groups, which are an informal self-help support group of around 10-20 members, as a manner to provide access to the poor, mainly for women and indigenous people who are excluded from some conventional banking. Methodologies for working with gender equality and indigenous population were introduced, based on the fact that the micro finance organisations before the programme never did not pay especial attention to women and indigenous population as credit clients and subject of economic rights.
(vi) In order to contribute to poverty reduction and housing deficit, the programme had influence on housing national policies and other actors involved in popular housing such as &quot;El Fondo Guatemalteco de Vivienda FOGUAVI&quot;, &quot;El Instituto de Fomento Municipal INFOM&quot;, and in some municipalities. For example, the programme contributed to update the National Housing Policy, as well as supported the construction of a municipal solid waste plant in Quetzaltenango and supported to FOGUAVI in the creation of policy, manuals, regulations and other tools so that the target groups living in poverty condition, through the national subsidy acquired a social housing.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="71004500" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1050103" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1350000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Guatemala 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Guatemala 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
