<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5208003303-GTM-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBIS and IW/Prevention Gender Based Violence</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IBIS and IW/Prevention Gender Based Violence</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet avser att bidra till att f&#xF6;rhindra k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld och     fr&#xE4;mja implementeringen av S&#xE4;kerhetsr&#xE5;dets resolution 1325.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project intends to contribute to prevent gender based violence    and the implementation of the Resolution 1325. The agreement was      amended, and was included IEPADES and UNAMG in the implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxfam IBIS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-25" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-25" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2017Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: - With respect to women&apos;s fight for justice, a historical trial set a precedent in 2016.  The project contributed to the development of the oral and public debate on the Case Sepur Zarco, resulting in the indictment of the accused for &quot;crimes against humanity in the form of sexual violence, murder, violation of personal dignity, especially humiliation, degradation and enforced disappearance&quot;.   This was the first time that that international transcendence crimes are tried in a national court. 
- The group of women (14)  from Sepur Zarco were supported by psychological and legal services, before, during and after the trial on sexual abuse suffered during the armed conflict.  The sentence was given on February 26, 2016 against two accused.
- As a result of the sentence, reparations measures were included as part of the State responsibility.   Even though the sentence was appealed by the accused and their lawyers, the group of women and the Alianza Rompiendo El Silencio has been following up on the implementation of these measures.  At the same time, during 2017 the partner has been ensuring the legal strategy so that the sentence remains firm .
- Before and during the trial, the political support from the international community was very important.  This dialogue and facilitation was facilitated by the Embassy of Sweden.
- A Gender Policy titled &#x201C; Pol&#xED;tica para la Equidad de G&#xE9;nero e Igualdad con Pertinencia Cultural entre Hombres y Mujeres en la Polic&#xED;a Nacional Civil 2017-20127&#x201D;  was improved, presented and it is in the implementation process within the National Police. 
- A group of 155 women from 5 Municipalities from Solol&#xE1;, Alta Verapaz, and Baja Verapaz were trained on Women&apos;s rights and prevention of violence.
- 14 municipal plans for violence against Women Prevention elaborated by community women leaders participating in the formation process, in coordination with the Municipal Office for Women. 
- A National Action Plan for the implementation of Resolution 1325 was approved by MIMPAZ (Mesa Inter-institucional sobre Mujer, Paz y Seguridad) in which 14 public institutions were involved. This Action Plan was presented on July 31, 2017 followed by the signing of an interinstitutional agreement to undertake the implementation of said Plan.  SEPREM was appointed as responsible for the planning and budgeting actions within each Ministry in order to implement activities included in the Action Plan.   However, it is important to note that the Action Plan was not formally approved by the President.  Given the current political context it is highly likely that the Plan will not be implemented accordingly, due to lack of political will.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52080033" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
