<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5520000001-GTM-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PAJUST II - Transitional Justice 2015-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PAJUST II - &#xD6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa 2015-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PAJUST aims at strenthening transitional justice.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">PAJUST syftar till att bidra till &#xF6;verg&#xE5;ngsr&#xE4;ttvisa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Guatemalan State applies integral mechanisms of transitional justice for victims of the internal armed conflict (IAC), in coordination with civil society and in accordance with the international framework for Human Rights. Victims of the IAC enjoy full exercise of the transitional justice rights and expand their means of life.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">3796282.016300286</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">4207327.762519722</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">3796282.016300286</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">4207327.762519722</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">-1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-03-01">8067099.284638</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-28">2609943.8862064467</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-28">2337404.3125109565</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">701221.2937532869</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the past decade, Pajust has played an important role for advancing transitional justice in Guatemala and has contributed to laying the foundations for a society that respects the rule of law and to transform society in a more peaceful direction where the root causes of the conflict are addressed. Many challenges have surrounded the work, but the programme has also had an important impact. One factor that has contributed was the diversity and complementarity of actors within the program. PAJUST has been actively working for the right to truth, justice, reparation and guarantees of non-repetition, and this integrated approach has been highlighted as an important factor to advance in this often very sensitive area of work.
The programme has worked with a high number of partners, including state institutions and civil society. With regards to state institutions the work has been challenging and the results achieved limited. There are some successful examples, including the work with the Ministry for Education and the Attorney General&apos;s Office. The work with civil society has been highly important and a driving factor behind the advances of the programme and transitional justice in Guatemala. PAJUST and partners have worked closely with communities, survivors and witnesses at local level, and supported the work to protect human rights and to keep historic memory&#xA0; alive.
The programme was structured around the four components, truth, justice, reparation, and guarantees of non-repetition, and some of the results include:&#xA0;
Truth
PAJUST has contributed to the right to truth and in consolidating&#xA0;peace and historical memory.&#xA0;
Through the work with the Historical Archive of the National Police (AHPN) more than 25 million documents were rescued and digitalised, these documents are from the deadliest years of the internal armed conflict in Guatemala and help shed light of what happened. These documents are important not only for families, survivors and researchers, but also important as evidence in the trials.&#xA0;Together with civil society, PAJUST has contributed to the exhumation, identification and inhumation of thousands of victims and has enabled families to know the truth about what happened to their loved ones. The results of this work is also key evidence in the trials.&#xA0;
Through support from PAJUST many still living people who went missing during the conflict have been identified and hundred of families have been been able to reunify.&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;Justice
PAJUST, together with civil society and the Attorney General&apos;s Office, has accompanied&#xA0;many judicial processes and in 17 cases sentences have been dictated in accordance with international standards on human rights and transitional justice. This has contributed to reducing impunity for crimes committed&#xA0;during the armed internal conflict and to increasing access&#xA0;to justice. This has also contributed to a strengthening of the justice system.&#xA0;
PAJUST, together with implementing partners, contributed with workshops, expert witnesses, facilitated more than a thousand statements, and, importantly, legal and psychosocial support to survivors and witnesses. More than 110 women survivors of sexual violence actively participated in processes of seeking justice and important advancements were made in several cases, recognizing sexual violence as a crime against humanity.ReparationA mentioned above, thousands of victims have been identified. This work has been done by civil society in coordination&#xA0;with the Attorney General&apos;s Office. The work has been closely coordinated with victims associations, families and communities. The remains&#xA0;have been returned to their families and communities and has enabled dignified burials in accordance with local traditions and beliefs. Families have received legal and psychosocial support throughout the process.&#xA0;
In the Ixil area PAJUST worked together with the UN Joint Programmes (financed by Sweden) and several communities could benefit from improved access to basic services and living conditions.Guarantees of non-repetition
Almost half a million people participated in historical memory initiatives, including youth and students who have received civic training on historical memory, transitional justice and culture of peace. More than 600 teachers have received training and have the tools and guides to teach in schools.
PAJUST&#xA0;also supported an important exhibition on history, memory and racism in Guatemala City, and a local museum on historical memory in one of the areas most severely&#xA0;affected by the armed conflict.
The above are some of many examples of the results achieved.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55200000" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
