<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5208002502-GTM-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indigenous Fund III-New Initiative/Ibis.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Mekanism f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d till urfolk i Guatemala</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Huvudm&#xE5;let med programmet &#xE4;r att bidra till &#xF6;kad respekt f&#xF6;r urfolkens kollektiva r&#xE4;ttigheter som de uttrycks i ILOs konvention 169, samt till aktivt deltagande fr&#xE5;n urfolkens m&#xE4;n och kvinnor i politiskt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; lokal och nationell niv&#xE5;. Utformningen av st&#xF6;det baserar sig p&#xE5; urfolkens m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, b&#xE5;de kollektiva och individuella, och f&#xF6;ljer s&#xE5;ledes b&#xE5;de AIDPI och ILO konventionen 169.
Programmet kommer huvudsakligen att arbeta inom tv&#xE5; omr&#xE5;den, vilka reflekteras i de tv&#xE5; syftena: (i) st&#xF6;d till urfolksbyar, s&#xE4;rskilt f&#xF6;r st&#xE4;rkandet av deras interna organisation och fr&#xE4;mjandet av deras kollektiva r&#xE4;ttigheter, och (ii) st&#xF6;d till p&#xE5;verkansarbete p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;, inklusive r&#xE4;ttsomr&#xE5;det (skapandet av r&#xE4;ttspraxis).
Mekanismen har tv&#xE5; delm&#xE5;l: (i) Framsteg har gjorts i fr&#xE4;mjandet av urfolkens r&#xE4;ttigheter till sitt eget territorium, s&#xE5; som det uttrycks i ILO konventionen 169, samt g&#xE4;llande urfolkens sj&#xE4;lvbest&#xE4;mmander&#xE4;tt inom dessa territorier ang&#xE5;ende &#xE5;teruppbyggandet av livet och respekten f&#xF6;r urfolkens politiska, sociala, ekonomiska och kulturella r&#xE4;ttigheter. (ii) Urfolken g&#xF6;r framsteg g&#xE4;llande att influera politiska institutioner, samt r&#xE4;ttsinstitutioner, ang&#xE5;ende prioriterade fr&#xE5;gor.
Den huvudsakliga imlementeringsformen f&#xF6;r mekanismen &#xE4;r genom offentliga utlysningar f&#xF6;r projektf&#xF6;rslag. Baserat p&#xE5; m&#xE5;l och planerade outputs definierade i programdokumentet och kontextanalysen, kommer Ibis att l&#xE4;mna f&#xF6;rslag till styrkommitt&#xE9;n g&#xE4;llande inkomna ans&#xF6;kningar. Ibis en Guatemala, som &#xE4;r en internationell enskild organisation har genom en &#xF6;ppen upphandling utf&#xF6;rd av  Sveriges ambassad, Guatemala, blivit tilldelad kontraktet som administrativt ansvarig f&#xF6;r insatsen, se ambassadens beslut GUA/UTV/2014/03, av den 11 februari 2014, om tilldelning av det aktuella kontraktet. Det totala svenska st&#xF6;det till insatsen &#xE4;r 49 miljoner SEK under perioden mars 2014 &#x2013; december 2017.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the programme is to contribute to a greater respect for the collective rights of indigenous people, as stipulated in the ILO Convention 169, and  to the active participation of the indigenous peoples, men and women, in the political decision-making at local and national levels.  The approach is based on the rights of Indigenous peoples; both collective and individual rights, and thus follows the AIDPI and the ILO Convention 169.  The contribution will work mainly in two areas, reflected in the two objectives: (i) support to indigenous communities, particularly to the strengthening of their internal organisation and the promotion of their collective rights; and (ii) support to advocacy at national level, including in the area of justice (creation of jurisprudence).
The Mechanism has two specific objectives; (i) Progress has been made in the promotion of the rights of indigenous peoples to their own territory, as stipulated in the ILO Convention 169, and towards the self-determination of the indigenous peoples within these territories, reconstituting the life and respecting indigenous peoples&apos; political, social, economic and cultural rights. (ii)  The indigenous peoples are making progress in influencing  political and judicial institutions on priority issues. 

The main implementation modality for the Mechanism is through public calls for project proposals.  Ibis will, based on the objectives and planned outputs defined in the programme document and the context analysis, make proposals to the SC on the calls for proposals to be made. Ibisen Guatemala, which is an international NGO, won the contract in the open procurement process performed by the Embassy of Sweden,  Guatemala, for the administrative responsibility for the Mechanism, see the Embassy&#xB4;s decision GUA/UTV/2014/03, dated 11 February, 2014. The total Swedish contribution to the intervention will be 49 million SEK for the period March 2014 - December 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To contribute to a greater respect for the collective rights of indigenous peoples, as stipulated in the ILO Convention number 169, and to the active participation of the indigenous, men and women in the political decision-making at local and national levels..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dev. country based NGOs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">67673.5812475401</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">191252.2985301271</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">51675.5682814235</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">67673.58124754</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">191252.298530127</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">51675.5682814235</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-03-01">367136.401405</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-28">27814.9127538302</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">39858.7034796426</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-02-28">50945.3928558718</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-28">36874.4071275195</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">66331.0037606919</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">37101.4686866051</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-28">51675.6115234033</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the external evaluation, the program has contributed to the establishment of a collective political protagonist/actor with organizing capacity and competency for dialogue and proposal development to define national and regional policies. Examples of the strength built among indigenous communities, organizations, and authorities supported by the program can be seen in the proposals, follow-up, and discussion around the legislative initiatives submitted to the Congress of the Republic (Among others: The Law for Midwife Dignification (Decree No. 3-2010) and the Specific comprehensive law for protection and maintenance of weaving, garments and collective intellectual property (Initiative No. 52-47) through Women&#x2019;s Association for the Development (AFEDES).
In addition, there were seven sentences/Ruling from the Constitutional Court on issue of Land and Territory and one sentence from the Supreme Court. With regards litigation and appeals filed; processes to reconstitute indigenous communities; various rulings handed down by the Constitutional Court in favor of indigenous peoples and their rights; and the jurisprudence set by these rulings. The legal rulings are particularly focused on the rights to Free, Prior, and Informed Consent, bilingual intercultural education, an interculturally rooted healthcare system, recovery, restitution and regulation of land seized over the course of different historical contexts, and individual and collective reparations for indigenous communities affected by the internal armed conflict or by extractive industries projects.
Other relevant outcomes are related to: a) developing internal decision-making systems around natural resources and the right to consultation and consent according to indigenous peoples&apos; worldviews and the provisions established in International Labor Organization (ILO) convention 169; b) greater capacity for alliance-building and collaboration to position, exercise, and defend indigenous rights in decision-making spaces; c) budget allocation for municipal and departmental policies and programs. Another important outcome was also achieved in productive processes promoted in the communities, especially involving indigenous women who had been victims of violence in income-generating initiatives, helping them to meet their basic needs and ensure food security.
Land and territory
The right to land and protection of territory was a central issue for the program. Land and territory are not only issues of historic and structural importance for the country, they are also a pressing community demand and a transcendental component for the continuity and lives of indigenous peoples. In this context, the program provided legal advice and accompaniment to indigenous authorities and organizations seeking solutions to current conflicts, as well as the resolution of emblematic cases to restore rights to community lands, defense, protection, shelter, and community administration of territory.
The principal cases accompanied over the course of the program are related to the restoration and regulation of a total of 1,710 caballer&#xED;as (over 76,000 hectares). The term &#x201C;caballeria&#x201D; is a historical unit of measurement that varies by country, but in Guatemala is approximately equivalent to 45.16 hectares- of land. Of this total, 81 caballer&#xED;as (3,617 hectares) of communal land were returned to the Maya Chajoma&apos; people&apos;s Chuarrancho indigenous community (Guatemala), benefiting approximately 8,535 families; 635 caballer&#xED;as (28,359 hectares) for the Chort&#xED; indigenous communities of Camot&#xE1;n, for 3,478 families (Chiquimula); and 694 caballer&#xED;as (30,994 hectares) for the Q&apos;eqchi&apos; indigenous communities of El Estor, Izabal, for approximately 4,720 families. An additional 300 caballer&#xED;as (13,398 hectares) are still under litigation at the Constitutional Court; despite the efforts undertaken by the Indigenous Municipality of Solol&#xE1; (Solol&#xE1;) and the Council of Q&apos;eqchi&apos; Authorities of Los Copones (Ixc&#xE1;n, Quich&#xE9;), there is still no judicial ruling forthcoming.
Land restitution processes were fundamentally advanced through strategic litigation underpinned by historical, anthropological and documentary research. The information generated by these research initiatives has also served to strengthen community identity, rebuild historical memory surrounding the displacement from their lands, and understand the historical nature of the dispute around land rights and territory. The research has also opened political and legal space to continue to expand the files and address new cases. Specifically, the documentary and records research helped to uncover new evidence to demonstrate the historic ownership of community lands, such as the cases of Totonicap&#xE1;n and Solol&#xE1;. Recovery of communal lands brings up a series of challenges, including the creation of community land maps, land management for territorial governance, delivery of community land deeds, and others. To address these challenges, the program supported the creation of procedural manuals designed to fit the community reality and world view.
Access to justice
The program promoted access to the service of justice nationally and internationally as a core pillar for the full exercise of the individual and collective human rights of indigenous men and women, seeking to set significant jurisprudence. The main actions undertaken in this field included support to indigenous organizations in litigation, legal aid, specialized studies and the design of a roadmap for compliance with legal rulings. Additionally, the program enabled access, engagement, and familiarity for indigenous peoples&apos; and indigenous authorities&apos; representatives with international and United Nations organizations for human rights protection.
These connections included promoting direct participation in thematic hearings at the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights -IACHR (&#x201C;Human Rights Situation for Indigenous Peoples in the Context of Oil Palm Agro-Industry Activities in Guatemala&quot; at the IACHR in its 156 Ordinary Session, seeking to open political and legal channels to influence the search for justice, for the State of Guatemala to take on its responsibility for the defense of the rights of indigenous peoples) the 86th session of the Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination (CERD).
A delegation of indigenous peoples presented a shadow report in Geneva and hold extra-official meetings with members of the CERD prior to the state exam and in the preparations for the Permanent Forum meeting of experts on indigenous issues, with the intent of influencing the agenda and recommendations from the 15th term of sessions for the states.&#xA0;
On a national level, the program supported indigenous organizations and authorities to strengthen their participation in the justice reform process promoted by the three branches of the state. In this process, the authorities and organizations participated actively and submitted proposals to reform the constitution of the republic in recognition of the existing indigenous legal system (In the context of the launch of the dialogue process for justice sector reforms, the Mechanism promoted a process of dialogue, analysis, and advocacy among indigenous peoples to push for recognition of the indigenous justice system in the reforms, as well as the democratization of the ordinary justice system. Along these lines, the Mechanism promoted and undertook a series of events with indigenous peoples&apos; authorities and organizations to analyze the proposed reforms). One of the relevant outcomes from this process was to position the indigenous peoples&apos; justice system on the national agenda. This outcome not only contributed to opening a debate on the topic and revealing entrenched prejudice against the indigenous peoples and their justice systems; it also helped to position the importance of coordination between the indigenous justice systems and harmonize these systems with the conventional justice system.&#xA0;
Additionally, the program accompanied and monitored several emblematic or high-impact cases from the internal armed conflict. One of these cases is that of 36 Ach&#xED; women survivors of sexual violence. This case was accompanied by Bufete Jur&#xED;dico de Rabinal a local third party partner of the Mechanism. Nonetheless, the presiding judge decided to absolve the defendants, dismissing the charges against three of them and granting a provisional closure for the other three argumenting lack of evidence. The Bufete Juridico representing the 36 plaintiffs has appealed the court resolution.
Another case refers to forced disappearances and crimes against humanity committed by members of Military Zone 21. This case was accompanied by Asociaci&#xF3;n de Desarrollo de V&#xED;ctimas de las Verapaces [Verapaces Victims Development Association, ADIVIMA], as one of the claimants in the process. This case is better known as CREOMPAZ, as the area previously occupied by Military Zone 21 is currently home to the Regional Training Command for Peace-Keeping Operations (CREOMPAZ), located in Cob&#xE1;n, Alta Verapaz. The program has contributed in conducting research, supporting public hearings and elaborating legal strategies for the case in close coordination with other plaintiffs.
On an international level, several cases have been filed with the Inter-American Human Rights System. For example, the program monitored and supported two cases of crimes against humanity and human rights violations against the Ach&#xED; indigenous peoples. One of these cases centers on land seizure and displacement of 85 families from the community of La Laguna Chisaqcab o Suscab in the municipality of Cubulco, department of Baja Verapaz. During the internal armed conflict, this community was the target of systematic persecution and inhabitants were forced to abandon their lands. The other case focuses on disappearance, forced displacement, and extra-judicial killings, known as the Chichupac Case (Rabinal, Baja Verapaz).
The first case, La Laguna, was filed with the Inter-American Human Rights Court (IAHRC), and it is currently in process; further information has been requested from the survivors. A notification of admissibility for this case is expected this year from the IAHRC. The Chichupac Case was filed by Bufete Jur&#xED;dico Popular de Rabinal with the IAHRC in 2007, and admitted to the docket in 2010. In November 2016, the IAHRC issued a ruling concluding that the State of Guatemala was responsible for human rights violations, and recommended individual and collective reparations for the affected people, with proper mechanisms established for this end. In March of this year (2019), the Presidential Coordinating Commission for Executive Policy on Human Rights (COPREDEH) and the Ministry of Public Finance (MINFIN) initiated the process of individual reparations, with a group of 24 people from the village of Chichupac and neighboring communities. The amount allocated for reparations for compensation of material and immaterial harm comes ton 1,035,000 quetzales (nearly 120,000 Euros). In late May, 195 people signed a payment agreement for compensations for a total of 8,929,713 quetzales (approximately 1,033,000 Euros).
Another case accompanied by the program refers to the comprehensive reparations process for victims of the harm produced by the Chixoy hydroelectric dam. This case was successful in bringing individual and collective compensation for the affected families. The individual reparations amounts currently to 195,000,000 quetzales (22,600,000 Euros) for 2,258 indigenous Ach&#xED; families (of a total of 2,329), along with collective reparations in the form of projects for road-building, water and environmental sanitation, and others. This means that only 71 families have yet to receive the individual economic compensation package.
While the program has undertaken large-scale efforts to make progress under this axis, it is one of the areas of the intervention with the fewest achievements, as there are serious obstacles in access to justice. As an example a bill of law (the National Reconciliation Law) is debated in congress and if approved it would allow amnesty for crimes against humanity committed during the 36 years of the internal armed conflict.
Indigenous women&apos;s rights and gender equality
Indigenous women&apos;s human rights and gender equality are strategic through-lines for the program and essential elements in the project objectives and outcomes. The program thus supported indigenous women&apos;s organizations and authorities such as Asociaci&#xF3;n Pol&#xED;tica de Mujeres Mayas Moloj; Movimiento Nacional de Comadronas [National Midwives Movement]; Movimiento Nacional de Tejedoras [National Weavers Movement]; Consorcio de Asociaciones de Mujeres de Santiago Atitl&#xE1;n [Consortium of Women&apos;s Associations of Santiago Atitl&#xE1;n]; Asociaci&#xF3;n de Mujeres Nuevo Horizonte [New Horizon Women&apos;s Association]; Asociaci&#xF3;n de Mujeres AMOIXQUIC [AMOIXQUIC Women&apos;s Association], among others to build conditions and institutional structures committed to women&apos;s rights and dignity. To do this, studies and research were conducted, policies, strategies, and campaigns were designed and implemented, and a training school was established to focus on women&apos;s rights and gender equality. Over the course of the program, these interventions contributed to an increase of 1,437 women participating in community authority structures and indigenous peoples&apos; authorities. Additionally, the program accompanied and advised victims in cases of violence (claims of physical or sexual assault, psychological aggression, child support, and others).
Additionally, a &quot;National Mayan Women&apos;s Agenda&quot; was constructed as a lobbying and negotiation tool in decision-making spaces, including engagement with the Congress of the Republic and different institutions within the executive branch. It is worth noting that despite these efforts and the proposals developed by Moloj within broader alliances with other women&apos;s organizations, the proposed reforms to the Elections and Political Parties Law ultimately failed in a second vote.
In addition to these efforts, the National Midwives Movement worked with other indigenous authorities such as the Municipality of Solol&#xE1; and women&apos;s organizations to fortify the role of midwives within the indigenous peoples&apos; health system and their linkage to the official healthcare system. Concretely, the movements filed a complaint to the Constitutional Court for omission by state institutions, given their failure to guarantee the sexual and reproductive health of indigenous women, and their lack of knowledge, respect, and promotion of the rights of midwives. The Constitutional Court concluded that the state had failed to uphold its responsibilities and requested that the necessary legal, technical, and operational steps be taken to promote respect for indigenous women&apos;s rights and midwives. Lastly, the program continued to provide legal aid and accompaniment in these cases, and undertook ongoing municipal-level campaigns for the prevention of gender-based violence. Indigenous authorities from 48 Cantones in Totonicap&#xE1;n and Solol&#xE1; and other relevant local indigenous women were involved in these campaigns.&#xA0;
Exercise of economic and social rights
In this field, the program has supported production and economic processes with women&apos;s and indigenous peoples&apos; organizations. These processes occurred through citizen rights training initiatives, helping to build greater awareness of rights (economic, social, and political rights), improved living conditions, and greater capacity to engage with the state.
The program supported the development of production processes with indigenous peoples&apos; organizations, especially for indigenous women victims of violence, to help generate economic income and contribute to the economic rights of approximately 2,705 families from different communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52080025" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
