<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5520002501-GTM-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">20 Anniversary Guatemalan Peace Accords</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">20 Anniversary Guatemalan Peace Accords</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consensus is reached among different Guatemalan sectors, about the relevance of the 1996 Peace Accords, as an agenda for inclusive and democratic development, addressing the challenges of strengthening of the Guatemalan democracy, with the purpose of creating support of relevant stakeholders for the implementation of pending issues and reforms included in the Peace Accords in the areas of Human Rights and Justice, Gender, Indigenous Peoples, Agrarian situation and Public Security.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Fredsavtalen som  undertecknades f&#xF6;r 20 &#xE5;r sedan har endast delvis genomf&#xF6;rts och utg&#xF6;r fortsatt en mycket viktig utg&#xE5;ngspunkt f&#xF6;r utvecklingspolitiken i ett land pr&#xE4;glat av djupa sociala klyftor och konflikter. Insatsen syftar till &#xF6;ka f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;elsen och v&#xE4;cka debatt kring Fredsavtalen som en relevant utvecklingsagenda f&#xF6;r Guatemala, och d&#xE4;rmed stimulera till reformer f&#xF6;r dess fulla genomf&#xF6;rande. Insatsen innefattar st&#xF6;d till fyra guatemalanska civilsamh&#xE4;llsorganisationer med h&#xF6;g trov&#xE4;rdighet. Organisationerna kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra analys samt ordna seminarium och andra aktiviteter f&#xF6;r att uppm&#xE4;rksamma Fredsavtalens betydelse.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention targets the 20 anniversary of the Peace Accords, as an opportunity to address the pending issues of the peace process for the building of a strong democratic institutions, which facilitates the protection of human rights, the economical development, and the inclusion of indigenous peoples, among other aspects. The counterparts of this program, four Guatemalan civil society organizations ( Fundacion Propaz, Demos, Fundaci&#xF3;n Esquipulas and Fundamaya) will conduct research, analysis, advocacy and organize public debates to promote an informed discussion on the Peace Accords and raise awareness about the importance of addressing the pending issues of those Peace Accords.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Propaz</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundacion Propaz</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">385671.7115643079</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">385671.7115643078</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-01">385671.711564</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">385671.7115643079</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results of the contribution do not provide evidence of reaching consensus and support of relevant stakeholders for implementation of pending issues and reforms of the Peace Accords. While the general expected results of the contribution were not achieved, some small, contextual results were achieved within the four separate small projects constituting the contribution:
Fundacion Esquipulas implemented project centered on interesting the younger generations, the &quot;millenials&quot;, on the historic importance of the regional peace processes and reconciliation, through public events directed to decision makers, government authorities and the youth. The Central American Encounter of Emerging Leaders brought together 25 youth leaders from Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Nicaragua, Costa Rica and Panama to create a network and platform to replicate the experience in other countries. While this effort to create bridges and strengthen youth leadership regionally was valuable, there is no information what kind of follow-up Fundacion Esquipulas is giving the initiative to make the efforts more sustainable.
Instituto DEMOS sensitized youth of the Peace Accord messages through street theater, identifying current challenges in the constiruction of peace. A total of 205 youth from Guatemala and El Salvador participated in different activities aimed at promoting political&#xA0;conciousness and participation in youth. According to the final report, DEMOS estimates that street theather is an effective communication method with high potential for promoting political participation and impact. The Embassy has no information how DEMOS has carried on work with the youth who were formed through the project.
Fundacion Maya implemented a small project to provide opportunity for leaders and authorities of 10 indigenous communities to reflect on the Peace Accords and contruction of peace in Guatemala from the perspective of the indigenous mayan communities. Serious challenges were identified in the construction of participatory,&#xA0;pluricultural, multi ethinic and multilingual democracy where ethnic minorities can participate on equal terms exercising their ethnic identity and rights. The most important unexpected result was the recognition of national institutions and authorities of the role and function of indigenous communities and authorities in the construction of peace during an activity in the National Palace. The project played a role in fomenting a common and joined position of indigenous authorities for the promotion and defence of their rights, positioning them as relevant actors in the national arena.
Fundacion Propaz implemented a project which sought to bring together different sectors to dialogue and reflect on implementation and challenges of the Peace Accords and construction of democracy,&#xA0;with the intention of giving new meaning to the ideals of the Peace Accords in current context. Additionally, investigation was conducted and published to document and reflect on the achievements of the Peace Accords. Propaz implemented with some success all its planned activities;&#xA0;however, real impact and sustainable results of these efforts are not measurable.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55200025" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
