<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-IND846</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Collaboration with the FABC for Ecological Communication and Youth Mobilisation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Commission for Ecology of the Conference of Catholic Bishops of India (CCBI) and the FABC (through its Office for Human Development / Climate Change Desk) recognise the need and urgency to respond to socio-ecological crisis evident in the cry of the Earth, the cry of the poor, and the cry of the young. 

Building on the Commission for Ecology&apos;s previous experience, programmes and feedback, this project proposes to: 1. Make available a booklet on ecological best practices to bishops, parishes, formation and religious houses in seven Asian and Indian languages, viz. Bengali, Hindi, Malay, Mandarin, Sinhala, Tamil and Vietnamese, and 2. Expand its Eco Youth Movement to Asia by organising five regional exposure programmes and conducting one hybrid youth event 

The overall goal of this project is to demonstrate the cultural palatability of ecological conversion in India in the context of language and involvement of the youth demographic as a model for replication in other Asian countries. The Commission for Ecology&apos;s mission and this project is well aligned with CAFOD&#x2019;s Our Common Home Strategic Framework.  The project will: 1. Bring about positive impacts on vulnerable youth and influence Church leaders for systemic change 2. Amplify local voice, agency and leadership by strengthening the capacity of bishops, priests and religious  3. Create a culture of encounter between the Church hierarchy and the laity 4. Facilitate an on-going ecological conversion.
 
It is important to note that though CAFOD does not have an active presence in India, much of the Commission for Ecology&apos;s work at the CCBI has a regional Asian reach and prioritises addressing the challenges of climate change across Asia, aligning well with CAFOD&apos;s work in the region. The FABC referred this project to CAFOD given its regional reach and it will be funded by the AME regional grants budget on a one off basis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="IND846" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="IND846" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commission for Ecology of the Conference of Catholic Bishops of India (CCBI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="IND846" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="31130" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">9999</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55742">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-02-28">9999</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="70873">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-02-28">9999</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commission for Ecology of the Conference of Catholic Bishops of India (CCBI)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
