<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28819</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulftainer Corp</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulftainer Company Limited (Gulftainer or the Company), a UAE Limited Liability Company founded in 1976, has decided to develop multiple ports and logistics activities in Iraq (the Project). The Company intends to team up and invest alongside various local partners and benefit from the countrys reconstruction efforts as well as the expected transport and logistics needs of the Country. Gulftainer has developed plans to invest into the following ventures in different parts of Iraq:     Operation and management of container and cargo terminal / berths awarded to Gulftainer at Umm Qasr Port, located about 70 km south of Basra and owned by the state-owned General Council for the Ports of Iraq. As part of the agreement, Gulftainer is expected to undertake some civil works to upgrade the berth structure and invest in new cargo handling equipment.    In partnership with various entities, development and operation of transport and logistics services for the oil and gas industry in Northern Iraq. Services to be provided include on-site and off-site transport, plant hire, storage, warehousing, freight forwarding, crane hire and workshop services.    Transport and logistics services throughout Iraq with an initial focus on Northern Iraq. Development and operation of a Cargo Village at Sulaimaniyah airport in partnership with a local partner. The facility is expected to target general cargo such as foodstuff and perishables as well as oil &amp; gas related equipment.  In addition, Gulftainer is also exploring additional logistics and transport projects in different parts of the country especially in Southern Iraq in order to address the upcoming growth of the UmmQasr / Basrah / Baghdad transport corridor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Once regarded as having one of the Middle Easts most comprehensive transportation systems, Iraqs transport and logistics infrastructure has suffered from more than two decades of neglect and underinvestment. Rehabilitation of such infrastructure is a major national and regional trade issue. Gulftainer investments in Umm Qasr Port and Sulaimaniyah airport should help solve this issue and thus contribute to Iraq integration in the regional and global economy.  Iraq heavily relies on imports for its consumer goods and for its reconstruction program. Cost effective transport of imported goods is therefore critical to Iraqs economy. World Banks Doing Business indicators however shows that Iraq is facing difficulties in terms of logistics performances. Gulftainers investments to modernize one of Umm Qasr berth combined with its experience to efficiently manage container terminals should contribute to improve the situation.  At present, a substantial portion of goods coming into Iraq are off-loaded at ports in the neighboring countries such as Kuwait, Turkey and Jordan and are then transported into the country by road, which tends to increase the time and cost of delivering the goods to the end consumer. The Project will have a significant impact on reducing these impediments to trade in Iraq and foster the countrys reconstruction efforts along with the economic growth and development.     Efficient and well-developed transport and logistics infrastructure is an essential component for the expected growth in the countrys Oil &amp; Gas production &amp; export-related activities and the project would play a strong role in facilitating these improvements.  In addition to its direct impact on trade, the Project will also contribute towards socio-economic development through the creation of several hundred jobs, reduction in the cost of goods paid by the end consumer (through reduction of costs incurred in the transportation process) as well as substantial royalty payments to the Government of Iraq.  Through its involvement in Iraq (Umm Qasr port in particular), Gulftainer will also play a strong role in training and improving the skills of the employees that would be seconded from IMTC, help introduce industry best-practice and contribute its valuable know-how in managing ports and logistics operations, which would help in improving the overall efficiency of the sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GULFTAINER COMPANY LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28819" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-09-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andrew Barley Terminal Manager Gulftainer Co. Ltd. Office C/o. South Oasis Co. Ltd. Next to Minawi Basha Hotel Basrah, IRAQ Tel : 00964 (0) 7703227749 Mobile : 00964 (0) 7800253089 (Zain - Iraq) Mobile : 00964 (0) 7704975282 (Asia Cell - Iraq) Mobile : 00971 (0) 504817153 (UAE)</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MENA Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-MENA Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to be located in the northern part of Iraq, i.e. Kurdistan (the areas of Chemchemal and Sulaymaniyah) and in the southern part of Iraq in Umm Qasr, about 70 km south of Basra.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>26.0000000000 50.5500000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CA - Storage (Including Agricultural Products)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $45.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-09-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-09-30">45000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-09-30">45000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GULFTAINER COMPANY LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28819/gulftainer-corp">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
