<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9552</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Societe des Caoutchoucs de Grand Bereby</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name:    Cote DIvoire - SOGB       Region:Sub-Saharan Africa   Sector:   Project No:009552   Projected Board Date:June 11, 1999   Company Name:Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; des Caoutchoucs de Grand B&#xE9;r&#xE9;by (&quot;SOGB&quot;)    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	SOGB is controlled by B&#xE9;r&#xE9;by Finances (Befin), which owns 65.2% of the Company, along with the Government of C&#xF4;te dIvoire, and private investors. Befin is in turn controlled by Compagnie Internationale de Cultures (Intercultures), an affiliate of the Belgian holding company Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Financi&#xE8;re des Caoutchoucs(SOCFIN), and other investors include IFC, DEG, PROPARCO, and Compagnie des Caoutchoucs de Pakidi&#xE9;. SOCFIN is part of the Rivaud and Bollor&#xE9; groups, which have large investments in Africa. SOCFIN directly or indirectly owns oil palm companies in C&#xF4;te dIvoire, Cameroon, Malaysia, and Indonesia, and currently manages 169,584 ha of oil palm plantations and 36,600 ha of rubber plantations in Asia and Africa. SOGB is managed by Socfin Consultant Services (SOCFINCO), a key affiliate of SOCFIN, which specializes in providing management as well as consulting services to the oil palm and rubber industries.        Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total project cost is estimated at US$23.8 million. The cost of the agricultural component (Phase I) to be partly financed by IFC is estimated at US$10.3 million.The IFC loan of US$6million will finance about 58% of the Phase I investment program, while the remaining funding will be financed by the revenues of the Company&apos;&apos;s rubber operations.    Location of project and Description of site    	The project is located on the SOGB concession, 25-km northeast of Grand-B&#xE9;r&#xE9;by in the southwestern part of C&#xF4;te dIvoire.     Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	SOGB is the leading rubber producer in C&#xF4;te dIvoire.  The Company exploits a 35,000 ha concession, out of which 15,000 ha are planted with rubber trees, mainly on the highlands. The project comprises two phases, consisting of: (1) the establishment of a 5,000 ha oil palm plantation, in the low-lying lands of the concession, and (2) the construction of a 20 Mt. per hour oil extraction mill in year 2003, to process the plantation&apos;&apos;s palm fruit bunches. The project will enable the Company to optimize the use of its land, continue improving its overall efficiency, and diversify from rubber production. It will take advantage of the strong demand for edible oil in the Ivorian market and the UMEOA countries.     IFC has already invested in the Company through the acquisition of 16.7% of the shares of Befin when SOGB was privatized in 1995, and is interested in supporting the Company&apos;&apos;s long-term development and its efforts to improve further its efficiency. IFC will provide long-term financing that is not otherwise available in Ivory Coast as existing long-term liquidities have usually shorter terms and have dried up following a boom in investments over the last few years. The project will create about 250 direct jobs and additional contract jobs for field maintenance and harvest work. In addition, it will enable the Company to improve further the efficiency of its rubber operations through the redeployment of part of its staff. It will also have a positive environmental impact by reducing fire hazards through planting and thereby preserve the primary forests located on the concession.      Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure and the following potential environmental, social, health and safety impacts of the project were analyzed: impacts to natural habitat, potential impacts related to economic displacement, integrated pest management, air emissions, solid waste handling and management, water use and waste water quality and occupational health and safety.    The area to be developed comprises land cleared for rice cultivation, low bush and scrub vegetation and degraded secondary forest and there will be no loss of primary or good quality secondary forest or other significant natural habitats. No new land is to be acquired and no economic displacement will occur. The company will implement standard Integrated Pest Management approaches as the oil palms develop and no banned or restricted agrochemicals will be used.  Air emissions from the CPO mill will be in compliance with World Bank Group requirements, waste water will be treated and used for irrigation and solid waste will be disposed of as fertilizer or for road construction purposes.    The company provides training in the use and handling of all agrochemicals and provides worker health facilities (including a hospital).  Employees who work with chemicals receive regular health checks on a six monthly basis and all employees who use agrochemicals are provided with appropriate personal protective equipment.     	    The  is  from the InfoShop.        Date SPI sent to InfoShop:     May 11, 1999      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Societe des Caoutchoucs de Grand Bereby</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9552" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-11-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cote D&apos;Ivoire</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="CI-Cote D&apos;Ivoire">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.0000000000 -5.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AI - Natural Fibers (Cotton, Sisal, Jute, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $6.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-11-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-11-12">6000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-11-12">6000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Societe des Caoutchoucs de Grand Bereby</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9552/societe-des-caoutchoucs-de-grand-bereby">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
