<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>KE-KRA-P051502549C-001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="KE-KRA-P051502549C" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders-Kenya</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safety and security of human rights defenders</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Secure the operating environment of HRDs through progressive enactment of enabling and/or elimination of restrictive laws and policies 2. Facilitate meaningful contribution to the safety and security of HRDs by various stakeholders 3. Ensure responsive and appropriate protection mechanisms for HRDs at risk or in distress 4. Strengthen the institutional development and organisational performance of NCHRD-K</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Defenders</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The funded project, Safety and Security of Human Rights Defenders, aims to promote the safety and security of human rights defenders in Kenya through advocacy, capacity building and protection. In order to effectively pursue the set out strategic objectives, NCHRD will seek to realize four (4) key outcomes: Strategic Outcome 1: Conducive environment for HRDs progressively secured at county and national levels. The long-term security and safety of HRDs is to be secured through promotion of a conducive environment at both national and sub national level in which respect for human rights is accorded to all. Strategic Outcome 2: Contribution of key stakeholders to safety and security of HRDs strengthened Safety and security of HRDs depends on the individual actions and interventions of a variety of key stakeholders including state and non-state actors and those who provide vital services to HRDs at risk - lawyers, medical personnel and counsellors. However, enhancing the respective capacities of these key stakeholders is critical in ensuring they intervene as optimally as possible. Likewise, empowering HRDs (as individuals and organizations) is also a key preventive measure. Strategic Outcome 3: Responsive and sustainable protection mechanisms for HRDs in Kenya strengthened NCHRD&#x2019;s core business is about responding to HRDs facing harm. The Coalition will therefore pursue such strategies as legal aid, medical and social support, provision of refuge and relocation. Where the response required goes beyond the scope and resource capacity of the Coalition, such cases shall be referred to relevant organizations. NCHRD will also pursue options aimed at guaranteeing the sustainability of these interventions. Strategic Outcome 4: Institutional development, organizational performance and sustainability of NCHRD strengthened. NCHRD will pursue measures aimed at enhancing its ability to discharge its mandate in an effective, efficient and sustainable manner. The institutional framework of the organization shall be reviewed and improved continuously to ensure effective governance of the organization. Performance management is key to ensuring the organization delivers its obligations to various stakeholders. Sustainability measures shall be implemented to guarantee the continued existence and vibrancy of the organization.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P051502549C-001" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="KE-KRA-P051502549C" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders-Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="KE-KRA-P051502549C-001" crs-channel-code="20000" ref="KE-KRA-P051502549C" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders-Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001408" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders, Kenya (NCHRD-K) is a membership organization registered in Kenya as a Trust. It was founded in 2007 in response to the challenges faced by human rights defenders in the course of their work.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kamau Ngugi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 7216200100</telephone>
   <email>info@hrdcoalition.org</email>
   <website>https://hrdcoalition.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.POX 26309 - 00100 Nairobi</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-01-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2018-06-13">42651772</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="999ORTGS5716218">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2018-07-24">20132703</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the first tranche of a two year project to carry out Safety and Security of Human Rights Defenders funded by Embassy of The Kingdom of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001408" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry Of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="KE-KRA-P051502549C-001" ref="KE-KRA-P051502549C" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders-Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="999ORTGS2431119">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="KES" value-date="2019-03-25">20386480</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the second tranche of the two year project on Safety and Security of Human Rights Defenders in Kenya funded by the Embassy of the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000001408" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="KE-KRA-P051502549C-001" ref="KE-KRA-P051502549C" type="22"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="VIDEO/MP4" url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-wVmerT8KE4">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRDK 10 years celebrations video supported by the grant</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-04-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional Development, Organisational Performance and Sustainability of National Coalition of Human Rights Defenders Strengthened.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD will pursue measures aimed at enhancing its ability to discharge its mandate in an effective, efficient and sustainable manner. The institutional framework of the organisation shall be reviewed and improved continuously to ensure effective governance of the organisation. The strategies to be pursued hereunder include: &#x2022; Strengthening the policy environment of NCHRD: this will entail review of policies of the organization as well as adoption of new ones in relation of human resources, communications and membership development &#x2022; enhancing human resources management: this will be critical in streamlining performance management at NCHRD, using best practices and modern tools &#x2022; strengthening corporate governance structures and processes: NCHRD will maintain its governance structures, observe statutory meetings and ensure an active and engaged membership &#x2022; Enhancing monitoring, evaluation, reporting and learning (MERL)system: to improve generation, management and sharing of knowledge to support decision-making, corrective actions and learning, NCHRD will adopt tools, frameworks and processes that strengthen its MERL system &#x2022; Continuously expanding a diversified and stable resources base for NCHRD sustainable: NCHRD will develop a suitability strategy which shall guide resource mobilization and investments to guarantee the continued viability of the organization. &#x2022; Enhancing administrative and coordination capacity: NCHRD will continuously procure and upgrade its secretariat equipment and facilities to ensure optimum level of service delivery and coordination of its networks.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity, project/programs reviews and evaluation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conduct activity, project/programs reviews and evaluation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor engagement activities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Carry out meetings with donor and development partners.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="1" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop and adopt gender policy</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop and adopt gender policy</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="1" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional Strategic Planning</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K Strategic Plan is due 2019-12-31 hence need for a new SP 2020-2024</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="1" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Annual periodic system audit</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K conducted audit for financial statements for the year 2018</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="2" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Board Meetings and Annual General Meeting</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K conducts board meetings on quarterly basis and AGM once per year.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="4" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procure and maintain secretariat equipment and facilities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Procure office equipment, payment of rent, utilities and office cleaning</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="52" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="52"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project staff cost</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Payment for gratuity, insurance scheme (Medical, life insurance, GPA)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="60" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Responsive and Sustainable Protection Mechanisms for Human Rights Defenders in Kenya Strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD&#x2019;s core business is about responding to HRDs facing harm. The Coalition will therefore pursue such strategies as legal aid, medical and social support, provision of refuge and relocation. The strategies to be pursued under this outcome include: &#x2022; Rendering Rapid protection response to diverse HRDs at risk rendered in a timely and efficient manner: NCHRD will employ diverse protection responses and provide a communication infrastructure for receiving and processing requests for interventions &#x2022; Strengthening active support networks for protection strengthened: NCHRD will mobilize and participate in joint activities with other organization that provide protection services and support to HRDs with a view to harmonizing approaches and promoting synergies &#x2022; Continuously Improving standardized case management procedures and practices: this will be done to ensure protection responses are within acceptable range of best practices. NCHRD-K will maintain a case database which will be analyzed regularly to assess trends and map interventions &#x2022; Enhancing sustainability of protection support to HRDs: NCHRD will put in place sustainable mechanisms to guarantee provision of responses beyond the life of this strategic plan e.g. protection fund, referrals, mentorships and advocacy for promulgation of Nairobi as a hub city (to provide safe refuge for HRDs from other countries).</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.DOCUMENT+JSON" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/ADVOCACY-AND-PROTECTION-20200706100756.docx">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Responsive and sustainable protection mechanisms for HRDs in Kenya strengthened</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The strategy was implemented under the Protection Programme with the aim to develop appropriate preventative and reactive intervention strategies for the protection of HRDs. The programme analyses the HRDs&#x2019; working environment on an ongoing basis and develops security management strategies accordingly. This is done through risk assessments and fact-finding missions on reported cases of threats and violations of HRDs&#x2019; rights, to ensure the safety of HRDs and bring those responsible to justice. The protection programme provides legal, medical, psychosocial and safety support to HRDs at risk.</narrative>
    </description>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-07-06"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rapid protection response to diverse HRDs at risk rendered in a timely and efficient manner</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K Protection unit based in Nairobi respond to urgent protection needs of HRDs through relocation, bail, legal intervention, medical and counselling support,</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="15" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K Protection unit based in Nairobi respond to urgent protection needs of HRDs through relocation, bail, legal intervention, medical and counselling support</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="27"></target>
     <actual value="27"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active support networks for protection strengthened</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Convene protection support networks at county and national level</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="2" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nascent support networks for protection of HRDs at county level</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Standardised case management procedures and practices continuously improved</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K conducted a case management protocol development</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="1" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Need regular review to respond to the diversity of HRDs at risk, including marginalised and minority HRDs</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability of protection support to HRDs enhanced</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment and maintenance of a protection fund to support HRDs at risk Organising placements, mentorship, and fellowship programme for HRDs at risk Engage in advocacy for promulgation of Nairobi as a hub city for HRDs at risk</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="1" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection support for HRDs dependent on project funding</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="6"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution of Key Stakeholders to Safety and Security of Human Rights Defenders Strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safety and security of HRDs depends on the individual actions and interventions of a variety of key stakeholders including state and non-state actors and those who provide vital services to HRDs at risk - lawyers, medical personnel and counsellors.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.DOCUMENT+JSON" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/CAPACITY-BUILDING-REPORT-FOR-RNE-20200706090746.docx">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTRIBUTION OF KEY STAKEHOLDERS TO SAFETY AND SECURITY OF HRDS STRENGTHENED</narrative>
    </title>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-07-06"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacities in security management, monitoring and documentation and sustainability enhanced in 10 regional networks in Kenya</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">HRDs will be trained in security management and monitoring, documenting and reporting</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="41" year="2018">
     <location ref="Kenya"></location>
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of members of target Human Rights Defenders Networks profess basic knowledge and skills on above topics</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="21"></target>
     <actual value="21"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced capacities of service providers (including doctors, lawyers &amp; counsellors) in provision of quality and responsive support to HRDs in 47 counties and at least 2 thematic groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K planing to enhance the capacity of our service providers and create a service provider database.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="20" year="2018">
     <location ref="Kenya"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
     <actual value="47"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced capacity of individual HRDs in critical skills for their safety and security</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K has developed a comprehensive training manual for Trainer of Trainers in security management for HRDs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="30" year="2018">
     <location ref="Kenya"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="70"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced capacities for policy and legislative advocacy on human rights issues among HRDs and Duty Bearers</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge on human rights issues has increased among both stakeholders and duty bearers</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="15" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="70"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conducive Environment for Human Rights Defenders Progressively Secured at County and National Level</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Progressive elimination of unlawful and undue restrictions to HRD work at county and national levels: this will entail policy, legislative and legal advocacy aimed at either repeal or invalidation of restrictive laws and administrative actions but also the enactment of enabling measures by governments at both national and county levels. NCHRD will seek to influence treaty mechanisms that have the potential for exerting pressure on the Kenyan state to realize the desirable policy or legislative actions. &#x2022; Enhancing integration of human rights-based approach (HRBA) in policy development and programming at county and national levels with adequate participation of HRDs: NCHRD will empower HRDs to participate in national and county development planning processes wherein they shall advocate for adoption of HRBA. It is expected that the resultant development frameworks will embrace human rights principles and thereby create an enabling environment. The mere presence of the HRDs in these process will in itself foster better understanding among duty bearers of HRDs and their work. &#x2022; Enhancing profile and public perception of HRDs at county, national and international levels: actions that seek to project HRDs and their work in positive light among key stakeholders and the public shall be pursued. This is meant to build public support and appreciation for HRDs and their work and hence enable them to operate freely. &#x2022; Enhancing collaborative actions and synergies for change among HRDs at all levels: advocacy on difficult issues is more impactful and feasible if pursued collaboratively by actors that share similar ideals and aspirations. NCHRD will therefore actively mobilize for support for its advocacy agenda and reciprocally join forces with other like-minded actors seeking positive change.</narrative>
   </description>
   <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.DOCUMENT+JSON" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/ADVOCACY-AND-PROTECTION-20200706100756.docx">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONDUCIVE ENVIRONMENT FOR HRDS PROGRESSIVELY SECURED AT COUNTY AND NATIONAL LEVELS</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The advocacy program of the NCHRD-K focused on attaining a conducive working environment for HRDs, through strategic partnership and producing evidence-based reports on the situation of HRDs in Kenya. This in turn would inform protection and advocacy strategies against violations targeting HRDs in the course of their work. The information was shared with partners at national, regional and international level so as to improve the effectiveness of the protection of HRDs, hold perpetrators accountable as well as expand the scope of State responsibility for protection of HRDs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <category code="B01"></category>
    <language code="EN"></language>
    <document-date iso-date="2020-07-06"></document-date>
   </document-link>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support 2 meetings with duty bearers at county levels (Public participation and access to information</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The conversation circles are meant to engage HRDS with duty bearers in the counties they come from by getting an understanding of the access to information act and Interrogate their access to information, participation in the network activities as well as within the&#xA0;county affairs, Identify challenges they face as they engage in network and county activities and link them with key partners within their counties</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="0" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop and disseminate booklets to profile situation of HRDs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To achieve this, NCHD-K will carry out a research on the situation of HRDs. The NCHRD-K has commissioned the collection of data to identify the security concerns of HRDs and CSOs following the 2017 elections. This will also provide for the legislative environment in which HRDs are operating with recommendations on a less restrictive environment to inform NCHRD-K and partner programming.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="1" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Defenders Academy and Human Rights Defenders Award Ceremony (Nairobi)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Do an annual HRD convening to equip the HRDs with knowledge and skills in emerging issues on safety and security. The Academy is culminated by the HRD Award Ceremony which seeks to recognise, profile and award the work of human rights defenders in Kenya.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="2" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prepare and disseminate 2 thematic reports on HRDs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K engage or plan to do research to highlight working environment of Human Rights Defenders in Kenya.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="2" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support periodic joint actions with partner organisations (IDAHO,16 days of activism, 2/3 gender campaign)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K took part in joint actions with other human rights actors as part of consolidating its efforts for a conducive working environment for human rights defenders. NCHRD-K also supported activities by human rights defenders that seek to enhance their collaborative efforts in advocacy and protection.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="3" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prepare and disseminate alternative/shadow reports to Treaty Bodies, Special Rapporteurs and Mandates</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NCHRD-K has on its own and together with partners developed shadow reports to special mechanisms. That is the African Commission on People and Human Rights (ACPHR) and the UN mechanisms in an effort to advocate for a conducive working environment for HRDs in Kenya.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline iso-date="2018-07-01" value="4" year="2018"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
