<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7960</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dunapack Rambox Prodimpex LLC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Romania-Rambox Prodimpex LLC              Region    Europe        Sector       Project No007960   Projected Board DateMarch 3, 1997   Company NameRambox Prodimpex LLC   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Dunapack Paper and Packaging Limited     Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	US$12.1 million including an IFC loan of US$3 million and equity of up to US$1 million.    Location of project and Description of site    	The plant will be located in Sfantu Gheorghe which is in the southern part of Transylvania in Romania, about 200 kilometers from Bucharest.  The Company has purchased 4 hectares of land in Sfantu Gheorghe which is one of the most industrialized regions in Romania and has good transportation and communication facilities as well as a plentiful supply of workers.  The plant will be located less than one kilometer from the railway station and will be connected to the railway grid by a private railway.  In addition, the plant is well connected to the road network in Romania.               Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project involves the consolidation and expansion of Dunapack Paper and Packaging Ltd.s (Dunapack) activities in Romania.  Dunapack, the largest manufacturer of paper and packaging materials in Hungary, currently has two subsidiary companies in Romania:  (a) Dunapack Impex (DI) which was established in September 1994 as a sales and marketing company for corrugated products; and (b) Dunapack Rom-Convert (DRC) which was established in April 1996 to convert corrugated board, bought from a local company (AMCO), into boxes.  The proposed project would consolidate the operations of DI and DRC into one new company, Rambox, which would further integrate backwards into the production of corrugated board.  The designed capacity of the consolidated plant is expected to be 20,000 tons per year (tpy) which will be expanded to 30,000 tpy in the second phase of the project. The entire production will be primarily for the domestic market.           Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure. The key environmental, health and safety issues considered in this project include: liquid effluents, employee safety during construction, employee exposure to noise and chemicals; and fire prevention and life safety, including emergency response.  Based on its review of available information regarding potential environmental impacts and proposed mitigation measures, IFCs Environmental Division has concluded that the proposed project will meet World Bank environmental, health and safety policies and guidelines and host country requirements.  The facility development includes the construction of water purification, waste water treatment and recycling systems.  Waste water including treated process water and domestic sewage will be discharged to the Sfantu Gheorghe sewage treatment plant.  The boiler system and process drying will be fired with fuel oil.  The boiler specifications will be selected to ensure the operation achieves World Bank air emission guidelines.  The Company will recycle all production waste which will be baled and shipped to paper mills for use in the production of paper.  Employees will be trained to ensure safe working practices including orientation for emergency response situations.  Dunapack will conduct training programs and monitor the use of safety equipment to ensure compliance.  Provisions for fire protection and prevention in the new facilities will comply with World Bank guidelines.    The  is  from the Public Information Center.         Date SPI sent to PIC     January 30, 1997      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dunapack Rambox Prodimpex S.R.L.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7960" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-09-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-10-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Romania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="RO-Romania">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>46.0000000000 25.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AG - Paper Packaging Products (Including Boxes, Cartons, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $4.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-09-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-09-14">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-09-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-09-14">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-09-14">2000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dunapack Rambox Prodimpex S.R.L.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-09-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-09-14">2000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dunapack Rambox Prodimpex S.R.L.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7960/dunapack-rambox-prodimpex-llc">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
