<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7869</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Romanian Efes Brewery S.A.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Romania - Efes Brewery Project      RegionEurope   Sector   Project No007869   Projected Board DateJanuary 30, 1997   Company NameRomanian Efes Brewery SA   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The principal sponsor and shareholder is the Efes Group, the beverage arm of the Anadolu Group, which is a large diversified industrial group in Turkey.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total project cost is US$70.0 million.  IFC is proposing to invest up to US$25.0 million in the project, including an A loan of US$12.0 million, a B loan of US$8.0 million, and equity of up to US$5.0 million equivalent.    Location of project and Description of site    	The project will be located in Ploesti, the capital city of Prahova county, approximately 60 km north of Bucharest.  The site is a 12 hectare plot of land on the outskirts of Ploesti.  It is adjacent to a railway network with good access to all parts of Romania, as well as the main road linking Ploesti to Bucharest.  Adequate water will be available from the municipal water system of Ploesti and from wells which will be drilled on the site.       Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project is to construct and operate a brewery in Romania, with an initial production capacity of 750,000 hl per year.  The brewery will be owned by Romanian Efes Brewery SA, a Romanian company controlled by the Efes Group.  The brewery will be constructed over a two-year period, incorporating modern brewing and packaging technology.  Compared with beer from the countrys existing breweries, the projects beer will be more hygienically produced, will be of more consistent quality, and will have a longer shelf-life.  A modern distribution system will also be developed, combining both direct delivery and the use of exclusive wholesalers.                                                                                                                                          The economic rationale for the project is to supply good quality beer to the Romanian market at the lowest possible economic cost.  Given that the cost of transporting beverages is high relative to their value, the economic cost of producing these products locally is lower than the alternative of importation.  This economic saving will also lead to a reduction in retail prices of quality beer in the country, which will benefit consumers.  Furthermore, the project will have a positive development impact in the country by generating employment, by increasing skill levels in the workforce, and by developing the countrys business infrastructure, including distribution, wholesale and retail networks.  Overall, the project will assist the countrys transformation from a command, supply-driven economy towards one that is service-oriented and market-driven.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure; principal issues include water supply, liquid effluent treatment, air emissions, solid waste reuse and disposal, potential contamination of site from present or past uses, potential use of CFCs, fire and explosion prevention, and workplace health and safety.  Steam boilers at the brewery will be operated with low sulfur fuel to minimize sulfur dioxide emissions.  A new wastewater treatment facility will be installed such that liquid effluents will meet the respective Romanian standards and the World Bank guidelines.  The company will clean and reuse all types of product containers.  The site has not been contaminated by either present or past uses.  Ammonia will be used as the refrigerant for central cooling systems.  Fire protection programs will be implemented to meet local requirements and World Bank guidelines.  Efes will implement workplace safety and employee protection programs at the plant.  Employees will be provided with and required to use appropriate personal protective equipment.  Training will be provided in workplace safety procedures, accident prevention, fire protection, emergency response and the use of personnel protective equipment.    The  is from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     December 23, 1996      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interbrew Efes Brewery</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7869" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-01-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-06-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Romania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="RO-Romania">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>46.0000000000 25.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BB - Breweries</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $17.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-01-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1998-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-01-29">17000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-01-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-01-29">17000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interbrew Efes Brewery</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7869/romanian-efes-brewery-s-a">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
