<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5203024901-YEM-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">YNDCRTF Trust Fund Constitutional Reform Yemen</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">YNDCRTF Trust Fund Konstitutionsutveckling Jemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A multi donor trust fund established with the aim to support Yemeni efforts to organise and lead a national dialogue process and a constitution reform process that is transparent, inclusive and efficient. This contribution is channelled to development of the constitution and includes among other things technical and political advice and support to the national secretariat, as well as efforts to reach out to the Yemeni public.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">En multi donor trust fund etablerad med syftet att st&#xF6;dja jemenitiska anst&#xE4;ngningar att organisera och leda en nationell dialogprocess samt en konstitutionsutvecklingsprocess som &#xE4;r transparent, inkluderande och effektiv. Det h&#xE4;r st&#xF6;det g&#xE5;r till utveckling av konstitutionen och inkluderar bl a tillhandah&#xE5;llande av teknisk och politisk r&#xE5;dgivning och st&#xF6;d till det nationella sekretariatet samt insatser f&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; ut till den jemenitiska befolkningen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen&apos;s democratic transition is successfully implemented in a peaceful and inclusive manner</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2478170.2357177217</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2478170.2357177217</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-509246.1849215833</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-03-01">2478170.235717</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-08-28">2478170.2357177217</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">-509246.2420287863</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The support to the Yemen National Dialogue and Constitutional Trust Fund aimed at supporting the political transition in Yemen and more specifically the National Dialogue and Constitution Making Process. The results with regard to the national dialogue process are described separately (under the specific contribution for the national dialogue).
With regard to the constitutional process, in March 2014 a constitution drafting committee of 17 members including 4 women (quota from National Dialogue outcome) was established after a Presidential Decree. Also a secretariat composed of 50 experienced members of the former national dialogue secretariat was established to provide technical and operational support to the constitution process. Further, a National Body was established by a presidential decree with one of the objectives to review the draft constitution and ensure that all the relevant conclusions from the National Dialogue were accurately reflected.
The project covered the Secretariats staffing costs, office setup and deployment of 23 international experts to provide technical support to the constitution drafting committee. The secretariat also worked with national consultants to provide analysis on the the most controversial issues etc. UNOPS provided operational, logistical and human resource support to the Secretariat. Retreats were held as well as a study trip to Berlin (funded by Germany) to look into aspects of federalism. Presentations and working papers were produced by technical experts and discussed as input to the process. Due to changes in the political arena and the deterioration of the security situation during the third quarter of 2014 the process was halted.
The process to finalise the draft constitution was made in UAE (retreat funded by the UAE government) due to the security situation in Yemen. The focus on the final phase was on chapters on independent institutions, public finance, rights and freedoms, the judiciary, the legislative authority, the executive authority, police and armed forces, and on land, water and environment. The draft was completed in late December and submitted to the president on January 2015. Thereafter the situation further deteriorated with return to war.
During 2015 the process was put on hold due to the deterioration of the situation. During early 2015 campaigns promoting National Dialogue Outcomes and the new constitution continued. A media and communication plan were developed for public participation and referendum. In February 2015 the YNDCRTF Steering Committee decided to suspend activities due to the situation. At the time the situation was not clear and a resumption of the process was possible. Therefore the Secretariat continued to work on preparations and productions to be ready if the process was resumed. The secretariat was scaled down and continued to work for preparing for sudden resumption while at the same time preparing for a closure. By end of September 2015 the Secretariat officially closed.
One objective with the project was to was to ensure inclusion and adoption of key child and minority rights provision in the new constitution through improved citizen participation. UNICEF was responsible for implementation of this part of the project. The majority of the child and minority rights that were advocated for under the project were included in the draft constitution including a definition of a child as anyone under 18 years, minimum of marriage set at 18 years, the right of a Yemeni child to a name, a home, right to free health and education, and the right to protection from violence and traditional harmful practises including female genital mutilation among others. The draft constitution also set provisions to protect minorities including right to employment and participation and protection from discrimination. Despite the suspension of the project, UNICEF was not able to suspend the local partners grants and their activities continued during 2015. Therefore their community outreach and engagement program continued with focus on child rights awareness and protection of these rights during conflicts. UNICEF conducted outreach activates in over 367 villages and 106 districts in 15 governorates reaching about 153 219 people. Through partnership agreements with nine local organisations, 1853 community outreach facilitator volunteers were trained in participatory communication skills to plan and engage communities in discussions on NDC outcome and child and minority rights. 21 780 house visits, 553 focus group discussions and 772 community meetings were held.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52030249" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110303" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1850000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional MENA 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt MENA 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
