<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Global Action For Safer Cities Phase 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To provide a powerful evidence-based platform for interaction and exchange as well as expertise services for stakeholders and partners from the crime prevention and law enforcement field as well as the various sectors of urban development.Although small, this project will enable UN-HABITAT to establish necessary mechanisms that will allow for enhanced access to safer cities knowhow for cities and partners to exchange and consolidate their ongoing efforts to address urban safety for all and to leverage resources with other projects. This project will largely seek to build on existing UN-HABITAT plans within the area of advocacy, outreach and communications and importantly the agency wide World Urban Campaign.Project&apos;s alignment to local, national, regional, global prioritiesThe project will provide relevant support to countries with existing National Crime Prevention Strategies as well as those where UN41ABITAT technical support was provided to incorporate safety into their National Development Policies.This will be augmented by the range of norms and standards which the UN has adopted to provide guidance on aspects of urban safety These include the UN Guidelines for the Prevention of Crime and Criminal justice adopted in 2002 (ECOSOC 2002/13). In addition, the Geneva Declaration reaffirmed the will and commitment of member states to address the prevention of armed violence al the local level as a pre-requisite to achieving the Millennium Development Goals and Targets. This process is now advancing to the recognition of Cities as a signatory of the Geneva Declaration which is due at the end of 2011. Various declarations by cities and other stakeholders have also been made at various UN HABITAT conferences in support of Safer Cities. For instance, the Durban International Conference on Sustainable Safety: Municipalities at the Crossroads (November 2003) reiterated the importance of adopting a preventive approach and identified key areas of intervention such as encouraging partnerships, developing crime prevention Cools, strengthening links between safety and governance, focusing on vulnerable groups and on action addressing marginalization fostering city40&#xE6; city operation and creating safer urban design and better management of public spaces (linking with slums upgrading). The Monterrey International Conference on the State of Safety in World Cities (October 2007) also reaffirmed the importance of urban safety in human settlement development and on sustainable urban development. The conference launched the IJ&#xC4;LHABITAT Global Report on Human Settlements, which for the first time focused on issues of urban safi&#xB1;4y and security, subsequently providing a conceptual framework for urban safety within the human settlements agenda.Economic and Social Council resolutions 2002/13 of 24 July 2002, 2003/26 of 22 July 2003, 2005/22 of 22 July 2005 and 2008/24 of 24 July 2008, called upon Member States, relevant United Nations bodies and international financial institutions to integrate into their social and economic policies and programs crime prevention considerations. In this context, beyond the role of UN-HABITAT, the development and implementation of local crime and violence prevention approaches at the local level has gained recognition among other United Nations and other international entities as follows:	With UN Women in the Global Program Safe Cities Free of Violence Against Women and Girls (2010-2015)2. The United Nations Development Program (UNDP) has also established a Community Security and Social Cohesion Agenda as part of its facilitation of an Joint Programming on Armed Violence Prevention (AVPP)O The World Health Organization (WHO) has also acknowledged the growing importance of the Safer Cities approach in its Global Campaign on Violence Prevention. The World Bank and the World Bank Institute have also integrated elements of the Safer Cities approach in their Urban and Local Government Programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Clarissa.Augustinus@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">511377</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">672995</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">745818</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 1: Strengthened capacities of local and national governments and other actors in mainstreaming the safer cities approach and the culture of prevention (enhanced urban safety and social cohesion approach and the culture of prevention (enhanced urban safety and social cohesion approach) into urban planning management and governance frameworks through the establishment and implementation of a Global Network for safer cities</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 1: Strengthened capacities of local and national governments and other actors in mainstreaming the safer cities approach and the culture of prevention (enhanced urban safety and social cohesion approach and the culture of prevention (enhanced urban safety and social cohesion approach) into urban planning management and governance frameworks through the establishment and implementation of a Global Network for safer cities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of local and national governments implementing crime and violence prevention strategies and action plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of local and national governments implementing crime and violence prevention strategies and action plan</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2011: 58" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 2: Strengthened capacities of local and national governments and other actors in implementing urban safety and social cohesion programmes and projects through the increased access to safer cities</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 2: Strengthened capacities of local and national governments and other actors in implementing urban safety and social cohesion programmes and projects through the increased access to safer cities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1)Number of local and national governments engaged in knowledge exchange on implementing crime and violence prevention strategies and action plans.
2) Number of local and national governments connecting to expert service on urban safety.
3) Number of local and national governments using the tools and training modules uploaded on the virtual platform</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1)Number of local and national governments engaged in knowledge exchange on implementing crime and violence prevention strategies and action plans.
2) Number of local and national governments connecting to expert service on urban safety.
3) Number of local and national governments using the tools and training modules uploaded on the virtual platform</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2011: 58" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
