<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3102</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pro-Poor Planning Of Climate Resilience In Marginalized Neighborhoods</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main purpose of
the project is to support cities and UN member states to: 

&#xA7; Improve climate resilience in selected
marginalized neighborhoods,

The Purpose is to be understood within
the context of ongoing city-wide climate resilience and resilience planning
efforts. In other words, while the emphasis of the present Project is on neighborhood-level work &#x2013; and thus
primarily focused on building climate resilience through &#x2018;hard and soft&apos;
measures, the project approach is only complete if those neighborhood actions
are complimented by efforts to integrate those actions into city-wide efforts.
Thus, we will seek to implement the Project in cities that are currently
receiving relevant city-wide assistance from other UN-Habitat projects &#x2013;
ideally CCCI, PSUP and CRPP (to be confirmed) - that the present Project can
complement. 

The purpose of the project is therefore to achieve an
integrated approach, covering three important dimensions of climate resilience
planning:

Improve neighborhood-scale resilience planning, including (in all or some pilot locations) increased
access to basic urban services, and thus addressing and building resilience
through, and of, the physical environment. Those &#x2018;hard&apos; measures are to be
complimented by an innovative participatory approach, Community-based Resilience (CBA), to build the resilience also of
the people residing in those deprived locations. Through community engagement
in the respective project locations, either using existing community structures
(preferred) or creating community structures for the purpose of resilience
building. The project will employ a participatory approach, implementing
lessons from PSUP, in order to carry out the neighborhood vulnerability
assessments and resilience planning exercises, and in order to link the community
planning to the city wide planning processes, and by that empowered the urban
poor to plan and take climate action. The third dimension to improve the
resilience of marginalized neighborhoods is to integrate the neighborhood-scale efforts into city-wide planning
and climate resilience action &#x2013; and thus &#x2013; to a certain extend &#x2013; bring those
effort into the formal city-wide system.



We will achieve this purpose in
part through developing and testing new tools for pro-poor climate resilience
planning. This will draw on several bodies of experience at UN-Habitat and in
the broader development community. Firstly, UN-Habitat&apos;s Cities and Climate
Change Initiative (CCCI), supported by Sida and others, has developed tools for
assessing city-wide vulnerability to the impacts of climate change.
Additionally CCCI has supported poor neighborhoods that are highly vulnerable
to the impacts of climate change within the context of broader, city-wide
efforts, for example, in: (i) the vulnerable Guet Ndar neighborhood of low-lying
St. Louis, Senegal, where UN-Habitat helped the city to build adaptive capcity
in vulnerable coastal communities and mobilized fund to relocate the highly vulnerable
poor families; and (ii) the poor, flood-prone neighborhood of Bwaise in Kampala,
Uganda, where intensive neighborhood efforts complemented development of a
proposed city-wide strategy for integrated flood risk management. Resilience
work in Mozambique &#x2013; in part carried out under CCCI &#x2013; has resulted in
measurable and lasting resilience of vulnerable communities through the
provision of resilient Infrastructure, coupled with community engagement,
capacity development and training on resilience. Other experiences from
Mozambique indicate that early involvement of vulnerable communities in planning
and mapping can help adequately identify risks and vulnerabilities and thus
improves the quality of interventions in adaptation to in coastal
neighborhoods.

Secondly, UN-Habitat&apos;s Participatory
Slum Upgrading Programme (PSUP) has developed solid methodologies related to
in-situ slum upgrading. PSUP assessment methodologies, which already touch on
climate change as well as other relevant cross-cutting issues such as human
rights and gender, can be built on. Moreover, to the degree that the Project
will be implemented in PSUP countries/cities, it can draw upon PSUP&apos;s network
of national and local governments, communities and other stakeholders. 

Thirdly UN-Habitat&apos;s Urban Basic Services Branch has
undertaken pilot projects in marginalized neighborhoods as part of broader,
city- or even nation-wide approaches to improve basic service provision.
Fourthly, pilot cities have gained experience from participating in the City
Resilience Profiling Programme of the Risk Reduction and Rehabilitation Branch.
And finally the Global Land Tool Network (ULLGB) and others have argued
persuasively that strengthening security of tenure represents a fundamental
approach to building resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Planning and Design</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rafael Tuts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Marcus.Mayr@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-01">872476</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">385232</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">741530</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved integration of pro-poor planning for marginalized neighborhoods at the city level (primary) and beyond (secondary).</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved integration of pro-poor planning for marginalized neighborhoods at the city level (primary) and beyond (secondary).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">City-wide planning processes include neighborhood (Slum) specific aspects</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">City-wide planning processes include neighborhood (Slum) specific aspects</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3,one per location">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of officials assigned to maginalised neighboods</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of officials assigned to maginalised neighboods</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15,one per location">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved resilience planning at the neighborhood level, including (in all/some pilot locations) increased access to basic urban services.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved resilience planning at the neighborhood level, including (in all/some pilot locations) increased access to basic urban services.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of partner city, regional and national authorities that have adopted and implemented policies, plans or strategies that contribute to climate change mitigation &amp; adaptation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of partner city, regional and national authorities that have adopted and implemented policies, plans or strategies that contribute to climate change mitigation &amp; adaptation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assess climate change risk/vulnerability in a participatory manner, resulting in comprehensive vulnerability assessments, with particular attention to gender and marginalized groups (one per location).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assess climate change risk/vulnerability in a participatory manner, resulting in comprehensive vulnerability assessments, with particular attention to gender and marginalized groups (one per location).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The urban poor are empowered to take climate action and build resilience in collaboration with other stakeholders and partners</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The urban poor are empowered to take climate action and build resilience in collaboration with other stakeholders and partners</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of households in target neighborhoods aware of climate-related natural disasters and demonstrate greater resiliency</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of households in target neighborhoods aware of climate-related natural disasters and demonstrate greater resiliency</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="To be provided upon finalization of Household Survey" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="To be provided upon establishment of baseline">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
