<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-9827</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Design Governance (Urban Maestro)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The primary aim of Urban Maestro is to
stimulate political, professional and civil society support for the more
effective use of urban design governance approaches by raising awareness of
their potential amongst decision makers and other agents of change at the
appropriate levels. It won&#x2019;t be the objective of the research project to
determine whether &#x2018;good&#x2019; or &#x2018;poor&#x2019; design has been achieved in any given
circumstances, but instead to explore the impacts that design governance
practices and different modes of leadership are having on shaping both the
environment within which decision-making on design occurs (the process impact)
and on what that means for the places that are being shaped and/or re-shaped
over time (the outcome impact).

Good urban design governance is needed. Throughout Europe, local, regional and national
administrations have established sophisticated urban development control systems
that are meant to ensure the compliance of urban development with basic urban
design qualities. These systems also define the rules through which development
interests can express their aspirations and protect their interests through
urban design. For every built environment intervention, the line-up of
stakeholders, the leadership and the power relationships are different,
although design remains a common and constant means through which the built
environment is negotiated and re-negotiated over time.

Within this context, the governance of
design is primarily concerned with establishing and shaping the decision-making
environment within which choices about the design of particular projects (large
or small) are later made. In other words, it is not concerned with actually
designing projects, but instead with setting the parameters within which others
design.

Recent research has demonstrated the
profound health, social, economic and environmental benefits that flow from a
well-designed built environment (www.place-value-wiki.net), but not all tools
and processes are equally successful at positively shaping such places, and
more often than not, one mechanism introduced for one purpose (e.g. to keep
traffic safe) may have unintended consequences elsewhere (e.g. in reducing
walkability).

Most politicians, scholars and other
stakeholders would agree that the quality of urban design matters when it comes
to promoting the achievement of sustainable development, but very few would be
able to explain &#x201C;Why&#x201D;, and even less &#x201C;How&#x201D; to achieve urban spatial quality.
These are issues that the project will explore, notably through examining the
often untapped potential of the soft or informal tools of design governance.

The potential to move
beyond formal design governance tools. Formal, or conventional tools for design
governance (the hard power) typically include instruments such as development
plans, design standards, state subsidies and investment, construction permits,
development consent, urban development charges, expropriation modalities and a
wide diversity of public-private arrangements.

If formal design governance instruments work
well at preventing the worst forms of development, they are often less
successful at stimulating the best. Despite the creativity of many built
environment professionals, beyond their historic cores, European cities are
characterised by sprawl where a true urban realm is often absent and where
characteristics of car dominance, hard landscape, single use, segregation, and
so forth, predominate.

While Europe is often seen from the outside as
the patria of &#x201C;good&#x201D; urbanism, the Davos Declaration was forthright in its
criticism of &#x201C;the growth of faceless urban sprawl and irresponsible land use&#x201D;
across Europe. This will vary from the sorts of car-reliant, infrastructure
heavy but social infrastructure light suburbs that surround many of Europe&#x2019;s
cities to the hard inhuman overdevelopment that increasingly features in too
many city centres. Both are focussed on achieving short-term economic benefits
at the expense of long-term health, social, cultural and environmental
outcomes. They call into question the capacity of public authorities to
stimulate urban spatial quality, and deliver sustainable urban development.

Such observations are not limited to the
European context. In its 2009 global report on Human Settlements dedicated to
urban planning, UN-Habitat noted that &#x201C;traditional approaches to urban
planning, particularly in the developing world, have largely failed to promote
equitable, efficient and sustainable human settlements and to address
twenty-first century challenges, including rapid urbanization, shrinking cities
and ageing, climate change and related disasters, urban sprawl and unplanned
peri-urbanization, as well as urbanization of poverty and informality&#x201D;.

Softer, informal forms
of intervention may be more effective. In fact, despite the emphasis placed on rules
and regulation in the dominant design governance practices of Europe, there is
a much larger toolkit available to the public sector through which to
positively shape the built environment. Numerous national and local
administrations, as well as a number of civil society groups have taken
innovative initiatives to stimulate the emergence of higher quality urban
development through the development of new tools and processes.

For example, research examining the period
1999-2011 in the UK has identified a wide range of both formal (required by
statute) and informal (non-statutory) tools that were in active use during the
period. These range from direct financial incentives to secure a better
designed built environment, to guidance and educational initiatives, to the use
of peer review and different forms of advocacy (Carmona et al, 2016, Design
Governance, the CABE Experiment, Routledge).

Reports from Belgium, Ireland, the Netherlands,
Germany, Denmark, Spain and other European Member States show seemingly
interesting results in the form of multi-stakeholders design platforms,
citizen-led urban observatories, urban quality negotiation schemes, urban labs,
knowledge building, capacity development, advocacy, certified competitions and
awards, neighbourhood and thematic committees but also direct and indirect
technical assistance or mentoring to local or regional authorities (EFAP 2012,
Survey on Architectural Policies in Europe). Few of these are required in
legislation, and instead act to shape the design decision-making environment
through encouraging, informing, nudging, and assisting stakeholders towards
better design practices. Yet little systematic work has been done in order to
capture and share best practice.

The same is apparent globally. Whilst there is
some evidence of innovative practices in the United States, Australia, Brazil,
Singapore, and a few other countries, in contexts of rapid urbanization,
notably in emerging economies or in the developing world, where informality is
the norm, urban development is often hardly controlled, or controlled only
crudely through formal (hard power) instruments of urban design governance.
Demonstrating the effectiveness of softer approaches to urban design governance
in Europe will have potential for significant application in emerging
economies, the developing world and crisis areas, contexts in which citizen
participation and the establishment of multi-stakeholders platforms has often
been presented as the one-size-fits-all solution to urban challenges.

Synergies between
innovation in urban design governance and urban finance. Urban planning and design does not
work in isolation. Beautiful design solutions are of little value if not
connected to a legal and economic system that will allow for their implementation
and long-term maintenance. For this reason urban design governance emcompasses
the spatial, economic and legal dimensions of decision making over the form and
shape of the urban environment, and urban design governance outcomes and
processes are deeply shaped by the availability of economic resources and the
nature of financing instruments for urban projects.

The challenge is to enter a virtuous circle in
which the capacity of local authorities to raise finance and take decisions is
eased by their reputation for careful stewardship over their urban environment,
so that the urban environment itself becomes an attractor to investment
(private as well as public) and value added from a public interest perspective.

Whichever mechanism is selected, there is the
potential to use financial tools alongside or as part of the design governance
toolbox in such a way that &#x2018;good behaviour&#x2019; is rewarded &#x2013; including the
delivery of high quality design &#x2013; and &#x2018;poor behaviour&#x2019; discouraged, notably the
creation of unsustainable development. The critical task for the state is not
simply to incentivise development, but to incentivise high quality development.
In this endeavour, financial incentivisation, either directly or indirectly,
can form a key weapon in the design governance arsenal. Innovative financing
instruments, notably when directly connected to aspirations of civil society
for higher quality environments, can also offer an entry point for local
authorities to engage in softer urban design approaches (see the Eutropian book
for examples).

Knowledge on design
governance innovations is insufficiently shared across Europe. Whilst European academics,
organisations and practitioners have made significant contributions to debates
about urban quality and European examples are often held up as exemplars, there
has been little attempt to systematically learn from the European experiences
beyond individual cases. In part this is because of the complexity of the
diverse systems of European urban governance, and because of the perception
that urban design and urban finance is beyond the limits of European
institutions&#x2019; competencies. Arguably it is the absence of pan-European networks
with a focus on sharing practice that leads many practitioners, globally
(including in Europe), to look to the US for models (good or bad) to emulate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liaison Office - Brussels</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jean Bakole</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Frederic.Saliez@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-01">1634645</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">509130</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 1: An overview of the European urban design governance landscape is made available, with an emphasis on the informal (soft) tools of urban design governance and associated innovative financing tools that help to deliver urban quality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 1: An overview of the European urban design governance landscape is made available, with an emphasis on the informal (soft) tools of urban design governance and associated innovative financing tools that help to deliver urban quality.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of baseline study</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of baseline study</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No" year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of a peer-reviewed identification of innovative practices.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of a peer-reviewed identification of innovative practices.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 2: The practices that are most effective at positively shaping the quality of places are identified and understood in detail, through direct engagement with the individuals and organizations responsible for their development and implementation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 2: The practices that are most effective at positively shaping the quality of places are identified and understood in detail, through direct engagement with the individuals and organizations responsible for their development and implementation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of most effective practices identified</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of most effective practices identified</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in workshops</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in workshops</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100 (total for all WS)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of an online documentation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Availability of an online documentation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Yes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 3: A peer-to-peer collaboration and learning network is established among the multi-stakeholders that support the range of innovative design tools and processes.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 3: A peer-to-peer collaboration and learning network is established among the multi-stakeholders that support the range of innovative design tools and processes.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of institutions and individuals contacted through workshops and other project activities and tools</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of institutions and individuals contacted through workshops and other project activities and tools</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 4: Public authorities and other organizations in Europe and beyond are encouraged and enabled to adopt an enhanced policy agenda of urban design governance, based on a full understanding of the range of urban design governance tools and processes, proven successful stories and lessons learnt from failure, and the innovation made possible through better understanding and collaboration.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 4: Public authorities and other organizations in Europe and beyond are encouraged and enabled to adopt an enhanced policy agenda of urban design governance, based on a full understanding of the range of urban design governance tools and processes, proven successful stories and lessons learnt from failure, and the innovation made possible through better understanding and collaboration.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in summer school</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants in summer school</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to urban design governance expressed by public authorities and other organizations</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to urban design governance expressed by public authorities and other organizations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
