<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2553</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water, Sanitation And Hygiene In Disaster Prone Communities In Northern Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project proposal is pursuant to the need to include water and sanitation and hygiene (WASH) as an urgent and complementary need in UN&apos;s overall support to disaster prone communities in the three northern regions of Ghana. It is conceived within the framework of the Joint UN programming approach UN-Habitat, UNDP, UNICEF and WHO as the main UN Agency partners to collaborate with GoG partners on providing improved and resilient WASH facilities and services in disaster prone communities in the 3 Northern Regions. In line with the outcomes 4 and 5 of the UNDAF, this project also provides a framework for DFATD to partner with the UN team in this effort and to contribute to GoG&apos;s efforts towards the implementation of the Ghana Plan of Action for Disaster Risk Reduction and Climate Change Adaptation.
Consistent with Ghana&apos;s aspirations, the vision and collective programme of the United Nations Development Assistance Framework (UNDAF) for the period 2012-2016 seeks to advance a coherent vision for the UN system in support of key priorities of the Government&apos;s Development Agenda. The UNDAF aligns with the Ghana Shared Growth and Development Agenda (GSGDA) through four thematic areas[1] including infrastructure and human settlements development. WASH is an UNDAF outcome area under the infrastructure and human settlements development thematic area. The 2012-2016 UNDAF includes a key programme component on water, sanitation and hygiene to be implemented in the 5 most deprived regions (Central, Northern, Upper East, Upper West and Volta) of Ghana. The UNDAF Action Plan (UAP) puts some focus on the poorest regions of the country, in particular the activities of the Joint UN Office in Tamale, which focuses on the three northern regions, and includes support to disaster prone communities in these three regions.
Natural disaster occurrence in Ghana consists of droughts, epidemic outbreaks, floods, and wildfires. In the 3 Northern regions, disasters significantly impact vulnerable populations in disaster prone areas, and may lead to unnecessary losses of social and economic capital. In particular, recurrent flooding events, which are the most pervasive in terms of financial damages and numbers of people affected, usually result in the disruption of services from WASH facilities, which could lead to significant damages to property and trigger other emergency situations such as outbreaks of diarrhea, cholera, and other water related/borne diseases. The combination of these effects reduces the productivity of the population and the losses they suffer are immense and seriously affect their economic and social circumstances. These events tend to have devastating effects on the development of affected communities. 
Having to ensure that when such floods occur the quality of water supply is not contaminated (during collection, handling, storage, and use) also presents immense challenges to the health of these communities. Rehabilitation costs are usually unaffordable and communities have suffered a drastic fall in their living conditions and opportunities for future development, pushing them further into poverty and deprivation. 
The situation is further aggravated in those communities where there is a lack of WASH facilities and services. In such circumstances, the challenges include the prevalence of water borne, vector borne and sanitation related diseases as a result of poor drinking water quality and inadequate sanitation. Women, children and the youth suffer the most from the effects of this lack of access to WASH facilities and related services. Initiatives that address and improve the WASH situation for people in disaster prone communities contribute significantly to address most MDGs.
In a recent report, the National Disaster Monitoring Organization (NADMO) indicated that it had taken a census of people living in flood prone areas of the country, including the northern regions, and had allocated safe havens in these communities to prepare for the onset of the major rains. 
The project will work in close collaboration with NADMO in this context, and contribute to WASH components with respect to prior preparations towards mitigating disaster events, make recommendations for interventions during such events, and implement WASH solutions that could be resilient to the effects in the disaster prone communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP (incl. one UN fund)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Basic Services</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Andre Dzikus</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Andre.Dzikus@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-01">8760102</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">7184034</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">4775466</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved hygiene practices among women, men, girls and boys before, during and after
disasters in disaster-prone communities in Northern Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved hygiene practices among women, men, girls and boys before, during and after
disasters in disaster-prone communities in Northern Ghana</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of women, men, girls and boys practicing improved hygiene in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of women, men, girls and boys practicing improved hygiene in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of women, men, girls and boys practicing improved hygiene in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of women, men, girls and boys practicing improved hygiene in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved planning and implementation of WASH programs by local institutions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved planning and implementation of WASH programs by local institutions</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of local institutions effectively planning and implementing resilient WASH programs in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of local institutions effectively planning and implementing resilient WASH programs in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of local institutions effectively planning and implementing resilient WASH programs in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="29">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of local institutions effectively planning and implementing resilient WASH programs in disaster-prone communities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased equitable use of disaster-resilient improved sanitation and water facilities by
people in disaster-prone communities in Northern Ghana</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased equitable use of disaster-resilient improved sanitation and water facilities by
people in disaster-prone communities in Northern Ghana</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using equitable use of disaster-resilient WASH facilities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using equitable use of disaster-resilient WASH facilities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using equitable use of disaster-resilient WASH facilities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people using equitable use of disaster-resilient WASH facilities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
