<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-13127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing, Land And Property Rights&#x2019; Challenges Faced In Syria By Refugees Currently Living In Lebanon - Humanitarian Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Major HLP issues have been
identified as part of the primary assessment conducted in the joint
UN-Habitat/UNHCR study on refugees from Homs City in Lebanon, including
documentation issues, inheritance issues, damage and destruction of records and
physical assets, HLP challenges specific to women-headed households, among many
other issues. The study also highlighted the importance of contextualizing the
identified HLP issues to derive responsive solutions. The context pertains to
the legislative, administrative and urban planning frameworks that govern and
shape land/property tenure systems and HLP rights, in different urban and rural
areas. HLP issues are critical for multiple humanitarian actors and are central
for planning urban recovery in the short and long term while adopting a &#x201C;do no
harm&#x201D; approach. Therefore, there is a need for an additional in-depth
processing and analysis of the identified HLP issues, with the aim to determine
the available options for protecting HLP rights of refugees and the needed
options for advocacy and programming.

The study identified that safety and
security, access to livelihoods, services and housing in Syria are key factors
for considering repatriation. The study found that 67.5 percent of Homs refugee
households currently did not have ownership documents to their primary property
in Syria, with nearly 70 percent being owners of their property in Homs. The
study brought to light gender-related issues as well, where 30 percent of
surveyed Homs female headed households were widowed and 45 percent had a
missing husband, with an anticipated difficulty and complexity in initiating
inheritance or restitution of their properties. The study looked at push-pull
dynamics, focusing on the perspective of refugees (HLP status in Lebanon, and
conditions in areas of origin through the unpublished study), and the
implications of the different return scenarios.

The &#x201C;Two-Year HLP Framework for
Syria&#x201D; highlights priority interventions in the short, medium and long terms
across five thematic pillars: legal framework, HLP documentation and land
administration, HLP dispute resolution and social cohesion, housing and urban
planning, and rural land management. The proposed research project will provide
knowledge and information that will directly contribute to the work done under
at least two of the five pillars as follows: for the first pillar, the research
will categorize the types of HLP claims and link them to the relevant legal
framework that can address them, to be translated into actionable options, thus
guiding refugees to manage and protect their HLP rights within the realm of
Syrian legal systems/institutions. It would also allow exploring options that
refugees have during their displacement (outside of Syria) beyond safeguarding
their available documents (especially given that a very small percentage of
refugees holds documentation of their HLP back in Syria), for better
humanitarian response in host countries. The research and more importantly the
application will raise the HLP awareness of Syrians allowing them to identify
dispute resolution forums that they can access.

The
research will help identifying the challenges encountered by displaced Syrian
in accessing HLP documentation, including cadastral evidence, and provide
recommendations on how HLP documentation can be protected, retrieved or
reconstructed. The data analyzed will
also help in developing possible scenarios for restitution (individual or large
scale) of properties illegally sold or undergoing secondary occupation. The
scenarios to be developed will take into account relevant existing legal
frameworks and look at what additional measures will be required for such
process ( e.g. legal amendments,
simplified bureaucratic procedures, institutional capacity building, cost
estimation, time estimation, etc.).This research component is crucial for the
larger goal of increasing awareness among refugees on their HLP rights as they
assess whether to go back to Syria and providing actionable options according
to the different HLP challenges. The research team will support the process of
developing the building blocks of the digital platform and will provide its
users with answers/instructions on &#x201C;what to do&#x201D;, by allowing for a categorization
of HLP issues, identification of options/actions and outlining due process by
case (for example: a household who lost its civil and/or HLP documentation; a
household who was a former resident of an informal settlement; a female-headed
household who hasn&#x2019;t initiated an inheritance process; a female-headed
household with a missing&#x2014;not deceased&#x2014;husband; etc.) according to existing
laws. It is important to note that the research and app development processes
will proceed in parallel and feed information into each other. Further, the
research component will better inform programmatic and advocacy needs that need
to be integrated in humanitarian and development responses, in the coming years
as the protracted crisis evolves.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEUTSCHE GESELLSCHAFT FUR INTERNATIONALE ZUSAMMENARBEIT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-05" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Ayoub.Mebrahtu@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Asia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Asia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-05"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">123231</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">109395</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
