<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2070</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pacific Regional Support Programme. : Strengthening Pacific Urban Agenda Implementation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objectives of this
proposal are to: (i) provide regional ToT and development of
suitable toolkits so as to support the foundations for country up-scaling and
regional replication of CDS, SUS and other proven good urbanization practices
and processes, (ii) manage lessons learned and knowledge acquired so as to
strengthen implementation of the Pacific Urban Agenda (as contained in the
Pacific Plan) national obligations and commitments, (iii) facilitate and
institutionalize urban policy dialogue into regional and national planning so
as to establish consensus with stakeholders on urbanisation priorities,
strengthen partnerships, and up scale resource mobilization to achieve better
urban outcomes, and (iv) strengthen monitoring by the SPC of the urban
commitments made under the Pacific Plan activities (namely, the PUA). The
latter will include an assessment of options to establish a Pacific Regional
Urban Observatory. The proposal will support the requests of the 3 PICs and
others to concurrently develop and implement their CDSs and SUSs by providing
regional (i) institutional strengthening, (ii) knowledge management and (iii)
support to strengthen urban policy and project development. It is hoped such
processes will lead to (iv) improved monitoring of urban performance by PICs
including integration of city and national responses to addressing urban issues
vis a vis the PUA and the Pacific Plan. 

Key outcomes resulting from the above
will be strengthened national capacity to undertake up scaling of under
serviced settlements, an increased number of PICs wanting to undertake CDS and
SUS, more national policy makers, planners and training partners interested in
addressing urbanisation issues, and development of a formal mechanism to
capture, share and disseminate knowledge learned. Commitments under the PUA
should also be pursued and monitored. More effective human capacities and
strengthened national and regional institutional structures should result in
the better management of the impacts of urbanization in a sustainable manner
and the improved performance of urban areas. By monitoring and sharing lessons
and knowledge acquired, the CA Regional Support component will add further
value to the effectiveness of the CDS and SUS processes being undertaken in the
3 selected PICs, including national, city and community levels. 

Under this CA Regional Support proposal, the suite of institutional
capacity building activities that will share global toolkits for national
customization and the possible development towards the end of proposal
implementation of a &#x201C;Pacific Regional CDS and SUS toolkit&#x201D; along with the
results emerging from national experiences such as good practice and lessons
learned, which will feed into the development of a Pacific Urban Knowledge
Management framework. This
will emphasize dialogue and dissemination of urban information and knowledge
gained. An agreed and accepted regional
institutional policy dialogue framework will add value to both regional and
national urban monitoring arrangements as well as implementation of national
initiatives such as the CDS and SUS. Regional and national realignment will
demonstrate the importance of urbanisation and the need for timely urban
management responses, including far stronger institutional arrangements such as
the possible development, for example, of a Pacific &#x201C;Regional Urban
Observatory&#x201D; as well as regional urban management tools. This would form part
of a network of National and sub-Regional Urban Observatories planned by
UCLG. The benefits of a Pacific Regional
Urban Observatory would be the sharing of information, the provision of
technical assistance (for example, urban data processing support, examples of
data use by community organizations, and methods of data analysis), monitoring
of regional agreed urban tools such as Pacific Urbanisation Development Goals,
the institutionalization of knowledge exchange, the standardization of
indicators and the development of Pacific regional dialogue on indicator use. The scope of this CA Regional Support
proposal also places a strong emphasis on strengthening capacity to document
and analyze knowledge acquired. This includes knowledge creation, sharing and
dissemination to promote and support the preparation and implementation of
local, town, city and national led CDS and SUS, building on lessons learned
from Samoa, Fiji and PNG to other PICs. Given
that a knowledge platform has been established in the Geography Department of
the University of the South pacific (but is no longer being updated), the CLGF
are discussing establishing a Local Government Resource Centre (with website
for urban issues), and UNESCAP has approved funding to support knowledge
management activities under its project &#x201C;capacity-building of SIDS to
incorporate the Mauritius Strategy into NSD strategies&#x201D;, this regional support
proposal will review where and how best knowledge management frameworks should
best be anchored and support development of an urban component to give
visibility and disseminate PUA compliance through best practices, initially on
behalf of PIPA as it receives strengthening support under Component 5, with
intended sharing of the urban component to a PIPA website as this develops.
PIPA has planning (and lands, surveying, environmentalist professional)
membership representation from PIC local and central government, and has been
receiving modest resource support from AusAID through the Planning Institute of
Australia (PIA). PIPA provides a network of Pacific planning professionals,
often geographically isolated, where they seek to share and obtain information
on current urban development activities and experiences such as squatters,
customary land mobilization and informal settlements. Members of PIPA are interested in addressing
urban solutions which are seen to be working in pilot projects around the
Pacific, expanding the number of stakeholders involved (especially development
partners), building skills and filling capacity shortages (such as in mediation
and negotiation), and strengthening the planning process to which solutions
such as CDS and SUS must be developed and molded. 

A key outcome of developing an urban
knowledge management framework will be strengthening of country CA project
implementation and monitoring and through such monitoring, collation of the
documentation of the implementation of the 3 country CA proposals. Lessons
learned would be synthesized and through such analysis, UNESCAP will coordinate
development of the Pacific knowledge management framework located in its
Pacific Office (EPO), Suva, Fiji, which has been a major supporter of the PUA
and its implementation within the region. A Knowledge Management officer would
be supported by this proposal, UN-HABITAT and EPO to maintain the collection of
documents, an online portal that is linked to other pertinent websites and
disseminate information to ensure accessibility to this information.

The knowledge management framework
would be focused initially on a website portal with access to documentation, as
well as PIPA coordinated regional workshops for the sharing of lessons,
knowledge acquired and implications. This would assist in the process of
fulfillment of country responsibilities under the PUA and Pacific Plan whilst
providing access to assistance on developing urban work plans, urban
indicators, squatter upgrading, mainstreaming CDS and SUS into NSDPs, access to
toolkits and the like. In this context,
members of PIPA would become the core capacity building arm for practicing
urban planners, managers and decision makers in the Pacific region. PIPA as the
regional focal point would ensure that the CDS and SUS principles and practices
as adapted to the Pacific are disseminated and up scaled nationally to members.
Working with development partners, the knowledge management framework would
assist to underpin sustainable urbanization policy dialogue in the region, such
dialogue feeding back into regional policies and plans such as the Pacific
Plan, as monitored by the SPC. 

This proposal&apos;s scope includes assisting SPC to undertake
high level policy dialogue with PICs so as to institutionalize the PUA, CDS and
SUS processes into national urban policy frameworks. A Pacific Ministerial Conference on the &#x2018;State
of Urbanisation in the Pacific&apos; would be one way to achieve this, to be held
towards the end of this Regional Support proposal&apos;s implementation, when the
good practices and lessons learned would be synthesized and visible. As SPC is already working with PICs in
developing three yearly Joint Country Strategies (JCS), it has already started
to mainstream the PUA, CDS and SUS concepts into these processes. This proposal
will therefore also support SPC to strengthen the monitoring of PUA
implementation and supporting initiatives. The objective is to enable SPC to
become more effective in its regional reporting and monitoring role of ensuring
commitments under the Pacific Plan (namely, the PUA) are progressed as well as
mainstreaming other urban initiatives. To assist SPC in its monitoring role,
the possible development of a Pacific Regional Urban Observatory including
development of a set of Pacific urbanisation Development Goals will be
explored. This will providing longer term &#x2018;backstopping&apos; support to SPC as it
takes on this new PUA monitoring and assistance role. The latter are vital to ensuring
sustainability of efforts at the regional level, given the role of PIFS as the
lead regional agency.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yoshinobu FUKASAWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Bernhard.BARTH@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Asia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Asia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-01">349600</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">317684</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">210000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacities to implement the Pacific Urban Agenda are strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacities to implement the Pacific Urban Agenda are strengthened</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pacific Urban Forum held with strong regional participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pacific Urban Forum held with strong regional participation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2012">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Event</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Event</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
