<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3114</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Urban Agenda Knowledge Transfer</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project&apos;s focusThe experience of compiling
practices for the sake of sending to international awards has been relevant,
and successful for its time, but limited for not being able to respond
effectively to the demand for knowledge.
The Latin American and Caribbean Forum on Best Practices has managed to
sustain a network of urban actors in the region, compile and review practices
for visibility in the Dubai International Award, feed the database of
UN-Habitat, and produce several publications over the years.During the last few years,
the project financed by the Ministerio de Fomento, has been promoting
activities and developing outputs to build a regional knowledge management
strategy. The idea is to achieve significant impacts by working towards a more
formal knowledge management program that is demand-driven and based on the
logic of going to scale addressing the themes of the New Urban Agenda. In addition,
the goal is to also take advantage of internal projects to promote the exchange
of the tools and methodologies in place towards achieving sustainable urban
development.ROLAC&apos;s knowledge management
strategy has been drafted and is in the process of approval. Its concentrates
efforts in its comparative advantages and aims to foster a complete knowledge
management cycle, from identification to transfer and communication of projects
and practices. In other words, takes advantage of the work carried out,
strengthening the good relationship with its regional partners and adapts
institutional methodologies to the region&apos;s specificities. The goal here is not
to replicate solutions, but to proof methodologies in the territory via project
implementation, learn lessons from its implementation and offer such solutions
combined with other specificities to other contexts and scenarios. The overall
goal is to address local challenges with an integrated approach to foster
sustainable urban development. The
knowledge cycle should work in coordination with project implementation and
communication to provide input for
future ROLAC&apos;s projects based on the process and lessons learned both
internally and externally.In this way, its important to
recognize strategic partners such as the Forum and continue to work
collaboratively to support their work as a strong and revitalized regional
actor. They have great capillarity in the region and can be important
interfaces of methodologies and practices in the local level.Also in line with this
strategy, the second component of this project, aims to advance beyond the
first stages of the knowledge management cycle, namely the identification and systematization
of projects, to a more-hands on approach toward the knowledge transfer of
lessons learned to new projects. The idea is that the project receiving these
inputs can avoid errors and maximize its results. Flagship Initiatives and
their potentialVarious of the New Urban
Agenda strategies and studied concepts have been put in place in the last few
years: city extensions, city infills, NUP, housing at the centre,
three-pronged-approach (urban legislation, urban planning and design and urban
economy). Once these principles are used they must adapt to local context and
respect traditions and culture in order to guarantee success. The scope, setting, phase,
decision processes and stakeholders influence the opportunities to the success
of the project. These concepts have been proofed in a few countries through
concrete projects and have shown positive results and lessons learned, yet are
still in the process of being tailored. In this way, these projects offer
solutions that are more consistent with the region, yet can continue to
incorporate new regional inputs and variables to the discussion on sustainable urban
development. Please see attached list of flagship projects in the region. The flagship projects have a
huge potential for cities looking for similar knowledge on the most varied
themes. In other words, not to tap nor transfer this knowledge forward in
effective ways, would mean a loss of the enormous potential of this asset. The
transfer exercise would help further the process of sustainability and ensure
that implemented practices are continuously improved. Ultimately the transfer
of existing knowledge may create win-win situations for both recipients as well
as providers of successful and innovative practices; &#x2022; For the provider: maximize the use and adaptability of its
efforts, in addition to learning from adaptations in new contexts, and &#x2022; For the recipient: useful knowledge and exchange from a
renowned and recognized experience to lead to fruitful results.In this way, these flagship
projects will aim to provide an opportunity to leverage the debate on
sustainable urban development, improve the understanding and tools to take
advantage of opportunities associated with urbanization from an
interdisciplinary approach via a concrete approach. The pilot project Achieving
Sustainable Urban Development (ASUD), has been implemented in five different
countries has the potential to leverage sustainable urban development in the
region. In LAC the project was implemented in Colombia, the Colombian national
office is in the process of compiling results and lessons learned. This project
will also enable a better exchange with the national offices and to learn from
their experience, provided it&apos;s a regional project. The novelty of the ASUD as
well as other projects is its interdisciplinary approach based on three main
building blocks, which must work together to achieve the desired results. In
other words, good planning and urban design must interact with participatory
policy and legislative framework to support ultimately resulting in productive
cities and improvements in welfare levels financial system.Both ASUD, like other
flagship projects have identified several lessons that are valuable to
consolidate this second urban transition in the region and use as a basis to exchange
the developed methodologies and knowledge built over time within ROLAC. In this
way, this project will work from the built legacy from working with the Forum
and its networks as well as with the national offices in the region. In accordance with the above,
and based on the example of the already implemented projects, the MOU 2016 aims
to &quot;build on the built&quot; (legacy) taking into consideration the
lessons learned over the years since Habitat II to seize the opportunities of
urbanization in the XXVI century, leveraging the knowledge created to other
cities.Considering the work done in
recent years, this project aims to:&amp;gt;Add to the efforts made
in previous action plans regarding the creation of a critical mass of documented
(systemized) projects that exemplify sustainable urban development;&amp;gt;Promote technical
capacity of intermediate cities in the region;&amp;gt;Work on the tripod
approach of the New Urban Agenda and projects ( &quot;flagship projects&quot;)&amp;gt; Addressing the most
challenging issues in the region: inequality, insecurity, informality, low tax
collection capacity, low investment in infrastructure, low local technical
capacity, among others;&amp;gt;Recognize the Forum&apos;s
work as a network and as entities committed to promoting knowledge management
in various themes and with various actors.&amp;gt;Display clearly what has
been the Best Practices Program during these 20 years and the important role
played by the Latin American and Caribbean Forum, jointly and through ROLAC, in
two directions:a) as a network for
exchanging experiences and knowledge, and articulation of common interests
between Spain and the Latin American and Caribbean region from a
multidisciplinary vision andb) for the enormous work of
identifying and documenting many good practices, which today are part of a
structured Library, easily accessible by all. Link: http://habitat.aq.upm.es/busqueda/bestpr.html/ http://mirror.unhabitat.org/content.asp?typeid=19 catid=34 cid=10264Project&#xB4;s strategyAs mentioned the project has
two focus areas: the first one was to take advantage of Habitat III to showcase
the Forum&#xB4;s legacy to plan for the future. In this regard, ROLAC worked
collaboratively with the Forum to develop a few communication materials,
including: flyer, poster and video, as well identified 4 best-practices from
the Dubai Award to evaluate their impact over the years. The goal is also to
start thinking of best-practices in a more dynamic fashion, considering that practices
change and can either be outdated or influence other programs and practices
along their lives, thus they need to be evaluated periodically. The Habitat III
conference also offered an opportunity for the Forum&apos;s organizations to participate
in dialogues with other networks working with knowledge management. Each one of
the Forum&apos;s organization was asked to write down their reflections about their
exchanges and possibility for future collaboration. This input, as well as the documents that came
out of the Habitat III conference together with a strategic vision both from
headquarters and also from the region on knowledge management will provide rich
material to formulate a white paper to be validated and signed by various
stakeholders in order to have a clear vision for the next 20 years. The
stakeholders are regional players and partners committed to supporting the
means of implementation of the New Urban Agenda. Also, the project will
focus on promoting concrete examples of
the New Urban Agenda, facilitating exchanges with a wide arrange of cities and
offering knowledge management services. Thus, a wide open-call will be launched
in the region to promote the opportunity of cities getting to know the flagship
projects. The strategy will also be to combine the open call with identified
work opportunities to combine supply with demanded knowledge to achieve a
significant impact. The open-call should be further discussed with the national
hubs in the region for them to also provide input on what is the best way to
offer cities that already have strategic partnerships or that are part of a
metropolitan area this opportunity. Thus, a consultation process will be
carried out and based on this recommendations, a open-call will be developed. In
the open call, cities should prove reasoning on how this knowledge transfer
contribution will add value to their in place working plans. Communication material will
be developed for cities to get to know such flagship projects, and the tools
and methodologies used in them will be showcased, in order for cities to get to
know the tools of the NUA. The projects will specify what they have done in the
implemented regional cities, clearly state principles of the NUA and also
mention the participatory process addressing cross-cutting issues (youth and
gender participation, beneficiaries, etc). The initial idea is that the two
flagship projects that receive the highest number of demands from applying
cities will be the projects selected to engage in knowledge transfer. The
applying practices will be chosen according to the below criteria by a
selection committee. Once selected, the practices will be informed and the city
focal point will coordinate with the project manager an agenda to receive a
UN-Habitat specialist to exchange. Also the UN-Habitat specialist will ensure
that local stakeholders of both projects can dialogue via email or skype to
promote peer-to-peer exchange, and if funds allow to also participate in the
in-situ mission. The mission will aim to help the applicant city with a
long-run plan. Criteria to consider when
choosing city: 1. Be an intermediary city in LAC as per definition from the
State of LAC cities report of UN-Habitat2. Expressing willingness to implement the integrated programme
in a sustainable manner, including its three complementary components3. Proposing co-financing component (in cash or in kind) to the
approx. 50-100 K Dollars that the programme will invest in the city.4. Commitment of National/Subnational levels of government to
enrich multi-level policy dialogue and/or co-financing the programme.5. Demonstrate commitments to UN-Habitat
principles and cross-cutting issues (gender, youth and climate change), as well
as security and resilience as other LAC challenges will attempt to be address
when choosing cities. The application process will
provide the input to carry out the selection process, either through the
application process or via strategic exchanges. It is important to note that
the transfer of a best practice can take various dimensions and levels and
should also be considered a bilateral process, where both sides have a fruitful
experience. Knowledge transfer is best pursued through peer exchanges. To date
the transfer of this knowledge has been difficult to promote, due to the lack
of committed funds for the exercise of peer transfer of knowledge and
practices. 

































































































































































To be successful, a transfer
exercise must be systematically planned to fully understand: what can actually
be transferred, why and how. This Project aims to capitalize in a larger scale,
through guided peer exchanges, on the experience and vast assets that has been
compiled via local stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTERIO DE FOMENTO - ESPA&#xB1;A PUERTOS DEL ESTADO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spain</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elkin Velasquez Monsalve</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Carolina.Guimar&#xE3;es@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-31">122727</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">94591</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">122631</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consensus on knowledge governance for NUA has been created by the end of the project.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consensus on knowledge governance for NUA has been created by the end of the project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieved consensus on a Whitepaper on knowledge management for NUA, this document will take as input the document produced mainly from content at Habitat III.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieved consensus on a Whitepaper on knowledge management for NUA, this document will take as input the document produced mainly from content at Habitat III.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">stakeholders have looked and signed the document.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">stakeholders have looked and signed the document.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selected cities have an improved understanding of NUA concepts and directives.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selected cities have an improved understanding of NUA concepts and directives.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selection Committee nominates representative for mainstreaming (gender, youth and someone who is focal point for environment).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selection Committee nominates representative for mainstreaming (gender, youth and someone who is focal point for environment).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Committee nominates representative for mainstreaming (gender, youth and someone who is focal point for environment) with accepted invitation.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Committee nominates representative for mainstreaming (gender, youth and someone who is focal point for environment) with accepted invitation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of cities with formulated and adapted practices/documents according to the exchange carried out with UN-Habitat experts during technical mission.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of cities with formulated and adapted practices/documents according to the exchange carried out with UN-Habitat experts during technical mission.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">cities with formulated and adapted practices/documents according to the exchange carried out with UN-Habitat experts during technical mission.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">cities with formulated and adapted practices/documents according to the exchange carried out with UN-Habitat experts during technical mission.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cities plans disaggregate their impact on the environment, youth and gender</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cities plans disaggregate their impact on the environment, youth and gender</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">cities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">cities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
