<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-1905</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Solidarity Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three decades of conflict, natural disasters and deteriorating economic conditions have caused massive population movements, both within Afghanistan and towards neighboring countries. Since the fall of Taliban regime, the massive inflow of more than 5 million refugees has increased the overall population of Afghanistan by 20 percent, with some regions having been affected more severely than others. Over the past three years, the worsening of security conditions in the South, East and Western provinces have forced further waves of population movements and internal displacement.                 Unable to reintegrate in the communities of origin due to the lack of social and economic opportunities and security, many of the population, particularly returnees and IDPs have sought for better life through secondary migration toward major urban centers within Afghanistan. Herat, Mazar-e-Sharif and Bamiyan are some of key cities where significant number of migrated population, refugees and IDP are currently living in displacement. It is estimated that 148,000 persons returned to Herat, 100,000 to Mazar-e-Sharif and 25,000 to Bamiyan. There are 1.9 million registered refugees in Pakistan and one million in Iran, and estimated two million illegal migrants in Pakistan and 1.4 million in Iran. Their imminent deportation will add to the strain currently experienced. Approximately 530 persons per day are reported to have been deported from Iran during the past eight months and the trend is likely to continue. Half of them are settling in Herat and others in Farah and Nimroz. Reportedly, Iran will issue about 50,000 exit permits per month till August 2012. In addition, ongoing drought in northern, northeastern and western Afghanistan is likely to place 1.5-2 million people into difficult living conditions, which will undoubtedly force them to move to urban centres, Mazar-e-Sharif being one.The arrival of these additional people into Herat, Mazar-e-Sharif and Bamiyan cities will rapidly exert pressure on local infrastructure and services exacerbating pre-existing vulnerability conditions. This will impact on the way urban development is managed particularly in settlement planning and providing access to basic services, infrastructure and labor markets. Status quo is not an option and would further lead to instability of settlements and the cities themselves.Moreover, the Government of Afghanistan and the international community have pledged their continued support to improve human security, governance and development in the transition cities. If local people participate in planning processes and see little or no result from external development assistance they may become disillusioned and frustrated with their governance. Many people may be forced for their own survival to engage in illicit activities such as drugs or can be attracted to re-join the insurgents to obtain incomes.The situation thus is dire and has to be addressed now. Based on its global mandate on urban development and proven track record in Afghanistan over the past 20 years, UN-HABITAT is uniquely placed to support communities in these cities and enable them to live a dignified life. Promotion of community solidarity through empowerment, job opportunities, easier access to infrastructure, and strengthened and accountable local governance are urgently required in order to prevent instability of the cities.One of the key lessons learnt by UN-HABITAT in Afghanistan is that anti-governmental elements (AGEs) do not infiltrate where communities are organized and empowered. As the AGEs will become more active when the winter ends early next year, it is important to launch this proposed project right away.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yoshinobu FUKASAWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Srinivasa.Popuri@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-03-01">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">4999757</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">5000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance governance and management capacity of Municipalities to absorb the influx of the migrated people, returnees and IDP, and to effectively plan and manage urban development so as to make cities more livable.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance governance and management capacity of Municipalities to absorb the influx of the migrated people, returnees and IDP, and to effectively plan and manage urban development so as to make cities more livable.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved government policies; capacity development activities completed; government budget allocation to urban development; municipality person-days spent on the Programme</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved government policies; capacity development activities completed; government budget allocation to urban development; municipality person-days spent on the Programme</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Number of government policies improved; the number of capacity development activities completed;
 % of government budget allocation to urban development; number of municipality person-day spent on the Programme">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal is to support the transition strategy of the Government of Afghanistan through strengthened institutional capacity of the legitimate governance institutions in the transition cities. Development objective is to contribute to improved living conditions and well-being of Herat, Mazar-e-Sharif and Bamiyan citizens through building community solidarity, strengthening municipal institutions, structures and service delivery.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal is to support the transition strategy of the Government of Afghanistan through strengthened institutional capacity of the legitimate governance institutions in the transition cities. Development objective is to contribute to improved living conditions and well-being of Herat, Mazar-e-Sharif and Bamiyan citizens through building community solidarity, strengthening municipal institutions, structures and service delivery.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number guidelines and policies developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number guidelines and policies developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="n/a" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of an improved and sustainable access to basic services and prioritized infrastructure, settlement upgrading and regularization at the CDC and ADC levels and reintegrating the population living in the areas into society</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of an improved and sustainable access to basic services and prioritized infrastructure, settlement upgrading and regularization at the CDC and ADC levels and reintegrating the population living in the areas into society</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of families (both men and women) to have access to social services at CDC and ADC levels infrastructure and they are integrated into society</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of families (both men and women) to have access to social services at CDC and ADC levels infrastructure and they are integrated into society</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Registration of 30 CDCs (about 7,500 families) in Herat and Mazar-e-Sharif, and 6 ADCs (about 4,800 families) in Herat, Mazar-e-Sharif and Bamiyan with the relevant municipalities to legitimize their presence">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
