<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3278</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project For City Resilience In Afghanistan (Pcr)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The
proposed Programme will build Afghanistan capacity for urban DRR and resilience
at three interlinked levels - community, city and national level for safe,
resilient and sustainable cities. It will demonstrate how the post-2015
frameworks, namely the Sendai Framework on DRR, Paris Agreement on Climate
Change and the SDGs as well as the New Urban Agenda can be localized in a
coherent and integrated manner. The experience through the programme will
benefit Asia-Pacific as well as other regions, therefore making Afghanistan a
global leader in DRR and Sendai Framework implementation.

Overall
Objective of the
Programme is to assist the National Unity Government to make Afghan cities
safe, resilient and sustainable by reducing disaster risk, human and economic
losses and impacts, especially on the life of women and girls and vulnerable
people.

Specific
Objective of the
Programme is to strengthen the capacity of selected Afghan cities for disaster
risk reduction through a people centred preventive approach and demonstrate
innovations in localizing the Sendai Framework and other post-2015 frameworks
and agendas.

The Programme targets three cities, Kabul (the capital with medium
earthquake risk and some flood risk) and Mazar-i-Sharif (the third largest city
with medium earthquake risk and high flood risk). Mazar-i-Sharif is located in
North West region which is the most disaster vulnerable region in Afghanistan.
The community level activities will target six GAs and 30 CDCs that consist of
about 6,000 HH. The direct beneficiaries at community level will be around
54,000 people and 4,250,000 at city level.

Outcome 1: Enhanced urban communities&apos; resilience to disaster and
climate change

Output 1.1: Community mobilization for resilience building

The Programme will mobilize approximately 6,000 HH in two cities to
formulate CDCs which consist of average 250 households and GAs which consists
of about five CDCs. In cooperation and coordination with ANDMA provincial
offices and Municipal governments, those CDCs and GAs will be formulated and
registered to the municipalities.

Communities will elect its chairperson, vice chairperson, secretary
and treasurer through transparent and democratic manner. Gender-mix CDC will be
recommended but if not accepted by community, they will formulate Male CDC and
Female CDC. In case of establishing Male and Female CDC, the vice chairperson
of male CDC will be a female CDC chairperson in order to reflect women&apos;s view
in the male CDCs which act as general CDC in the community.

Once CDCs are formulated, the chairpersons from each male/female
CDC make up the board members of the GAs.

Output 1.2: Community Resilience Action Plan (Community-RAP)

GAs will carry out participatory risk and resilience assessment to
identify priorities and infrastructure need. First, with the scientific
evidences on disaster risk in the city presented by UN-Habitat team, the
community will prepare the risk map which present possible disaster risk areas
with information on houses, public buildings and space (e.g. schools, health
facility, mosques, parks, public toilets, emergency storage facility, waste
collection points), and public infrastructure (e.g. street, bridges, canals,
drainage, stairs, street lightning) at risk. Also, vulnerability and capacity
assessment will measure the level of community risk awareness, preparedness,
current practices and capacity for retrofitting, application of building codes,
and safety of infrastructures. Based on the risk map and vulnerability and
capacity assessments, the community will formulate Community RAP including
disaster preparedness plan. In the process, appropriate technology and
financial mechanisms for infrastructure improvement will be identified in
coordination with Municipalities, Ministries and academia.

Output 1.3: Community disaster risk awareness and preparedness to
multiple hazards strengthened

Based on Community RAP, community will conduct non-structural
activities such as disaster drill and disaster education using developed
disaster education materials at CDC and GA level, at Mosque, school and
community buildings. The Programme also conducts peer learning and exchange
visits for sharing good practices.

Output 1.4: Community essential infrastructure more resilient to
disaster and climate risk 

Based on Community RAP, small scale DRR infrastructures in
neighbourhood will be reinforced/build at Gozar level. Example includes;
enhanced Flood Canals, improved drainage system, built and rehabilitate mosque,
community buildings and public spaces (with public toilets) as escape place in
case of earthquake and flash flood. The improvement and construction work will
be carried out by community with technical supports by Municipalities and
UN-Habitat.

Output 1.5: Reinforced Earthquake resilient houses in two cities

The Programme will support MUDH and ANDMA, in coordination with
related stakeholders such as academics and engineering associations to develop
the criteria of earthquake vulnerable housing. Based on the criteria, the
Programme supports municipalities and ANDMA to identify houses at the risk of
seismic failure. In two target cities, the programme will reinforce 50 the most
vulnerable houses per city. At the same time, training for masons, housing
construction workers, building inspectors and community members will be
provided.

To implement this activity, tools developed by UN-Habitat and other
organization such as UN-Habitat SHERPA methodologyand the International
Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies (IFRC) Participatory
Approach for Safe Shelter Awareness (PASSA)tool will be utilized.

Outcome 2: Strengthened municipal capacity for people-centred preventive
DRR

Output 2.1: City Risk and Resilience Profiles

Utilizing existing disaster risk and vulnerability information on
targeted cities including the recent survey by ANDMA supported by the World
Bank, the Programme will identify multiple hazards and at-risk areas.
Municipality and ANDMA provincial office with support from academics will
develop risk/hazard mapping integrating with geospatial information from &#x201C;State
of Afghan Cities&#x201D; data which has land use data with dwelling information
considering social environmental and economic factors that contribute to
vulnerability.

The Programme will also support capacity assessment of
Municipalities&apos; capacity that includes staff, institution and infrastructure,
using proven tools including the Sendai Framework Urban-Local Indicators.
Together with those baseline data, structural and non-structural needs will be
identified.

Output 2.2: People-centred and Risk-informed City Resilience Action
Plans (City RAP) 

The Municipality in collaboration with ANDMA will formulate City
Resilience Action Plan (City RAP) in participatory way. City RAP will be
developed based on City Risk and Resilience Profile (Output 2.1) and ensures
that City RAP embrace Community-RAP and their implementation (Outcome 1).

The capacity of Municipality government and ANDMA provincial office
will be enhanced through developing partnerships with communities, academia,
engineer associations, civil society organization (CSO) and private sector
through this participatory process. In the implementation stage, cooperation of
all these stakeholders are essential.

Output 2.3: Structural/Non-Structural improvements for more
resilient Cities

Based on City RAP (Output 2.2), concrete priority structural and
non-structural measures will be implemented to strengthen the resilience of the
city such as;

&#x2022;
Improve/develop critical infrastructure such as canal/river bank improvement,
drainage system, vulnerable bridges and shelters; Plant vegetation on slopes,
reinforce public buildings such as schools, health facilities and government
buildings;

&#x2022;
Advocate/raise awareness on disaster risk by distributing DRR information,
organizing events, public service announcements (PSA) through radio;

&#x2022;
Strengthen institutional capacity for risk-informed planning and decision
making by Municipality government and ANDMA provincial office through on-the
job-training and workshops;

&#x2022;
Identify gaps and reinforce the implementation of Building Code, training for
construction workers/private sector on DRR and strengthening capacity of
municipal government on Public-Private Partnership (e.g. for seismic resilient
design housing)

Output 2.4: Successful Afghan community and city resilience
building approaches institutionalized and replicated

In order to spread the impact of the Programme Municipality
governments and ANDMA provincial offices will disseminate good
practices/lessons learnt through workshops and knowledge products.

The Programme will also share successful Community-RAP and City-RAP
for scaling up in other cities. Municipality and ANDMA provincial officials
will be trained on these approaches and provided with tools to facilitate other
communities in applying good practices. In addition, international training
will be provided for the targeted cities to learn best practices from Japan and
other countries in the region.

Outcome 3: Strengthened national capacity for risk-sensitive urban
development to contribute to Sendai Framework implementation/ monitoring

Output 3.1: Improved risk-sensitive urban policy and decision
support tools

National level workshops will be held to share good practices and
lessons learned on building resilience at community and municipal levels so
that those good practices will be reflected in national policy, procedures and
tools to support decision making. 

The Programme will also provide policy recommendations and
technical support for the improvement of policies and regulations for
risk-sensitive and resilient urban infrastructure planning and development, especially
for MUDH on Resilient Urban Policy and for DMM/IDLG and MRRD on Citizen Charter
Afghanistan Project.

Output 3.2: Demonstration of coherent implementation and monitoring
of Sendai Framework, SDGs and New Urban Agenda

The Programme will support the roll out of Sendai Framework monitor
at national level in Afghanistan with participation of all relevant
stakeholders. This will take into consideration the related SDGs and their
targets and indicators those to monitor the Paris Agreement and New Urban Agenda.
It will also support ANDMA to establish linkage with the City Risk and
Resilience Profiles (Output 2.1) as local monitoring of Sendai Framework.

In addition, the Programme will promote city-to-city learning to
share successful approaches through experience sharing workshops and seminars
among Afghan cities. It will also promote Afghan experience sharing at regional
and global level through regional and global platforms for DRR.

Output 3.3: People-centred preventive approach to disaster
promoted in Afghanistan through practical actions by the government

The Programme will support risk sensitive planning in National
Citizen Charter Afghanistan Project through providing advices, draft guidelines
and awareness rising materials for DRR mainstreaming in &#x201C;Citizen Charter&#x201D; (both
in rural and urban).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yoshinobu FUKASAWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Srinivasa.Popuri@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster prevention and preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-01">3296800</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">2528924</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">3296800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced urban communities&#x2019; resilience to disaster and climate risk</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced urban communities&#x2019; resilience to disaster and climate risk</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community perception on communities&apos; resilience toward disaster and climate risk</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community perception on communities&apos; resilience toward disaster and climate risk</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="To be assessed" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of community members who understand the risks in their neighbourhood</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of community members who understand the risks in their neighbourhood</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="To be assessed" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced urban communities&#x2019; resilience to disaster and climate risk</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced urban communities&#x2019; resilience to disaster and climate risk</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community perception on communities&apos; resilience toward disaster and climate risk</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community perception on communities&apos; resilience toward disaster and climate risk</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="To be assessed" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of community members who understand the risks in their neighbourhood</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of community members who understand the risks in their neighbourhood</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="To be assessed" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">community members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of community members who have act to mitigate the risk and are ready to act collectively to respond to disaster</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of community members who have act to mitigate the risk and are ready to act collectively to respond to disaster</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="To be assessed" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">community memebers</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">community memebers</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened municipal capacity for people-centred preventive DRR</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened municipal capacity for people-centred preventive DRR</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of activities in City-RAP that two Municipalities implemented</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of activities in City-RAP that two Municipalities implemented</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adoption and use of City RAP guideline and Community RAP guideline by two municipalities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adoption and use of City RAP guideline and Community RAP guideline by two municipalities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">guideline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">guideline</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened municipal capacity for people-centred preventive DRR</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened municipal capacity for people-centred preventive DRR</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of activities in City-RAP that two Municipalities implemented</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of activities in City-RAP that two Municipalities implemented</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adoption and use of City RAP guideline and Community RAP guideline by two municipalities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adoption and use of City RAP guideline and Community RAP guideline by two municipalities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">guidelines</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">guidelines</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened national capacity for risk-sensitive urban development that contribute to Sendai Framework implementation and monitoring</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened national capacity for risk-sensitive urban development that contribute to Sendai Framework implementation and monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acceptance of policy recommendations (signed document) and implementation of those policies</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acceptance of policy recommendations (signed document) and implementation of those policies</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">policies</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">policies</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Usage of tools and existence of a report on Sendai Framework</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Usage of tools and existence of a report on Sendai Framework</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">tools and report</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">tools and report</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
