<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-13064</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fostering Local Communities Of Solidarity For Migrants And Refugees From Venezuela</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat, IOM and UNHCR as United Nations Agencies with
mandates regarding Human Settlements, Migration and Refugees protection are
proposing this inter-agency project to reduce vulnerabilities of migrants and
refugees and address the impact on host communities in order to design stable
and durable solutions with medium and long-term vision in Latin America and the
Caribbean communities.

As a result of the emerging crisis, more than 3 million
Venezuelans now live out of the country, with the numbers of emigration growing
strongly over recent months. While initially a majority had moved to the United
States and Spain, this changed significantly with the growing number of persons
leaving in 2017. At present (October 2018), more than 2.6 million have moved to
Latin American neighboring countries (first and foremost Colombia with
1,174,000 migrants, but increasingly also Peru with 506,156, and Ecuador
221,000. In Colombia, this also includes 300,000 Colombian returnees who had
fled violence in Colombia, as well as numerous families of mixed Venezuelan and
Colombian nationality. The legal status of Venezuelans varies across and within
the countries in the region, which can determine their rights to work and to
access basic services.

As a consequence, migration is placing significant pressures
on institutions, service provision systems, the labor market and the social
dynamics of the receiving cities. These include: (i) the greater demand for
articulation, coordination and response capacities of national and local
institutions; (ii) the overflow of demand for services such as health, housing,
education, social protection and water and sanitation, among others; (iii) the
accelerated increase in the demand for work, which affects employment levels,
quality and salaries; and (iv) the outcrop of tensions between the local
population and migrants, explained by the greater competition for already
scarce resources.

The situation is still very much in evolution, and decisions
in one country (e.g. Ecuador with the introduction of a visa requirement or
changes in residence permit) have shown repercussions in overall movements. A
large number of Venezuelans also transit through Colombia to Ecuador and Peru
(which now both also host a large number of Venezuelans) and further South.
Given their proximity, islands in the Caribbean continue to attract
Venezuelans. In all recipient countries, urban centers are attracting most
Venezuelans, offering greater economic opportunities.https://r4v.info/es/situations/platform

Latin America distinguishes itself by a very progressive
framework towards human mobility including asylum. Numerous agreements on free
movement, the 1984 Cartagena Declaration (translated into legislation of 15
countries in the region), the 2002 Mercosur Residence Agreement, several Andean
Community normative instruments (&#x201C;Decisiones&#x201D;) and the 2014 Brazil Declaration
and Plan of Action are an expression of the region&#x2019;s leadership in fostering
regional and integrated responses to migration and asylum. At a stocktaking of
the Brazil Plan of Action in February 2018, States issued the so-called 100
points of Brasilia, contributing to the consultations on the Global Compact on
Refugees. In it, States reiterated their &#x201C;commitment to regional solidarity,
south-south cooperation and shared responsibility to find effective and
predictable responses to the humanitarian needs of displaced persons,
asylum-seekers, refugees and stateless persons&#x201D;. Many of the good practices
highlighted relate to local integration. The important role of local
authorities is also recognized. 

While more persons are entitled to protection under the 1984
Cartagena declaration and the 1951 Convention Relating to the on Status of
Refugees, a limited number have filed asylum claims (e.g. in Peru, 150,270 out of more than 365,924 by 31 October 2018).
On the basis of general migration legislation or special measures, countries in
the region have already issued more than 1 million temporary and permanent
residence permits between 2015 and 2018. Both refugee and other residence
permits generally guarantee the right to work, health and education, freedom of
movement, and the right to start a business and the possibility to access
social protection schemes. However, some Venezuelans lack regular status, and
access to passports or other documents in Venezuela and abroad is extremely
difficult.

The EU has been at the forefront of pushing forward comprehensive,
development-led responses to forced displacement, its approach set out in the
2016 communication &quot;Lives in Dignity&quot; and confirmed in the new
European Consensus on Development. The EU thus supports a large number of host
countries worldwide in fostering the socio-economic inclusion of forcibly
displaced persons and resilience of host communities. The present action would
foster the new approach in the Americas. As regards local actors, the
Communication stressed: &#x201C;Close cooperation with local authorities as well as
longer-term investment in their response capacity is crucial to ensure local
ownership and the sustainability of the response. The most innovative
approaches are developed at this level, such as cooperation between cities to
boost capacity in areas like urban planning, local economic development and
service delivery.&#x201D;

Moreover, Council Conclusions of June 2018 on EU Cooperation
with Cities and Local Authorities in Third Countries recognised the relevance
of urban settings and urban challenges in humanitarian crises, and the need for
sound humanitarian and development approaches linking sustainable development
solutions, urban planning and resilience. The Conclusions provide the policy
framework for reinforced dialogue with local authorities and other urban actors
(planners, etc.) in crisis and disaster preparedness contexts, and the
mainstreaming of vulnerable groups in EU support to cities and local
authorities.

The action also builds on UNHCR experience with the Cities
of Solidarity initiative (CoS) contained in the 2004 Mexico Declaration and
Plan of Action. CoS recognizes the centrality of cities &quot;to provide
effective protection which encompasses enjoyment of social, economic and
cultural rights and observance of the obligations of refugees&quot;. Cities of
Solidarity also &#x201C;aim at facilitating the implementation of public policies,
within an integrated social strategy&quot;.

The action is also linked to IOM&#x2019;s Migration Governance
Framework (MiGOF) developed to help define what &#x201C;well-managed migration policy&#x201D;
might look like at the national level. To help operationalize the MiGOF, the
Migration Governance Indicators (MGI) were developed as a tool based on policy
inputs, which offers insights on policy levers that countries can use to
develop their migration governance. The MGI seeks to help countries in the
assessment of the comprehensiveness of their migration policies, as well as to
identify gaps and areas that could be strengthened. The MGI which is currently
being piloted at the city level in Montreal (Canada), Sao Paulo (Brazil) and
Accra (Ghana), aims to advance conversations on migration governance by
clarifying what &#x201C;well-governed migration&#x201D; might look like in the context of SDG
Target 10.7.

UN-Habitatis committed to the daily involvement of urban
dwellers in the development decisions and planning outcomes that affect their
daily lives. In this case, the host communities and migrants. The fresh and innovative notion of prosperity
developed by UN-Habitat, that will be applied in this project, raises a vision
of sustainable urban development in which the fight against exclusion and the
rights of a few, does not limit the possibility that prosperity will be shared
by all. The integration of tangible and intangible values ??inherent to this vision of
shared prosperity is essential for the respect of the Rights of women,
children, the elderly and all kinds of minorities, which in many cities today
suffer in different ways of exclusion. Also, UN Habitat have experience on
inclusive cities, inclusive urban policy processes, migration related projects
in the Mediterranean and the Arab Regions and projects on sustainable planning
solutions for shelter / camps (in Africa and Asia) as well as urban crisis
situations (Iraq, Sri Lanka, Afghanistan, Ethiopia...) which have promoted benefits
for migrant/refugees, IDPs and host communities.

Finally, the action is articulated and complemented with the
Regional Refugee and Migrant Response Plan (RMRP) launched on December 14th
2018 and developed by the Platform for Inter-institutional Coordination for
Refugees and Migrants of Venezuela to meet the needs of 2.2 million refugees
and migrants in 16 countries. Its main objective is to coordinate the response
to the needs of refugees, migrants, returnees and host populations, in a
complementary manner with the Government. The RMRP is a coordinated operational
response among 95 partners in order to generate complements and synergies in
the field work that directly benefits migrants, the host populations and the
authorities. The specific objectives of the platform are: a) To serve as a
coordination space for its members with the purpose of facilitating a joint
operational response that supports the efforts of the Colombian state, based on
the rights of those in need of international protection and the migrant
population; b) Seek to ensure that refugees and migrants have equality in
access to services and available humanitarian resources without discrimination
or distinction of age, gender and diversity; and c), Advocate for the
principles of humanitarian protection with a focus on rights, at an individual
and community level, to promote positive and constructive relations with host communities.

In the problem analysis, it is important to distinguish
short-term from medium-term challenges in an evolving situation. Countries
hosting Venezuelans in the region are mostly upper middle-income countries and
in line with the Agenda for Change, EU bilateral cooperation has already been
or will be phased out. 

Nevertheless, in a short-term perspective, the large-scale
arrival of Venezuelans has overwhelmed local and to some extent national
response capacity. An increase in demand has caused pressure on provision of
basic services, notably education and health, and the identification of
particular vulnerabilities, such as those related to human trafficking and
exploitation. Xenophobic incidents are on the rise. 

Taking a medium term perspective, it is likely that a
significant number of Venezuelans will continue to leave their country in 2019
considering the expected further degradation of the economic situation, as
hyperinflation and recession are expected to continue. While the establishment
of diaspora networks will facilitate movements, those with greatest mobility
will have already left and some lack resources to move beyond the area of
immediate arrival. At the same time, as set out above, most Venezuelans leave
their areas of immediate arrival in order to move to other countries, and
within these countries, to urban centers in the hope of greater economic
opportunities. This might not only include capital cities, but also secondary
and smaller urban centers. Host community reactions also affect the decision
for onward movements. 

The attention of Venezuelan migrants and refugees,
especially with a vocation for permanence, presents some challenges to cities
of neighboring countries:

&#x2022;
Physical and environmental challenges
associated with immediate greater pressure on infrastructure, access to shelter
and housing, and basic services. And mid-term affections to the affordability
of the housing sector, over demand of public transport systems, greater demand
for urban land, public space and social facilities such as schools and health
facilities, and negative consequences on the environment caused by a lack of
urban management decisions and inadequate response to resource depletion and
waste management. 

&#x2022;
Socio-economic challenges derived from
the increase in the urban population. When root causes and local governments
fail to response to the immediate needs of these vulnerable groups,
unemployment and thus poverty rates tend to rise among the migrant groups and
employment markets tend to transform into informal and or oftentimes illegal
jobs, as well as a sense of competition between host and migrant communities
over job opportunities (particularly seasonal and informal jobs);

&#x2022;
Fiscal challenges due to pressures in the
municipal budgets and the inability of many local authorities to raise their
own funds to deal effectively with urban problems, as well as the lack of
subsidiarity principles existing in highly centralized Latin American countries
where local authorities lack power and responsibilities over such matters;

&#x2022;
Urban governance and management challenges
linked to centralized decision-making and local institutions that do not have
sufficient tools and resources to manage the growth of the city and maintain
urban security and social cohesion. 

The aforementioned challenges occur naturally within cities,
reflective also of the fact that Latin America is already the world&#x2019;s most
urbanized continent with more than 80% of the population living in cities.
However, this also represents a big opportunity to address the situation and
improve reception agreements that offer adequate legal protection and services
delivery, such as basic sanitation and services related to their short, medium,
and eventually long-term needs. International experience in large-scale
migration suggests that, even when migration may represent challenges in the
short term, its proper management can create economic growth in the medium and
long term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-16" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-05" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elkin Velasquez Monsalve</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Adriana.Plata@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="DO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominican Republic</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="EC" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecuador</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominican Republic</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominican Republic</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecuador</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecuador</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-08-16"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-05">6791370</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">2739430</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Strengthened host communities&#x2019; acceptance and economic and social inclusion of vulnerable migrant and refugee populations in host communities.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Strengthened host communities&#x2019; acceptance and economic and social inclusion of vulnerable migrant and refugee populations in host communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1) Access to education and health of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) compared to the national/local average (disaggregated by sex, age, disability and displacement status)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.1) Access to education and health of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) compared to the national/local average (disaggregated by sex, age, disability and displacement status)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project." year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2) Extent to which national policies reflect recommendations provided by displaced persons and their organizations</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.2) Extent to which national policies reflect recommendations provided by displaced persons and their organizations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project." year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="To be determined once baseline data is available">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Migrants and refugees&#x2019; populations are better protected and have improved access to documentation, orientation and basic rights.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Migrants and refugees&#x2019; populations are better protected and have improved access to documentation, orientation and basic rights.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1) Number of target population that have been advised to obtain documentation and improve legal stay (disaggregated by sex, age, disability and type of document).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1) Number of target population that have been advised to obtain documentation and improve legal stay (disaggregated by sex, age, disability and type of document).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="To be determined once baseline data is available.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.2) Proportion of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) in urban areas living in slums, informal settlements or inadequate housing (dis-aggregated by displacement status)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.2) Proportion of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) in urban areas living in slums, informal settlements or inadequate housing (dis-aggregated by displacement status)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project." year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="To be determined once baseline data is available.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3) Percentage of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) without civil registration documents (disaggregated by sex, age and displacement status)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3) Percentage of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) without civil registration documents (disaggregated by sex, age and displacement status)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project." year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="To be determined once baseline data is available.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce vulnerabilities of migrants and refugees and address the impact on host communities</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce vulnerabilities of migrants and refugees and address the impact on host communities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proportion of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) living below the national/local poverty line, compared to the national/local average (disaggregated by sex, age and displacement status)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proportion of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) living below the national/local poverty line, compared to the national/local average (disaggregated by sex, age and displacement status)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project." year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unemployment rate of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) compared to the national/local average (disaggregated by sex, age, disability and displacement status)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unemployment rate of the target population (resident/host communities and displaced persons) compared to the national/local average (disaggregated by sex, age, disability and displacement status)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="A baseline will be defined in Result 1 implementation of the project." year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-09-05"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
