<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2440</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter And Coordination Support In Syrian Cities For The Most Vulnerable Idps&apos;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the programme is to 1. Increase capacity to provide emergency shelter assistance and essential services
for affected people in Syria 

2.Enhance the operational capacity of national and international
humanitarian responders and support existing local and community coping mechanisms.


Population and geographical targets:

The project has the following population and Geographical
targets:

Neighbourhood
coordination and community contracting:

&#xB7;
Geographical target: City of Homs

&#xB7;
Neighbourhoods: 2 neighbourhoods agreed by
stakeholders between population of 20,000 to 80,000 chosen for the pilot
approach 

Target
beneficiaries: 20
communities @ 500 families each (5000 families per neighbourhood). Total 50,000
direct beneficiaries&apos;s targeted in two neighbourhoods

Shelter sector
support

Geographical
target cities for Shelter assessment, housing damage assessment and Rapid City
profiles: City of Homs, Aleppo, Lattakia and Jaramana (Rural Damascus). Homs,
Aleppo and Rural Damascus Governorates have the highest number of IDPs.

Target beneficiaries: Atleast 50,000 in each city. Total target of
people reached 200,000 for 4 shelter assessments. 

Geographical
target for municipal shelter coordination:
Municipal coordination: City of Homs and Aleppo to coordinate at least 30 shelter actors in each city
including local authorities and respective technical departments, private
sector, charities and national NGOsin each city.

Families indirectly benefitting with improved shelters through shelter
strategy and options: Target 200,000.Outcome 1

Improved emergency response for communities and coordination at city and
neighbourhood level with local stakeholders

This outcome and result focuses upon building coordination support for
emergency response in affected cities and urban centres in Syria and responding
to priority emergency needs on community based prioritized set of projects in 2
neighborhoods. A UN humanitarian coordination framework for multi sectoral
purposes will be developed at Damascus level and piloted in the city of Homs.
Results and experience will lead to scaling up the approach in Syria in other
key locations. The primary objective of
developing a coordination framework for UN country team is to decentralize
humanitarian coordination at neighbourhood and city level to be as close as
possible to communities, municipalities and neighborhoods. Technical assistance to local partners on
defining recovery and response in key sectors is part of the pilot. The city of
Homs is proposed as a pilot due to the growing humanitarian needs, presence of
UN operational hub and a large number of actors that need to be coordinated to
leverage capacities. Coordination will take place in two neighborhoods as a
pilot where actors covering basic services, health education, shelter and other
areas will be convened together to promote coordination in an integrated
manner. 



The city scale is comprised of two levels: The neighborhoods in Syrian
cities are often an area comprising population between 2.000 and up to 250.000
inhabitants. The two neighborhoods and communities will be selected through
local community meetings with community based organizations, IDPs and community
members. The goal is to choose one neighbourhood each in Government and
opposition controlled areas to begin neighbourhood emergency response planning in
these affected neighborhoods. Since the neighborhoods in Syria are normally
dense and are currently hosting large numbers of IDPs, local emergency action
plans for each neighbourhood will be further divided into 20 communities as
units.



Providing access to public services as education or healthcare as well
as ensuring functioning basic infrastructure services of water, sanitation,
waste collection and energy can protect people from further deprivation and
violence by reducing immediate risks. The local emergency plans will identify
local community initiatives to be supported in 20 communities during the
project duration. 



Capacities of local NGO, Syrian Arab Red Crescent and community based
organizations will be strengthened in this process. Neighbourhood based local
emergency plans will facilitate decision making, consensus, prioritization of
efforts already taking place or in need of support. 



Outcome 2 

Increased availability of shelter needs assessment data, municipal
shelter coordination and strategy among sector partners Syria has 14
Governorates and each Governorate includes a range of districts, administrative
units as towns and cities. Currently IDPs are sheltering in informal shelters, public
and private buildings, rental accommodation, unfinished and sub-standard private
apartments and vacant places and slightly damaged houses. However the largest numbers
of Syrian IDPs are being hosted by friends, families, neighbors and relatives.
In addition, vacant houses in areas where people have left for other cities are
in use by IDPs. Current response to shelter needs is based on Government
managed collective centres where over 800 shelters are targeted covering less
than 5% of IDP population across Syria. UN-Habitat&apos;s added comparative
advantage in the shelter sector working group will be to understand the needs
of the remaining 95% percent IDPs and develop shelter support options for short
and medium term response. As no data and assessment for the sector is
available, SDC funding will be utilized to develop shelter needs and housing damage
assessments in 4 pilot cities by launching the assessment and developing a
strategy in cooperation with shelter sector leads and partners. 

Municipal shelter
coordination and strategy for the city will be improved through leading two municipal
pilots in select cities of Aleppo and Homs. The pilots will reinforce and
establish shelter coordination and information capacity in the municipal
technical services departments. Aleppo city is selected due to the scale of displacement
and IDPs residing across the city in dormitories, public and private buildings,
slightly damaged houses, host families and rental apartments and make shift
shelters. Whereas city of Homs, the third largest city in Syria, is a UN hub
and lacks shelter coordination and strategy among municipal authorities and
shelter partners. 

The key specific strategic
results will be as follows: a) increased municipal shelter coordination among
local authorities, technical services departments, NGOs, charities, private
sector, engineering and architecture related professional bodies and communities;
b) development of shelter packages and options in cooperation with shelter
sector partners particularly for host families, IDPs in informal shelters and
in need of upgrading or new shelter options and repair related support, and; c)
development of an overview of cities, displacement and hosting support, and
shelter, infrastructure and basic services needs through rapid city profiles.

This strategic outcome
will support the development of the next SHARP for 2014 and support for
additional shelter response options beyond collective centres only. The
analysis and outcome of 4 shelter assessments, housing damage assessment and
rapid profiles will lead to development of short to medium term solutions,
options and strategy for the sector. During field visits by members of shelter
working group, gaps in shelter
options and availability of shelter and housing packages to support IDPs
residing in various shelter conditions are supported by the shelter sector.
Shelter packages must also address upgrading support and site management that
will be required for both private finished and buildings and host communities. 

Outcome 3

Increased knowledge and technical
resources available to shelter sector stakeholders on addressing immediate shelter
needs



While technical capacities in development sector including engineering,
architecture and physical planning are strong in Syria, these actors are not substantively
engaged in coordinated emergency shelter response although more recently the
Engineers Syndicates have become engaged. Lack of appropriate and affordable
framework for addressing needs of Syria&apos;s urban population has historically contributed
to significant informal construction practices. Around 40% of housing in urban
areas is informal. There has been limited attention to the importance of gender
issues in urban planning and development, and limited experience in pro-poor
housing approaches. Understanding of environmental issues is however better
developed and practices on historic conservation are well developed
particularly as a result of GIZ&apos;s technical assistance.

Issues of community participation, gender, environment and pro-poor
housing form the backbone to inclusive reconstruction. Current knowledge gaps
and lack of appropriate practices in this area will be a major constraint in
securing a housing rehabilitation and reconstruction process that is conducive
to addressing causal issues of the Syrian crisis, unless capacities can be
built amongst key urban civil society stakeholders (professionals, academics,
private sector and communities) and local government on such issues. 

Building on the results of Outcome 2, local expert inputs, better
understanding of environmental and gender issues related to housing as well as
issues of informality, the project will provide technical resources and
strategies to guide the shelter sector in providing appropriate shelter
solutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SWISS AGENCY FOR DEVELOPMENT AND COOPERATION SDC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Switzerland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Ansa.Masaud@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Arab Republic</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Arab Republic</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reconstruction relief and rehabilitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-10-01">831578</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">974525</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1036964</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter rehabilitation programmes in crisis responses have contributed to sustainable and resilient cities and other human settlements</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter rehabilitation programmes in crisis responses have contributed to sustainable and resilient cities and other human settlements</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 coordination mechanism for cities agreed by UN agencies and UN country team</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 coordination mechanism for cities agreed by UN agencies and UN country team</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 coordination framework</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 coordination framework</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased support for shelter, basic services and livelihoods for the most vulnerable urban communities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased support for shelter, basic services and livelihoods for the most vulnerable urban communities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="n/a" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">20 community initiatives supported</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20 community interventions supported">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">20 community initiatives supported</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 shelter needs and housing damage assessment findings for cities developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 shelter needs and housing damage assessment findings for cities developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 shelter assessments with IDPs and host communities are developed</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 shelter assessments with IDPs and host communities are developed</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">New tool for municipalities developed on shelter coordination and information</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">New tool for municipalities developed on shelter coordination and information</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">A new tool in form of GIS data and information is developed to support shelter coordination in Syrian cities.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A new tool in form of GIS data and information is developed to support shelter coordination in Syrian cities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter options strategy developed based on shelter assessment</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter options strategy developed based on shelter assessment</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter options including shelter assistance to IDPs and host communities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter options including shelter assistance to IDPs and host communities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">10 new partnerships developed with shelter partners, universities, professionals</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">10 new partnerships developed with shelter partners, universities, professionals</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter partnerships developed between agencies, universities and NGOs.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter partnerships developed between agencies, universities and NGOs.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 shelter municipal technical coordination systems are established in Homs and Aleppo to support needs assessment</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 shelter municipal technical coordination systems are established in Homs and Aleppo to support needs assessment</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1 shelter coordination mechanism in Damascus" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">shelter municipal technical coordination systems</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">shelter municipal technical coordination systems</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
