<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3165</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Environmental Reviews In Urban Development Processes; And Creating Policy Frameworks On Environment And Climate Change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main developmental objective of the project is to highlight the central role of environmental reviews in urban development decision-making and identify and validate key implementation issues. Building upon this, the work will also begin to outline capacity building needs and coordination approaches that are appropriate to resource poor contexts. Specific recommended actions and activities will be identified, including any common needs for legislative, regulatory or administrative reform. This will: assist countries in the implementation of multilateral obligations; promote coordination between levels of government; and, increase the efficiency and reliability of decision-making at the local level. Ultimately, these activities will contribute to enhancing the quality of sustainable development decision making in urban areas. The project will be beneficial to support the implementation of UN-Habitat&apos;s legislative reform processes at country level and to provide UN member states with knowledge material and training packages to improve their environmental reviews and advance in the achievement of several SDG goals and targets and in the implementation of the Habitat III New Urban Agenda.These knowledge products will be beneficial to local and national governments willing to reform their environmental review frameworks, to international organizations and researchers.In particular, strengthened environmental reviews in urban development processes and their integration into broader decision making frameworks will support the creation of policy frameworks able to protect and safeguard the world&apos;s natural heritage, improve air quality and municipal waste management, mitigate and adapt to climate change and improve resilience to disasters (SDG goal 11) and develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels (SDG goal 16). The direct short- term benefits produced by the project outputs and their utilization are:Improved government effectiveness in particular the quality of policy formulation and implementation, reinforcing the link between public policy and law;Reinforced rule of law through the increased implementation and effectiveness of environmental reviews and urban legislation in general;A simpler and clearer environmental reviews system will reduce corruption and discretion of public officials and improve the efficiency of the public administration;Better understanding by city leaders of constraints in their current legal and institutional framework; andIncreased consideration of environmental implications of planned city extensions.Collaborating Partners: A driving principle of all activities in UN-Habitat is partnership. Through an active sense of cooperation and partnership, the organization strives to utilize all available resources as effectively and efficiently as possible while also leveraging other resources where possible.UN-Habitat&apos;s work on urban law is delivered in close collaboration with international expertise drawn from academia and the private sector using the umbrella of the Urban Legal Network. Government partners from existing UN-Habitat projects will be invited, with priority to existing activities with the most direct relevance and partners committing to reform. International agencies, particularly UNEP and the World Bank have already shown interest to participate. Contributions will also be sought through the framework of the United Nations Advisory Committee of Local Authorities (UNACLA), relevant multilateral environmental agreements and local government forums such as United Cities and Local Governments (UCLG) and UNACLA. Lastly, a number of Norwegian partners with comparative advantage and recognized knowledge have been identified and will be invited to collaborate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-16" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Robert.Lewis-Lettington@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Legal and judicial development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-11-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-16">312670</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">312627</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">306157</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased understanding of the relationship between environmental and development decision making in the urban context that identifies the principal challenges and options to address them efficiently at global and country levels.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased understanding of the relationship between environmental and development decision making in the urban context that identifies the principal challenges and options to address them efficiently at global and country levels.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% increase in the understanding of the participants to the EGM (before and after survey)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% increase in the understanding of the participants to the EGM (before and after survey)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-11-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50% increase">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of case studies developed and level of participation to the EGM</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of case studies developed and level of participation to the EGM</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-11-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of downloads of the knowledge material produced.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of downloads of the knowledge material produced.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-11-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2000 (the year after the publication)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
