<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2129</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Public Sector Modernisation Programme (Ipsm) Phase Ii</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GoI is in the initial stage of reform, which entails deliberate effort to build awareness, understanding and commitment to the reform process. Initiatives focused in these areas comprise the underlying purpose of I-PSM Phase II. 

The programme seeks to strengthen the regulatory and institutional framework and processes of national and local governance to enhance service delivery. 
Particular focus will ensure that sector service delivery efforts and corresponding human rights are universal where they can be (health, education and water supply and sanitation) and targeted to the poorest of the poor wherever possible. The programme adopts participatory approaches and aims to re-train and restructure ministries and governorate offices, Iraqi citizens will have a clear understanding of the structures and processes in government, its decision-making, and how they can participate in these processes. 

I-PSM Phase II responds to the findings, lessons learned and recommendations of Phase I. The programme is designed with a holistic approach to governance reforms, capacity development and sector modernisation.
The proposed intervention addresses the need of carrying out a long term, comprehensive and whole of government reforms at national and sub national levels focused on improving service delivery to the citizens in the three sectors of education, health and WATSAN. In Phase I (2010-2012), functional reviews of these sectors were carried out jointly by the concerned Ministries of GoI and UN agencies. UN agencies provided technical assistance in preparing the road map and costed service delivery models of the three sectors. Phase II will support the GoI in implementing the roadmaps prepared in Phase I. Besides the reform initiatives planned for the whole of the government in Iraq, KRG has agreed to undertake a comprehensive civil service reforms for the Region.

The Programme has four themes: i) Developing institutional arrangements and the distribution of roles, authority and decision-making mechanisms; ii) Piloting reform in three key sectors: health; education; and water and sanitation (WATSAN), focusing on (1) modern  institutional arrangements (with requisite laws, legislations, regulations and plans, policies and strategies( (2) Public Private Partnership (3) Cost-effective fiscal management and (4) Modern human resources management methods; iii) Supporting system-wide reform for gender mainstreaming, e-governance, national statistics and development management; and iv) Supporting decentralised service delivery and local governance initiatives, particularly focusing on development of tools for social participation.

UN-Habitat&apos;s expertise and background in service delivery, particularly in the field of water and sanitation, its ongoing relationship with the MMPW, and its knowledge of effective modes of decentralization are key reasons for UN-Habitat&apos;s participation in the overall programme.  UN-Habitat will focus on programme outputs relating to assisting the GoI in developing reform and modernization plans for the Water and Sanitation Sector, as well as improving decentralized service delivery in target sectors &#x2013; with enhanced local governance and participation.  

UN-Habitat in partnership with UNICEF will support reforms to water and sanitation sector through implementation of sector specific modernisation plans and capacity development programmes, as per the agreed roadmaps of I-PSM Phase I by the relevant line ministries, and in the KRG (upstream and downstream reform). This intervention aims directly at improving service quality through development of service delivery models, developing operational arrangements for utility, focusing on rationalized use and use practices as well as developing a medium-term fiscal framework to be a link between the policy making process, priorities and budget. 
Furthermore, UN-Habitat in partnership with the other UN agencies will provide support to strengthen the local governance institutions at the provincial and city-level, promote participatory processes, improve urban governance and support decentralised service delivery, including fiscal decentralisation (downstream reform). UN-Habitat&apos;s focus will be studying the options of urban local governance including providing recommended options as well as enhancing the GoI&apos;s capacities to support public sector modernization at provincial/local levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP (incl. one UN fund)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Fiona.McCluney@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">3143946</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">2606373</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">3107563</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GoI is implementing reform and modernization plans in WATSAN sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GoI is implementing reform and modernization plans in WATSAN sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pilot location proposed, organizational arraignments for corporate utility model developed, TOR for management contract and key performance indicators developed, household water diaries prepared with women, Sector strategy and policy developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pilot location proposed, organizational arraignments for corporate utility model developed, TOR for management contract and key performance indicators developed, household water diaries prepared with women, Sector strategy and policy developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">MMPW, MoEnv and relevant GoI WATSAN working groups</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">MMPW, MoEnv and relevant GoI WATSAN working groups</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GoI sub-national governance and decentralized service delivery systems strengthened through enhanced participatory processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GoI sub-national governance and decentralized service delivery systems strengthened through enhanced participatory processes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of recommendations identified, # of officials and politicians trained, Social participation toolkit prepared, No. of assessments conducted, No. of joint UN pilots launched, Study tour on urban governance suggested and # of politicians participating, Plan and Curricula for training centre developed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No. of recommendations identified, # of officials and politicians trained, Social participation toolkit prepared, No. of assessments conducted, No. of joint UN pilots launched, Study tour on urban governance suggested and # of politicians participating, Plan and Curricula for training centre developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministries, Governorates, Provincial Councils, Directorates, NGOs, CSOs, ILGA, Directorates in Ministries, Private Sector</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministries, Governorates, Provincial Councils, Directorates, NGOs, CSOs, ILGA, Directorates in Ministries, Private Sector</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
