<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2579</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing The Role Of Union Of Municipalities To Respond To Refugees&apos; And Host Communities&apos; Needs In Beirut/Mt Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the July 2006 Israeli war, UN-Habitat Lebanon implemented a project titled &#x201C;Good governance for enhanced post-war reconstruction in South Lebanon&#x201D; which aimed at enhancing the capacities of affected families and municipalities to better manage the reconstruction process. Within this project, three Regional Technical Offices (RTOs) were established in three targeted Unions of Municipalities (UoMs); Tyre, Bint Jbeil and Jabal Amel. The RTO&apos;s engineers and field officers, being part of the local communities, were able, in a short period of time, to mobilize and immediately provide assistance to affected families as well as to concerned municipalities. By assisting the municipalities with rapid technical assessments of the buildings needing reconstruction work, and providing information and guidelines for house owners with ABCs in repair work, the RTOs contributed to a broad and swift rehabilitation process with the local actors at the steering wheel. 


Based on the previous experience UN-Habitat now replicates the RTO model to support the efforts of providing shelter and services for Syrian refugees as well as meeting the needs of the house communities, by enhancing the role of local authorities. In the first pilot phase two RTOs will be established under the mandate of two Unions of Municipalities within the Saida/Zahrani and Chouf districts. After the pilot RTOs are put in place and anticipated system and mechanisms tested, the approach will be applied in more Unions with further geographical outreach. The aim is to establish a model that could work within all Unions of Municipalities in Lebanon, covering more than 800 of the 1000 Municipalities in the country. To ensure that the project is able to rapidly apply the model in new Unions, a second batch of another three Unions of Municipalities is identified. 
This proposed Project, with a focus on enhancing the involvement of municipalities in responding to the needs of Syrian refugees, would i) complement the efforts of the Government, UNHCR, and other UN, national and international agencies, ii) accelerate the assistance process addressed to refugees, and iii) reduce the tension between host communities and refugees.The goal of the project is to respond to the immediate needs of Syrian refugees and host communities in different areas of Lebanon while laying the foundation for medium and long term sustainable solutions. 

In line with the project goal, the proposed action is planned to achieve two main objectives: 
- Accelerate the accommodation process of refugee families through the active involvement of municipalities and unions of municipalities in identifying, assessing and facilitating sound shelter facilities that comply with UNHCR standards and norms. 
- Support host communities through the implementation of sound projects that would respond to community groups needs and would enhance the delivery of basic urban services taking into account the existing and forthcoming numbers of refugees.


The strategy would include the following:
At the national level, UN-Habitat has been coordinating and will continue collaboration with UNHCR, the Ministry of Social Affairs (MoSA), the Ministry of Interior and Municipalities (MoIM) and other concerned governmental institutions and International agencies. This is being done through taking part in donor meetings as well as working groups, mainly shelter and WASH, and inter-agency meetings.
At the regional levels, in addition to municipalities and unions of municipalities, bureaus and representatives of government and international and UN agencies would constantly be engaged in the project processes, notably the Qaimmaqams (Heads of district/Caza leading the regional security cells), UNHCR and other international agencies regional offices. The project will also collaborate and complement on-going and recent UN initiatives in the targeted areas dealing with issues related to Syrian refugees.


The project will set up a model whereby unions of municipalities, municipalities, and communities are actively and constantly engaged in responding to the needs of the Syrian refugees. Partnerships with key local actors represent a core value for this project. The involvement of local actors will prevent possible bottleneck situations in the response, as it will not be limited to agencies already concerned with overstretched capacities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNHCR/UNBRO  -Switzerland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Tarek.Osseiran@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster prevention and preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">348178</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">381444</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">300000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerate the accommodation process of refugee families through the active involvement of local authorities and unions of municipalities in identifying, assessing and facilitating sound shelter facilities that comply with UNHCR standards and norms.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerate the accommodation process of refugee families through the active involvement of local authorities and unions of municipalities in identifying, assessing and facilitating sound shelter facilities that comply with UNHCR standards and norms.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of emergency shelters provided</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of emergency shelters provided</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">households</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="600">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">households</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support host communities through the implementation of sound projects that would respond to community groups needs and would enhance the delivery of basic urban services taking into account the existing and forthcoming numbers of refugees.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support host communities through the implementation of sound projects that would respond to community groups needs and would enhance the delivery of basic urban services taking into account the existing and forthcoming numbers of refugees.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of staff employed to administer project</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of staff employed to administer project</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">(7 by UN-Habitat, 10 by RTO)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">(7 by UN-Habitat, 10 by RTO)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
