<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-8815</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">County Spatial Planning In Kenya: &#xA0;Support To Preparation Of Moyale Integrated Urban Development Plan, (Isudp) Marsabit Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With
the advent of devolution, resources are trickling into the counties from the
national government, livelihood opportunities are evolving and new income
streams are being adopted by the communities. For example, Marsabit is
increasingly having communities settling in more permanent settlements as they adapt
to new livelihood activities as opposed to the traditional nomadic/migratory
trends. Major transport arteries including the northern corridor have attracted
linear settlements while commercial nodes are fast growing into market centers.
There is likelihood that these emerging market centers will attract population
from the rural peripheries while the population in the settlements is expected
to grow. There is need to develop spatial planning frameworks that supports
coordinated growth and development along these corridors.



This project aligns to the United Nations Country
Team&#x2019;s flagship Ethiopia-Kenya Cross Border Programme targeting Southern
Ethiopia and Marsabit County in Kenya to reduce vulnerability and increase
resilience of communities affected by conflict and climate induced migration
along the border regions: Marsabit, Isiolo and Garissa and neighbouring
counties whose populations is affected by the above vulnerabilities. The proposed project also builds on the
latest efforts of the UNCT to develop a UN Joint Programme on Spatial Planning
and seeks to operationalize the National Spatial Plan (2015-2045), the overall
framework for sectoral planning that aims to address the disconnect that has
existed for a long time between physical and economic planning. The project
further operationalizes the County Governments Act (2012), the Physical
Planning Act, the Urban Areas and Cities Act (2011) and the County Integrated
Development Plans for Marsabit. The ISUDP, a normative output of the project,
will be a policy document guiding spatial distribution of land uses and
development control will be strengthened for the operationalization of the plan
in the township. As a result, the project will be seen as both normative and
operational (integrated). Lessons learnt during the development and operationalization
of the ISUDP will be documented and shared as best practice. While the
geographical scope of the project (2,374sq km) may be larger than the area of Kalobeyei
Advisory Settlement Development Plan (2016-2026), measuring 15sqkm, lessons
learnt by UN-Habitat from Kalobeyei will inform the preparation of the ISUDP. Lessons
from far afield such as preparation of the Kisumu Lakefront Development Plan;
the Darfur Spatial Plan addressing similar characteristics and the National
Spatial Plan for Rwanda will also enrich this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COUNTY GOVERNMENT OF MARSABIT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-14" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Jeremiah.Ougo@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-01">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">195465</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
