<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2958</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Un Advisory Committee Of Local Authorities - Unacla Project 2016 - 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Given the ongoing
political processes relating to the implementation of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable
Development and Habitat III, the role of UNACLA will be to ensure how best can
it support and strengthen the voices of local governments in these efforts
within the UN system. This project intends to ensure that local governments are
able to contribute towards the ongoing debate relating to national and
international processes on sustainable urban development. 

This project intends
to directly contribute to the goal of the UN-Habitat Strategic Plan for
2014-19, which is &#x2018;well-planned, well
governed and efficient cities and other human settlements with adequate
infrastructure and universal access to employment, land and basic services,
including housing, water, sanitation, energy and transport.&apos; UNACLA also
plays a complementary role to UN-Habitat&apos;s mission of collaboration with relevant stakeholders and other United Nations
entities to support local authorities to respond positively to the
opportunities and challenges of urbanization by providing normative or policy
advice on transforming the cities into inclusive centres of vibrant economic
growth, social progress and environmental safety.

Sustainable
urbanization offers a number of avenues for overall sustainable
development. Increasingly, cities are
identified as the locus for change and the venue where policies and actions are
mobilized. Cities have been able to forge new linkages among actors and offer
innovative solutions that have been included in national agendas with greater
possibilities of influencing regional and global development. Local governments
have emerged as key institutional drivers of city/regional growth. Their work,
vision and solutions transcend local political confines and exert regional and
global influence. Urbanization offers
many opportunities. It is these opportunities that the New Urban Agenda seeks
to build on by recognizing the
central role of local authorities in establishing and enforcing rules and
regulations, promoting sound urban design, fostering urban economic growth
through spatial planning and infrastructure investments - all critical components for the achievement
of Goal 11, and that the New Urban Agenda seeks to build adequate conditions at
local level to achieve Goal 11.

Local government
has and continues to make a strong case for its role as an implementing partner
of the SDGs to be fully recognized-to ensure that global and national targets
can be set, delivered, and monitored locally. Not only are many of the key
services essential to meeting Goal 11 at the local level, but local governments
are in the best position to ensure that the needs of local people are
understood and met, and that the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development and
its Goals and indicators are locally owned, inclusive and &#x201C;leave no one
behind&#x201D;. Simultaneously, the challenges to ensure that countries, in particular
the LDCs are also able to harness the potential of urbanization for
implementing the 2030 agenda for sustainable development are also known.

Furthermore, at the second United Nations
Conference on Human Settlements - Habitat II - held in Istanbul in June 1996,
national governments committed themselves to the objective of decentralising
authority and resources (Habitat Agenda, para 45(c)). They also
recognised local authorities as the closest partners of central governments,
and as essential in the implementation of Agenda 21 and the Habitat Agenda
(Istanbul Declaration, para 12). 

Since Habitat II, UN-Habitat
has developed its working relationship with the international associations of
cities and local authorities in the framework of a Memorandum of Understanding
with the World Associations of Cities and Local Authorities (WACLAC) setting
out mutual commitments to collaboration in a number of key policy areas related
to the implementation of the Habitat Agenda. The preparation of the World
Charter of Local Self-Government is one of these joint
undertakings. Its aim is to draw up an
internationally agreed, adaptable framework for the practice of local
democracy, as a vital contribution to the improvement of people&apos;s living
conditions in all continents and regions.The Charter has been signed by 120
countries including Turkey. The implication of the signing of the Charter is
that the countries have agreed to have a local independent administration. 

United Cities and
Local Governments (UCLG) was created in 2004. It was established to represent and defend the
interests of local governments on the world stage, regardless of the size of
the communities they serve. Headquartered in Barcelona, the organisation&apos;s
stated mission is:

&#x201C;To be the united voice and
world advocate of democratic local self-government, promoting its values,
objectives and interests, through cooperation between local governments, and
within the wider international community&#x201D;.

UCLG&apos;s work
programme focuses on:

Increasing
the role and influence of local government and its representative organisations
in global governance. 

Becoming
the main source of support for democratic, effective, innovative local
government close to the citizen. 

Ensuring
an effective and democratic global organisation.



The formal partnership between UCLG and
UNACLA has served to strengthen local authorities representation in processes
of the UN, with UNACLA as convenor on the one hand and UCLG as the most
representative global organisation of local authorities on the other.
UN-Habitat and UCLG signed a formal agreement in 2006 focusing the collaboration
on (a) good governance, (b) international dialogue on decentralisation, (c)
global observatory of local democracy and decentralisation, (d) localising the
MDGs and (e) revitalisation of UNACLA. 

Furthermore, The Global Task Force (GTF) brings
together global organisations and networks to promote and highlight the role of
local governments. GTF is the umbrella network
of 20 global organisations (including the UNACLA) with the objective of
&#x2018;bringing together the local government
efforts to be recognized and empowered by the future UN Development Agendas,
and to ensure the complementarity between the Post- 2015 Development Agenda and
Habitat III processes.&apos;

Diagrammatic
Representation of the Global Task Force Membership 



Outside the GTF there are other prominent
local organizations working towards the same mandate as well. One such example
is CITYNET that was created in response to the needs of growing cities in the
Asia Pacific
and is focused in technical cooperation amongst its city membership.

Given the
active involvement and engagement of the local government associations towards
these sustainable urban development processes, by a
letter dated 3 April, 2015, the UNACLA Chair communicated to Dr. Clos a
proposal to redefine the role and work of UNACLA by review of its membership
and focus of its work. During the UNACLA
members meeting held at the 25th UN-Habitat Governing Council
Session in Nairobi, Kenya on 15 April, 2015, the members discussed and
supported the proposal of the Chair to restructure UNACLA. Three main decisions were taken at the
meeting- 1. UNACLA membership would consist of 20 members from the UCLG and
Global Task Force- that is, the membership would become institutional. 2. The
operations of UNACLA should be kept to the political and advisory. 3. UNACLA
Reporting should be formalized. The Committee members will make a report every year to the
Executive Director of UN-Habitat, who will take it into account in his
reporting to the UN Secretary-General and to the UN-Habitat Governing Council
every 2 years.

The new
focus, membership and reporting requirements of the Committee would allow for
institutional representation, which would enable the Committee to be able to
better perform its political, policy and advisory role, and allow for the
members to strategically engage with the Habitat III process, the new urban
agenda and implementation of the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda.



Diagrammatic
Representation of UNACLA Reporting



The Executive
Director of UN-Habitat, Dr. Clos, approved the new membership of UNACLA and
invited the members for the Committee&apos;s meeting that was held in New York
during the post-2015 summit on 27 September, 2015. During the meeting, the members observed that the
Committee should be used for building an institutional partnership and to
further engage with the UN by having a Work Plan on the lines recommended by
Dr. Clos which included the establishment of a Habitat III Working Group to
engage in the ongoing processes including contribution to the zero draft
outcome document. The members were in agreement on strengthening the role of
local authorities and their associations for the implementation of the 2030
Sustainable Development Agenda and to make UNACLA an important ally for local
governments within the UN system, including the implementation of Habitat
agenda that would strengthen the representation of local authorities in the UN
system. 

Based on the new
membership and policy focus of UNACLA, the overall objective is for UNACLA is
to serve as a complimentary mechanism to substantive and programmatic processes
to enrich the voice of local governments towards 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development,
Habitat III, and other relevant milestones of the UN system in sustainable
urban development, including the new urban agenda. It is also to strengthen the capacity of the
local authorities &#x2013;&#x2013; in addressing urban challenges and taking advantage of the
opportunities. It is also to be an
inclusive participatory mechanism to ensure that the voices of the local
authorities are also well represented in these important global processes.





Based on the new UNACLA structure, the
Committee&apos;s objectives are as follows- 



To ensure
representation of local authorities and their associations in policy making
processes related to sustainable urban development processes; 

To serve as a
complimentary political, policy and advisory mechanism to enrich the voice
of local authorities and the local government associations in the
implementation of Goal 11 of the 2030 Development Agenda, participation and
engagement in Habitat III, and the New Urban Agenda;

To give opportunity to local authorities and their
associations to influence-Habitat&apos;s work program; and,

To serve as the forum
for inter-agency dialogue, consultations and sharing of best practices on
sustainable urban development processes.



It is expected that through the new UNACLA restructure,
local governments including those from LDCs, through their Local Government
Associations will be given the opportunity to speak with a unified voice within
the UN system to influence the work program of UN-Habitat, communicate key
messages on priority themes, and be strategically represented, particularly in
global development forums and national and international processes on
sustainable urban development, and better enable local governments to broaden
their dialogue with UN Habitat and other UN agencies. The UNACLA members will
also be able to lobby for the signature of the Charter so as to increase the
number of countries that would support it as the Charter is an international
treaty, and when signed, it is at the same level as the Constitution.



Proposed UNACLA Contribution to Habitat III, New Urban Agenda and Goal 11 of the 2030
Agenda for Sustainable Development

The trend of urbanization is
at the city level to which the UNACLA members belong. As of 2014, 54% of the world&apos;s population lives in urban areas. This
percentage is expected to increase to 66% by 2050 &#x2013; involving an addition of
2.5 billion people to the global urban population.[2] Local
authorities from LDCs face the most prominent challenge to address rapid
urbanization and progress towards transformative urbanization.Goal 11 of the 2030 Sustainable Development
agenda, on &#x2018;Making cities and human
settlements inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable&apos;, and its targets
signify prominent attention to urbanization in the development arena. Several
other Goals including that on climate change and migration also carry focus
that is relevant from an urban perspective. Habitat III will be an opportunity
to?discuss and chart new pathways in response to the?challenges of
urbanization and the opportunities it offers?for the implementation of the sustainable
development?goals,[3]
with a?view to generate a &apos;New Urban
Agenda&apos;. [4]

The New Urban Agenda seeks to build on the
opportunities offered by urbanization by recognizing the role of central and
local authorities in establishing and enforcing rules and regulations, promoting sound urban design,
fostering urban economic growth through spatial planning and infrastructure
investments - all critical components for the achievement of the 2030
Sustainable Development Agenda Goals.

The Committee is
uniquely positioned to make the following substantial contributions to these
sustainable urban development processes-

&#xB7;
Positioning local authorities as frontiers of the implementation of the New Urban
Agenda, including monitoring and measurement of Goal 11 by building adequate
conditions at the local level, including providing support to the local
authorities of the LDCs.

Enabling
the LGAs and local authorities to form
partnerships and strengthen their network for implementation of the 2030
Development Agenda, and developing a consolidated and unified position on
engagement in Habitat III and contribution to the New Urban Agenda at a global
level.

&#xB7;
Complementing the
constituency driven mechanisms before the United Nations, such as the Global Task Force of
Local and Regional Governments for 2030 Agenda on SustainableDevelopment and
Habitat III.

An opportunity for local authorities to address
the UN system to
communicate key messages on priority themes, and be strategically represented
in global development forums and national and international sustainable urban
development processes.

&#xB7;
Strengthen the relationship of the local
authorities with national governments and international organizations.

&#xB7;
Support the World Charter of Local
Self-Government which is a vital instrument towards the international
recognition of the important role played by the local authorities in the
cities, and to encourage and promote local democracy and decentralization.

&#xB7;
To gather the LGAs
perspectives to inform the outcomes of the High-level ongoing Regional Preparatory
Meetings on sustainable urban development issues.



Diagrammatic Representation of Possible UNACLA
Contribution to Sustainable Urban Development Related Political Processes





 http://citynet-ap.org/category/about/history/





Supra Fn. 2





 UN-Habitat Urban Visions No. 3, Vision for
Habitat III, available at-
http://unhabitat.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/UN-Habitat-Urban-Visions-No.3-Vision-for-Habitat-III-2013.pdf





 Ibid.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">External Relations</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Diana.Lopez Caramazana@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="3"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">405348</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">546042</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">enhance visibility and enrich the voice of local governments and their associations towards the political processes relating to Habitat III in sustainable urban development, and other relevant milestones of the UN system, including the new urban agenda</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">enhance visibility and enrich the voice of local governments and their associations towards the political processes relating to Habitat III in sustainable urban development, and other relevant milestones of the UN system, including the new urban agenda</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Local Authorities that sign the World Charter on Local Self Government with support of UNACLA.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Local Authorities that sign the World Charter on Local Self Government with support of UNACLA.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="25%" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
