<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2669</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Affordable Housing Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan has a long history of housing policy development and has been
active in international fora since the adoption in 1988 of the Global Strategy
for Shelter to the Year 2000 by the General Assembly of the United Nations. The
main steps were the following:1989: Adoption of the National Housing Strategy that covered all
housing components and produced a set of recommendations that governed the
Jordanian housing sector&apos;s activities for 20 years.1992: Merging of former Housing Corporation and Urban
Development Department to form the HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION
(HUDC) to become the official umbrella for the housing sector. HUDC was
mandated to work in two areas: housing production and housing policies. 1996: Launching of the Housing Reform Project that addressed the
major issues of the housing sector. The main accomplishments of the reform
were: 










 
  establishment of Jordan Mortgage
      Refinance Company
  granting the private sector rights to
      use standards (plot sizes) developed by HUDC
  launching partnership with the private
      sector, 
  changing zoning criteria : re-zoning and
      down zoning for smaller plots
  cancellation of the Housing Bank law to
      encourages banking competition in housing finance
  rationalizing of housing subsidies.TheHUDC&apos;s mandate is to develop comprehensive housing policies; activate
public-private partnerships; and enable limited income groups to access
adequate housing, A second function of HUDC would be Detailed Action Planning
in collaboration with MOMA (UPD) and municipalities, for selected urban areas.
This task should be financed by the clients/beneficiaries. It will entail:

. identifying with municipalities areas envisaged for future housing
development;. liaising with UPD to review their macro-zoning plans;. preparing action plans (trunk infrastructure development) for priority
areas.
 

 
Solving this problem is a priority for two reasons. The first is the high numbers of refugees
that have arrived in Jordan, all of whom need somewhere to stay. It is unlikely that there will be a swift
solution to the Syrian crisis, and it is anticipated that Syrian refugees are
likely to stay in in Jordan for at least the next 5-10 years. A solution that providesadequate housing
at scale is crucial for refugees and vulnerable Jordanian families, both of
whom have an urgent need for adequatehousing now and in the coming
years.

The second reason is that low and middle income Jordanian families are
finding housing options are limited for them as well. There is a strong demand for adequatq housing
for young Jordanians so that they can start families of their own, but supply
is becoming increasingly scarce as demand has risen substantially.

The solution contained in this programme will address both elements of
this immediate problem. Jordanians, who
have the right to buy and own land and property, will contribute with their own
down payments and borrowed funds, utilizing their individual credit capacities,
and will be responsible for on-going rental collection and mortgage
repayment. Although smaller than current
housing average size, these units are designed to be combined or expanded once
the mortgage is fully repaid. Syrian and
other refugees and low income Jordanians will have immediate access to rental
housing at affordable rates.The proposal is to
construct smaller 60-67 sqm affordable housing units, which will be designed to
be convertible at a later stage to larger 120-135 sqm units (in line with
existing market expectations), for rental to Jordanian or Syrian families in
the near term. The units will conform to all existing regulation and
legislation regarding the design and construction of houses. Apartment units will also be eligible,
provided they meet the other requirements of the programme. Units may be
constructed individually on an owner&apos;s existing land, as well as on a larger
scale by developers, potentially in mixed use developments, on land tracts
contributed by government with an associated cost of no more than 20% of the
overall build cost for each affordable unit. In mixed use situations, cross
subsidies may be applied to manage this land cost level (and potentially the
overall affordable unit cost). As initially
contemplated, the owner/purchaser of these newly constructed units will obtain
10 year financing, for up to 80% of the purchase cost, from banks at market
rates. Purchase cost is expected to be
JD 12,000 per unit (~$15,000). A minimum
20% cash deposit will be mandatory (less than the normal requirement needed, in
order to allow the participation of a greater number of Jordanian households).
If the owner chooses to install a refugee family or a vulnerable Jordanian
family in the unit, the bank lending to the affordable unit purchaser may
receive an interest rate subsidy (equal to the difference between the market
rate and a rate at which the loan repayment is equivalent to an affordable
rent) [direct from government][direct from donors/government] with respect to
the loan in question. Depending on final
determinations of construction costs, affordability and local bank capacity,
other financial subsidies may be applied, some of which are discussed below.
The individual owner will undertake usual landlord roles to ensure that the
property is maintained and the tenant pays rent on time, in order that the
owner&apos;s loan at the bank remains current through the combined receipt of the
rent collection and the interest subsidy. The programme objective is to
construct 30,000 new units over 3 years that will be privately financed, yet available
at affordable rent levels for refugee or vulnerable Jordanian family housing.The primary stakeholders of this programme are Jordanian families (as
landlords), refugees and vulnerable Jordanian families (as tenants).The Jordanian families will be owners and landlords of the small rental
properties, providing either their own land for construction, or purchasing
land to construct up to two units or buying from a developer up to two
completed units of housing. They will
manage the rental property (undertaking maintenance and rent collection) and
will apply the rental income to debt service.
Small and mid-sized developers and construction firms will be encouraged
to participate in the programme.Refugees and vulnerable Jordanian families in need of low cost rental
housing will be tenants of the housing units, paying rent at an affordable
level linked to the owner&apos;s mortgage repayment amount.Local banks and financial institutions will provide mortgage financing
for up to ten years, potentially complemented by subsidy or guarantee elements
provided (by donors or government) that will reduce interest rates or improve loan
to value ratios, in order to provide opportunity to lower and middle income
Jordanians to participate who might not otherwise be able to finance an
additional housing unit.The Government of Jordan and donors will also be stakeholders. They may
provide a subsidy or or other incentive to increase the supply of adequate housing. If resources are sufficient, these
stakeholders may also provide an additional subsidy to the Jordanian owners as
inducement to house a refugee or vulnerable family, for example in the form of
a conditional partial loan paydown after an agreed length of tenancy. The role of the UN and GoJ will be to provide
oversight to ensure that the subsidies are applied effectively in order that
these vulnerable target communities benefit from the stable, affordable rental
housing provided.The Housing and
Urban Development Corporation within the Ministry of Public Works and Housing
(MoPWH) will be an important Government counterpart as the lead Government
institution responsible for housing.
HUDC&apos;s mandate is to develop comprehensive housing policies; activate
public-private partnerships; and enable limited income groups to access
adequate housing. HUDC, through the
process of developing the National Resilience Plan (NRP) indicated its
intention to update the national housing policy, which was originally developed
in 1992. This project will work closely
with HUDC to develop a broad study of the housing market that will feed into
HUDC&apos;s broader policy reform agenda.
This, combined with the additional detailed studies to be undertaken
during the project, will provide valuable evidence to support policy
reforms.The Ministry for
Municipal Affairs (MoMA) also plays an important role in housing supply. It includes an Urban Planning Department that
designs and approves land-use plans for all municipalities with the exception
of the largest ones (such as Amman and Aqaba). They play an important role in
ensuring that humanitarian and popular responses to the refugee crisis do not
exacerbate urban sprawl, which is 7 times more expensive to service than more
compact models of development. The
Programme will provide housing construction incentives for development to occur
in more compact and sustainable forms.Broader
stakeholder consultations have confirmed that there is significant interest in
the initiative. The Municipalities of
Sahel Horan, Serhan and Ramtha (all heavily impacted by the refugee crisis)
have identified municipal land close to the city centres that they wish to
develop for housing. They have requested
UN-Habitat support, however, to: (i) improve the building designs and layout;
(ii) structure the financing; (iii) review various management options (eg.
rental housing) that would provide them with a sustainable revenue stream. Thus, the project will also help reduce the
deficits that plague many Jordanian municipalities. UN-Habitat has just started a municipal
creditworthiness programme to help improve municipal finances and these two
programmes will complement each other.Positive meetings
have also been held with the Central Bank, commercial banks and
developers. The Central Bank confirmed
that commercial banks have significant capacity to increase term lending for
housing within their loan portfolios.
Commercial banks have indicated their interest in developing new loan
products for this market segment, but are not yet sure how to engage with this
new group of &#x201C;clients&#x201D;. Commercial banks
in Jordan have, in aggregate, the needed term funding to meet the anticipated
financing needs of this $450 million programme.
Developers have confirmed the feasibility of designing a house to the
specifications provided and at the price indicated (JD12,000 or $15,000). A Jordanian institute has expressed its
interest to sponsor a national design competition to promote more compact,
affordable and livable urban housing.Additional
stakeholders may also include humanitarian NGOs. NRC and Premi&#xE8;re Urgence, for example, have
approached UN-Habitat to identify how its emergency shelter grant may be
complemented by an affordable housing loan.
Similar consultations will also be held with other NGOs which have
already secured grant funding for housing rehabilitation. In both cases, the limited scale and focus of
humanitarian funding can be complemented by more development oriented
funding. By combining humanitarian and
development funding, this programme will achieve outcomes more in line with the
right to &#x201C;adequate housing&#x201D;.UN-Habitat is providing knowledge services in terms of programme
delivery and the leveraging and alignment of government support. It is also providing advisory services. Specialized financial services will be
provided for financial structuring, negotiation and delivery through UN-Habitat
consultants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-18" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Iman.Zaki@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reconstruction relief and rehabilitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-09-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-18">1251098</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">194769</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">189844</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Framework, rules, procedures and capacity to implement adequate housing programme developed and agreed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Framework, rules, procedures and capacity to implement adequate housing programme developed and agreed</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policies and procedures developed and agreed  in principle by stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policies and procedures developed and agreed  in principle by stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Project feasibility has been established through preliminary design work" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreements concluded</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-18"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Agreements on contribution of different stakeholders agreed">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreements concluded</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government, municipalities, financial institutions, housing actors have better information and analysis of the adequate housing demand and supply in Jordan</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government, municipalities, financial institutions, housing actors have better information and analysis of the adequate housing demand and supply in Jordan</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adequate housing demand and supply issues better understood by key stakeholders from Government, private sector, civil society and UN/NGOs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adequate housing demand and supply issues better understood by key stakeholders from Government, private sector, civil society and UN/NGOs</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No common understanding exists" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main issues identified and understood</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-18"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Agreement on critical demand and supply side factors">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main issues identified and understood</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Demand for preferred rental condition against potential supply of adequate housing  units is quantified and understood by all stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Demand for preferred rental condition against potential supply of adequate housing  units is quantified and understood by all stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No specific figures currently available for adequate housing demand/supply" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unmet demand for adequate housing units</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-18"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Demand quantified">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unmet demand for adequate housing units</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter rehabilitation programmes in crisis responses have contributed to sustainable and resilient cities and other human settlements</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter rehabilitation programmes in crisis responses have contributed to sustainable and resilient cities and other human settlements</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable refugees and vulnerable Jordanian families have increased access to adequate housing</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vulnerable refugees and vulnerable Jordanian families have increased access to adequate housing</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="No data exist for unmet adequate housing units being built" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">adequate housing units built</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-09-18"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20 vulnerable households">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">adequate housing units built</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
