<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2923</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Federal Government Of Somalia And United Nations Joint Programme On Youth Employment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills development needs to be part of a comprehensive, integrated
strategy for inclusive growth. There needs to be greater private sector
involvement and skills interventions with a sectoral focus. Skills development
must be tailored to the needs and aspirations of the young Somalis as well as
the needs of the private sector. It needs to fit within the overarching goal of
developing and maintaining a growth trajectory and competitiveness of various
sectors of the economy that necessitates a skilled workforce that is aligned to
industry requirements. A comprehensive
youth skills package will be provided for youth from different
socio-economic backgrounds and according to the skills needs of the selected
value chains that will have been analysed. We will utilize existing vocational training
centres to deliver competency-based training programmes which respond to the
needs of Somali employers, as identified during the value chain study.
Beneficiaries will be provided with certification upon the completion of the
training.Identifying current and anticipating future
skills needs is the first building block of relevant training and skills
strategies. Several methods are
used to forecast future skills needs. These include: forecasting occupational
and skills profiles; labour market information systems and employment services;
engagement with the private sector; and assessments of the performance of
training institutions and the employment outcomes of their trainees.There exist opportunities for more specific technical and vocational training and
entrepreneurship training at various stages of value chains, particularly
in input supply and production to promote the inclusion of youth. Lack of
skills in particular crafts is one of the biggest problems which can be tackled
through the provision of well-designed training courses to increase the
productivity of youth. Similarly, opportunities for business start-ups and
growth of existing businesses can be facilitated through a comprehensive
management/training programme aimed at starting and improving businesses and
providing business development services (BDS).It should be noted that youth aspirations are different from what is
offered in some sectors, in particular the farming sector. Regardless of the economic opportunities available in the farming
sector, young Somali men and women are being utilized as labourers within
family farms which youth are not interested in.Key to the project strategy will be making the agriculture sector
attractive for youth who are not necessarily looking to be involved in farming. This will be achieved through the involvement of youth in the
livestock, input provision and processing stage of the value chains which will
be selected. This is because youth will be involved in agriculture when it
offers real business opportunities. Farming will also be attractive for youth
if it is technology driven. Enhancing timely access to market information and
communication, production techniques, new technology and financing
opportunities will modernise the farming sector and will take full advantage of
a generation of young Somalis who are more technologically inclined, more
educated and more willing to taking higher entrepreneurial risks than their
elders.It is important that skill development initiatives do not only focus
on hard, job-related skills, but also on &#x201C;soft skills&#x201D; that are deemed more and
more important by employers and are needed for the personal growth of youth. The &#x2018;Youth for Change&apos; initiative of UNDP, UNICEF, and ILO has shown
that through psycho-social rehabilitation and skills development, youth can be
discouraged from joining criminal and violent groups, can recuperate, and can
give something back to their families and communities. This is a process of
empowerment that can lead to children going to school and youths taking up
vocational training. It shows how such engagement with youth can promote social
cohesion and peace. &#x201C;Soft skills&#x201D; like leadership, personal financial planning,
communication and information technology will encourage development of positive
attitudes needed for employment. Other useful life-skills include health
information, civic engagement, protection of rights and political inclusion.
Psycho-social counselling and support services are necessary for youth who have
been victims of violence and need re-integration into society and will be
mainstreamed within the life-skills package. Building on a Construction Sector Analysis conducted under the SECIL project, a one-stop youth centre will be
established in Mogadishu focusing specifically on construction skills
development and building material production combined with life skills
training. In order to specifically target young women, the one stop youth
centre in Mogadishu will also provide hospitality training.The three satellite centres will
be linked to vocational training centres rehabilitated by ILO and will be
located in other urban areas than Mogadishu and will provide life skills
training only. The main One stop youth centre
in Mogadishu and the three satellite centres; this centre will utilize an integrated approach to youth
development by providing both young men and women with safe spaces in urban
settings where they can undergo specialized vocational training(in the case of
Mogadishu), meet and access information and resources critical to creating
livelihoods. The Centre will also offer young men and women a choice of various
arts, culture, recreation, and health services. Separate programmes and space
for young men and young women will be developed where needed. This component will
be expanded based on the needs identified by the city and the youth of
Mogadishu.Capacity of Benadir Regional
Administration (BRA) to implement youth projects and mainstream youth aspects
into local government projects and programmes, in particular the one stop
centre, will be strengthened through the establishment and training of a youth
unit and a youth advisory board at BRA. The Role of the youth unit and youth
advisory board will be established by BRA and FGS but may include mainstreaming
youth issues at the local level, policy development (for local government),
organisation of youth events, job fairs etc. Both, youth unit and youth
advisory board, will be a model for other urban areas to be replicated and
scaled up in the second phase of the programme.





















In terms of capacity development, relevant government ministries and institutions will acquire
institutional and technical capacity development on methods of collection,
analysis and storage of labour market and skills data. Their national statistics
centre (Minister of Planning and International Cooperation) along with the Ministry
statistical units, will be strengthened with technical assistance from a
technical expert who will be seconded to the line ministries. This assistance
will improve labour market information analysis processes and institutional
capacity at the national and regional level. The development of a full-fledged labour
market information system will take many years; however, the proposed programme
will begin to train ministries and institutions for better collection and
analysis of data relevant to developing appropriate skills training programmes
for youth employment. Furthermore, tools, equipment and operational support
will be provided to vocational training institutions and the one-stop youth
centre. Identifying, selecting and training teachers in the development of competency-based
curricula, and in the delivery and assessment of these training courses, will
be core activities for capacity development of technical vocational training
institutions. Furthermore, training managers will be provided with mentoring
support to ensure the sustainability of vocational training centres.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP (incl. one UN fund)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-29" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Britta.PETERS@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-09-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-29">4374800</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">3547658</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">4374800</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced longer term employability of youth in sectors with high growth and employment potential.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced longer term employability of youth in sectors with high growth and employment potential.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of trained youth employed within 6 months</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of trained youth employed within 6 months</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of trained youth employed within 6 months</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-09-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of trained youth employed within 6 months</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth who have received training (basic literacy, numeracy, life-skills, vocational and business training).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth who have received training (basic literacy, numeracy, life-skills, vocational and business training).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth received training</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-09-29"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20,000:
   13,000 (urban) 
   7,000 (rural)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of youth received training</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
