<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-8547</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Guidelines_Nor</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.3.	PurposeThe overall Objective of the Project is to:Enhanced knowledge and technical capacities in applying urban and territorial planning to guide improvements in the health of both places and people, in compliance with the International guidelines on Urban and Territorial PlanningThe Project will achieve this Objective through the following Expected Accomplishments (EAs):?	EA1: Enhanced global awareness of tools, frameworks and practices that employ urban and territorial planning as a means to improve the health of environment and population.  ?	EA2: Strengthened technical and institutional capacities to improve policies, plans, designs and implementation processes in two selected countries.environmentally sustainable cities and territories and better health outcomes for the population.Based on current active engagements, there are three potential entry points for work on urban health and environment (e.g.) air quality where UN-Habitat and partners have ongoing initiatives. The Guidelines will be implemented in three countries where the entry point is a specific health concern: Ebola in Liberia, Air Quality in Belarus and mitigation of short-lived climate pollutants in Ghana. The Advisory services and capacity development will be based on guiding frameworks that will be developed in the project to develop a coherent approach to urban environment and health through urban planning based on available UN-Habitat and WHO tools.2.4.	AlignmentThe Project aligns with existing priorities, as follows:Local Priorities	This project will be implemented in two cities where improving urban health is a local priority. Candidate city may be sought from amongst the countries with demand for implementation of the International Guidelines on Urban and Territorial Planning at country/city level and UN-Habitat Regional and Country Offices.National Priorities	Improving urban health is a high priority in Liberia which has recovered from an Ebola epidemic. Energy efficiency and green urban development is a priority in Belarus under the GEF. Countries where implementation of IG-UTP has been introduced or is awaiting to be introduced based on demand have also been short-listed (e.g. Tunisia, Vietnam).Regional Priorities	The Geneva UN Charter on Sustainable Housing discourages urban sprawl and emphasizes urban and territorial planning to achieve compact housing and settlements. It advocates for more integrated urban development and regeneration with workplaces and services brought into closer spatial relation to housing, while taking into account potential dangers and hazards;Global Priorities	The project will contribute to the implementation of the New Urban Agenda on territorial development which identifies health outcomes (healthy cities, public health and individual health) as intimately related with sustainable urban and territorial development.The Sustainable Development Agenda includes several relevant targets, including the following which are most relevant:SDG 3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages3.9: By 2030, substantially reduce the number of deaths and illnesses from hazardous chemicals and air, water and soil pollution and contaminationSDG 11: Make cities and human settlements inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable:11.a: Support positive economic, social and environmental links between urban, per-urban and rural areas by strengthening national and regional development planning11.3: By 2030, enhance inclusive and sustainable urbanization and capacity for participatory, integrated and sustainable human settlement planning and management in all countries11.7: By 2030, provide universal access to safe, inclusive and accessible, green and public spaces, in particular for women and children, older persons and persons with disabilities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Planning and Design</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rafael Tuts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Remy.SIETCHIPING@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-01">204000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">201578</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">200291</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA1: Enhanced global awareness of tools, frameworks and practices that employ urban and territorial planning as a means to improve the health of environment and population.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA1: Enhanced global awareness of tools, frameworks and practices that employ urban and territorial planning as a means to improve the health of environment and population.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three knowledge products developed to support the implementation of the Guidelines from an environment and health perspective.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three knowledge products developed to support the implementation of the Guidelines from an environment and health perspective.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0 documents" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3 documents">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA2: Strengthened technical and institutional capacities to improve policies, plans, designs and implementation processes in two selected countries.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA2: Strengthened technical and institutional capacities to improve policies, plans, designs and implementation processes in two selected countries.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 70% of policy-makers / planners / participants have confirmed better understanding of the IG-UTP and ability to mainstream health into urban and territorial planning.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 70% of policy-makers / planners / participants have confirmed better understanding of the IG-UTP and ability to mainstream health into urban and territorial planning.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0 %" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70 %">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
