<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-740</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Empowering Urban Women Entrepreneurs Through Housing Development And Land Ownership In Ethiopia And Mozambique.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are living in an increasingly urbanizing world
and recent estimates indicate that more than 2 billion people will be added to
the number of urban dwellers in developing countries over the next 2 decades . In many cities of developing countries more than half of the urban
population lives in slums and squatter settlements in sub-standard housing and
without basic services. In some African cities, the figures are as high as
60-70 percent. Women constitute the majority of both urban and rural poor the
world over. Many informal settlements have a high proportion of female-headed
households. Globally, it is estimated that 41% of female-headed households live
below the locally defined poverty line.

Unequal power relations between women and men,
unequal inheritance rights in some countries, limited or no access to
productive resources such as land and property, credit and technologies, as
well as inadequate support for women entrepreneurship are some of the major
causes of women&apos;s poverty. Many times inheritance is treated as a secondary
issue in policies concerning women, Yet inheritance is the
commonest way women are denied fair access to land. In some countries the
constitution still provides for discriminatory customary practices against
women. &quot;Women are still grossly denied the right to adequate housing and
related rights such as land and water. We live in a world today where
millions of women are homeless and landless. Many millions more due to
non-implementation of their rights to housing and land, are one step away from
becoming homeless and landless. Poverty is a critical overlaying factor that
intersects with the other factors to deny wornen their right to adequate
housing.&quot;Security of tenure for women and children may not be
realized, due to unequal household relationships based on discriminatory laws,
customs, traditions and/or economics. In settlements upgrading involving
regularization of tenure, or in new projects, specific measures must be taken
to ensure that extension of secure tenure benefits men and women.

Achieving the millennium development
goals agreed to by all governments will not only require us to provide shelter
for the homeless but to provide decent and affordable shelter for more than a
billion slum dwellers by the year 20203 . One of the challenges in
meeting the Millennium Development Goals on the prevention of slums is
mobilizing financial resources necessary for both upgrading and slum prevention
by supplying nevv and affordable housing to lower income groups on a large
scale.

If adequate financial resources are not set aside
for the developinent of urban shelter and requisite services, then the growing
urban population will be caught up in the vicious circle of poverty and will
live in deplorable housing and have poor health. In many developing countries,
it is unlikely that conventional sources of funds will be available for
investment on the scale required to meet the projected demand for land and
housing development. Complete houses available through mortgage finance are way
beyond the reach of many people in the developing countries because they are
not able to raise the requisite deposits and income criteria set by
conventional mortgage institutions* The mujority of the urban poor are only
able to build their houses incrementally in stages, as and when financial
resources become available,

Governments in the HABITAT Agenda affirmed their
commitment to gender equality. They expressed a need for undertaking
legislative and administrative reforms to give women full and equal access to
economic resources, including the right to inheritance and the ownership of
land and other property. At its 19111 Session, the UN HABITAT
Governing Council adopted Resolution 1 9/16 Women&apos;s roles and rights in human
settlements development and sfum upgrading, which invites governments to
increase financial and other assistance to LVN-HABITAT to enable the
Programme to strengthen the mainstreaming of gender issues and the work of the
Gender Coordinating Unit, in particular in support of gender specific slum
upgrading projects and especially those related to employment creation, women&apos;s
empmverment, housing improvement and property rights. The Governing Council at
its 20th Session adopted resolution 20/7 on Gender equality in human
settlements development, which further urges governments to promote proactive
policies in favour of strengthening effective women&apos;s rights to land and shelter.
Governments reaffirmed their support for women&apos;s rights to land, housing and
property when they adopted Resolution 2] /9 Women&apos;s fand and property rights
and access to finance.

The General Assembly in paragraph 58 in Resolution
A/RES/60/1 2005 World Summit Outcome adopted at its 60th Session
reaffirm that the full and effective implementation of the goals and objectives
of the Beijing Declaration and Platform fbr Action and the outcome of the
twenty-third session of the General Assembly is an essential contribution to
achieving the internationally agreed development goals including those
contained in the Millennium Declaration and resolves to promote gender equality
and eliminate pervasive gender discrimination by: (a) GLIaranteeing the free
and equal right of women to own and inherit property and ensuring secure tenure
of property and housing by women; (b) Promoting women&apos;s equal access to labour
markets, sustainable employment and adequate labour protection; and (c)
Ensuring equat access of &apos;Nomen to productive assets and resources, including
land. credit and technology.

Mozambique

Mozambique emerged from a devastating civil and
near bankruptcy in 1992. The country has been recovering since then and is
recorded as an international success story even though it is still one of the
poorest countries in the world&quot;. The civil vvar prompted an unprecedented
migration to urban areas, The end of the civil war only increased the urban
pressures as people were desperately seeking employment opportunities in the
cities. The majority of the migrants established themselves in informal
settlements.

Women&apos;s roles and their resource ownership are
greatly shaped by Mozambique&apos;s cultural and traditional background. According
to a study done by UN-HABITAT in 2004, women have not historically been able to
get land leases, to inherit nor have equal access to education. Over the years
the Mozambican government has made strides in attempting to address gender
inequalities, by giving constitutional protection against any form of discrimination,
as well as granting women an explicit right to lease land. In spite of
constitutional provisions on paper, in practice women still continue to be
denied land leases. They have a low representation in the f01mal employment
sector, have less access to education. and are less informed about their rights
and some become destitute upon death of a partner.






e

All land in Mozambique belongs to the state and people only
get occupation or lease rights. l&quot;he 1 997 Land Lavv granted individuals
land rights based on historical occupation, accepting oral witnesses for
ruling. While the law formally protects squatting practices as it allows people
to occupy land that they have been living on for a period of not less than ten
years, it has not proved effective in granting permanent settlement rights to
its occupants. Residents have constitutional rights to land they live on, even
if they have no formal title. If the government or municipality requires a
particular piece of [and, they are required to provide land elsewhere and to
compensate for any improvements.

Any dweller has the right to land he or she has occupied for
ten years provided it has been for residential purposes. Without a formal title
to land it is very difficult to obtain financing for small scale developments.
According to a study by UN-HABITAT 011 land management in Maputo it was
estimated that the cost of building a three bed-roomed house on land W&apos;ith
basic infrastructure such as water, electricity and sanitation at 3200 US
dollar&apos;.

Microfinance is promoted by the government, but niortgaging
land is illegal. Borrowers can therefore only use structures on rand they
occupy for collateral. Given the dominance of non informal methods of ownership
of land, the situation of secL1rity of tenure and ownership of land for women
are still problematic even though there are written laws protecting women. Most
of the poor who are mostly women do not have enough income to make their living
through the informal settlements.

Ethiopia

Ethiopia has a population of about 68 million and is the
second most populous country in SubSaharan Africa. In 1975 Ethiopia&apos;s
population was estimated at 33.9 million and 3.5 million people living in urban
areas. The population increased to 53.5 million with 7.3 living in urban areas
in 1994 and by 2002 the population had reached 67.7 million with 15 percent
urbanites and of these urbanites about 80 percent live in crowded slums and
other informai settlements 6 7.

Research carried out by UN-HABITAT in 1996 suggests that in
urban Ethiopia as a whole, 61 percent of the population is working in the
informal sector nearly two thirds of which are women. Studies done by the
Association of Ethiopian Microfinance Institutions in 2002 put the figure of
those employed in the informal sector at 51 percent of the economically active
and it was then estimated that 70 percent of these &#x2022;wvere women 8.

There are Inany constraints facing the fight against
poverty, including a dearth of food aid, inadequate health services for the
rural poor, and inadequate social infrastructure (schools, and water supplies).
Weak technical capacity and poor financial resources are also major
constraints. Social and natural calamities both contribute to maintaining the
pervasiveness of poverty in Ethiopia. 45 Percent of Ethiopia&apos;s population can
be categorised as absolutely poor . Urban poverty is manifested in persistently
growing unemployment, poor quality dwellings and homelessness, increasing
number of slums and squatter neighbourhoods, congestion, lack of basic services
and infrastructure.

Prior to 1975 Ethiopia had no clear urban land and housing
policies. After the ousting of Emperor Haile Selassi&apos;s regime by a socialist
oriented government all urban land and rental dwellings were nationalized by
passing proclamation No, 47/1975 in July, 1975. The proclamation abolished all
forms of tenure. According to the proclamation, any person or family was
granted use of urban land up to 500 square meters for the purposes of building
a dwelling. After 1975 all undeveloped land became state property and was
distributed to all Ethiopians who wanted to build their homes.

It is also important to note that large-scale private
housing construction through real estate developers and private rental housing
were prohibited. The open market exchange of houses was also not permitted.
Houses could only be sold to co-owners or to the government. The proclamation
which vvas issued in 19933 while maintaining urban land as public property,
introduced a lease holding system which underlined that the use right of land
would have both market value and time limit. Real estate developers were given
60 year leases whilst private developers were given 50 to 99 year leases. Under
the lease hold system an individual house cooperative member was allowed a plot
not exceeding 73 square metres free of charge for building a dwelling. Plots
between 75 and 175 square metres were leased out at a nominal fee of about 0.50
Birr per square metre per year. Some of the housing cooperative members who
could afford to pay opted for the larger plots. Land bigger than 175 square
metres was also available on the property market through public tender.

In 2004 the Ethiopian Government set up
the Integrated Housing Development Programme whose objective was to provide-low
cost housing for all sections of Lhe society. Starting 2005, Ethiopia&apos;s urban
development policies which were modeled around participatory democracy,
environmental soundness, capacity building and accelerated economic gro mM11
vvere f.ocusing mainly on providing efficient and effective public services for
urban residents. A Decentralized Land Development and Administration Agency
(LDAA) was established to spearhead the provision of serviced [and to meet
urban development needs in Addis Ababa and the other subcities. Under this
programme the urban poor were mobilized into housing cooperatives and as a
result women specific housing cooperatives were also formed. The government is
still up-scaling the initiative and it is hoped that by 2010 the programme
would have been introduced to more than 194 cities and towns and 400,000
housing units would have been built. The challenge to this programme is the
lack of intermediary organizations between the comnunity and women housing cooperatives
on the one hand and the government and the LDAA on the other. The proposed
women land Access Trusts for Ethiopia will go a long way in bridging the gap.

The culture that denies women the right to land is
considered to be the main threat to security of tenure f&#xF6;r women. Generally
speaking under Ethiopian culture security of tenure does not necessarily extend
to women, for instance, houses are either constructed or purchased in the name
of the husband. Should the husband die and the wife is still alive she has to
go through court proceedings to secure legal access to the family house. Should
a divorce or separation take place in wedlock, in nearly all the cases it is
the woman who is forced to look for another house. In the event that she has no
regular income of her own, she might be left with the humiliating option of
being homeless or in squatter settlements.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="IMPLEMENTING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MCM</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spain</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP (incl. one UN fund)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Mathias.Spaliviero@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-04-01">781600</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1172234</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1149600</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
