<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-7454</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical Assistance For The Implementation  Of New Urban Agenda At Local Level In Cuba (Nuac)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the
implementation of the Technical Assistance to accompany the Government of Cuba in
the implementation of the NUA that was carried out in Cuba in the period
2017-2018, the first step for the localization of the NUA has been to analyse
the current situation of the National Urban Policy of the country.

The analysis
on the territorial and urban context was conducted and its result has been an
approximation to the current situation of urban planning and territory
management in Cuba, but above all, it includes an analysis on the trends and
tendencies on which the implementation of the NUA should be focused and which
will be relevant in the coming years. 

Below are the main findings of the
analysis performed:

&#xB7;
Cuba has a high level of human
development despite having a low per capita income.

&#xB7;
The national population will begin to
decrease from 2025 if trends continue.

&#xB7;
Cuba shows a high level of
urbanization.

&#xB7;
The average population density in
urban areas is around 4,500 inhabitants/km2.

&#xB7;
The population is distributed in a
balanced way in a planned settlement system.

&#xB7;
The institutional structure of
urban planning is vertical, although a decentralization process started.

&#xB7;
Urban planning is characterized by
a well-defined order of instruments, but with difficulties in putting them into
practice.

&#xB7;
Land ownership is public.

&#xB7;
The concept of buildability is
little used.

&#xB7;
Cities have not been perceived as
engines of the economy.

&#xB7;
Tourism will grow in the coming
years, with a high potential for transforming territories and settlements.

&#xB7;
Local financing depends to a large
extent on the State and the mechanisms for the

urbanization generate resources are
incipient.

&#xB7;
The State is rethinking its housing
objectives given the lack of resources and the increase in demand.

&#xB7;
The basic infrastructure network
reaches almost the entire population, although its maintenance presents
challenges.

&#xB7;
The characteristics of the urban
displacements of the population reflect deficiencies in the mobility system.

&#xB7;
Research on climate change, as well
as studies of hazards, vulnerabilities and risks, constitute a strength for the
challenges that the country faces in its human settlements.

&#xB7;
An energy model dependent on oil,
but with expectations of diversification.

&#xB7;
Energy consumption is low, but CO2
emissions are high.

&#xB7;
Cuba has generated important
knowledge in environmental matters, but its implementation has been limited by
its economic situation.



The technical assistance
described in this document for the elaboration of a portfolio of projects for
implementing NUAC at local level in 14 municipalities through the
identification of urban projects files, which are to be executed from 1% for
territorial and local development, is an urgent need of local governments in
the country and will focus precisely on the following aspects:

1. Cuba shows high
level of urbanization. The current
urban population is 77.8%, which has remained stable for years. The percentage
of urban population is similar to the average of Latin America and the most
developed countries. Urban land occupies approximately 1.16% of the country&apos;s
surface, with a tendency to increase slowly due to the policy of city
compaction and protection of land resources.

2.
The
institutional structure of urban planning is vertical, although a
decentralization process started. The Institute of
Physical Planning (IPF) directs the territorial and urban policy. The fact of
being directly subordinated to the Council of Ministers, the highest
decision-making body in the country, suggests the importance given to
territorial issues. The provincial and municipal governments are in charge of
the territorial and urban planning of these instances, although the
decision-making capacity and the allocation of resources is still centralized
in a high percentage given to the economic circumstances of the country and the
necessary lookup for territorial equilibrium and equality of living conditions
for the population.






 
  
  Instances
  
  
  Plan
  
 
 
  
  Municipal Assembly or its Board of
  Directors
  
  
  &#xB7;
  General
  plan of the head municipality. General, partial and special plans of the
  other urban settlements, as well as the studies of location and details. 
  
 
 
  
  Provincial Administration Council
  
  
  &#xB7;
  General Plan of the
  head main city of the province.
  &#xB7;
  Other
  partial, special urban plans, as well as the studies of localization and
  details of provincial impacts.
  
 
 
  
  Council of Ministers
  
  
  &#xB7;
  Plan
  for the capital of the country and eventually another city prioritized by the
  State for its national impact.
  
 




3.
Urban
planning is characterized by a well-defined order of instruments, but with
difficulties in putting them into practice. Planning is
characterized by a hierarchy of instruments that act at different scales,
although the State level reserves the capacity to approve the most important
things, leaving the rest for the provinces and limiting the possibility of the
municipalities to approve their own instruments. However, the physical planning
system must coexist with other sectoral instruments of intervention in the
territory with which there should be maximum coordination. In general, the
planning system finds difficulties in realizing the plan in physical reality
due to the lack of sufficient resources and the complex circumstances in which
the planning processes take place. The improvement of participation in planning
development processes is an area of ??opportunity, and systematically the
planning instruments adapt to the new model of economic and social development
that the country has approved, and this model includes the policies that are
transforming urban dynamics.




 
  
  Planning Instruments
  
  
  Activities and Specific Areas
  
 
 
  
  Nacional
  
 
 
  
  General
  national scheme of territory management
  
  
  National
  guiding Instrument, general scope
  
 
 
  
  Special schemes of national territory management.
  
  
  Productive and unproductive activities.
  Hydrographic
  basins, mountain ranges, coastal territories, tourist regions, areas with
  special regulations, technical infrastructures, ones that go beyond the
  provincial framework and others by state decision.
  
 
 
  
  Provincial
  
 
 
  
  General provincial plans and schemes of territory
  management
  
  
  Provincial guiding instrument, general scope
  
 
 
  
  Special
  provincial plans and schemes
  of territory management
  
  
  Planning of territorial
  infrastructures
  
  
 
 
  
  Partial provincial plans and schemes of territory
  management
  
  
  Planning
  of integrated territories of the province
  
 
 
  
  Municipal
  and urban
  
 
 
  
  General plan of municipal territory management
  
  
  Guiding
  instrument of general scope
  
 
 
  
  Partial plan of municipal territory management
  
  
  Planning of integrated zones of the municipality
  
 
 
  
  Special plan of municipal territory management
  
  
  Planning of municipal
  infrastructures
  
 
 
  
  General urbanization plans of each city and
  settlement.
  
  
  Guiding
  instrument of general scope
  
 
 
  
  Partial urbanization plans of each city and settlement.
  
  
  Planning of integrated urban zones of the city
  
 
 
  
  Special
  urbanization plans of each
  city and settlement.
  
  
  Planning of system and infrastructures of the city,
  including the mobility
  
 
 
  
  Studies
  of localization and details at territorial, rural and urban scale
  
  
  Designing of areas and complexes; micro-localization
  of the investments
  
 




4. Local financing depends to a large
extent on the State and the mechanisms for the urbanization
generate resources are incipient. Although the existence of two
currencies (with different exchange rates) makes the calculation complicated,
data from ONEI indicate that share (%) of exports of professional services[1]
and tourism on the Cuban economy is 57% and 21% of total exports respectively.
More than 60% of the financing of urban development -investments in housing and
services, infrastructure and productive facilities- is made through the
investment of the ministries of related sectors. Local financing depends to a
large extent on national budget, although more decentralized fiscal systems are
being introduced that seek greater financial autonomy of municipalities and provinces,
which are still insufficient and are in the testing phase. Neither the
municipalities nor the central administration have mechanisms to capture and
share the value generated by urbanization, even though there is already an
embryonic housing market that benefits from public investments in
infrastructure and urban improvements. However, there is the case of the Office
of the Historian of Havana, which has had exceptional powers granted by the
government to obtain incomes from the development of tourism and commercial
activities to invest it in urban regeneration, constituting a precedent of how
it can be generated, captured and share the value. This process has been
accompanied by international donors that have allowed the improvement of the
world heritage in danger, but in turn that Office has extended the use of its
profits to other areas of the city which were also in a great need for
rehabilitation and conservation, as experience of a high value for the city.

   Proportion of the total expenses in execution of the
budget. Source: Statistics Yearbook 2015, ONEI.

The Project is aligned with the following priorities:
 
  
  Local Priorities 
  
  
  
   Municipal
       development plans of the 14 municipalities
   Municipal
       plans of territorial management and urban
       development of the 14 municipalities
  
  
 
 
  
  National Priorities
  
  
  &#xB7;
  Programmatic update of the Cuban
  Economic and Social Model through three documents approved in 2017:
  o The
  conceptualization of the Cuban Social and Economic Development Model
  o The Bases
  of the National Economic and Social Development Plan until 2030: Vision of
  the Nation, Axes and Strategic Sectors
  o The
  Economic and Social Policy Guidelines of the Party and the Revolution for the
  period 2016-2021
  
   The
       National Action Plan (NAP) of Cuba for the implementation of the NUA, (2018)
   Habitat
       Country Programme Document with Cuba 2014-2018
   United
       Nations Development Assistance Framework 2014-2018 (UNDAF)
  
  
 
 
  
  Regional Priorities
  
  
  
   Declaration
       of Santo Domingo in 2016, Federation of Latin American Cities,
       Municipalities and Associations (FLACMA)
   The Regional Action Plan for the
       Implementation of the New Urban Agenda in Latin America and the
       Caribbean 2016-2036 
   Sub-regional
       Action Plan for the implementation of the NUA in the Caribbean,
       2016-2036
   Regional Strategic Plan of the
       Regional Office for Latin America and the Caribbean of UN-Habitat
   Declaration
       of Buenos Aires of the XXVI General Assembly of Ministers and Maximum
       Authorities of Housing and Urban Planning in Latin America and the
       Caribbean (MINURVI)
   Monitoring
       of the Sustainable Development Goals in Mesoamerica and the
       Post-2015 Agenda
  
  
 
 
  
  Global Priorities
  
  
  
   Paris
       Agreement
   New
       Urban Agenda
   Quito
       Declaration and Thematic and regional declarations of the third United Nations Conference
       on Housing and Sustainable Urban Development-HABITAT III
   Agenda
       2030 and the Sustainable Development Goals, with the special emphasis on Objective
       11: Sustainable Cities and Communities, to make cities and human settlements inclusive, safe,
       resilient and sustainable.
   The
       Secretary-General&apos;s five-year action agenda, in particular regarding accelerating
       progress in the achievement of the objectives of Sustainable
       Development, focusing on inequalities and generating opportunities for
       women and young people.
  
  
 










[1] Health, education, and others.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Switzerland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-25" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-24" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elkin Velasquez Monsalve</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email></email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CU" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cuba</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cuba</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cuba</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-01-25"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-24">301205</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">278086</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cuba contributes to the implementation of the NUA at local level, maintains its leadership on the matter in the region, and transforms the NUAC into actions that are executable at local level using the 1%.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cuba contributes to the implementation of the NUA at local level, maintains its leadership on the matter in the region, and transforms the NUAC into actions that are executable at local level using the 1%.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of representativeness of social actors in the workshop</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of representativeness of social actors in the workshop</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age ranges of participants of the workshops (divided by sex)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age ranges of participants of the workshops (divided by sex)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of satisfaction of the participants at the workshops</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of satisfaction of the participants at the workshops</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Municipal strategy for implementing NUA</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Municipal strategy for implementing NUA</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of attendees to the workshops regarding number of people invited</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of attendees to the workshops regarding number of people invited</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants to the workshops</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of participants to the workshops</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100(Male 50 Female 50)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The municipalities of Cuba have instruments to carry out replicable demonstration actions that contribute to implement the NUAC and have impact at the local level.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The municipalities of Cuba have instruments to carry out replicable demonstration actions that contribute to implement the NUAC and have impact at the local level.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The impact of the radio and tv spots on NUA</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The impact of the radio and tv spots on NUA</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The DMPF have assumed a strong role in the process of elaboration of a local strategy for the implementation of the NUA</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The DMPF have assumed a strong role in the process of elaboration of a local strategy for the implementation of the NUA</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-24"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
