<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2439</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieving Sustainable Urban Development In The Philippines</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to address the gaps and deficiencies
in planning process (tools, parameters, indicators, standards and approaches) at
the national and local level and support cities in developing strategic sustainable
urban development plans and implement demonstration projects for identified
priority issues and possible interventions. The emphasis of the project lies on testing the three legged approach in a range of fast growing cities in the Philippines, namely Cagayan De Oro, Iloilo and Siliay. In addition the project also applies the ASUD approach in Zamboanga which is the largest city in the South of Mindanao. This city&apos;s growth is primarily linked to the Bangsamoro peace process and the influx of internally displaced persons. Hence testing new urban planning principles (see project strategy) in a post crisis city is to complement the broader appraoch. 

Silay

Identified and prioritized
issues/challenges:

1. Urban
Economy: local asset and competitiveness not maximized (cultural heritage
site, international airport, gateway to other Negros cities.

2. DRRM and
CCA: relatively new in integrating DRRM measures into development plans and
investment plan.

3. Urban
Planning/Land: needs technical assistance on strategic urban planning,
including the identification of city extension areas and resettlement issues
(socialized and low-cost) especially in the context of the new airport in the
city

Possible
interventions:

1. Urban
Economy: preparation of master plan for eco-tourism (cultural heritage and
forest eco-tourism), and linking economic activities and skills to support
long-term tourism potentials, conduct of value chain analysis for local tourism
sector and formulation of local economic development strategy.

2. DRRM and
CCA: DRRM training for LGU personnel; mainstreaming DRRM concepts and tools
with LGU mandated plans.

3. Urban
planning: identification of new city extension areas and plan preparation; resettlement planning incorporating mobility and access to
livelihoods and employment; enhancement of CLUP and its implementation
considering the resistance of landowners in converting their lands to
commercial or mixed-uses.



Iloilo City

Identified and prioritized
issues/challenges:

1. Urban
economy: financing of urban development plan (e.g. housing; road and
mobility; transport; new developed areas; livelihoods) employment issues
especially on youth sector; reviving the urban economy of the city center
(issues on informality); enhancing and promoting business sector participation.

2. DRRM/CCA:
up-scaling issues on mainstreaming DRRM at the Barangay level.

3. Mobility:
inner-streets and walkability issues.

4. Planning/Land:
City extension development and urban renewal.

Possible
interventions:

1. Planning
and city extensions: As Iloilo is
relatively advanced in urban planning (compared to other Philippine cities) and
a beneficiary of numerous ODA on urban development, the city can serve as the
core for knowledge management development. Iloilo can play a resource city role
in documenting and sharing good and best practices vis-a-vis urban planning and
implementation. However, it still needs technical support for sustainable and
affordable city extensions/expansion for the new development areas; supporting
city extension planning or city center up-grading and low-cost housing
integrating mobility issues and access to livelihoods.

2. Urban
economy: skills development training
programme for youth employment complementing the LED strategy of the city,
targeting the unregulated sector.

3. DRRM/CCA:
complementing the city/JICA community-based DRRM programme.

4. Mobility:
pedestrian and street regulation/ re-adjustment, piloting small scale demo
project to support the city transport plan; training on mobility and
planning/regulation to promote walkable cities concept.



Butuan City

Identified and prioritized
issues/challenges:

1. DRRM/CCA:
capacity building on mainstreaming DRRM into local development plans and
policies.

2. Urban
planning: issues on drainage development and skills/knowledge on new city
approaches to sustainable urban development and expansion of new growth areas;
socialized housing.

3. Urban
economy: livelihood and employment issues amongst displaced timber industry
workers (approx. 3,000 displaced workers), need to identify and develop alternative
or complementing livelihoods for the displaced individuals and groups (timber
industry).

4. Land:
Land management and resettlement expansion to absorb informal and displaced
timber industry workers. Need for GIS to
rationalize lot parcels for improved real property tax generation and land use
planning.

Possible
interventions:

1. DRRM/CCA:
capacity building on DRRM and CCA planning tools; software or tools development
for &#x201C;asset valuation&#x201D; for DRRM planning; contingency planning and quick damage
quantification for post-disaster recovery planning and programming
(&#x201C;preparedness for recovery&#x201D;).

2. Urban
economy: support to displaced workers, reviving local economy/business to
recover from the revenue losses due to closure of timber-related businesses in
the city, LED strategy formulation.

3. Urban
planning: technical assistance and demo project on resettlement;
preparation of city drainage master plan (to impact on mobility; economy;
environment; human settlements; environmental sustainability of the city). Need
technical assistance on mapping system/technology (GIS). Technical assistance on city expansion (uptown
site) and land management/ re-adjustment.



Cagayan de Oro City

Identified and prioritized
issues/challenges:

1. Urban
planning and land management: gaps on strategic urban planning tools and
knowledge and land re-adjustment.

2. DRRM/CCA:
capacity issues to mainstream CCA/DRRM measures into local plans and policies.

3. Mobility:
improved access of resettlement communities to urban services and livelihoods.

Possible
interventions:

1. Urban
planning: training on new concepts and city approaches on sustainable urban
development; continuation of ARCADIS technical assistance on integrated river
basin and flood management assessment and urban redevelopment of identified
blighted areas. Technical assistance in the preparation of spatial plan/design
for the identified urban extension area (Western Growth Node Area).

2. DRRM/CCA:
mainstreaming CCA/DRRM into local plans and policies (especially on identifying
and developing new growth areas and resettlement areas).

3. Mobility:
support to new relocation sites to ensure mobility and connectivity with the
overall city structure and services; pedestrian and street protection and
re-adjustment, training on land-use transport planning and mobility management.

4. Urban
Economy: livelihood support through skills training and employment support
especially among the typhoon-displaced communities.Manial - Estero de Paco

Identified and prioritized
issues/challenges:

Urban Planning: Urban environmental issues related to polluted estero (water way). Density and informal settlements.CCA/DRRM: Relocation and housing
     support for urban poor families (no tenure security) and those living in
     danger areas.Land: Need assistance on land management-
     maximization of land value and revenue generation for the city government.

Possible interventions:

1. Multi-stakeholder intervention (governance issue).The project also seeks to update national policies and planning
guidelines such as the National Urban Development and Housing Framework and the
City Shelter Planning Guidelines). Going
beyond the city&apos;s territorial jurisdiction and considering national priorities,
regional and cluster planning will also be promoted to respond to inter-LGU or
inter-city implementation on cross-boundary (e.g. ecological footprint or ecosystem-based
planning) and common urban development thematic concerns, including policy or
legislative reform agenda. 

As a pilot project, ASUD Philippines aims to ground-truth UN-Habitat&apos;s
new global program on sustainable urbanization (ASUD) and further enhance the
knowledge and practices as a collective and network of cities together with the
other four ASUD pilot countries (Colombia, Egypt, Rwanda and Mozambique).

The immediate
effect would be well planned cities and communities ready to implement spatial
and sectoral adjustments to its development plans taking into account urbanization,
economic development pace and risks. National government offices such as the urban
development and shelter agencies led by HUDCC and the DILG will benefit from
the updating of planning guidelines and sectoral development plans and frameworks.
Other LGUs will also benefit from models and learnings to be documented and shared.
UN-Habitat will provide the LGUs with policy guidance and technical assistance
on systems, tools and approaches covering the ASUD thematic areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Spain</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yoshinobu FUKASAWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Bernhard.BARTH@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1506964</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1739930</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">683350</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced technical and institutional capacities of eight (8) cities on sustainable urban development planning and governance</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced technical and institutional capacities of eight (8) cities on sustainable urban development planning and governance</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Number of cities with Local Economic Development Strategy and improved local revenue system. Number of sustainable energy strategies
- Number of cities with city extension plans
- Number of cities with sustainable urban mobility strategies</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Number of cities with Local Economic Development Strategy and improved local revenue system. Number of sustainable energy strategies
- Number of cities with city extension plans
- Number of cities with sustainable urban mobility strategies</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="- Two city requests for city extensions
- One city request for LED support
- 2 city requests for overcoming energy challenges
2 city requests for addressing mobility challenges" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Mobility Plan
- Energy Strategy
- LED Plan</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="- CLUP, CDP, LDIP and AIP of parter cities
- Project plans and LED plan in at least once city by 2014
- Two sustainable energy strategies
- Two sustainable energy strategies">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Mobility Plan
- Energy Strategy
- LED Plan</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacities for urban governance at national and local levels</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacities for urban governance at national and local levels</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Urban Policy (National Urban Development and Housing Framework including City Shelter Panning Guideline improved.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Urban Policy (National Urban Development and Housing Framework including City Shelter Panning Guideline improved.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="The national policies and guidelines on NUDHF and CSP need enhancement" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">NUDHF and CSP</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="- Updated NUDHF guidelines
- At least 3 cities have omplemented the policies and guidelines">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">NUDHF and CSP</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
