<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-8797</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Resilient Recovery Project For The Northern And Central Mozambique</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The final objective of the consultancy is to support the
Government of Mozambique in reducing the vulnerability to natural disasters and
increase the level of protection for of all children in schools that are
periodically affected by disasters in Zamb&#xE9;zia, Nampula and Niassa provinces,
through the implementation of improved reconstruction of school buildings,
which were drastically affected and damaged by the strong winds and floods
during the cyclone and rainy season 2014-2015.

The specific objective is to provide technical support to
rehabilitate 433 conventional material classrooms and to rebuild 1438
classrooms in an improved and safer way through the preparation, elaboration,
adoption and implementation of building school models of different typologies
and building materials adapted to natural hazards.

The global outcome of the consultancy will lay on making
schools and communities more resilient to natural hazards and contributing to
build safer educational environment, on the bases of capacity development,
appropriation ofknowledge and adoption oftechnical measures of improved
reconstruction by the participants in the Provinces of Zamb&#xE9;zia, Nampula and
Niassa. It is expected to capitalize on the benefits of this reconstruction
initiative - the first large-scale effort to be undertaken in the country - to
lay the foundations for future post-disaster recovery strategies and actions in
Mozambique.

The proposed technical approach involves various areas,
including: institutional development and capacities at central and province
level on management and programme planning, transference of technical
capacities on building-back-better reconstruction to the Govt. Technicians,
NGOs and contractors and the inclusion of a driven community process in the
field as well as the adoption of good practices and lessons leamed from
international experiences in post-disaster areas. The process will be under the
general coordination of the Ministry of Education and Human Development
(MINEDH-DIEE) and, in accordance with the provided Terms of References,
UN-Habitat will assist in four (4) main tasks, as following:

(l) Organizational, Institutional and Programme planning,
(2) providing technical support on building-back-better school projects and
development of the procurement documentation for hiring third implementing
partners (3) capacity building at central and province level and (4) field
monitoring and supervision through the implementation of a community based
approach at local level.

To achieve expected results, the
implementing methodology proposes six (6) Working Packages phased and
interconnected with each other and in alignment with the payment phasing,
during the 30 month of implementation. Each Working Package has been organized
to include the four (4) technical tasks above mentioned, which were agreed with
the WNEDH.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PM OF THE REPUBLIC OF MOZAMBIQUE TO UN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-07" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Mathias.Spaliviero@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-07"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-07">1269718</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">371886</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">748799</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
