<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-8523</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Municipal Finance Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Purpose and JustificationThe objectives of this programme are three-fold: (a) to create and disseminate knowledge products and share best practices on sub-national (local) government finance, (b) to provide advisory and technical support to sub-national authorities to improve their capacity to generate revenue generation from local sources and revenue management, and (c) To promote sub-national authorities to use innovative land-based financing mechanisms/tools such as land value capture, public private partnerships, and participatory budgeting.This programme will focus on cities at the global level to improve their revenue generation and financial management, build their technical capacity and knowledge improvement. This programme will contribute to achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (particularly goal 8 and 11), implementing the New Urban Agenda, and achieving commitments made in the Finance for Development, Addis Ababa Action Agenda (AAAA).In order to fulfill their mandate in a fiscally responsible manner local governments must have predictable transfers from their central or federal governments, significant sources of own tax revenues and nontax revenues in the form of user charges and fees. Adequacy of own revenues is the key to improved ability to deliver needed goods and services and to better accountability of local officials to their constituents. To effectively address the challenge of mobilizing adequate financial resources, urban authorities in developing countries also need financing instruments for capital infrastructure development. These involve a mix of capital grants and borrowing from different sources. Systemic shortages in all these conventional revenue sources have led local governments around the world to try innovative sources of financing ranging from instruments to capture part of land value increases associated with the building of capital infrastructure to the involvement in joint ventures with the private sector in public-private partnerships.One way to improve efficiency of municipal revenue is through better management of municipal assets. Asset management is a systematic process of operating, maintaining, upgrading, and disposing of assets cost-effectively. It also allows municipalities to manage assets to achieve the greatest return with the objective of providing the best possible services to their constituents.Municipalities also can increase their locally-generated revenues by identifying ways of better planning and budgeting and minimizing financial leakages and improving financial management and accounting systems. The other ways to improve operational efficiency of municipalities include (a) improving tax collection systems through the privatization of tax collection systems, (b) improving billing systems, (c) improving financial management by computerizing the accounting systems, (d) following standard auditing procedures, (e) introduce participatory budgeting, and (f) simplifying accounting systems.UN-Habitat ApproachUN-Habitat promotes local, regional and national authorities to adopt or implement policies and strategies that are supportive of improved municipal finance. The agency helps build the technical and institutional capacity of local authorities, particularly in Asia, Africa and Latin America, to improve the efficiency of revenue generation from local revenue sources. It is also assisting local authorities in introducing institutional and legal reforms that are necessary to generate additional financial resources, particularly through innovative endogenous land-based revenue-generating mechanisms.Specific services provided include help design local revenue enhancement tools and plans, evaluate and select appropriate financing mechanisms for services and infrastructure projects, develop strategies to implement public-private partnerships, undertake municipal credit ratings, and enhance ability to issue municipal bonds. Capacity-building support is also provided to national Governments for scaling up the application of innovative urban and municipal financing instruments.Since the beginning of Strategic Plan 2014-19, the agency has provided technical assistance to a total of 26 cities in Afghanistan, Pakistan, Somalia, Kenya, Haiti, Egypt, Rwanda, Mozambique, and the Philippines. In addition to providing technical assistance, the agency has created and disseminated many knowledge products and shared best practices in the area of local government finance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Economy</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gulelat Kebede</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Marco.Kamiya@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector financial management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-01">1200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">20491</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1149425</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 1:Improved capacity of partner
cities to implement plans or
strategies for improved urban
and municipal finance</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 1:Improved capacity of partner
cities to implement plans or
strategies for improved urban
and municipal finance</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partner
cities that have
adopted plans or
strategies for
improved urban
and municipal
finance</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partner
cities that have
adopted plans or
strategies for
improved urban
and municipal
finance</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0 cities" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5 cities">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of
municipal staff
trained in landbased
finance
strategies and
participatory
budgeting
processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of
municipal staff
trained in landbased
finance
strategies and
participatory
budgeting
processes</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100 staff
trained (in 5
cities)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentages of
increase in local
government
revenue in local
authorities that
have adopted
plans or strategies for improved
municipal finance</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentages of
increase in local
government
revenue in local
authorities that
have adopted
plans or strategies for improved
municipal finance</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Over 5%
revenue
increase in 2
years">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased number
of municipalities in
the global
municipal
database</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased number
of municipalities in
the global
municipal
database</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="100" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-08-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="110 (in 2 years)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
