<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3096</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Towards A Hlp Based Methodology For Stabilizing And Creating Conditions For Peace In Countries Affected By The Syria Crisis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall
goal: The HLP rights of
populations affected by the Syrian crisis are promoted and achieved through shared
relevant information to refugees, enhanced capacities of municipalities, and developed
HLP knowledge of both refugees and landlords.This goal will be accomplished by achieving
the following objectives:Objective-1:
Linkages between HLP issues and future return of refugees to their
homelands are assessed and analyzed. This involves examining relevant legal HLP
documents available with the refugees, as well as identifying the current
status of housing and tenure in refugees&apos; areas of origin. Objective-2:
Shelter conditions for refugees are enhanced and forced evictions
are decreased through properly shared HLP information and enhanced capacities
at the municipality, community, and refugees levels;Activities:Achieving Objective-1 involves undertaking
a rapid assessment of the current ownership and tenure rights of refugee
communities from Syria, and a detailed study of property state, legal
documentation and tenure rights in case and/or to motivate return to Syria once
the conflict has ceased. In order to get a full understanding
of the situation within a reasonable timeframe, the assessment will target
refugee families coming from the same region in Syria. It is likely that a
sample of 250 refugee families who were displaced from Homs and its vicinity,
and residing in different areas over Lebanon, will be part of the research on
HLP documentations. Taking into account the devastating amount of destruction
in Syria due to the war, the survey will also look into the state of the owned
properties in refugees&apos; homeland, which remains unknown and requires further
research. Under Objective 1, the following
activities will be undertaken:Develop the research tools: This will involve a multi-sectoral
questionnaire that will be used during the interviews with refugee households. The
questionnaire will mainly look into HLP legal documents that the refugees still
possess or not, and the implication of that when returning back to their
homelands. In addition, the questionnaire will seek to understand if other
issues rather than the HLP issues may also affect the return of families. This may
include health and education services, security and safety, and basic urban
services. In full collaboration with UNHCR, identify the sample-families who
will be interviewed. This will require review of refugee files to identify the
250 cases coming from Homs region. Conduct the research through household visits to the identified refugee
families. The study will involve a wide variety of cases to be assessed; people
whose houses were totally or partially destroyed, others whose lands and
properties were occupied or confiscated, areas were basic and social services
are absent or partially exist, etc. The research will be conducted in partnership
with UNHCR. This will also contribute to ensuring confidentiality of gathered data.
Analyze gathered information, identify gaps and challenges related
to the assessed sectors; HLP, health, education, security, basic services, etc.
Develop a checklist of issues and queries that need to be checked out and
identified at the level of the areas of origin of targeted
refugees/beneficiaries. Based on the developed checklist, conduct the field work in the areas
of origin of the interviewed refugees, to understand the current situation of
housing, tenure, and services in Homs region. This will be done through UN-Habitat
Syria Programme office through their field partners; mainly local/national
NGOs. The current security situation in the Governorate of Homs will allow for
such work to be carried out.Organize a national workshop involving concerned partners to
discuss the findings of the research and to agree on a set of recommendations
and measures to ensure refugees HLP rights upon their return to their homeland.Publish and disseminate the final report of the research.Objective-2 involves a wide range of activities targeting refugees,
local authorities, owners of housing units or lands, and local communities. As
most of HLP issues and forced evictions are reported to be happening within the
urban extensions of the cities, the proposed activities under Objective-2 will
be piloted in Bourj Hammoud, one of the highly dense areas within the Eastern
suburbs of Beirut. Bourj Hammoud is inhabited by a variety of nationalities; Initially,
Armenian refugees were the majority of the residents. However, the area
attracted foreign workers, mainly from Syria, Ethiopia and Sri Lanka due to
affordable renting prices and availability of cheap-labor jobs and informal
work. Before the crisis, the population of Bourj Hammoud was estimated at 75,000
residents, with poverty levels in 2004 reaching 8,500 people with income under
4$ a day. With the outbreak of the Syrian war, some 18,500 Syrian refugees
sought refuge in the area. This massive influx of Syrian refugees came to add
more strain on the neighborhood, which is already highly congested, and
challenged by a number of environmental as well as socio-economic problems.Due to the presence of a large number
of refugees who are mostly either renting single rooms or sharing small
apartments, conflicts with owners of shelter options which frequently lead to
forced evictions are being repeatedly reported. Refugees enter into rental
agreements verbally without any legal papers and without knowing their rights
and responsibilities. The same happens with owners who look for quick easy
profit without taking into account the legal aspects. Moreover, inhabitants
poorly know about HLP issues and they always put the blame on refugees for any occurring
conflict. The Project promotes the establishment
of a Reference Information Center within Bourj Hammoud which will be likely
hosted by a local NGO The center will provide legal advice, raise public
awareness on HLP rights, and enhance the capacities of local authorities on HLP
issues. While municipalities and their personnel will have their knowledge on
HLP legal issues developed, owners and refugees will be thoroughly informed and
advised on their rights and responsibilities. 5,000 Refugee household, 2,000 vulnerable Lebanese
population, and 500 owners of shelter options within the targeted area will
benefit from the services of the Info Center. Under Objective 2, the following activities
will be implemented: Establishing
Info Centers (IC) within the targeted areas: ICs aim to create local systems
that will reduce forced evictions through enhanced commitment of municipalities
towards HLP issues, and through improved local knowledge and practices related
to HLP issues including legal frameworks and rights on rental and contractual
procedures and arrangements. The IC will be
established as part of a local NGO structure within the targeted area, and will
include a Legal Advisor (LA) and a Social worker (SW) who will be reaching out
mayors, refugees and owners within the different communities. The LA and the SW
will closely coordinate with UNHCR field officers and outreach teams and will
also liaise with NRC to ensure synergies avoid overlapping of activities. 
 
  
  The key functions of the ICs are:
  
 
 
  
  Understand HLP issues and practices present within the targeted areas,
  and identify key challenges at the level of the refugees, host population and
  local authorities;
  Provide relevant services related to HLP. This involves promoting
  formal lease agreements that will reduce forced evictions.
  Raise public awareness on HLP issues: this will involve the
  development of materials that will be shared with targeted groups through AR
  campaigns.
  Establish info-sharing and referral mechanisms involving all concerned
  actors: UN-Habitat will ensure a close coordination between the IC and UNHCR
  field officers, ICLA/NRC, and other concerned agencies operating in the targeted
  areas.Awareness Raising: One of the key functions of the IC will be to increase local
awareness on HLP issues and legal rights on rental and contractual procedures
and arrangements. The campaigns will target different beneficiary groups;
unions and municipalities, owners and refugees, SDCs and local NGOs, etc.











































































Legal advice: The Legal
Advisor is expected to provide legal advice on rental and contractual
procedures. In addition, potential cases that require different type of legal
intervention or referral to appropriate actors, such as evictions, poor shelter
conditions and SGVB will be also provided.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ford Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Tarek.Osseiran@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">195635</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">200000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved knowledge on housing, land and properties issues</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved knowledge on housing, land and properties issues</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of households to be surveyed</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of households to be surveyed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">households</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">households</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Production of reports</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Production of reports</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">production HLP report and on Return report</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">production HLP report and on Return report</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">reports</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">reports</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
