<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2433</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Security Through Inclusive Socio-Economic Development In Upper Egypt</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to strengthening the economic security of
vulnerable communities in five mother villages and selected satellite villages
in Minya through creation of more and better employment opportunities and
increased employability of the local labor force, while contributing to
mitigate threats to environmental, personal, community and food security.The need for pro-poor economic growth and better targeting of development programs in Upper Egyptis well documented in the last Human Development Reports, as well as in Egypt&apos;s 2006 poverty map and its update in 2009. Upper Egypt is inhabited by 40% of the national population, and by 66% of Egypt&apos;s extreme poor, making it the most vulnerable region in the country. With a poverty incidence of 41.2%, Upper Egypt is almost doubling the national average of 21.6%.Minya was selected as the target governorate in consultation with the Government of Egypt because it displays high levels of persistent poverty, as well as the second lowest HDI ranking amongst governorates. It is the most populated in Upper Egypt, with approximately 4.6 million inhabitants, 82% of which live in rural areas. There are over 3,000 villages in the governorate, comprising more than 30% of the poorest villages of Upper Egypt. A number of assessments recently conducted under UN programs show high levels of unemployment and underemployment in Minya, especially in rural areas and among youth and women. The post-revolution economic downturn has triggered a rise in crime rates, food insecurity, child labor and added pressure on existing infrastructure and services as well as on local natural resources. Inter-linkages and dynamics among human security threats observed in Minya are described below.To work towards this purpose, UN-Habitat will work in partnership with other UN agencies ( UN RC, UNIDO, UN Women, ILO, IOM,) involved in the project to create and build the capacity of community and youth groups to play an active role in identifying community needs, formulating action plans, designing implementation strategies and fundraising from local partners. The project will coordinate with governmental authorities ( MoLD and Governorate of Minya) to ensure the mainstreaming of community engagement in planning and resource allocation.Economic security of vulnerable communities will be achieved through creation of a participatory plat form, human security forum, that will be a tool to identify real community needs and prepare community action plans with regards to achieving human economic security. UN-Habitat will adopt an urban upgrading approach to achieve this purpose, through neighborhood upgrading initiatives and other initiatives related to urban upgrading and governance.As a direct intervention, the project will implement upgrading projects which will serve beneficiaries to be more economically active and self- sufficient. To achieve this target, Human Security Forum will be created and activated on both village level and district level, the HS forum will include the active community leaders and members from different sectors like youth, women and community focal points adding to governmental officials and NGOs. The project will build the capacity of Human Security Forum to identify the community needs, form an action plan and to be able to raise resources for the implementation of the projects. An integrated capacity building program will be conducted to enable the HS fora to play its designed role. Training will be conducted by different project partners according to their mandates to provide the HS fora with skills to identify the community needs, creating dialogue with the government to meet the needs, conduct fund raising activities for sustainability and acting as a communication channel between the local community and local authorities.In order to sustain the interventions , the project will work to mainstream the the HS forum through up -scaling the concept to the governorate level, a linkage between the district level HS forum and the governorate of Minya to assure that the needs of the local communities are reflected in the upper level planning process. The HS forum will act as a bottom -up mechanism for planning and resource allocation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations General Trust Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Hedaya.Rania@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-06-01">649330</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">628794</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">649330</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community security and personal security are enhanced through activities to develop communities&#x2019; social capital, enhance cohesion and inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community security and personal security are enhanced through activities to develop communities&#x2019; social capital, enhance cohesion and inclusiveness</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">jobs generated (disaggregated by type of employment opportunity, age bracket and gender)
&#x2022;	Change in capital assets of target beneficiaries / households (disaggregated by gender, level of welfare and age group)
&#x2022;	# of individuals previously excluded from economic activity that have access to income generating opportunities for economic security (disaggregated by gender, level of welfare and age group)
&#x2022;	At least 20 projects are conceived locally to strengthen economic security (disaggregated by sector)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">jobs generated (disaggregated by type of employment opportunity, age bracket and gender)
&#x2022;	Change in capital assets of target beneficiaries / households (disaggregated by gender, level of welfare and age group)
&#x2022;	# of individuals previously excluded from economic activity that have access to income generating opportunities for economic security (disaggregated by gender, level of welfare and age group)
&#x2022;	At least 20 projects are conceived locally to strengthen economic security (disaggregated by sector)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened economic security in target communities through the creation of more and better employment opportunities and increased employability of the local labor force.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened economic security in target communities through the creation of more and better employment opportunities and increased employability of the local labor force.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">prevalence of crime and violence reduced (domestic, public space, age / gender specific)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">prevalence of crime and violence reduced (domestic, public space, age / gender specific)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-06-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
