<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3022</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Emergency Management Plans</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main purpose of the project is to enhance emergency preparedness
and crisis management capacities at the national and sub-national levels. A key element of this project is to strengthen the resilience at the
municipal, governorate and central levels and among vulnerable communities to
external crises and shocks through risk planning, management and financing,
emergency preparedness systems and capacities. A study identifying the existing
systems, capacities, gaps and needs will be undertaken under the directionof MOMA and in coordination with
MOIto inform the design of the specific support that will be provided to
the relevant institutions and vulnerable communities under this sub-component.
Based on the study, the subcomponent could support the preparation and
operationalization of emergency preparedness plans, training of communities and
public officials, establishment of crisismanagement protocols and systems, and
so forth. 



While Jordan has already shown an impressive level of resilience in
responding to the current refugee crisis, JESSRP is designed specifically to
further strengthen existing mechanisms and institutions that have allowed
highly affected communities cope so far, whether at the individual, community
or institutional level.



Subcomponent
2B will seek to strengthen the institutional capacity and resilience of
Government entities at the central, governorate and municipal level to better
address the adverse impacts of external shocks and stresses. While the
municipal grant seek to alleviate some of the more immediate stresses stemming
from current increased pressure on local services, this subcomponent will take
its point of departure from the fact that (i) this is neither the first nor
likely the last refugee crisis experienced by Jordan; and (ii) this is a
multifaceted crisis that requires drawing on expertise from many different
sectors at all levels of Government. 



A study will
be carried out during the JESSRP Project
implementation to analyze and assess the existing capacities, gaps and needs in
the areas of emergency preparedness, risk planning and management and resource
mobilization. The collection of timely and accurate information and the
management information flows forms the foundation for relevant crisis response.
Similarly, strategic communication has been
identified as a key element in natural disaster settings as it helps build
trust, credibility, and transparency by ensuring that the right messages are
reaching all relevant stakeholders.
Particular attention will therefore be given to this aspect of crisis
management and its usefulness in efforts to build resilience related to
man-made crises will be explored. The study will form the basis for the
design of a capacity enhancing program that will target specialized support to
different levels of government and identified communities. The study and
ensuing support will be carried out under the directionof MOMA and in
coordination with MOI.



The project will build the capacity of key Government agencies and vulnerable
communities in emergency preparedness, and risk planning, management and
financing. Information collated during the Assessment phase will
support the institutional mapping and
modeling exercise and a training gap analysis.



A detailed organizational assessment will be
developed and undertaken that ranges from the institutional to local levels.
The purpose of this activity is: to assess current municipalities&apos; capacities
for training, access to information and infrastructure for the critical DRR and
DRM knowledge areas; to establish municipal capacity baselines and examine the
potential effects of external opportunities and threats on capacity development
initiative strengths and weaknesses; to identify the critical capacities needed
by the project; to review the role of the private sector and non-governmental
organizations with respect to DRR and DRM; to identify the various capacity
development priorities of various stakeholders within the sector; and to review
any existing system for information exchange between organizational
institutional components.



A participatory stakeholder analysis exercise will
take place during the 3 days workshop with a sample of informants. This process
will allow a more detailed stakeholder profile of interests and
responsibilities in DRR at both the macro- and micro-levels. This analysis will
include perceptions of roles and responsibilities, especially by central and
local government departments. Wherever significant differences in the stakeholder profile around
the municipality of the selected cities are identified, this will also be
documented. This will be important in guiding a more detailed assessment of
capacities for action, generating a strategy for more integrated stakeholder
participation in DRR and DRM, and will facilitate prioritization of future
project work-planning in conjunction with parallel hazard and vulnerability
assessment activities.

In order to develop a more detailed understanding of
local level needs and priorities and how these are aligned with DRR and DRM, a
questionnaire survey will be conducted. The primary purpose of the survey will
be to evaluate the extent of public awareness, early warning and preparation
for natural hazards, the perception of levels of service and support that can
be provided by the state and other agencies, and also a personal awareness of
fundamental rights in a disaster. For evaluation of this final ethical
dimension, the Humanitarian Charter and the Sphere minimum standards for
disaster response will be used as a reference tool.



The
Project will entail developing a
priority action plan listing key institutional development activities related
to emergency preparedness and risk mitigation and management in consultation
with other agencies/entities (especially MOMA, MOI, , MOPIC, Governorates and municipalities, civil society
representatives), that can be implemented during the rest of lifetime of the JESSRP project as per the agreed timeline, ,as well
as sharing information and carrying out
strategic communication activities related to the subcomponent.



The Project will be jointly implemented in
collaboration with a National Jordanian NGO ( Jordanian Humanitarian Resilience
Society( JHRS), with UN-Habitat as lead Management. Within UN-Habitat the
project will be supported from concerned headquarters&apos; departments, namely the
Urban Risk Reduction Unit at the Risk Reduction and Rehabilitation Branch, the
UN-Habitat Office for Disaster Risk Reduction will provide the backstopping
technical and training support as indicated in technical proposal.

The Ministry of Interior/Ministry of Municipal Affairs (PMU) will
intervene in the planning, monitoring, implementation of the project, the respective Governorates and
Municipalities, local NGOs, CBOs
and government institutions, Academic organizations and professional networks will intervene in
the implementation of the project , planning, and implementation, Vulnerable
conflict affected families especially the most vulnerable: groups, youth and
women groups /host communities will also be engaged in the implementation of
the project.






http://www.gfdrr.org/sites/gfdrr.org/files/Chapter_3_Communication_in%20Post-Disaster%20Reconstruction.pdf</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-15" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Iman.Zaki@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster prevention and preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-15">139933</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">145702</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">139933</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">:     Key staff  in participating Governorates and municipalities, Community and professionals capacities enhanced through regular awareness and training,</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">:     Key staff  in participating Governorates and municipalities, Community and professionals capacities enhanced through regular awareness and training,</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of youth with enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of youth with enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of youth with enhanced capacities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of youth with enhanced capacities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of females with  enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of females with  enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">percentage of females with enhanced capacities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">percentage of females with enhanced capacities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of males with enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of males with enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">percentage of males with enhanced capacities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="35%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">percentage of males with enhanced capacities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of staff, community and professionals with enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of staff, community and professionals with enhanced capacities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">staff, community and professionals with enhanced capacities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="at least 100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">staff, community and professionals with enhanced capacities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">: Enhanced emergency preparedness and crisis management capacities at the sub national and national levels through development of Local Emergency and Risk Management Plans.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">: Enhanced emergency preparedness and crisis management capacities at the sub national and national levels through development of Local Emergency and Risk Management Plans.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Governorates and municipalities  with local Emergency and risk  Management Plans.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Governorates and municipalities  with local Emergency and risk  Management Plans.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Municipalities  with local emergency and risk management plans</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-04-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Municipalities  with local emergency and risk management plans</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
