<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2875</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Governments For Sustainable Urban Development (Umbrella Project)  Phase I</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strong and capable institutions are critical for sustainable urban
development. Improved governance processes are at the core of sustainable
management and planning of cities and towns. Laws and policies have to be adapted
to the local needs. UN-Habitat is working through this project to develop and
reinforce a conducive and enabling environment, which requires adequate legal
frameworks, political, managerial and administrative process, mechanisms, guidelines
and tools to respond to the needs of the population and its local
representatives. 

This project will assist in a catalytic manner
in advancing UN-Habitat&apos;s urban governance agenda and its norms, namely
sustainability, subsidiarity, equity, efficiency, transparency, accountability,
civic engagement, citizenship and security. 

The present project operates at different
levels 1) community, 2) municipal, 3) territorial (city-region), and 4) global,
always in collaboration with the national level. It specifically focuses on local
governments&apos; adequate responsibilities and functions (multi-level governance),
their capacity to implement and to control, community participation in the city
decision-making process, and institutional accountability and transparency. The project addresses the issues in four main areas
of work: 

The need to develop
governance arrangements at multilevel, with a focus on the territorial scale 

Local governments are placed in a network of
relationships and jurisdictions. Reinforcing their role, in a decentralized
framework, with a multi-sector vision and at different scales requires a
strong multilevel governance approach. There
is a need for a common vision on the political and conceptual approach of
multilevel governance and to unpack and translate this concept into
practical tools for the use of local leaders. There is also a need to communicate successful strategies applied for
others, to learn from other contexts either about the political process as well
as its implications for public services delivery and to establish new
horizontal cooperation between local governments. 

Challenges such as urban mobility, employment
and environmental sanitation, among others, extend beyond the realm of local
governments and cover various legal-administrative divisions in the territory, which
means that, in most cases they must be borne by more than one municipality. To ensure effective measures and to
achieve positive results for the citizens, tax-payers and economic agents,
coordinated action is required. Soft governance modalities, such as
inter-municipal cooperation, allowing for two
or more neighboring municipalities to perform together municipal administrative
tasks and deliver public services or any other governance arrangements at the
territorial scale could be explored. Sound territorial management is also
a way to go beyond the rural-urban divide and to address metropolitan governance.

The need to strengthen
municipal institutions by exploring other dimensions of governance 

Local governments do not have a
single relation with national or regional levels of governments and participation is not only a matter of
elections. Looking downstream and at non-state actors is increasingly
important to ensure a real participatory process and stronger inclusion of all
in the city decision-making process.
There is a need to identify new approaches and tools for renewed dialogue
between people and institutions. Building on this approach, the use of
ICT facilitates a two-way communication process, from community to local
government and from local government to community. Smart technologies appear to
be a tool to improve public service delivery, operational efficiency and ease
intergovernmental relations. This can be specifically applied to youth, who are
a large demographic in most urban centers and frequent users of mobile technologies.
Despite their growing numbers, youth are largely excluded from participation in
the policy-making and decision-making, leaving them socially and politically
marginalized. Youthful citizens are governance game changers and Smart technologies
are a lever and an opportunity to allow them to promote democratic public
choice making. In return, there is a need to transform their contribution into
better informed, more transparent and accountable local governments. In
addition to e-governance, informal governance is another aspect to be explored.
Informality is rarely considered as an asset and local governments often feel
powerless when confronted to this multi dimension reality. A third dimension to
be supported is the relationship of local governments with non-state actors and
corporate interests, a relationship which is often misunderstood, implicit or
unbalanced. More generally, these dimensions of local governance can inform
broader researches and definition of indicators.

The need to ensure municipal financial sustainability
with accountable leadership

Municipal finances are central to
local governments, as their strategic management plays a critical role in
ensuring long-term sustainability of local services. One key issue faced by
local governments is how to expand their resource base beyond central-to-local transfers.
Stakeholders are keen to integrate new ideas/tools on expenditure management,
tax base identification, local tax collection, etc. In all cases, improved
governance practices and enhanced accountability mechanisms (e.g., public
transparency of budgets, customer service contracts for public utilities,
adequate public asset management, clear monitoring of the performance of local
governments) have become central to sound city government and municipal
management. This project responds to the need to enhance knowledge and skills
of local governments in the field of municipal finance, to allow them fulfill their responsibilities. Taxation
requires both effective service delivery and transparent management to be
sustainable and accepted by citizens. The
development of tools to support municipalities in getting endogenous
resources (local service taxation and integrating informality) goes in parallel
with providing tools and how-to instruments to improve the management and
transparency of local finances. This latter is a crucial need, as transparency
and perception of local corruption is the necessary linkage between municipal
sustainability and governance. 

The need for political
support to local governments and their associations through the post 2015 and Habitat
III processes.

UN-Habitat and the Global
Taskforce have been made coordinators, together with UNDP, of the global
consultation &#x201C;Localizing SDGs&#x201D;. The LG Unit is aiming at getting innovative
processes at city level and good inputs to the SDG definition process, in particular
related to future &quot;means of implementation&quot;. This process is also
directly related to the campaign for an urban SDG, strongly supported by the Global Taskforce which brings
together bringing Mayors, Governors and local government associations to raise
their views and concerns at the UN and to create awareness on the needs of
local government regarding the international development agenda. In addition, the
preparatory process of Habitat III (decision making process in New York and in
Preparatory Conferences) requires also full engagement and support to local
governments. Habitat III will have to give solutions to this new role for
cities and local governments. Both processes require a combination of expert
meetings and the provision of materials, experience collection and technical
expertise displaying how and what local government can provide for the
achievement of sustainable urban development. There is also a need to ensure the
follow-up of these international and political processes: the outcomes of the Post-2015
and the New Urban Agendas are likely to call for stronger implication of local
governments, as essential responsible for their implementation. 

The project objectiveis to contribute to sustainable urban development and local democracy through capable, resourceful and empowered local governments. The strategic result is that local governments will have adequate governance structures, mechanisms and resources to fulfill responsibilities and influenceurbandevelopment agendas atall levels of interventions.The project envisages partnering
with various stakeholders at normative and operational levels to develop, test,
evaluate and disseminate tools, methodologies and knowledge to reinforce local
governments&apos; recognition and capacities in specific topics mentioned above. This
project will allow the coordination of on-going efforts in the area of urban governance
throughout the Agency and will leverage resources with other ongoing projects. This
project builds on existing workstreams within the area of governance and looks
at developing more adapted approaches and means of operationalization for local
and regional governments. As this is cross-cutting issues, each area will
involve cooperation with another unit of UN-Habitat and/or relevant partners
able to relate to and involve local governments. 

The project will target primarily
policy-makers at local and regional level who will be the end-beneficiaries of
the project, as well as local governments associations. Citizens and urbanites
will be the indirect beneficiaries of enhanced capacities (human, financial and
institutional) of their local representatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Capital Development Fund (UNCDF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Robert.Lewis-Lettington@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector financial management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-01">438000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">553959</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">132185</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced recognition of the role of local and regional governments in the design and implementation of the international agendas of post-2015 and Habitat III</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced recognition of the role of local and regional governments in the design and implementation of the international agendas of post-2015 and Habitat III</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Habitat III documents that explicitly reflect the local and regional dimensions of urban development.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Habitat III documents that explicitly reflect the local and regional dimensions of urban development.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100% of the Habitat III key documents">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of post 2015 key documents that explicitly reflect the local and regional dimensions of urban development.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of post 2015 key documents that explicitly reflect the local and regional dimensions of urban development.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100% of the post-2015 key documents">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved awareness and knowledge of additional dimensions of urban governance by targeted partners (ICT, informality, non-state actors) with youth and gender oriented applications</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved awareness and knowledge of additional dimensions of urban governance by targeted partners (ICT, informality, non-state actors) with youth and gender oriented applications</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of targeted partners promoting renewed approach of informality inclusion</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of targeted partners promoting renewed approach of informality inclusion</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Low practical knowledge on inclusion of informality at local level" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 80 % of targeted partners apply renewed approach of informality in urban governance">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of targeted partners using ICT in public management for enabled governance  with specific youth and gender orientation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of targeted partners using ICT in public management for enabled governance  with specific youth and gender orientation</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Low use of ICT potential for enabled urban governance" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 80 % of targeted partners promote inclusion of youth, women and girls through ICT">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened capacity of local and regional governments for functional multi-level and territorial (including metropolitan) governance frameworks</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened capacity of local and regional governments for functional multi-level and territorial (including metropolitan) governance frameworks</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of local and regional governments implementing functional territorial (including metropolitan) governance frameworks</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of local and regional governments implementing functional territorial (including metropolitan) governance frameworks</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Few functional governance arrangements at the territorial and metropolitan levels" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 80% of targeted local and regional governments implementing functional territorial (including metropolitan) governance frameworks">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national and local governments implementing functional multi-level governance frameworks</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national and local governments implementing functional multi-level governance frameworks</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Weak articulation between different levels of governments" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 80% of targeted national and local governments implementing functional multi-level governance frameworks">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened capacity of targeted local governments for improved transparency in municipal finance management</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened capacity of targeted local governments for improved transparency in municipal finance management</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence of  municipal financial accountability processes in targeted local governments</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence of  municipal financial accountability processes in targeted local governments</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Perception of highly corrupted local governments" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 70% of targeted local governments have financial accountability processes">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of targeted partners, implementing tools and approaches for transparent endogenous resources mobilization</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of targeted partners, implementing tools and approaches for transparent endogenous resources mobilization</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Weak transparency in endogenous resources mobilization" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 80% of targeted partners using appropriate tools and approaches for transparent endogenous resources mobilization">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">-</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
