<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2656</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessment And Technical Support To Darfur Land Commission And Addressing Land Concern At Return Sites</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of Darfur Development Strategy (DDS) foundational and short term
(FaST) the joint programme intends to address issue of land in Darfur which
constitutes a considerable challenge to Darfur peace initiatives, demanding equitable and sustainable interventions to develop holistic solutions to meet the basic needs and rights of all residents and develop in place land
policy and management in the long term, through sustainable land management. Ensuring durable solutions for the poor including the
displaced in Darfur is therefore a priority. Addressing the issues of land
policy, legislation and management in a politically, socially, economically
sustainable manner will require development of innovative approaches with the
bottom-up approach to ensure participation of all stakeholders at all levels to
reach a consensus between customary and statutory law. It also requires
adoption of dynamic, flexible and realistic land conflict resolution mechanism
and land legislation that ensures long term vision with short term practical
solution to the key land issues based on participatory priority setting. Fortunately and timely, the DLC has already
embarked on the Natural
Resources and Land Use Database and Mapping for Darfur; Traditional Land Use
and Hawakeer Management Study; Collection and Documentation of
Traditional Customs on Land Use in Darfur which provide ample opportunity for technical assistance and a new
perspective in looking at the problem of land tenure. 

The experience and knowledge of FAO on land
use planning and sustainable land resources management will be capitalized to keep
track and guide activities. Thus, VGGT tools and principles is an additional
instrument that compliments the experiences of UN-Habitat in resolving land
disputes. Such tools and the normative works of FAO, the knowledge base on
land, forests and water will be used in applying local land use plans and
sustainable land management practices learned from other countries in Africa
and the Near East Region with similar farming systems and agro climatic
conditions. 

Given the conflict situation in Darfur, the
project will apply conflict sensitive programming as a best practice in all
activities. This will include conducting
of conflict assessment in the 50 prioritized return villages and along the proposed
migratory corridors to help in targeting the interventions, identification of
key stakeholders and actors to guide the design of the appropriate actions. This will be a bottom up approach from
village and Admin Unit up to Locality and state levels and will be concluded
with Darfur and National level discussions.

The priority areas of interventions in
the 5 States of Darfur will be identified in close coordination with the DRA
and state Ministries of Planning, Ministries of Agriculture, Returnees CBOs and
CSOs. Rapid
assessment will be conducted for 50 returns villages with the purpose to identify suitability,
constraints and needs of the return villages, in coordination with Voluntary
Return and Resettlement Commission (VRRC), in order to provide important
information on the reintegration needs of the returnees. It will also represent
an important tool for planning medium to long-term recovery in Darfur. Return
villages will be assessed within the overall context of the spatial regional
strategic plan prepared by UN-Habitat, and will also be framed within the
reintegration context. To facilitate return of IDPs the project will develop of
land conflict resolution mechanism at local level which will base on the
assessment of indigenous and traditional system that based on mediation is based on win-win mediation. 

It is anticipated that this project
will establish the foundation for other FaST projects and as such strong
linkages and coordination with FaST interventions such as provision of basic
services, Return and provision of
sustainable energy should be encouraged and supported. 

Desk
review of the literatures, statistics and records on return villages will be
conducted in order to select appropriate return villages, for further assessment
and studies. Rapid assessment will be conducted for 50 returns villages with
the purpose to identify suitability, constraints and needs of the return
villages, in coordination with Voluntary Return and Resettlement Commission
(VRRC), in order to provide important information on the reintegration needs of
the returnees. It will also represent an important tool for planning medium to
long-term recovery in Darfur. Return villages will be assessed within the
overall context of the spatial regional strategic plan prepared by UN-Habitat,
and will also be framed within the reintegration context. It requires review
and preparation of recommendations for settlements hierarchy in support of
rural-urban linkages in terms of mutual benefit and interdependency between
town and village. Within this context the exercise will include the assessment
of existing infrastructure basic services and affordability of transport. At
the village level, village boundary including future expansion as well as a
buffer grazing zone around the village, following traditional practice, will be
delineated in a participatory planning in collaboration with Ministries of
Physical Planning and Public Utilities (MPPPUs) and Ministry of Agriculture and
Animal wealth, to avoid encroaching of the settlement at the expense of grazing
or agricultural areas in addition to planning for village facilities and
services, both existing and proposed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP (incl. one UN fund)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Wa&apos;el.Al Ashhab@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">14180748</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">8988493</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">14019577</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved land registration/property system and related conflict resolution mechanisms developed and operational</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved land registration/property system and related conflict resolution mechanisms developed and operational</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">new land legislation/law developed and operational</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">new land legislation/law developed and operational</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of legislation/laws</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of legislation/laws</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">villages mapped with planned land use/typology</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">villages mapped with planned land use/typology</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">#</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">#</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">female participants</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">female participants</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2014">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">%</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">%</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
