<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-13133</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening National And Regional Development Planning: A Spatial Development Framework For Guinea-Bissau And A Regional Strategic And Spatial Development Plan For The Archipelago Of Bijag&#xF3;s (Bijag&#xF3;s 2030)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea-Bissau currently faces a complex
scenario concerning population dynamics, which includes rapid and unbalanced
urbanisation and rural-urban migration. Whilst in 1997 only 22,5% of the population
lived in urban areas, in 2015 this number reached 42,16% (INE, 2015). At the
same time, the capital (Bissau) already accounts for more than 25% of the
national population, increasingly concentrating population growth. Significant
growth is also seen, apart from the capital city, in other cities of the
country, such as Bubaque, Gab&#xFA; and Bafat&#xE1;. 

Settlements around the country lack
functional services and infrastructure to accommodate existing and new demand.
Population tend to concentrate in bigger cities to find better services and
infrastructure. Nonetheless, those living in other regional centres and in the
countryside face issues in access to facilities such as banking and
transportation services, education and health facilities, among others and
often travel to the Capital to address their needs. Moreover, certain regions
of the country obtain more investments from development partners over others,
where even duplicity of interventions frequently occur, while other regions are
marked by the total absence of investments. This scenario is in part due to the
lack of planning tools in place and due to the lack of coordination of
interventions from multiple institutions.

To face these issues, there is a need for a
more equitable spatial development in Guinea-Bissau to take place, involving
data and mapping systems that can support a results-based management approach
and development strategies based on objective and scientifically accepted
criteria which are generated in a consensual manner, without leaving anyone and
anywhere behind. Therefore, governments at both national and local levels,
along with partners, must strategically invest in infrastructure and services
based on an integrated spatial development framework, which takes into
consideration current and future demographics and territorial issues. 

In the national Strategic Plan, Terra
Ranka, the country has identified nine hubs as important economic centres that
should be enhanced to promote dynamic economic activities, being the
Archipelago of Bijag&#xF3;s one of them. In the axis of Infrastructure and Urban
Development, highlighted in Terra Ranka, the country developed 4 fields of
action, including &#x2018;land planning and urban development&#x2019;. In this field, the
immediate goal is to &#x201C;renovate and build the principal urban centres in such a
way as to endow them with infrastructure and functional systems and set them up
as business hubs&#x201D;. In this framework, the development of the Bolama-Bijag&#xF3;s
archipelago is also a priority.

The archipelago entails an exceptional
natural site of 88 islands and islets recognized as a UNESCO Biosphere reserve
due to its natural environment wealth and cultural assets. The development of
ecotourism in the region also entails a national priority, with the designation
of the archipelago as a Special Tourism Zone, along with the preservation of
biodiversity and the need to develop infrastructure. 

Nevertheless, to achieve its potential,
Bijag&#xF3;s requires support in developing strategic development plans that provide
planning and design proposals, introducing innovative sustainable planning
models and a tested set of tools   principles adapted to the local context,
to ensure the sustainable development of the region. These plans should be
solidly built on a strong participatory approach and in the spatialization of
current development challenges and opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EUROPEAN UNION - DELEGATION TO GUINEA BISSAU</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>edinilson.silva@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="GW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea-Bissau</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea-Bissau</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea-Bissau</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">659030</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">593127</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
