<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-844</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khartoum State Urban Planning And Development Programme: Xbsud09x02</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the programme will be to present State of Khartoum with local level detailed development information that would enable effective land, infrastructure, and shelter policy management. This seeks to prevent the false idea of designing ambitious &quot;master plans&quot; in particular moments, whose implementation results nearly impossible, adopting instead the idea of strategic planning, as a continuing process on specific problems, With short, middle and long term actions. The strategic settlement planning programme, with the participation local stakeholder. will provide a future vision, actionable results, and an information base. The programme being visionary will provide a target for development; the programme being action based will also contribute to the efficient coordination of development activities in cities and villages; and the programme being information based will enable local authorities and other stakeholders to efficiently administer the urban setting retaining tradition right and providing for shelter rights.The programme is structured to implementing a broad-based and inclusive decision making process that will enhance local governance; the vulnerable including youth, women, and the poor will Interact with other executive, popular, civil society and private stakeholder. Finally. in seeking to develop strategies on land, basic urban services and shelter, the programme will endeavor to contribute to both the competitiveness and equity of the settlement.Operationally the programme include building the capacity or: l) urban planners and engineers in strategic planning, action planning, project management and implementation; 2) information management consultants in RS and GIS; 3) engineers In innovative approaches to basic urban services, and 4) economic consultants in localeconomic development. Sustainability will in next phases focus on institution training programmes in universities and training centres.Unlike the classic master plans that take many years to complete and are inadequate to address rapid urbanization and reduce urban poverty, the strategic planning that will be used or the formulation of strategic plans for villages and cities in Khartoum will addresses contemporary needs through participation and involvement or the key stakeholders and actors ta identify the strategic needs and entry points; and Integrationof sectors through a holistic approach including visioning, action planning and decision making to avoid duplication and overlaps and by identifying priorities and addressing them it becomes strategic in the sense of conserving resources and directly responding to needs as they emerge. In this context the project will benefit from UN-HABITAT support or urban, rural and strategic planning in Arab states in general and in Egypt inparticular where the RtJSPS was adapted to the legal framework End implemented to prepare plans for 127 cities, 4567 villages and hamlets. Alter three and half years, 4200 villages and 10 cities are completed, 367 villages and 97 cities are underway, The National City and Village Planning and Development Programme, being based on a rapid assessment approach, enabled the Government of Egypt to address urbanization issues in a timely fashion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Italy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Mathias.Spaliviero@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-01">994695</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">994687</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1020408</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To contribute to urban poverty reduction in Khartoum
State</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To contribute to urban poverty reduction in Khartoum
State</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To develop Strategic plans for three cities and nine villages within Khartoum state, to guide the state and local authorities to achieve a shared vision of the settlements future
Nine villages and three cities plans</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To develop Strategic plans for three cities and nine villages within Khartoum state, to guide the state and local authorities to achieve a shared vision of the settlements future
Nine villages and three cities plans</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2009-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2010-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9 village plans and 3 cities plans">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To develop priority actions identified in the strategic plans into fully prepared projects and &quot;bankable&quot; investment packages</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To develop priority actions identified in the strategic plans into fully prepared projects and &quot;bankable&quot; investment packages</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2009-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2010-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Number of projects and investments packages">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To strengthen local capacity to plan co-ordinate, and manage urban development and growth</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">To strengthen local capacity to plan co-ordinate, and manage urban development and growth</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2010">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2009-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2010-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Between 320-350 persons trained in GIS, Strategic planning, M&amp;E, urban management, participatory planning">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
