<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-8589</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dpa Land Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Many countries globally have introduced new land policies, especially in Asia and Africa. Often it is not possible for these countries to implement pro-poor and gender sensitive land policies, because the underlying tools and practices do not always exist, or have not been sufficiently documented and disseminated. Emerging from the 1990s some organizations and individuals have been trying to address this issue, but have struggled with the scale of the challenge geographically and conceptually. In essence, most developing countries use conventional land administration systems which cover less than 30 percent of the country, leaving up to 70 percent of citizens looking to informal and/or customary approaches for their tenure security.Prior to GLTN launch in 2006, an analysis was conducted which drew several important conclusions. First, while there are many examples of good land policies, there are few policies that have been fully implemented due to lack of pro-poor, gender-sensitive and large-scale land tools. Second, a conclusion was that conventional land titling approaches have largely failed to deliver their expected results: existing technical solutions are too expensive, inappropriate for the range of tenure found in developing countries, unsustainable financially or in terms of available capacity, and instead a range of land tenure options is more appropriate. Third, an agreement was that land sector work in country cannot be done at scale successfully in many countries without the combination of various underlying factors and strategies including better donor coordination, strengthening partnerships of key land actors, capacity development initiatives and continuous dialogues and communications between and amongst key stakeholders including government (at various levels), professionals, civil society groups, academia/research institutions, grassroots and target communities themselves. To address these challenges, UN-Habitat has taken the lead and facilitated the establishment of theGlobal Land Tool Network that aims at contributing to poverty reduction and to the achievement of MDGs through the development of pro-poor and gender sensitive land tools to improve tenure security of the urban and rural poor since its launch in 2006. GLTN Phase 1 has already achieved significant results in its 4 years of operations as concluded by the independent mid-term evaluation and echoed by various partners and land actors. For example, there is now a growing paradigm shift towards the adoption of a pro-poor, gender sensitive and large scale land tools, policies and approaches; as well as the recognition of the need for a &#x2018;continuum of land rights&#x2019; to replace the more conventional approaches of reliance on cadastre and individual titles. Global discourse on key GLTN&#x2019;s tools and approaches are well captured by various global and regional interventions. Examples include the following: World Bank is taking the lead in the development of Land Governance and Administration Framework (LGAF) globally; FAO is taking the lead in the development and implementation by member-states of the Voluntary Guidelines on Responsible Governance on Tenure of Land, Forests and Fisheries, wherein UN-Habitat has played a critical role, the adoption of the African Land Policy Framework and Guidelines which was supported and adopted by the Third African Ministerial Conference on Housing and Urban Development (AMCHUD) and the Bamako Action Plan.Moreover, Phase 1 has already developed significant land tools and training packages ready for rolling out with partners at national and local government levels . Some partners are already adopting these land tools for their use and for their capacity development initiatives. For example, the gender evaluation criteria tool has now been adopted by Huairou Commission for their implementation and training for trainers (ToTs) will be conducted before the end of the year. Likewise, the International Land Coalition has indicated that they would like to adopt and implement the same on their country-level projects in various countries. Training for land professionals on this tool has also started. As part of GLTN Phase 2, the gender evaluation criteria will also be introduced and mainstreamed in UN-Habitat operations particularly in providing in-country support to tool implementation in targeted countries and/or cities/municipalities and the needed capacity development initiatives will be undertaken. The Kenya experience in land policy formulation, donor coordination and engagement with non-state actors has been used as a model for other country&#x2019;s interventions by UN-Habitat (e.g. DRC, Eastern Caribbean Island States, South Sudan and Liberia). GLTN partners from the academia and training institutions are now adopting the land tools developed, concepts and training packages in their training and educational curriculum. For example, ITC-Netherlands is now teaching the concept and use of the Social Tenure Domain Model (STDM) &#x2013; a pro-poor land rights recording system to their Masters&#x2019; Program while the Technical University of Munich has been mobilizing resources to adopt some GLTN training packages for their curriculum as well as for conducting the same training sessions. GLTN&#x2019;s partnership with grassroots organizations has also yielded some significant successes. Aside from understanding the underlying reasons why good grassroots land projects have difficulties in going to scale, specific experiences like that of Brazil resulted in the regularization of an estimated 55,000 slum dwellers.While significant results have been achieved by GLTN Phase 1, a great deal more work is required for gains made to be consolidated and extended. GLTN Phase 2 will further expand its partnership and scope from its known international partners to UN-Habitat staff and selected land programmes/projects. It will also implement some of its priority land tools in targeted countries and/or cities/municipalities in partnership with UN-Habitat&#x2019;s field projects and/or international partners with their national and local networks, particularly in regard to the agencies new priority areas of urban land, legislations and governance. GLTN Phase 2, in close collaboration with UNHabitat&#x2019;s regional offices and field operations, and other partners will ensure that in-country interventions will be within the framework of &#x2018;One UN System&#x2019; as delivering as one and in accordance with the country&#x2019;s Poverty Reduction Strategy Papers (PRSPs) and/or strategic plans. The key objective is to have more change agents and champions that have the capacity and knowledge to promote and implement land policies, tools and approaches that are pro-poor, gendersensitive, effective and sustainable to improve tenure security of the urban and rural poor.In this context, there is an urgent need and increasing demand for GLTN to: continue its work; expand its brand and help develop capacities of its partners (internal and external); and support the adoption and implementation of pro-poor and gender appropriate land policies, tools and approaches at national and local government levels through forging strategic partnerships and piloting and working at country level.2.4 Describe project&#x2019;s alignment to local, national, regional, global priorities.GLTN Phase 2 will focused on global and regional needs and priorities particularly in regards to advocacy and awareness building, tool development process and implementation of capacity development initiatives. Phase 2 will also expand to targeted countries and cities/municipalities. As a key strategy, GLTN Phase 2 will be more effective in influencing the global and regional land actors and international organisations to shift their operations and policies towards recognition of the continuum of land rights and pro-poor and gender sensitive land policies, tools and approaches. GLTN will define priority countries for engagement in a specific area of intervention with appropriate actors. There is a global recognition that addressing land issues including tenure is a prerequisite for sustainable development and poverty reduction. Indeed, there is an increasing demand from international partners and UN-Habitat operational projects as well for GLTN to continue its work on pro-poor land tools. Also, a lot of donors, international financing institutions and development organisations are prioritising and supporting land projects at various levels. For example, African leaders have adopted a region-wide land policy framework and guidelines and through the UNECA, African Development Bank and African Union, they have started implementing projects and interventions within this agreed land policy framework. Working with ROLAC, the Eastern Caribbean States are also embarking on a land policy and GLTN tool piloting approach. Work will continue on the GLTN tool on global and land indicators with World Bank,Environment Management Group and others. Both Cities Alliance and IFAD have identified GLTN tools as a good potential area for investment, inclusive business models, STDM and tenure security. For the country programmes, AMCHUD Bamako Declaration by African Governments is recognising the need for pro-poor land tools to implement their country&#x2019;s land policies. Phase 2 will seize this opportunity and will continue to work along these global and regional priorities in the land sector.However, Phase 2 will expand its operations to work with internal partners in UN-Habitat and regional offices along with international partner organisations with their national networks to support land tool implementation in targeted countries and cities/municipalities particularly in Africa in the context of food security issues and sustainable urban development. Phase 2 will see to it that incountry support will be demand-driven and that these countries and/or cities/municipalities have the political will and commitment to adopt and implement GLTN tools and approaches. Also, in-country interventions would be linked to other global and regional initiatives (e.g. LPI).Moreover, Phase 2 will be implementing tools at national and local government levels in close collaboration with &#x2018;One UN-Habitat&#x2019; and will be within the UNDAF framework as &#x2018;One UN System&#x2019; delivering as one and in accordance with the country&#x2019;s Poverty Reduction Strategy Papers (PRSPs) and/or strategic development plans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Department for Political Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Clarissa.Augustinus@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-01">241031</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">256001</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">2933</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected Accomplishment 1: Strengthened land-related policy, institutional and technical frameworks and tools and approaches to address the challenges in delivering security of tenure at scale particularly for the urban and rural poor.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected Accomplishment 1: Strengthened land-related policy, institutional and technical frameworks and tools and approaches to address the challenges in delivering security of tenure at scale particularly for the urban and rural poor.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.i) - Number of partners,including (local/national)governments, showing interests and/or adopting GLTN developed pro-poor and gender appropriate and tools and approaches</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.i) - Number of partners,including (local/national)governments, showing interests and/or adopting GLTN developed pro-poor and gender appropriate and tools and approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="8 out of existing 50 partners" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="24 new partners demonstrating interests and/or adopting pro-poor land tools and approaches (at 4 partners a year">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected Accomplishment 2: Improved global knowledge and awareness on land related policies, tools and approaches that are pro-poor, gender appropriate, effective and sustainable towards securing land and property rights for all</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected Accomplishment 2: Improved global knowledge and awareness on land related policies, tools and approaches that are pro-poor, gender appropriate, effective and sustainable towards securing land and property rights for all</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.i) - Number of existence of propoor and gender-appropriate land tools and approaches in the plans, strategies and operations of partners and target groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.i) - Number of existence of propoor and gender-appropriate land tools and approaches in the plans, strategies and operations of partners and target groups</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="12 out of existing 50 partners" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="24 new partners incorporating propoor and gender appropriate land tools and approaches in their plans, strategies and operations">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.ii) - Number of partners, including governments (national and local), promoting and adopting pro-poor and gender appropriate land tools and approaches</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.ii) - Number of partners, including governments (national and local), promoting and adopting pro-poor and gender appropriate land tools and approaches</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="12 out of existing 50 partners" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="24 new partners promoting and adopting pro-poor land gender appropriate and tools and approaches (at 4 partners a year)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected Accomplishment 3: Strengthened capacity of partners, land actors and targeted countries, cities and municipalities to promote and implement appropriate land policies, tools and approaches that are pro-poor, gender appropriate, effective and sustainable.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expected Accomplishment 3: Strengthened capacity of partners, land actors and targeted countries, cities and municipalities to promote and implement appropriate land policies, tools and approaches that are pro-poor, gender appropriate, effective and sustainable.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partners, land actors and targeted countries and cities/municipalities promoting and implementing pro-poor and gender appropriate policies, tools and approaches to deliver tenure security at scal</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partners, land actors and targeted countries and cities/municipalities promoting and implementing pro-poor and gender appropriate policies, tools and approaches to deliver tenure security at scal</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="10 out of existing 50 partners" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20 new partners, land actors and targeted countries and cities/municipaliti es promoting and implementing pro-poor and gender appropriate policies, tools and approaches to deliver tenure security at scale:">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
