<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3410</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Sustainable Access To Safe Clean Water And Gender Sensitive Sanitation Services In Epworth</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the problem-what is the purpose of
this project? 

The project will enhance
sustainable access to safe clean water and gender sensitive sanitation services
by residents of the peri-urban area of
Epworth, Harare.

What specific aspect of the problem is the
project addressing? 

Specifically,
the action seeks to build the capacity of the communities in 3 wards of Epworth, the local authority and
supporting NGOs and CBOS so as to secure and sustain increased access to water
and sanitation services by the residents in the
targeted 3 wards in Epworth, in order to reduce poverty
and provide additional opportunities for improved livelihoods for these poor
communities.

Who
and how do target populations benefit directly from the project?

The action targets poor
residents of the targeted 3 wards in Epworth, 70% of which earn their
livelihoods from informal activities such as vending and small scale home
inductries. The targeted 3 wards of Epworth
have a total population of 97 124
(48 726 males and 48 398 females) with an average household of 3,6 (2012
Zimbabwe Census Report). The health of these people is expected to improve
while some will benefit from the training to be offered &#x2013; transformation  
leadership as well as skills training as pump minders and masonry trade.
Enterpreneurial skills and opportunities will also be built and provided
respectively.

How
does project respond to real needs and high-priorities of the target group? 



The project will have
some significant impact in strengthening the currently weak capacity of civil
society and local government institutions in addressing the water and
sanitation needs of the poor in peri-urban areas of Zimbabwe especially in the
context of the HIV and AIDS pandemic that has negatively impacted on most
development indicators in Epworth. CSOs and the local authority in the targeted
area will have their capacity enhanced to coordinate, plan, and support the
community management of water and sanitation services thereby making the
provision of the service more sustainable. Simultaneously, the approaches successfully adopted and tested
during the project stand a better chance
to be scaled up by the capacitated local authority to the other 4 wards in
Epworth that are not directly participating in this pilot phase of the project.
Government can even expand these
approaches outside Epworth to other municipalities in the country.

There will be improved
access to and use of safe water which meet
the needs of men, women and children in
Epworth. Specifically, a total of 11500 people will have improved access to
safe water supply resulting in at least
80% access in the 3 wards. The average consumption of water per person per day will
increase from 10 &#x2013; 15 litres to 25 &#x2013; 30
litres. In addition, 20 schools will have access to sanitation that is both
ecologically friendly and gender sensitive.

The peri-urban centres
will have increased access to and the use of safe and sustainable sanitation
services at household and schools, that will prevent or reduce the occurrence
and spread of water and sanitation related diseases such as diarrhoea,
dysentery, cholera, typhoid fever and skin diseases. The health status of the
communities will thus be improved. Access to sanitation will have improved by
20% in each of the targeted 3 wards covered by the project, benefiting a total
of 11500 people including Orphans and Vulnerable Children (OVC) and people
living with HIV/AIDS by the end of project. Men, women and children, especially
those infected and affected by HIV/AIDS will adopt improved hygiene practices,
which will directly improve their health status.

Putting water and
sanitation at the centre of improving people&apos;s livelihoods will ensure that the
additional economic benefits such as household income from maintenance activities
of artisans as well as proceeds from nutrition gardens will continue to
motivate communities to maintain the results of the action. Institutional
capacity building that emphasises local financial self-sufficiency and a
network of technical support services and a supply line for spares, will ensure
that the infrastructure continues to operate in a sustainable manner beyond the
projrect. The creation of WASH budgets by the local authority is likely to
motivate the central government to channel financial resources through this
avenue.

School children will
benefit from life skills they will acquire resulting in the adoption of more hygienic behaviour and practices, that
will be useful to them throughout their entire
lives as well as their families.



What and how does your project aim to
change/solve in regard to the identified problem? 

The project will
strengthen the capacities of civil society organisations (CSOs), community
based organisations (CBOs) and the local government to manage the provision of
watrer and sanitation services, and promote good hygiene practices within the
communities in the 3 wards. The project will build on the lessons learned and
good practices established from the implementation of two EU Funded Projects &#x2013; PEOPLE
UP Project   Social Accountability
project on CBP for Integrated Water Resource Management. Both were implemented
with UN Habitat support and developed relevant approaches that will be applied.

What
are the proposed solutions for the problem and why are they the most
appropriate to the problem? 

The action will work
with Epworth Local Board and use CFHD experience in the application of
participatory approaches and tools such as Community Based Planning (CBP),
Training for Transformation, Transformational Leadership. Technical training will
be offered on Community Based Management (CBM) model in water and sanitation
services as well as to develop the technical skills and build social structures
and capacities required to locally manage water and sanitation services. A
limited number of spares for water points will be provided as part of technical
training but self-reliance and leveraging of community resources for provision
of additional spares will be encouraged and supported to sustain the operation
and maintenance of water and sanitation services. Limited water purification
materials will also be provided for demonstration purposes. The action will
ensure that at least 50% of the participants in both the social and technical
interventions are women. Technologies such as rope and washer pumps will be
promoted which take into consideration women&apos;s physical abilities and needs.These
approaches are chosen to stimulate local responsibility and ownership of the
water and sanitation measures for sustanability. 

Who are the possible partners internal and
external that will help in implementing the solution? 

The
main project partners will be as follows:

Staff of civil
society organizations and local government structures to be trained in water,
sanitation and livelihood approaches.

Private Sector
Companies engaged in the supply of water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH)
equipment.

Men and women to
be trained in community management of water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH)
services

Men and women to
be trained in the maintenance of water points as Local Pump Mechanics (VPMs)

Men and women to
be trained in building and maintenance of ecological sanitation toilets 

Pupils and
teachers in the schools in the targeted 3 wards to have increased access to
water and sanitation services 

Men, women and
children in the targeted 3 wards in Epworth receive health and hygiene
education and benefit from increased access to water supply and sanitation
services.

Epworth
Local Board operating with only 5% of
the budget needed for WASH interventions and interested in the introduction of low cost technologies such as
sand abstraction and rope and washer pumps

Is UN-Habitat providing knowledge services
or high-level policy advisory services?

UN-Habitat in
collaboration with its partners will provide knowledge to be used for training
purposes as well as policy advisory services to the community, civil society
and the local authority.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL WATER CHALLENGE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-25" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Thomas.Chiramba@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply and basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-25"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-25">70000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">20364</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">70000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced capacity of Local Government, community based organization and Communities.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced capacity of Local Government, community based organization and Communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people economically empowered through project activities.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of people economically empowered through project activities.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Less than 20%" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-25"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved and increased access to water and sanitation services by communities in the targeted 3 wards</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved and increased access to water and sanitation services by communities in the targeted 3 wards</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total # of people with full access to improved water service levels for household levels. 


Total # of people with access to improved water service levels.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total # of people with full access to improved water service levels for household levels. 


Total # of people with access to improved water service levels.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Less than 20%" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-25"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduced occurrences of diseases and improved health of communities.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduced occurrences of diseases and improved health of communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people with improved sanitation service levels. 

Number of people with demonstrated sustainable hygiene behavior change</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people with improved sanitation service levels. 

Number of people with demonstrated sustainable hygiene behavior change</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Less than 20%" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-25"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11500">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
