<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3185</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urbanlex - The Urban Law Information System</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of this project is to achieve enhanced access to legal frameworks in urban areas by developing a database featuring urban legislation from all of the UN Member States.UN-Habitat has developed its urban legal data base &#x2013; UrbanLex- a free online global &#x2018;library&apos; of the legal instruments that govern urban development. The database features seven critical areas of urban law that are essential to the sustainability and development of urban areas. Under each legal area the user will find a catalogue of laws from a wide range of countries from all regions. The aim of UrbanLex is to be more advanced than a simple data repository, while still being easy for non-experts to use. A principal element of UrbanLex&apos;s value is in the digests that accompany each law, providing an accessible description of its key contents and objectives. The laws can be searched by region, country, theme, and keywords.The seven critical areas of urban law featured on the database include:Taxation, Finance   Economic DevelopmenGovernance and GovernmentInfrastructure and Basic ServicesUrban PlanningDisaster Recovery and Urban ResilienceBuilding and ConstructionLand and EnvironmentBeneath the digest a link to an external website or document that is relevant to the law is also provided. The purpose of the link is to provide the user with an opportunity to learn more about the law and what kind of effects it may have. Many of the external links will lead to information provided by our partners who specialize in the relevant legal area and expose the user to research institutions in countries all over the world.The reality is that researchers and urban stakeholders do not have the time or resources to find and compile urban law. As a result a knowledge gap formed around urban legislation, especially in developing countries where governments do not make all laws, and particularly regulations and local law, available online. This gap is obstructing research efforts and limiting the capacity to develop solutions. Urban residents and planners watch development take place in their cities and towns without any adherence to the legal framework, partly because of the limited access to the laws that shape that framework. UrbanLex provides a central source of information that not only fills this knowledge gap but also makes research and comparative analysis easy.The Urban Legislation Unit&apos;s knowledge of relevant legislation, acquired through ongoing work in cities around the world, gives a unique position to offer a solution to this issue. Our expertise combined with UN-Habitat&apos;s network of regional and country offices and international partners will enable us to grow a valuable and comprehensive database. Presently, we have a coordinator and programmer at the UN headquarters in Nairobi working on UrbanLex. Their efforts are primarily aimed at the support and development of the database as well as formalizing and liaising with partners for the population of the database as well as for the comparative studies.The project has considered the UN Delivering as One approach, which means that it intends to work in full coordination with other UN agencies, funds and programmes, e.g. through the United Nations country team (UNCT) and the UN Development Assistance Framework (UNDAF) at country level. Currently negotiations are underway with FAO, to establish a link between FAOLex and UrbanLex. Other partners are mainly universities and research institutes with a working knowledge of the relevant legal system. Our coordinator works in cooperation with the partners providing training and support where necessary and ensuring that the quality of the information in the database maintains a high level as UrbanLex accumulates more laws.Key activities of partners include:Collecting urban legislation from surrounding areasWriting a short digest for each law summarizing the relevant contentUploading official versions of laws into UrbanLex in original languageCategorizing legislation (i.e., geographical area, legal topic, keywords)Associating legislation with key wordsTo date, UrbanLex has established formal partnerships with:The Institute for Advanced Legal Studies in the United KingdomThe International Islamic University in MalaysiaRenmin University in China, andThe Istanbul Technical University in TurkeyFordham Law School in the U.S.AFurthermore, other MOUs and formalization procedures are in place with other institutions, such as:FAOUN-Habitat office in Egypt (Contributed around 35 laws; Contact: Mohamed Nada &#x2013; Mohamed Nada/UNHABITAT/NBO/UNO@UNON and lina.raafat@hotmail.com)The University of Lisbon (Portugal and Guinea-Bissau); (Contact: Professor Claudio Monteiro; cmonteiro@fd.ul.pt )Other Promising Partnerships include:Africa:-African Centre for Cities at University of Cape Town (SA)-Cairo University (Egypt)-International Law Institute, Africa Centre for Legal Excellence (UG)-Strathmore Law School (Kenya)-Wits University (SA)Asia:-CEPT University Ahmedabad (India)-RUC (China)Europe:-Catholic University of Leuven (Belgium)-Chalmers University (Sweden)-CNRS (France)-Radboud University (Netherlands)-University Polytechnic of Catalunya (Spain)Latin America:-Brazilian university group (Brazil)-Externado University (Colombia)-National Autonomous University of Mexico (Mexico)-Instituto Polis (Brazil)-Colegio Nacional de Jurisprudencia Urban&#xED;stica (Mexico)-Universidad de los Andes (Colombia)North America:-MIT, Lincoln Institute of Land Policy (USA)-NYU, Hauser Global Law School (USA)-Syracuse University (USA)Oceania:-University of Melbourne (AU)-University of Queensland (AU)Other Institutes:-European Law Institute-Italian Association of Urban Law-Swiss Institute of Comparative Law-WIEGO-The Israel-Affordable Housing Center at the Tel Aviv UniversityFurther core partnerships will be sought to bring the number of active partners to a regionally and linguistically balanced group of about twenty institutions to be responsible for the population of the database and linking to secondary information on the basis of common protocols. Swedish universities and research institutions, particularly those already engaged in the Habitat Partner University Initiative, will be approached for their interest as either core partners or as partners in the use of UrbanLex as a platform for comparative analysis.The development of UrbanLex will continue to be performed by the coordinator and programmer in Nairobi. They will work together to add user friendly features to UrbanLex, the purpose of which, is to open up the use of the database to a wide range of demographics. Some of the features being developed include:A multilingual interfaceAdvanced search toolsPartner page with links to partner websites and resourcesMobile device applicationOpen website to moderated public editing (Wikipedia model)Establish connections and networks using social media sites (LinkedIn and Twitter)Finally, we believe that the use of analytics software will enable us to monitor which countries are using UrbanLex, how often they visit the site and their user behaviour. As the databases grows, this will enable us to make the site more beneficial to users while providing donors and partners with information that allows the impact of UrbanLex to be evaluated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-16" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Robert.Lewis-Lettington@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-05-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-16">1262330</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">785797</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">921959</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to legal and institutional frameworks in 150 targeted states to guide sustainable urban development</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to legal and institutional frameworks in 150 targeted states to guide sustainable urban development</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of UrbanLex users across regions and institutions.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of UrbanLex users across regions and institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="4 regions with regular use. Average visits less than 1000 per month. Return visits less than 20%." year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of average visits per month on the use of the database.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-05-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5 regions with regular use. Average visits 6000 per month. Return visits 40%.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of average visits per month on the use of the database.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of principal national legislation documented on Urbanlex database covering all seven themes (Taxation, Finance &amp; Economic Development; Governance and Government; Infrastructure and Basic Services; Urban Planning; Disaster Recovery and Urban Resilience; Building and Construction; Land and Environment) in at least 150 states;</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of principal national legislation documented on Urbanlex database covering all seven themes (Taxation, Finance &amp; Economic Development; Governance and Government; Infrastructure and Basic Services; Urban Planning; Disaster Recovery and Urban Resilience; Building and Construction; Land and Environment) in at least 150 states;</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="20" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-05-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="150">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of key stakeholders to understand, draft and implement  good urban legislation for planned city growth.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of key stakeholders to understand, draft and implement  good urban legislation for planned city growth.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policies and strategies informed by Urban Lex</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of policies and strategies informed by Urban Lex</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-05-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of research and comparative analysis studies that have been supported by Urbanlex (memos, briefs, full assessment);</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of research and comparative analysis studies that have been supported by Urbanlex (memos, briefs, full assessment);</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-05-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of UrbanLex users across regions and institutions.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of UrbanLex users across regions and institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value=": 4 regions with regular use. Average visits less than 1000 per month. Return visits less than 20%." year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-05-16"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5 regions with regular use. Average visits 6000 per month. Return visits 40%.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
