<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3334</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerating Climate Action Through The Promotion Of Urban Low Emission Development Strategies (Urban-Leds Ii)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Urban-LEDS II Project
will build on and consolidate achievements to date, and expand the Project&apos;s
reach into four new countries. This includes building on and replicating city,
national and global-levelworking relationships and
networks established during Phase I, as well as using the proven approach and
existing methods, guidance, platforms and tools developed in the previous Phase
I and, where relevant, in other EU funded initiatives like the Global Covenant
of Mayors for Climate and Energy. 



The focus will be on deepening
and extending the project approach, transferring those methodologies, tools,
guidance and platforms to new countries (primarily Least Developed Countries-LDCs),
using the participating cities from Phase I as potential role models and peers,
specifically in their respective regions. 



Urban-LEDS II will leverage
progress made, and complete ICLEI&apos;s Green Climate Cities methodological process
cycle for the cities already in the implementation phase. It will also utilize,
where appropriate, other city-related instruments (e.g., as developed in the
framework of the Global Covenant of Mayors). Here the focus will be on
realising quick wins in terms of mitigation to ensure continuity and, wherever
relevant, to build synergies between projects, networks and methodologies. The
aim is to support finalization of quality local project preparation, financing
feasibility studies, linking the Urban LEDS to statutory city planning, and
activate the Transformative Action Pipeline &#x2013;TAP (a local demand-side project
pipeline).



The successful test during
Phase I of the Urban-LEDS approach in the context of emerging economies
(Brazil, India, Indonesia and South Africa) will be expanded in Phase II into
four new countries (Colombia, Bangladesh, Lao PDR and Rwanda) of which the last
three are LDCs. Thus the project will support eight new Model Cities and
approximately 16 new Satellite Cities, guiding their entry into low emission
development. It will also further connect the LEDS approach to a new secondary
theme, climate change adaptation and resilience, ensuring an integrated
approach while optimising planning and implementation of climate change action
within the wider sustainable development efforts and needs of these developing
nations. The aim is also to actively build the resilience of the most
vulnerable sectors of society, increasing their energy security in a
sustainable and climate change adaptation sensitive manner, in order to take
effective   robust climate change decisions.



When offering practical, tested guidance and tools to
local governments to support the capacity building of local leaders and
municipal staff, offers of capacity development can in at least some cases
include non-Urban LEDS cities, such as cities committed to relevant national,
regional and global initiatives. This process can rely on city-to-city learning
and peer exchange with successful Phase I LEDS cities located in the region. It
will help to expand the awareness, interest and capacity of local governments
in the eight target countries (and to a lesser extend in other countries of the
same regions), to progress with their Measuring, Reporting, and Verification
(MRV) process and to connect to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) as
well as the Paris Outcomes under the UNFCCC. The focus will be on the
promotion, recognition, recording, verification and integration of actions by
cities in reducing global emissions and increasing climate resilience within
the global climate regime, as well as in their national contexts.



The Project will support
counterparts and work towards vertically integrated climate action at the
national and local government level, in order to create synergies and achieve
greater coherence of plans, policies and actions. There can be no solution to climate change
without local climate and energy action. Vertical integration between different
levels of government &#x2013; from national to local &#x2013; is essential to coordinate and
mutually reinforce necessary approaches. It should provide a platform for
fruitful exchange, joint planning and coordination. This is key in addressing
climate change as well as sustainable energy planning, implementation and
reporting.



The main stakeholder groups
targeted are thus local, subnational and national governments in the eight
partner countries. Here key stakeholder groups are both political
representatives as well as staff, who would be responsible for strategy
development, policies and regulations, as well as implementation support of
climate action. The wider urban expert communities working on climate change
and in relevant sectors such as urban development, energy and transport, are
also relevant stakeholders and potential expert contributors. 



Cities and national
governments of other countries of the same regions will be secondary targeted
stakeholder groups that may be invited to attend, take part in or contribute to
workshops and activities, especially to enable building synergies and cooperate
with other EC funded cities and climate change initiatives like the Global Covenant
of Mayors for Climate and Energy as well as EU Delegations in partner
countries.



Throughout all activities, the strengthening of ownership of climate
action is an underlying principle, and, where appropriate, the Action will
target and include civil society, the private sector and academia in a
participatory manner in planning and implementing the interventions. This good
governance approach, particularly relevant in developing countries, will be an
explicit goal. Where possible, the Action will strengthen youth and women
empowerment and follow a human rights based approach. 

External and Internal Partners



Building on the history
of collaboration in the previous (first phase) Urban LEDS Project, ICLEI and
UN-Habitat will implement the Work Package activities jointly at global and
country levels. Project management and implementation will be led by
UN-Habitat&apos;s Climate Change Planning Unit at UN-Habitat&apos;s headquarters, and
ICLEI&apos;s Low Carbon Team at the World Secretariat (ICLEI WS). Both functional
units are responsible for assuring participation of their respective Agencies&apos;
structures in the regions and countries. 

We intend to partner with the Regional
Offices for Asia (ROAP), Africa (ROAf), and Latin America (ROLAC), particularly
through their country offices in the new Urban-LEDS II countries of Colombia,
Rwanda and Lao PDR. Their roles will include facilitating country-level
advisory group meetings, coordinating substantial inputs in the cities and so
on.     

During Urban-LEDS Phase
I we collaborated with UPDB&apos;s City Planning, Extension and Design Unit (CPEDU),
to field International Society of City and Regional Planners (ISOCARP) planning
experts in two Urban-LEDS cities (under resources mobilized separately); and
with UBSB&apos;s Urban Mobility Unit (UMU), for a bus rapid transit study in Bogor,
Indonesia (via an in-house agreement). Under Phase II we will look for similar
opportunities with UPDB/CPEDU and UBSB/UMU. Collaboration with Urban
Legislation, Land and Governance may be possible, e.g., in review of draft city
bylaws that help to implement low emission development strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Planning and Design</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rafael Tuts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Robert.Kehew@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Africa</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Africa</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Asia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Asia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional - Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office - Arab States</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office - Arab States</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-04-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-01">9842683</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">2278805</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">6933317</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 2 - Supporting Local Governments in developing and approving Urban Low Emission Development Strategies in four new target Countries</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 2 - Supporting Local Governments in developing and approving Urban Low Emission Development Strategies in four new target Countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">(a)  Number of new Model Cities have developed their Urban Low Emission Development Strategies (Urban LEDS)

(b) Number of new Model Cities submitted their Urban LEDS for  approval and obtain approval</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">(a)  Number of new Model Cities have developed their Urban Low Emission Development Strategies (Urban LEDS)

(b) Number of new Model Cities submitted their Urban LEDS for  approval and obtain approval</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="(a) 0 of 8 new Model Cities (cities not yet identified)

(b)  0 of 8 new Model Cities" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">8, two Model Cities selected per country

16, 4-6 Satellite Cities selected per country</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="(a) 2020: 100% of project Model Cities

(b) 2020: 75% of new project Model Cities">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">8, two Model Cities selected per country

16, 4-6 Satellite Cities selected per country</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 3 - Consolidating Urban LEDS achievements in existing (Phase I) Cities and Countries</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 3 - Consolidating Urban LEDS achievements in existing (Phase I) Cities and Countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">a)  Quantifiable local GHG reductions contributing to national reduction goals 






(b)  Indications of adaptation co-benefits in Urban-LEDS Model Cities reported</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">a)  Quantifiable local GHG reductions contributing to national reduction goals 






(b)  Indications of adaptation co-benefits in Urban-LEDS Model Cities reported</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="a) 0 (2017)







(b) 0 (2017)" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="(a) 75% align to national NDC targets (see overall objective), showcasing their leadership as Model Cities

(b) 75% report their adaptation co-benefits">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">n/a</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 4 - Promoting International, Regional and National State and City Cooperation on Urban Climate Action</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA 4 - Promoting International, Regional and National State and City Cooperation on Urban Climate Action</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">(a) Number of local governments (i #of project cities) and their staff (ii #of staff per city) participating in Urban-LEDS II capacity development offers/events

(b) Number of local governments (i # of project cities) and their staff (ii #of staff per city) participating in events (national, regional,  international) for  cities and city partners, to promote Urban LEDS</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">(a) Number of local governments (i #of project cities) and their staff (ii #of staff per city) participating in Urban-LEDS II capacity development offers/events

(b) Number of local governments (i # of project cities) and their staff (ii #of staff per city) participating in events (national, regional,  international) for  cities and city partners, to promote Urban LEDS</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="(a) i  0 (2017)
(a) ii  0 (2017)



(b) i  0 (2017)
(b) ii 0 (2017)" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 6 new EU Resource Cities commit to engage in Urban-LEDS II 

One study tour of project cities to EU cities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="(a) i  100% by 2020
(a) ii  5 Staff per city by 2020

(b) i  75% by 2020
(b) ii 2 Staff per city by 2020">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">At least 6 new EU Resource Cities commit to engage in Urban-LEDS II 

One study tour of project cities to EU cities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance vertical and horizontal integration of climate action in support of National and Local Strategies and Policies.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhance vertical and horizontal integration of climate action in support of National and Local Strategies and Policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">a)  National governments include urban climate action and emission reductions in National reporting and communication (in support of NDCs)

(b)  Number of national government representatives engaging in discussions with Urban-LEDS project teams and/or cities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">a)  National governments include urban climate action and emission reductions in National reporting and communication (in support of NDCs)

(b)  Number of national government representatives engaging in discussions with Urban-LEDS project teams and/or cities</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="a) Colombia: No
Bangladesh: No 
Laos: No
Rwanda: No
Brazil: In progress
India: Yes  
Indonesia: No
South Africa: In progress

(b) Status of Urban-LEDS I discussions with 4 existing target countries&#x2019; ministries" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">4
Project City Selection process is coordinated with relevant ministries in 4 new target countries</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="a) At least 1 positive situation per target country initiated by the respective national governments

(b) At least 16 (2 per country) national government representatives engage  in Urban-LEDS II">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4
Project City Selection process is coordinated with relevant ministries in 4 new target countries</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
