<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2919</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Development Finance  For Inclusive Growth: The Role Of Innovative Municipal Finance And Management In Achieving Local  Sustainability (Uncdf Project)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strong and capable institutions are critical for sustainable urban
development. Improved governance processes are at the core of sustainable
management and planning of cities and towns. Laws and policies have to be adapted
to the local needs. UN-Habitat is working through this project to develop and
reinforce a conducive and enabling environment, which requires adequate legal
frameworks, political, managerial and administrative process, mechanisms, guidelines
and tools to respond to the needs of the population and its local
representatives. 

The project addresses one of the main issue of the Local Government for Sustainable Urban Development Umbrella project

The need to ensure municipal financial sustainability
with accountable leadership

Municipal finances are central to
local governments, as their strategic management plays a critical role in
ensuring long-term sustainability of local services. One key issue faced by
local governments is how to expand their resource base beyond central-to-local transfers.
Stakeholders are keen to integrate new ideas/tools on expenditure management,
tax base identification, local tax collection, etc. In all cases, improved
governance practices and enhanced accountability mechanisms (e.g., public
transparency of budgets, customer service contracts for public utilities,
adequate public asset management, clear monitoring of the performance of local
governments) have become central to sound city government and municipal
management. This project responds to the need to enhance knowledge and skills
of local governments in the field of municipal finance, to allow them fulfill their responsibilities. Taxation
requires both effective service delivery and transparent management to be
sustainable and accepted by citizens. The
development of tools to support municipalities in getting endogenous
resources (local service taxation and integrating informality) goes in parallel
with providing tools and how-to instruments to improve the management and
transparency of local finances. This latter is a crucial need, as transparency
and perception of local corruption is the necessary linkage between municipal
sustainability and governance. 

Municipalities around the world are experiencing great innovation in the
field of municipal management, from collecting taxes through the mobile phone
to the implementation of new management strategies to save energy, and money,
in the run of public services and maintenance of essential infrastructure. This
common initiative by UNCDF, UN-Habitat and FMDV has been designed to address
this incipient innovation and make it available at a larger scale by bringing
together central and local governments in a necessary dialogue about innovation
on municipal management and finance. 

The partnership will set up a platform to gather lessons learned from
innovative experiences on Municipal finance and involve the UNCDF Municipal
Finance initiatives in the framework of Habitat III agenda. This UN Conference
will take place in Quito, Ecuador in October 2016 and the project will be part
of UNCDF&apos;s contribution to the upcoming debate by providing concrete lessons
learned from its own programs and experiences. A specific focus will be placed
on LDCs countries and medium scale cities to make those needs more visible and
understood by the international community, practitioners, partners and Member
states.



Objectives

The purpose of this common initiative is to assess the needs of
municipalities and central governments from LCDs countries around the issues of
innovation in municipal management and finance. The project will provide a
framework for the identification of innovative municipal finances in the
following fields of expertise:

Transfers from central to local governmentRevenue taxManagement of municipal assetsCity borrowing and bondsTransparency and accountability as a tool to increase local revenue and
better efficiency in the provision of basic services.









The project will also provide
a platform for debate and visibility of those specific needs and put this
discussions into the Habitat III agenda.

The project objectiveis to contribute to sustainable urban development and local democracy through capable, resourceful and empowered local governments. The strategic result is that local governments will have adequate governance structures, mechanisms and resources to fulfill responsibilities and influenceurbandevelopment agendas atall levels of interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Capital Development Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Capital Development Fund (UNCDF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-20" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Robert.Lewis-Lettington@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector financial management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-20">107000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">100330</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">107000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened capacity of targeted local governments for improved transparency in municipal finance management</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened capacity of targeted local governments for improved transparency in municipal finance management</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of training event on local development finance</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of training event on local development finance</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">training event organized on local development finance organized by UN Habitat</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2015-04-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">training event organized on local development finance organized by UN Habitat</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
