<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-10856</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Urban Plans For Small Cities In Egypt (Phase Iii)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xA7; Egypt is a moderately
urbanized country. The proportion of population living in cities has stood
relatively steady at 43% in the past 10 years. The average rate of urbanization
stands at 1-2 % for the same period.&#xA7; &#xB7;
The lack of visions to guide both
city development and sectorial strategies has led to widespread weaknesses in
urban development generally and in cities of specific nature especially. The
formation of slums and its relative social issues (gender and human security),
lack of local economic development, moreover the adequate provision of social
services, infrastructure and environmental degradation are considered from the
most notably rising issues facing these cities.&#xA7;
&#xB7; UN-Habitat has been supporting the Egyptian
Government to develop strategic urban plans for small cities since 2007 in
Phase I and II of the project, but in some cases, the plans were not
implemented. UN-Habitat has updated the strategic urban planning processes and
methodology in order to bridge the gap of implementation, as well as to reflect
the principles derived from the New Urban Agenda and SDGs. In this regard, it
should be mentioned that 42 small cities have authenticated strategic urban plans,
meanwhile there are 22 cities pending the accreditation of Ministry of Defense
and 10 still at the preparatory phase. &#xA7; &#xB7;
The GOPP reviews the way city
planning is undertaken and also reviews the adopted strategic approach to
specific cities and regional levels. The GOPP also reviews its national
programme to prepare General Strategic Plans for villages in Egypt. Since then,
it has shifted to prioritize Strategic plans for cities in order to strengthen
the urban rural links. An integrated approach is sought to identify priority
issues, link development planning and budgeting to city planning actions.&#xA7; &#xB7;
Based on the experience and the
lessons learned captured on the first phase of the project during which
UN-Habitat provided technical support to GOPP to undertake Strategic Urban
Plans, GOPP has requested UN-Habitat to carry out an assessment of the ToRs
used for the SUP exercise to identify gaps and challenges and propose solutions
to bridge the gaps and tackle the challenges. This assignment is currently
being implemented and it will reflect on the process to be undertaken during
the extension period.&#xA7; &#xB7;
GOPP gives priority to strategic
planning for small cities in Egypt as they act as transitional cities that
naturally support development economically. They also act as a mechanism to
implement its participatory bottom-up approach to urban planning and enhance
linkages with development planning at local, national and regional levels.2.1
Project OriginAs started in 2007, under a framework of cooperation between UN-Habitat
and GOPP the SUP for Small Cities in Egypt Project has been implemented. To
date, it finalized Strategic Urban Plans for 48 small cities using a
participatory and comprehensive planning methodology. Based on this success,
the GOPP requested UN-Habitat to continue its technical support to prepare SUP
for additional 12 cities using an enhanced methodology which will be based on
the lessons learned from the first phase of the project. In addition, based on
the extensive experience gained during this process, GOPP requested UN-Habitat
to support the policy dialogue in urban development issues, through the
organization of events to discuss issues relevant to urban development; the
issuance of the State of the Egyptian Cities Report and organizing the National
Urban Forum. Based on the success of the first and second phase of the project,
the GOPP has officially requested UN-Habitat to expand the range of work to
include completing and updating strategic plans for some small cities, which
have witnessed huge changes, and include some special-characterized and special
natural ecological cities in addition to its consequential activities.


















2.2
Core Issues AddressedSmall cities in Egypt face deteriorated urban conditions, increase
in informal urban growth, encroachment on agriculture land, and misuse of
marine and natural environment of these cities; resulting lack of basic urban
services. These problems have not been addressed in an integrated manner and
were not reflected in any urban planning strategies. In fact, the majority of
the small cities in Egypt have never had any physical development plan
addressing the urban future of these cities. The preparation of locally adopted
SUP will assist small cities to identify their urban challenges and define
strategic goals and actions in order to respond to these challenges in a
sustainable manner based on a thorough problem analysis. One of the essential
issues addressed is to organize workshops to address key urban development
related issues based on the experience and lessons learned from the project
phases in order to support improving the urban planning process in Egypt,
moreover to help in conducting policy tools, and to provide data and scientific
research that supports the development of policy recommendations.2.3
PurposeThe main purpose of the project is to
achieve better planning and sustainable management of secondary urban
settlements in Egypt. In this regard, the project will enhance the planning
methods and tools which are adopted by the Government of Egypt in order to
produce Strategic Urban Plans which respond to the local priorities in an
efficient and realistic manner. The project aims to achieve the following results:&#xA7; 1.
National
capacity for policy dialogue and sustainable urban development and management
strengthened; establishment of several operational urban observatories at regional
and local level; updating data on cities, and supporting the Government to
report on progress towards achieving the SDGs&#xA7; 2.
Improved
inclusive urban planning processes and methodologies established for the
preparation of SUP for secondary cities.&#xA7; 3.
National
capacity of managing the coastal cities&#x2019; waterfront and linkage of urban
development to economic and environmental sustainability strengthened.




















2.4
AlignmentThe project has been designed based on the development priorities the
country is currently facing. Hereby, it builds on the national challenges
highlighted in the Situation Analysis Report that was prepared jointly with
national institutions and civil society in relation to the 2013-2017 Egypt
UNDAF, the urban challenges highlighted by development partners active in the
urban sector in Egypt as well as on the currently ongoing UN-Habitat projects
in Egypt. Moreover, it is relevant to the development agenda in the Arab
Region. Recently published UN-Habitat books highlight developmental challenges
urban areas are facing in the Arab Region (State of African Cities 2010, State
of the Arab Cities Report 2012) and globally (State of the world&apos;s Cities
2012/11).The main national level policies that will affect the stated problem
and proposed solutions amongst others are the Egyptian Constitution, the
Building Law and its Executive Regulations, the Law on the Preparation of the
State General Plan and its implementation, the local Administration Laws,
Education-related Laws, Presidential Decrees, Presidential Decrees related to
Industrial and Commercial Zones, the Ministry of Social Solidarity Law and
Presidential Decree, the State General Budget Law, the New Urban Communities
Authority Law, Laws concerning Desert Lands and Laws linked to state / public
property. The project builds on the experience of previously and currently
ongoing UN-Habitat projects in Egypt; namely Strategic Development Plan for
Greater Cairo, SUP for small cities, the Strategic Development Support Project,
Strengthening Development Planning and Management in Greater Cairo Region. In
addition to that, the project will closely link with the Achieving Sustainable
Urban Development (ASUD) Global Programme, with Egypt being one of the five
pilot countries as well as the Urban Law Reform Assessment. Lessons learnt and
Best Practice drawn by the project will inform the national level policy
discourse.
 
  
  Local Priorities
  
  
  &#xA7;
  -
  Access to suitably located,
  properly serviced and adequately priced land that is adapted to the needs for
  community development, housing with adequate provision of public spaces and
  basic urban services;
  &#xA7;
  -
  Coping with population growth
  for balanced urban development by focusing on the development of small and
  medium sized cities, to eradicate poverty and improve the socio-economic
  status within those deprived areas;
  &#xA7;
  -
  Decentralization of planning,
  management, and implementation.
  
 
 
  
  National Priorities[1][1]
  
  
  Cross-Cutting institutional Challenges (capacity building, coordination and
  connectivity, scaling-up Best Practice, access to reliable Data);
  Sustainable and inclusive growth (high and sustainable growth , unifying laws on social protection,
  providing an enabling environment for business and entrepreneurship,
  implementing Small and Micro Enterprises Strategy, youth employment, CSOs as
  change agents, export led manufacturing industry, sustainability and product
  diversification in tourism);
  Socio-political rights (poverty
  reduction, implementing social policy and programs, demographic transition,
  reducing child deprivations and regional disparities, women&#x2019;s participation
  in social and economic activity, gender responsive budgeting, pre-school
  education for equal opportunity, access to quality basic education, literacy
  and adult education, reforming vocational training systems, R D and
  innovation, dealing with health repercussions of environmental degradation,
  infectious diseases, strategy on prevention of HIV/AIDS, eradicating child
  malnutrition, decentralization and democratization, protection and respect
  for human rights);
  Environmental and sustainable resources (investment in the agricultural sector,
  deteriorating land efficiency with increased fragmentation of agricultural
  holdings, strengthening technical and institutional capacities for managing
  natural resources, expanding fisheries, shortage of Nile waters, renewable
  energy, energy security, climate change, protecting the environment, land
  allocation, expanding transport facilities)
  
 
 
  
  Regional Priorities
  
  
  &#xA7;
  -
  Population and urbanization;
  economic role of cities; urban development and housing; environment and
  transportation; urban governance systems; migration and remittance; urban
  land markers, transnational urban systems[2][2]
  &#xA7;
  -
  Informal settlements growth in
  urban and pre-urban areas; serviced land and enforcement of development
  regulations; demand for affordable housing (both rental and ownership); land
  management, role of local authorities and private sector; fiscal
  decentralization and institutional reforms (phasing out parallel hierarchies
  of appointed executives and elected councils at provincial and municipal
  level to allow for greater self-determination); property registration
  (promotion of adherence to procedure, enhanced security of tenure, better development
  controls, improved land taxation and rent collection, enhanced municipal
  own-source income from land transactions and land ownership); climate change
  and urbanization[3][3]
  
 
 
  
  Global Priorities[4][4]
  
  
  Urban trends: urbanization
  as a driving of demographic change: wealth of cities versus slums and
  informal settlements; suburbanization and urban sprawl, spreading low-density
  urban patterns and negative environmental, economic and social externalities;
  urban Sprawl in an environment of poverty exacerbates the urban divide.
  Divide cities: income
  inequality; space inequality; inequality of opportunities; social divide
  (poverty, health, education).
  Bridging the urban divide: the right to the city; regional dynamics of inclusion; economic,
  social and political dimension of inclusion; social inclusiveness and a
  multi-dimensional approach; political inclusiveness and democratic
  governance; culture.
  
 





























[1][1] Handoussa, H.
(Coordinator of Situation Analysis Taskforce), Situation Analysis: Key
Development Challenges Facing Egypt, 2010.





[2][2] UN-Habitat, State
of Arab Cities Report 2012 _ Challenges of Urban Transition, 2012





[3][3] UN-Habitat, State
of African Cities 2010 &#x2013; Governance, Inequality and Urban Land Markets, 2010





[4][4] UN-Habitat, State
of the World&#x2019;s Cities 2010/11 &#x2013; Bridging the Urban Divide 2010</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Hedaya.Rania@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-01">1963500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">427315</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved inclusive urban planning and methodologies established for small cities and cities of special nature</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved inclusive urban planning and methodologies established for small cities and cities of special nature</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Urban Plans developed for 8 small cities adopting improved urban profiling and participatory budgeting techniques</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Urban Plans developed for 8 small cities adopting improved urban profiling and participatory budgeting techniques</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="-" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop Strategic Urban Plans for 8 cities of unique environmental nature.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Develop Strategic Urban Plans for 8 cities of unique environmental nature.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="-" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved human and institutional competencies for urban planning and governance</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved human and institutional competencies for urban planning and governance</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="-" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Informed decision making in urban development enhanced</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Informed decision making in urban development enhanced</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">National and local government officials using the urban monitoring system for decision making by the year 2019</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">National and local government officials using the urban monitoring system for decision making by the year 2019</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="-" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50 of people with direct access to  information and urban data of the urban monitoring system">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
