<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3195</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Human Settlements In Urban Areas To Support Reintegration In Afghanistan (Shura)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The
purpose of the Programme is to provide a &#x2018;foundation&apos; for integration of
returnees and protracted IDPs. &#x2018;Integration&apos; in this context refers to a situation whereby these
populations live in conditions comparable to the host community and do not
suffer any ongoing disadvantage as a result of their displacement. Currently a
portion of recent returnees are receiving humanitarian assistance, in the form
of food and NFIs, temporary shelter, water, sanitation and hygiene, health and
protection assistance whilst some protracted IDPs receive intermittent
assistance such as &#x2018;winterisation&apos;. However, assistance tends to be limited to
one month packages and there remains a critical gap between this assistance and
longer term efforts to create self-reliance. The most critical component of self-reliance is access to appropriate
livelihood opportunities; typically, low skilled, low income roles in the
informal economy. In the current Afghan context, it is impossible to create
suitable livelihoods opportunities on a suitable scale to meet demand in new
locations detached from existing markets. Rather it is essential to reduce
barriers to the displaced accessing existing markets; typically
concentrated in urban and peri-urban areas and strategic district municipalities
and, to augment the capacity of those markets to absorb the influx. In doing so
it is vital to ensure that settlements are distributed effectively, to prevent
overcrowding/market saturation. Well located land can then serve as a platform
for the resilience of returnees and IDPs to be the driving force in their own
integration, as well as being a productive contribution to hosting areas. No Shortage of
Well Located Land A comprehensive study of land use in all 34 of
Afghanistan&apos;s provincial capital cities revealed that on average, 27% of all
built up areas are vacant land (land either not subdivided or subdivided but
not occupied), reflecting decades of land grabbing, land sales by
municipalities, and private sector speculation. 23% of Kabul city&apos;s built up
area is vacant plots, compared to Kandahar&apos;s 36%, whilst in Herat, a staggering
42% of the total built up area is vacant plots. These vacant plots are
sufficient to accommodate another 4 million people in major urban centers at
current densities (without establishing any new residential land).Clearly, not all of this vacant land is acquirable for the purposes of providing tenure security for the displaced. Land is frequently highly contested; questions of the use of valuable urban/peri-urban land are inherently political, potentially controversial and always complex. However recent years have seen a marked improvement in levels political support for local integration and a growing consensus that the current approach to displacement is not feasible. The recent successful implementation of a number of high profile local integration initiatives, coupled with the spike in returns from neighbouring countries has contributed to unprecendented levels of political support for durable solutions. There is currently an opportunity to capitlise on that support to secure suitable land.In addition to Afghanistan&apos;s major urban centres, secondary and
tertiary cities as well as larger &#x2018;strategic&apos; district municipalities play
vital economic and political roles, as well as a vital role in managing urban
growth and balancing the impacts of informal and rapid urbanization.
Tertiary cities and strategic municipalities tend to be either border towns,
city extensions or agricultural hubs, with a significant population and a
significant hub of economic activity. Research shows that these areas
also have an extremely high proportion of the built up area as vacant land and
high potential to assist with the reintegration of the current returnee/protracted
IDP caseload.Potentially appropriate land to form a platform for reintegration is
not confined within municipal boundaries. In 2016 UN-Habitat conducted a
comprehensive study of land use in five &#x2018;City Regions&apos;; defined as areas in
proximity to and with a functional relationship with a metropolis. The trend of
large amounts of vacant is also evident in these areas. In the case of the
&#x2018;central city region&apos;, it was found to contain 20,548Ha of vacant land in
proximity to cities. Whilst not all of that vacant land has potential to be
developed into a durable solution, initial investigations suggest that a number
of areas are appropriate .A Nascent Land
Administration SystemNot all of vacant land is owned by the state, however anecdotal
evidence suggests that a significant portion is. A pervasive issue in
Afghanistan is the nascent land administration system. Currently only 35.5% of
land in the country has been surveyed, and only 30% of land in urban areas and
less than 10% of land in rural areas has been registered through official deeds
by the Primary courts. Additionally, under Presidential
Decree 83 (2003), all untitled land in Afghanistan is presumptively owned by
the State. The ownership and
boundaries of land parcels are identified through the &#x2018;Tasfiya&apos; (land clearance)
process, administered by ARAZI. Currently however, ARAZI&apos;s Tasfiya team is
severely understaffed and underequipped, and currently only has the capacity to
&#x2018;reactively&apos; conduct Tasfiya, normally associated with large infrastructure
projects. Building the capacity of the Tasfiya team to proactively conduct land
clearance and identify potential implementation sites is thus a crucial step in
the inception phase of the SHURA Programme.Addressing the Core IssueBy ensuring that
returnees/protracted IDPs have tenure security in appropriate locations, all
investment in sites directly contributes to augmenting self-reliance.
Conversely further investment in areas that are unviable due to their location
too far from existing livelihood opportunities is fundamentally unsustainable.Returnees and IDPs will benefit
by obtaining tenure security in viable locations, where they can immediately
commence investment in themselves and in their communities. The experience of
the past decade demonstrates that displaced Afghans possess significant
resilience, evidenced by their ability to establish new lives in locations of
displacement or by their remaining in urban areas for extended periods despite
being marginalized. This resilience is an asset that Afghan cities cannot
afford to squander. Providing tenure security in appropriate locations allows
returnees and protracted IDPs to become productive contributors to the local
area and the city as a whole, rather than living on the margins and being
dependent indefinitely on humanitarian aid. Host communities will also benefit
both directly and indirectly; as the productive potential of returnees and IDPs
is &#x2018;unlocked&apos;. An &#x2018;Area Based Approach&apos; to development interventions will also
ensure that both the displaced and hosting areas benefit from an increased
level of basic services. Linkages with the Citizen&apos;s Charter National Priority
Program will also ensure that hosting areas have increased access to basic
services to offset the additional load represented by an influx of
returnees/IDPs. UN-Habitat is contributing to high
level technical guidance in terms of land identification, and policy guidance
in terms of supporting the creation of a new Presidential Decree to facilitate
the model&apos;s implementation. UN-Habitat is further contributing policy guidance
in the form of the activities of the HLP Task Force, through development of
documents such as the &#x2018;Minimum Standards for Site Selection Guidance Note&apos;.The core objectives of the Programme are as follows:Overall Objective: Supporting returnees, protracted IDPs and landless Afghans to
sustainably re/integrate into inclusive urban areas and become productive,
self-reliant and resilient citizens of Afghanistan.Strategic Objectives: Facilitate the
integration through the provision of well-located, serviceable land in
proximity to appropriate livelihood opportunities in proximity to urban
centres, secondary and tertiary cities and strategic district municipalities. Fill the
&#x2018;Humanitarian-Development Gap&apos; by facilitating the distribution of emergency
assistance in locations that have been identified for durable solutions; where
returnees and IDPs have security of tenure, providing a platform for
self-reliance and avoiding the creation of camps/open-ended humanitarian
situationsAugment
self-reliance through the delivery of permanent development interventions to
ensure access to shelter and basic services in appropriate sites in parallel
with emergency assistance Mitigate the
negative effects of an unplanned influx of returnees and prevent further ad hoc
settlement in urban informal settlementsSpecific Objectives Identify vacant state land in proximity to
major urban centres, secondary and tertiary cities, strategic district
municipalities and other centres of return that has the potential to be a
platform for durable solutions for returnees and IDPs Ensure the appropriate planning and
distribution of settlement based on a comprehensive assessment of the carrying
capacity of identified sites, incorporating economic, environmental and social
considerations to avoid the negative effects of urbanisation/an influx of new
arrivalsIntegrating lessons learned of the past decade,
employ innovative approaches to tenure security to provide rapid access to
appropriately located land through a collective &#x2018;permission to stay&apos; approach, that can subsequently be converted
into occupancy certificates and eventually formal land titles.This will include both appropriate vacant sites, and existing IDP/returnee hosting sites.Facilitate targeted efforts to augment the
absorption capacity of identified hosting areasEmploy innovative approaches to build relations
and mitigate conflicts between returnees/IDPs and host communities Ensure adequate, permanent access to shelter
and basic services in target areas in line with the minimum standards outlined
in the GoIRA&apos;s National Priority Program the Citizen&apos;s CharterIn coordination with key government
stakeholders, create a widely accepted, scalable and replicable methodology for
providing durable solutions to facilitate the integration of returnees and
protracted IDPs.Partner Activities The proposed activities will form
a &#x2018;foundation for integration&apos; based on appropriately located land and access
to livelihoods. A number of key partners, including GoIRA, UN agencies and civil
society will contribute to or &#x2018;build on&apos; the envisioned foundation. Proposed
activities are well suited to the mandate and expertise of UN-Habitat; appropriate
land identification, site planning, site preparation and community led improvements
to basic services. Other core activities such as land acquisition and
beneficiary selection will be the responsibility of the GoIRA, in particular
key partners ARAZI, MoRR, MUDH, CRIDA and relevant municipalities. Following
the acquisition of land, support from humanitarian actors will be required to
facilitate the rapid relocation of returnees and IDPs to identified sites, and
to meet basic needs while beneficiaries establish themselves in new areas.
Following this initial phase, development actors, including INGOs, NGOs, and
other civil society actors will assist in bolstering access to basic services
and augmenting the self-reliance of beneficiaries. The Programme also presents significant
opportunities for government partners, UN agencies, CBOs and others to conduct
interventions aimed at augmenting the capacity of the local economy and
community to absorb the influx of new arrivals, and joint programs with the
host community and the displaced to mitigate conflicts and build relations. Two
core project activities that do not fall under the mandate/responsibility of
UN-Habitat but warrant further discussion are land acquisition and beneficiary
selection.Land AcquisitionAccess to land is one of the most
pervasive issues in Afghanistan, purportedly being the single largest driver of
conflict in the country. Thus
the acquisition of well located, potentially valuable land for returnees, IDPs
and landless Afghans is an inherently political and contentious activity.
However, working closely with government partners in the Programme&apos;s design
phase, UN-Habitat has identified a number of appropriate sites that meet all
relevant criteria for potential durable solutions and, perhaps most
importantly, were identified by ARAZI, municipalities and other key government
actors as being politically acceptable and feasible for acquisition by ARAZI
within a reasonable time frame. This &#x2018;long list&apos; of potential sites will be
further developed during the inception phase of the project, through activities
such as the &#x2018;Mayor&apos;s Workshop&apos; to identify potential sites. Additionally, intensive
engagement with key government partners including the office of the President
was conducted during the Programme&apos;s design phase. The primary focus of engagement
was the unviability of the current approach to displacement (the Land Allocation
Scheme) and advocating for a new approach based on well located land. This key
message has resonated at the highest levels, with H.E. President Ghani
committing to support the proposed new approach and immediately establishing
three high level Working Groups (Technical, Financial and Policy) to facilitate
durable solutions in keeping with the model outlined in the SHURA Programme.In addition to the President, key
government &#x2018;champions&apos; including the CEO of ARAZI, the Minister of Urban
Development   Housing, CEO of CRIDA and the Deputy Minister for
Municipalities among others have also indicated their support and are actively
participating in working groups. At the President&apos;s request, working groups
include participants from a Deputy Ministerial level and have decision making
authority. In short, the current returnee crisis has led to unprecedented
levels of political will to abandon the failed approaches of the last decade
and pursue durable solutions. The Programme aims to capitalize on and &#x2013;through the
creation of more local integration &#x2018;success stories&apos;-build further political
support. The process of land acquisition will be complex and politically
contentious, however a key Programme output is the improved capacity of ARAZI&apos;s
Tasfiya Department to proactively conduct land clearance, resolve land disputes
and facilitate the acquisition of land.Beneficiary Selection/Eligibility Criteria A central failing of the LAS was the exclusion of undocumented returnees and,
through the requirement that IDPs return to their province of origin, the
de-facto exclusion of the majority of Afghanistan&apos;s internally displaced.
Integrating this lesson, an underpinning principle of the SHURA programme is to
be as inclusive as possible; of both documented and undocumented returnees,
protracted IDPs and potentially the most vulnerable landless Afghans. Beneficiary
selection/eligibility criteria are a highly political decision, thus must
originate from GoIRA, however UN-Habitat along with other key stakeholders is
participating in a sub-working group under the auspices of the Policy working
group created by H.E President Ghani to support government partners in developing
a more inclusive model. The model will be based primarily on a multiple layered
assessment of vulnerability, coupled with the verification of legitimate need as
evidenced by beneficiaries&apos; sustained occupation of distributed land. Eligibility
criteria are being finalized, however will likely include returnees (both
documented and undocumented), protracted IDPs and potentially the most
vulnerable among landless Afghans.Among the obligations of the &#x2018;Permission to Stay&apos; tenure documents is the
requirement that recipients immediately construct shelter and remain on land
for a minimum period of 10 years. Conditions in newly acquired plots will
initially be very basic, with recipients required to live in temporary shelter
(most likely tents) for several months while constructing incremental shelters.
Under the LAS, a large number of allocated plots remain vacant, being retained
by owners for speculation purposes, whose non-occupation of land demonstrates
the lack of a legitimate need. Under the SHURA Programme, a communications
campaign will sensitize all potential beneficiaries to their obligations and the
penalties for not complying with such. Long term occupation of land will be
verified through the use of biometric registration of all beneficiaries, with
rolling checks at regular intervals to establish original recipients have
remained on land. Given the history of corruption in the LAS and to discourage
fraud, it is recommended that a zero tolerance policy be applied; with
households failing to meet obligations immediately forfeiting land. Typical
conditions in sites will also be publicized through the communications
campaign, as will the prohibition of trading in land parcels for a period of 10
years. The communications campaign will ensure that potential applicants are
well informed of sites conditions, obligations and penalties. It is anticipated
that once conditions are widely known, and perhaps once penalties begin to be
enforced, a significant proportion of potential applicants will &#x2018;self-select&apos;
to not participate in the Programme. Meaning that if households possess the
means to pursue other means of integration, it is likely that they will choose
those option and only the most vulnerable with no alternatives will opt in for
the Programme. In this way legitimate need is verified through households&apos;
continued presence on land, and the most vulnerable households are targeted.



































































































Although not falling directly under the responsibility of the agency,
UN-Habitat will support a transparent and targeted beneficiary selection and
verification process based on the above principles throughout Programme
implementation and monitoring activities. 






GoIRA State of Afghan Cities
2015






See GoIRA Future of Afghan Cities 2016 






Afghanistan Independent Land
Authority ARAZI 2014






UNAMA 2014 &#x2018;The Stolen Lands of Afghanistan and its
People&apos; 






United States Institute of Peace 2014 &#x2018;Addressing
Land Conflict in Afghanistan&apos;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRY OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS - DENMARK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-28" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-28" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yoshinobu FUKASAWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Srinivasa.Popuri@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-28">35581275</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">4906742</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">24061487</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beneficiaries provided with tenure security and permanent housing</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beneficiaries provided with tenure security and permanent housing</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of permanent dwellings constructed through the Home Owner Driven (HOD) system</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of permanent dwellings constructed through the Home Owner Driven (HOD) system</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1725 plots">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In collaboration with key government partners and UN agencies, beneficiary selection system established and functioning in areas of high return; beneficiaries selected in a manner that is efficient, equitable, transparent and identifies the most vulnerable among the displaced</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In collaboration with key government partners and UN agencies, beneficiary selection system established and functioning in areas of high return; beneficiaries selected in a manner that is efficient, equitable, transparent and identifies the most vulnerable among the displaced</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beneficiary selection system established and functioning</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beneficiary selection system established and functioning</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1,725 of the most vulnerable returnee households">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobilisation of Community Development Councils (CDCs) and Gozar Assemblies (GAs) to represent community interests, be the driving force in meeting development challenges and to be the body through which funds are channeled to beneficiary households for permanent housing.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobilisation of Community Development Councils (CDCs) and Gozar Assemblies (GAs) to represent community interests, be the driving force in meeting development challenges and to be the body through which funds are channeled to beneficiary households for permanent housing.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CDCs and GAs mobilised, registered with Jalalabad municipality, with functional bank accounts</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of CDCs and GAs mobilised, registered with Jalalabad municipality, with functional bank accounts</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBA">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of well-located, serviceable land with access to appropriate livelihood opportunities in proximity to existing markets in urban hubs, secondary and tertiary cities and strategic district municipalities.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of well-located, serviceable land with access to appropriate livelihood opportunities in proximity to existing markets in urban hubs, secondary and tertiary cities and strategic district municipalities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">$ of appropriate sites identified, acquired, prepared to accommodate IDPs and Returnees and provided with basic services in keeping with the minimum standards outlined in the Citizen&#x2019;s Charter National Priority Program</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">$ of appropriate sites identified, acquired, prepared to accommodate IDPs and Returnees and provided with basic services in keeping with the minimum standards outlined in the Citizen&#x2019;s Charter National Priority Program</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1,725 plots">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support returnees, protracted IDPs and landless Afghans to sustainably re/integrate into inclusive urban areas and become productive citizens of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support returnees, protracted IDPs and landless Afghans to sustainably re/integrate into inclusive urban areas and become productive citizens of Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws approved, land allocated and IDPs, returnees integrated in</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws approved, land allocated and IDPs, returnees integrated in</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="n/a" year="2021">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-28"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1 Executive Decree
Land TBA">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
