<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-10875</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening The Long-Term Resilience Of Subnational Authorities In Countries Affected By The Syrian And Iraqi Crises</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The large increase in
population since the Syria crisis began is putting public institutions under
extreme pressure to deliver basic services to an increasingly high number of
vulnerable people. In a context of shrinking national resources, this is
testing the limits of infrastructure and public services that were already
fragile before the crisis.

Seven years on and the
reality of the response on the ground in most affected regions indicate that
sub-national authorities are yet to play a consistently effective role in
guiding the response and in coordinating and tracking the diverse range of
interventions being implemented by a multitude of actors including
de-concentrated sector service providers, international aid organizations,
civil society and the private sector.
This reality is resulting in a significant level of inefficiency and
redundancy in the delivery of much needed aid and in numerous cases, in the
misguided targeting of valuable interventions.
It also represents a missed opportunity to affect a longer-term process
of development of sub-national systems of governance and the coherence of the
distribution of roles and responsibilities among sub-national tiers of
administration or government and between them and central ministries that in
most cases, continue to hold the bulk of the mandate for the delivery of most
basic social and economic services and infrastructure.

Iraq

The economy of the KRI
which kept the Syrian refugees employed since 2011 has severely shrunk since
2014 when investment stopped following ISIS occupation of Mosul, leaving
minimum livelihood opportunities for displaced families. In addition to this,
fighting to retake Mosul from the ISIS has triggered significant further
displacement.



A policy of free
movement in and out of the camps and the facilitation of work permits allow
refugees to freely pursue employment opportunities. This has led to similar
rates of employment of both host and refugee communities: 32% aged 16-59 are
employed and 57% of men and 6% of women are employed according to a survey made
in four camps. Unemployment and under employment increased affecting more
refugees and especially women, 100% of households with at least one family
member with disability reported unemployment. In terms of job compositions,
more than 50% of host communities are employed by the Government, while the
same percentage of the refugees is self-employed. Of major concern is the
significant increase in competition for available jobs, especially in camps in
Erbil and Dohuk where the highest number of refugees and IDPs are sheltered.
Distance to job location and discrimination were found minor factors as proved
by the 13% of camp and 30% of host communities who have established businesses
in relation to the needs of the camp. 

Poverty is increasing
in the whole country, but at a higher rate in ISIS-affected governorates
including the KRI. Microsimulation estimates suggest a reversal of the hard-won
welfare gains of the past, with poverty rising in overall Iraq from 19.8% in 2012
to 22.5% in 2014. Poverty was accompanied by a massive human capital deficit;
in health, education and access to basic services. Many Iraqis live close to
the poverty line, vulnerable to increases in the price and availability of
necessities, and/or the loss of assets and livelihoods. According to the World
Bank projections, the number of people living below the poverty line was 2.8
million at end 2014. IDPs make up half a million of Iraq&#x2019;s poor in 2014, with
an estimated poverty rate of 40%, almost twice the average. The KRI experienced
a quadrupling of poverty rates and increased competition for jobs, goods and
services.

Infrastructure was
also severely impacted and affected in the KRI by the influx of IDPs and
refugees. Between October 2012 and September 2014, the additional demand for
water for IDPs and refugees is estimated at 11% and the KRI needs to meet an
additional estimated total water demand of 17.1 million square meters per year.
The sharp increase in demand for water has not been accompanied by investments
in water and wastewater infrastructure. Sanitation remains a major concern,
most notably in IDP camps. The major gaps relate to physical facilities,
namely, the lack of wastewater treatment plants. The lack of sanitation
increases public health risks and environmental pollution.

Based on the rapid
needs assessments and field surveys conducted by UN-Habitat, the majority of
vulnerable IDPs and Syrian refugee families live in over-crowded rented houses
of urban neighbourhoods without tenure security or basic safety, structural and
sanitary standards. While some of the IDPs were able to stay temporarily with
their relatives or to rent apartments, massive numbers of IDPs are still in
need of shelter and basic services. As addressed in the Iraq Humanitarian
Response Plans 2015, 2016 and 2017, the number of IDPs in some of Iraq&#x2019;s major
cities has now exceeded their original population, putting host communities
under severe pressure. Inadequate housing conditions contribute to significant
protection needs, endangering women and girls. Women, men, girls, and boys face
increased vulnerability to sexual and gender-based violence in insecure shelter
conditions without doors and locks. Exposure to risk and feelings of
vulnerability are pervasive among refugees and IDPs, especially for women and
adolescent girls of reproductive age. These women and girls also have specific
needs related to menstruation and cultural norms of modesty which often are not
met in existing shelter conditions. This could significantly hinder early
recovery efforts and further deteriorate the socio-economic wellbeing of the
displaced and local populations, as well as leading to social tensions and
public discontent, potentially resulting in additional widespread social unrest
and violence.



Even among IDPs who
are willing to return, several factors prevent or delay the return, including
damage to housing, poor access to basic services, deterioration of community
cohesion and security, limited economic opportunities, and disputed land and
property claims. In Sinjar, aside from widespread physical destruction and the
presence of unexploded ordinances, lack of proper documentation on housing,
land and property rights has been preventing many IDPs from settling back in
their former properties, some of which have been in the meanwhile usurped, as
highlighted by assessments conducted by UN-Habitat. 

The proposed project
was designed in coordination with both the Federal Government of Iraq and the
Kurdistan Regional Government, and priorities are determined against needs
assessment conducted at the end of 2016.



Lebanon

The Urban Dimension of the
Crisis

Syrian refugees are located throughout Lebanon due to the absence of
official camps; 87% of them live in 251 localities (in certain municipalities
they outnumber local residents) and in these same localities reside 67% of the
Lebanese poor population. By mid-2017, it was estimated that 74% of refugees
fall under the poverty line and 58% cannot meet survival minimum expenditures.



Between 2014 and 2017, the percentage of Lebanese who did not report
any inter-community tensions dropped from 40 to 2 percent. Competition for
jobs, political and cultural differences, and pressure on resources and
utilities are the top three sources of tensions. 94% of Lebanese respondents
agree that the presence of Syrian refugees in Lebanon is placing too much
strain on resources. Areas identified as most vulnerable in the
251-vulnerability map, which include all large cities of Lebanon and their
suburbs, consistently suffer from less access to services, more insecurity,
higher levels of tensions and more exposure to violence than non-vulnerable
areas.



Local Authorities and a More
Resilient Response 

Within this context,
municipalities have a critical role to play in the country&#x2019;s response to the
impact of the Syria crisis and there is growing intention to engage more
municipalities at the services as well as at the social cohesion levels.
However, this will require increased funding and empowered human resources at
municipal level, as well as enhanced collaboration and communication with
central and subnational government. 70 percent of municipalities are too small
to provide basic services pre-crisis, 57 percent lack an administrative
structure, and 40 percent have only a single employee (often working on a
part-time or voluntary basis).

In the absence of a decentralised system,
increased interaction between the national and local level will allow for
enhanced responsiveness and support by central public institutions and
ministries to the needs of municipalities. The response in Lebanon is testing
approaches to increase effectiveness of municipalities through enhancing
local-regional-national level coordination and improving capacities in a
targeted manner. This work is seen as a potential source for informing a future
decentralization reform and to strengthen social stability in Lebanon &#x2013; as
recent analysis has also demonstrated that residents&apos; trust in their local
authorities is a key component of social stability

Justification/Key Challenges

Despite increasing
efforts from national and international actors to largely and actively engage
municipalities in the response, municipal performance is hindered by the
following key challenges:



Highly Centralized
System: according
to the Law 118/77, municipalities enjoy administrative and financial
independence, however in practice, they are bound by the highly confessional
and political systems which restrict decision making at the central level. 



Limited Financial Resources: municipal finance relies mainly on
the funds channelled through the Independent Municipal Fund (IMF), controlled
by the Ministry of Interior and Municipalities (MoIM), and fed from the taxes
collected by key public service providers (e.g. electricity, communications,
water, etc.) Amounts channelled to municipalities through the IMF are
calculated based on a complex formula that considers the number of registered
population and the percentage of fees collected annually by municipalities.
However, in reality, the size of municipal annual budgets and their liquidity
are subject to the availability of cash within the Ministry of Finance. Except
for the funds channelled by the central government, municipalities seldom take
any initiatives that may enhance local revenues. Moreover, municipalities did
not receive increased national revenues to deal with the impact of the Syrian
crisis within their localities. 

Lack of Skilled Human Resources: insufficient funds and the
bureaucracy within the existing systems restrict the ability of municipalities
to recruit the necessary technical and administrative personnel. This in turn
hinders proper municipal planning and efficient service delivery as it
negatively impacts the quality and cost effectiveness of proposal plans and
interventions. 

Bureaucratic Administrative Process: According to the Lebanese
Administrative structure, municipalities fall within the jurisdiction of the
Ministry of Interior and Municipalities, for processing their daily business.
Municipalities are required to obtain ex-ante approvals from the Qaemaqam, the
governor, and the minister according to set expenditure thresholds. This
extensive administrative process has been impeding municipalities to meet the
needs of their communities in a timely manner and affecting the overall
municipal performance and operations.

Overlapping   Unclear Mandates: the highly confessional and
politicized system in the country has led over the years to overlapping
mandates and conflicting responsibilities between municipalities and line
ministries, and amongst the ministries themselves. The competition over
decision making and the confusion over the scope, scale, and level of work have
led to improper planned, cost ineffective, unaligned service delivery systems
at the local, subnational and national levels. This was made evident during the
response to the Syrian refugee crisis, whereby local and national authorities
made contradictory statements in response to proposed solutions and roles
clearly overlapped.

The proposed action will build on the already existing context, here refer
to section 1.4.2 on complementary actions, and in particular the existing work
of UNDP and UN Habitat with regards to Host Communities and Urban populations.
However, the overarching intent will be to go one step further than previous
interventions and develop capacity, particularly at the sub national level,
that will result in Unions of Municipalities and Municipalities being better
able to manage the impact of the crisis. The intention is to leverage the
investments in a manner that enables systems strengthening and results in
stronger, more capable and accountable sub national structures. This is in
essence the transformative agenda of the Resilience approach where funding
targeting a crisis contributes to longer term change</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP REGIONAL HUB FOR ARAB STATES</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Talar.Oskeridjian@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster prevention and preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">24971363</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">3293114</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
