<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-13121</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Design Of Coahuila&#xB4;S Integral Strategy Of Adequate Housing And Sustainable Urbanization, Aligned To The Principles Of The New Urban Agenda And The Sustainable Development Goals</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical assistance will be
carried out to support the effort of the newly created Ministry of Housing and
Land Management and the Ministry of Infrastructure, Urban Development, Mobility
in the state of Coahuila, with the purpose to define a strategy that on the one
hand contributes to the urban integration of inadequate housing already
existing; as well as to lay the foundations for the construction of new complex
rooms that adhere to the principles of adequate housing.

The realization of the Project is
relevant and justified because the situation in Coahuila reflects the chaos in
the development of housing that has arisen nationwide. This means that Housing,
predominantly social, has been built in the unconsolidated areas of urban
settlements that are generally located on the periphery; therefore, they are
difficult to access, are disconnected from urban centres and offer limited
access to development opportunities.

Likewise, preference has been given
to the design of horizontal cities characterized by low density, high
dependence on private vehicles as a means of transport and high levels of
pollution. As well as the degradation of urban infrastructure and the lack of
public spaces and green areas. All together for the government represents a
great challenge due to the higher demand of the provision of public services
that are increasingly expensive due to the remoteness in which the new housing
complexes are located.

The result of this situation is to
have a high number of abandoned or disused homes because they do not offer the
necessary conditions to live in them and their inhabitants decide to lose their
assets to move to other units that, if they have the necessary services and ,
usually, closer to your workplace.

The technical assistance offered to
the Government of Coahuila is aligned with the Sustainable Development Goal 11:
Sustainable cities and communities, specifically with goals 11.1, 11.2 and 11.3
that address ensuring access for all people to adequate housing and services,
access to mobility and to increase inclusive and sustainable urbanization.



Likewise, it is aligned to the
National Development Program 2019-2024 which, under Axis 2: Social Policy,
contemplates in section VIII Urban Development and Housing that &#x201C;social housing
will be a priority and thousands of improvement, extension and development
actions will be carried out.&#x201D; [1]

The federation, through the Ministry of Agrarian, Territorial
and Urban Development (SEDATU for its acronym in Spanish), is responsible for
&quot;developing and conducting housing policies&quot;[2]
and &quot;issuing the guidelines on (...) land use or use, as well as
housing&quot;[3]
justifying the involvement of said agency, as well as the national agencies
related to the housing that depend on it.

The Agricultural, Territorial and Urban Development Sector
Program 2019-2024 is currently under development and UN-Habitat has been part
of the elaboration process in which the general housing policies will be
defined. In that sense, SEDATU has assumed the rectory of the housing policy
and the maximum objective is that every family can enjoy adequate housing,
which is in full agreement with the purpose of the work that will be carried
out in Coahuila.

The attributions of the federative entities (also known as
states) are &#x201C;to promote the fulfillment and effective protection of human
rights related to the territorial planning of human settlements, urban
development and housing&#x201D;[4],
which is why legally the counterpart - the Government of Coahuila - would have
powers on the object of technical assistance to be carried out.

Accordingly, it is aligned with the
State Development Program 2017-2023 of the State of Coahuila that in its Axis
4: Social, inclusive and participatory development with its Objective 4.9:
Housing and basic services whose central premise is &#x201C;to contribute so that coahuilenses
in a situation of vulnerability and with lower economic income have access to
decent housing, improving the quality of materials, with basic services and
providing their inhabitants with legal certainty about their heritage.&#x201D; [5]

By virtue of the foregoing, it can
be affirmed that the proposal for technical assistance is in full agreement
with the principles and objectives of the global agendas, as well as the
guidelines of the national and state government.

The Project has been conceptualized
from an integrated perspective in which it has sought to create a balance
between its normative, planning, and operational components. The purpose is to
anchor institutional changes in legislation and regulations to ensure its
adoption; besides considering the inclusion of the design of an institutional
mechanism for the observation of its application in the long term; and finally,
the strengthening of the installed technical capacities of local governments
considering their transcendental role in the territorial application of the
strategy.

It is through the integration of
these components that it is ensured that there is a joint support between the
normative and the operation aspects, ensuring that this raises the chances of
success to achieve the objectives and the expected benefits that have been
raised. In addition to contributing to improve the installed capacity of local
actors contributing to the appropriation of the project so that it can be
implemented without the need for permanent assistance from the agency.









[1] National Development Program consulted in https://www.dof.gob.mx/nota_detalle.php?codigo=5565599 fecha=12/07/2019



[2] Article 41 Section I of the Organic Law of the Public Administration of Mexico.

[3] Article 8 Section IV of the General Law of Human Settlements of Mexico.

[4] Article 10 Section III of the General Law of Human Settlements of Mexico.



[5] State Development Program consulted in https://coahuila.gob.mx/archivos/pdf/Publicaciones/PED2017-2023/Plan_Estatal_Desarrollo_baja.pdf</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOBIERNO DEL ESTADO DE COAHUILA DE ZARAGOZA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Latin America and Caribbean</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elkin Velasquez Monsalve</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Eugenia.De Grazia@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="11430" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advanced technical and managerial training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="22010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communications policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-01">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">50000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
