<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3213</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Un-Habitat &#x2013; Usmid  Technical Assistance For Territorial And Metropolitan Planning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the problem-what is the
purpose of this project?

The project will represent UN-Habitat&apos;s contribution to an endeavour
that would culminate in a longer &#x2013; term and more comprehensive advisory service
aiming to address the urban planning problems and help Ugandan Government
officials to find their own responses for good urban/spatial planning and
provide better services within the local authorities. The main purpose is to
develop the capacity of selected Ugandan Government Officials to manage
sustainable urban development for different scales of cities beyond this
initiative and in longer terms, enhance intersectoral and interdepartmental
approaches by training them to &#x201C;think out of the/their box&#x201D;, jointly work on strategies
and concrete projects (where applicable), enhance collaboration with national
and international experts and academia and give a long-term support by
providing technical advisory services and tools for physical planning.What specific aspect of the problem
is the project addressing?

The project will develop the capacity of both
thelocal government
officials from municipalities covered by the USMID program by improving their
knowledge and capacity in urban/spatial planning as well as governance and
finance aspects (three pronged approach).As USMID is assigned
to enhance institutional performance of 14 municipal councilsacross Uganda, in
order to improve their urban service delivery, a more integrated territorial
development can be expected as major outcome.Who and how do target populations
benefit directly from the project?The target groups that stands to benefit most from the project are the
urban poor and vulnerable groups both those living in the metropolitan areas
and small and secondary cities as well as peri-urban areas as they are mostly
affected by poor planning (suffering from congestion, poor access to
sanitation, poor housing, informality etc.). Well planned and efficiently
managed cities and municipalities that are more socially inclusive and
institutionally integrated, compact and better connected and resilient to
climate change have proved to influence economic growth. One mayor tool to be
used for the capacity building will be the promotion of the International
Guidelines for Urban and Territorial Planning. Improved living conditions,
enhanced connectivity and land tenure regulations ensure that urbanisation can
become an engine for economic development, leading to increased employment opportunities
and reduced poverty. An improved economic situation, due to newly developed
strategies for boosting the economy not only in the Greater Kampala
Metropolitan Area will also benefit youth due to better employment opportunities
throughout the country. In the second phase of the project, trainings and
advisory services on physical planning aspects such as beautification and
public space will support women and youth in the municipalities. Those
trainings will be included a strong gender perspective. During the planning
studios, environmental issues such as flooding can be chosen as main issue,
based on the need of the respective municipality.How does the project respond to real
needs and high-priorities of the target group?







The Ugandan population needs a balanced economic
growth and improved living conditions as well as equal opportunities for all.
Among the main challenges are the rapid growth of populations combinedwith low levels of economic activity due to inadequate physical and
human capital plus the insufficient capacity to generate new jobs. The lack of
evidence-based and anticipating planning lead to growth of slums and informal
settlements, dilapidated housing, and poor sanitation; weak coverage of basic
infrastructure services, notably water, energy, and sanitation, which makes it
difficult to improve welfare in either urban or rural environments; youth bulge
in urban areas; and very high traffic
congestion.
In consequence, those issues hindered economic growth and employment
opportunities; they should be addressed by a well-planned urbanisation, promoting
of inclusive and participatory urban planning, management and governance
processes, but also by improved coordination among various institutions
involved in urban and physical planning and enhanced the capacity of key
players to effectively continue building on past achievements. In addition to
this, promoting local economic growth
and creating job opportunities from infrastructure and urban development
projects as well as an improved security situation due to well-planned urban
areas (public spaces) will also have a direct impact on women and youth and
will support the economic and social development in the 14 communities.

What and how does your project aim
to change/solve in regard to the identified problem?

The project is a contribution toenhancing the capacityof Ugandan Government
officials in order to provide better urban services in the phase of the
up-coming adoption and (in longer terms) implementation of the National Urban Policygeared towards
resolving urban planning problems. Main focus of the project is on the support
of the Uganda Support to Municipal Infrastructure Development (USMID) Program
to improve the capacity of local authorities tomanageincreased
urbanisation.What are the proposed solutions for
the problem and why are they the most appropriate to the problem?

Enhancing the
capacity of Ugandan Government Officials on the one hand, and providing
improved methods and tools on the other will be achieved through training activities.
In addition to this, a participatory and inclusive dialogue among stakeholders (including
peer-to-peer learning) will result in a better appreciation of challenges and support
finding tailored solutions in collaboration with local academia and the support
of the other municipalities covered by the USMID program. After a profound
assessment of the capacity needs, the capacity development activities will include input sessions on planning, finance
and governance (based on the three pronged approach), dialogues with
international experts and discussions on good (international and Ugandan)
practices and case studies as well as exchange visits and field trips to
successful projects. One important aspect should be a sound assessment
(profiling) and data collection in the municipalities in order to develop
evidence based strategies. The collected data will be gender specific. The
participatory and intersectoral /interagency team work as well as additional advisory
services during the planning studios to plan (and in long term) implement
projects and the increased capacity of urban key players will be leading the
way forward in managing urban development in the Republic of Uganda, without
imposing prefabricated models that are not apt to the local context.Certain capacity development activities will be based on the UN-Habitat MetroHUB
methodology, which not only includes planning, governance and finance aspects,
but integrates social and environmental components, capacity building and
acupuncture projects.Who are the possible partners,
internal and external that will help in implementing the solution?Several UN-Habitat Branches/Units (Urban Economy;
Urban legislation, land and governance; Urban Basic Services, Regional Office
for Africa;) (The branches provided input and advised at the formulation stage
of the project. Their role during the implementation stage is need based and
might not need inhouse agreements.)Municipal Infrastructure Development (USMID) ProgramAfrican Development BankMakerere
University Kampala (MUK)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MINISTRY OF LANDS/ HOUSING &amp; URBAN DEVELOPMENT - UGANDA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Planning and Design</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rafael Tuts</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Remy.SIETCHIPING@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">685000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">46279</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">62190</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA1: Enhanced capacity of staff of Ugandan metropolitan and local government authorities to manage urban services</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EA1: Enhanced capacity of staff of Ugandan metropolitan and local government authorities to manage urban services</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">I.A.1: Number of institutions and authorities with development plans and strategies</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">I.A.1: Number of institutions and authorities with development plans and strategies</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Assumption:
0 Institutions and local authorities" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Report including data collection, case studies and best practices</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2 of the 14 institutions and local authorities covered by the USMID program have urban development plans and strategies">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Report including data collection, case studies and best practices</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">I.A.2:  Number of staff capable of effectively managing urban projects using new (project)  tools and methods on urban planning, governance and finance</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">I.A.2:  Number of staff capable of effectively managing urban projects using new (project)  tools and methods on urban planning, governance and finance</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Assumption:
0 staff capable of effectively managing urban projects using new (=project) tools on urban planning, governance and finance" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Report including data collection, case studies and best practices</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30%* of the staff working on urban development in the 14 municipalities covered by the USMID program are able to efficiently manage urban projects (*the exact number of staff in the municipalities needs to be assessed)">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Report including data collection, case studies and best practices</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
