<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3379</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation Of The New Urban Agenda (Nua)_Crpp-Ufm</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OBJECTIVE, PURPOSE   EXPECTED RESULTSA memorandum of Understanding between UN Human Settlements Programme (UN-Habitat) and the UfMS was signed on 5th April 2016 in the UfMS premises. The MoU was signed between UfMS and UN-Habitat in general, comprising therefore The Regional Office for Arab States in Cairo, Global Water Operator&#x2019;s Partnerships Alliance (GWOPA), and Resilience Office (CRPP) located in Sant Pau premises, in Barcelona as well as the rest of offices, programmes, and initiatives of the agency.The MoU ensures the collaboration between the two institutions with a view to developing strategies, initiatives and projects within member countries of the UfM to promote an integrated approach to urban development which includes among others, resilience and disaster risk reduction as well as water and environmental management. Cooperation would also involve the existing Urban Projects Finance Initiative (UPFI) and support capacity building activities in the region.On the margin of the UN Conference on Housing and Sustainable Urban Development (Habitat III), the Union for the Mediterranean organized in Quito on 18 October 2016 in cooperation with the UN Human Settlements Programme (UN-Habitat), among other partners, the Networking Event &#x201C;Union for the Mediterranean &#x2013; Urban Projects Finance Initiative (UPFI): Towards a New Urban Agenda for the Mediterranean region&#x201D;.On the occasion of the Senior Officials Meeting of the Union for the Mediterranean, held on 7 and 8 April, 2014, at its headquarters in Barcelona, the UfM Secretariat officially launched the Urban Projects Finance Initiative (UPFI). The purpose of this financial initiative was to identify and select sustainable urban development projects likely to be endorsed by the Union for the Mediterranean and financed and implemented in the short term.The selected projects are part of an integrated regional development programme of projects on urban development, rehabilitation, renovation or even de-pollution. Each project has its own identity which may be sector-specific and/or local in order to meet the particular needs of populations, but the projects are also part of an integrated needs-based approach and must be part of a global sustainable development strategy.The New Urban Agenda was agreed at the United Nations Conference on Housing and Sustainable Urban Development (Habitat III) in Quito in October 2016. On the occasion of the Second UfM Ministerial Conference on Sustainable Urban Development to be held in Cairo, Egypt, on 15-16 May 2017, UfM Member States will adopt a comprehensive UfM Urban Agenda and its operational action plan, outlining the new sustainable urban priorities for the Mediterranean, with a view to addressing the region&#x2019;s demographic and environmental challenges, thus contributing to achieving theThe Secretariat of the Union for the MediterraneanPalacio de Pedralbes. C/ Pere Duran Farell 11. 08034 Barcelona. Spain. Tel: +34 93 521 4100. Fax: +34 93 521 41013Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).Building on UPFI best practices, the study will propose ways to effectively implement the UfM Urban Agenda. UN-Habitat foresees a programme (to be launched in April) aimed at assisting governments to develop their urban policies. The study will link the New UfM Urban Agenda with the UN-Habitat foreseen programme and will explore ways of future collaboration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THE SECRETARIAT OF THE UNION FOR THE MEDITERRANEAN</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-23" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Risk Reduction and Rehabilitation</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joannes Meeuwissen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Esteban.Leon@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="74010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster prevention and preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-23">23104</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">23104</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
