<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-4421</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical Cooperation For Long-Term Capacity Building For Syrian Experts &#x201C;Training For All&#x201D; Ii</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Throughout the crisis,
Syrian human capital and institutional capacity have significantly declined. If
this issue remains unaddressed, the capacity of the Syrians and their
institutions to address people&#x2019;s immediate needs and deliver essential services
(electricity, health, water and others) will be seriously affected.
Furthermore, over half of the working age population are now unemployed. Since
the onset of the crisis, training/learning opportunities have been limited,
creating a significant deficiency, and therefore pressing needs, in skills
development in various segments of the population. This is particularly the
case for young people who tend to be more vulnerable to recruitment by armed
groups. 

The project is aligned with the principles of human
security approach. The proposed project is a comprehensive response to address
the multiple aspects of human insecurities people in Syria are experiencing and
to strengthen resilience within a fluid environment. The project will take a
people-centered approach by focusing on building resilience of people and
communities through strengthening their ability to cope, recover, and lay the
foundations for better recovery during and after the crisis. This project also
includes youth-specific interventions that focus on strengthening the
leadership role of young women and men, building their capacities, and
supporting their empowerment and participation. The project adopts a
conflict sensitive approach and ensures the application of the do-no-harm
principles.

UN agencies and partners in Syria have been providing
immediate humanitarian assistance to the most affected people in the country.
In the past years, there has been a realisation that resilience-based approach
is necessary to respond to the protracted crisis so as to build sustainable
solutions for addressing the various effects of a seven-year conflict. This
approach requires removing unnecessary barriers between humanitarian and
development actors, so that they jointly work towards strengthened
interventions to address needs through sustainable solutions with a stronger
resilience focus, which is one of the prominent features of
humanitarian-development nexus. Therefore, the participating humanitarian and
development UN agencies will team up together to jointly implement and &#x201C;deliver
as one&#x201D; this project to respond to people&#x2019;s needs in the short term and empower
them over time to reach better outcomes. This project is implemented under the
New Way of Working (NWOW) approach focusing on the collective outcome of
enhancing the human capital inside Syria.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Szilard.Fricska@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Arab Republic</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syrian Arab Republic</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-01">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">400000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-4422" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
