<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-9847</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessing The Feasibility Of Applying A Global Definition Of Cities/Urban Areas In Support Of Global Monitoring Of Sdgs And Nua Urban Targets</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and reporting on SDG Goal 11 and many other urban targets creates major concerns that other SDGs or non-urban targets do not necessarily confront. National statistical systems need to coordinate with local authorities and service providers to collect information for several indicators at the city level, using both conventional (i.e. census data) and modern (satellite imagery and ICT) forms of data collection, including the integration of qualitative data.Cities and countries are also struggling to understand how urban indicators will be disaggregated along key dimensions, including age, sex, disability status, social groups, income levels, migratory status and locations. Too often, existing city data is either not properly documented and harmonized, or not adequately detailed to enable disaggregation. In other countries, city data is simply not available on many critical issues related to urban growth and development. As a result, many people are not counted and many aspects of their life and the city conditions are not measured. For city residents, this can lead to the denial of basic rights, and for the city, the possibility of missing important opportunities for development. Local and national governments realize that without adequate technologies, manpower and resources many people and places can indeed be left behind.While the above challenges are being addressed by custodian agencies and other partners, a key impediment to collection of data that represents the true character of urban settlements at the local level, and which is regionally and globally comparable, is the lack of consensus among experts and organizations on a globally applicable city definition - with common thresholds that can be applied across countries. Attainment of such a definition will not only help countries to use a standard method to delineate their cities and collect data on them, but will also ease the comparison of city data across countries. This will also help to better understand intra and inter country urbanization trends/ variations, and in turn to inform development of practical and locally adaptable policies on sustainable urbanization. Monitoring and reporting on the urban related SDGs (especially SDG 11) and the New Urban Agenda (NUA) will largely benefit from the adoption of a globally applicable city definition. Such a definition will ensure that the study areas for the urban SDGs are standardized and easily reproducible, and ensure that national level data can easily and uniformly be disaggregated between urban and rural areas.The ability for countries to collect data and report on the urban SDGs in a timely manner greatly relies on the adoption of a globally applicable city definition. Countries have already expressed the lack of such definition as a major impediment to their monitoring and reporting efforts on almost all SDGs, especially because the monitoring framework requires disaggregation of data based on type of settlement (urban vs rural). Attainment of a global city definition is in itself a consultative process which involves multi-level engagement with statistical and decision making agencies at countries, and mass piloting of the emerging proposals.The current project forms part of this consultative process and seeks to pilot the application of the DEGURBA approach to city definition in four regions &#x2013; Africa, Asia, Latin America and the Arab States. The project will make it possible to compare results across countries, and also with those attained through application of the other existing approach to city definition &#x2013; the urban extent method &#x2013; which has already been applied in 200 cities from all world regions. The ultimate result will be increased knowledge base among experts, countries and international organizations working towards a global city definition, which will in turn help fast track the conclusion of discussions towards a harmonized city definition. This is an important milestone for UN-Habitat&#x2019;s support to countries to monitor and report on SDG 11. It will also support the agency&#x2019;s pending activities on finalization of guides and tools, customization of various manuals, and provision of technical advisory services to countries on collection of data and reporting on SDG 11 and other urban indicators.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-12" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Capacity Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Halfani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Eduardo.Moreno@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-12"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-01">967725</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">93607</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">632319</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	Improved global understanding of urbanization patterns</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	Improved global understanding of urbanization patterns</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.	Number of countries reporting city-level data based on globally comparable definition</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.	Number of countries reporting city-level data based on globally comparable definition</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="20" year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.	Number of countries reporting on SDG11 and NUA using global level city definition</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.	Number of countries reporting on SDG11 and NUA using global level city definition</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="30" year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.	Level of comparability of city data across the world</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.	Level of comparability of city data across the world</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Low" year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="Medium">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
