<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-2367</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cities Prosperity Initiative (2013-2015) - Municipality Of Zapopan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN-Habitat Cities Prosperity Initiative is a strategic policy initiative for cities and partners that are committed to aligning their policies, operations and strategies with UN-Habitat&apos;s fresh notion of prosperity. Cities are expected to work simultaneously in the five dimensions of prosperity: productivity, infrastructure, quality of life, equity and environmental sustainability. 
The City Prosperity Initiative is a practical framework for the formulation, implementation, and monitoring of sustainability policies and practices to increase prosperity levels at city level. It is an initiative that provides collaborative solutions to the most fundamental challenges facing cities.
Specifically, it is an Initiative of 250 cities globally that are committed to a more holistic, people-centred and sustainable notion of prosperity and pledge to deploy necessary efforts and resources to move forward in the prosperity path will be created. The aim is to enable a shift away from prevailing narrow and lopsided conceptualizations of prosperity and related policies and actions. The rationale for this is that without a new and revised conceptualization of prosperity at strategic policy levels, cities risk promoting strategies that threaten rather than enhance sustainability.
By estimating the City Prosperity Index (CPI) of cities based on globally comparable data, UN-Habitat will create an invaluable baseline for tracking progress in terms of prosperity. In addition, in conducting estimations in cities through the Initiative, UN-Habitat will also adapt the CPI to correspond to locally available data, policy priorities and needs. Thus, the Initiative will enable globally comparable yet locally specific estimation and monitoring of urban prosperity.
Three intermediate accomplishments of the Cities Prosperity Initiative will be:

Improved policies and strategies of cities towards prosperity path are catalyzed through customised action plans. 
Cities begin to implement actions and policies to advance on a prosperity path based on a customised action plan. 
Cities have enhanced capacity to measure and monitor present and future progress towards the prosperity path.
At a more local level, the Cities Prosperity Initiative aims at:

Reinforcing local capacities to increase economies of scale and agglomeration for improved wellbeing and prosperity through localized urban planning and design interventions. 
Assisting in implementing a variety of technical solutions for improving the functionality of the city and achieving sustainable urban form. 
Assisting in packaging projects through pre-feasibility studies and project viability for financing.
The benefits of engagement arising from the Technical Advisory Package offered by UN-Habitat through the Initiative are captured in the table below.





Technical Advisory Package
UN-Habitat will provide additional support to cities for: 


Benefit
This will produce:


1. Adopting an established and globally recognized policy framework (Prosperity Index and Wheel of Prosperity) for the development and implementation of policies and actions to increase urban prosperity. 

Certificate recognizing the participation of the city in the Cities Prosperity Initiative


2. In-depth and customized estimation of the City Prosperity Index. 

New up-dated City Index. 


3. Conducting a diagnostic and proposing a General Action Plan with policy recommendations to advance prosperity. 

Action Plan and Road Map


4. Sharing best and emerging practices to advance practical solutions and strategies to city challenges 

Best practices sharing 


5. Utilizing UN-Habitat Cities Prosperity Initiative tools and resources, and the opportunity to engage in specialized work-streams as per the different dimensions of prosperity. 

Accessing tools and resources


6. Accessing UN-Habitat extensive knowledge of and experience with sustainable urban development issues related to the 5 dimensions of prosperity. 

Accessing a critical mass of knowledge and technical advisory services


7. Advancing, sustainable solutions and key proposals in partnership with key stakeholders 

Sustainable solutions 


8. Assisting in packaging for funding and linking cities to finance, identifying possible financial sources.

Linking cities to finance


9. Establishing a local monitoring mechanism with baseline data and benchmarks

Creating a monitoring mechanism


10. Linking cities and partners across regions and local networks and promoting South-South cooperation 

Sustainable solutions 


11. Evaluating efforts and processes deployed to advance prosperity 


Lessons Learned

Following from the above, the expected outputs of the project are as follows:
1.Cities create conditions to embark on actions and policies to advance in a path of prosperity
2.Cities begin to implement actions and policies to advance in a path of prosperity based on a tailored General Action Plan and related Road Map
3.Cities are capable to monitor, measure and evaluate progress towards the prosperity path
The City Prosperity Index, together with a conceptual matrix, the Wheel of Prosperity, both of which are meant to facilitate designing of clear policy interventions, will form the basis of the technical advisory package described above. This is accompanied by additional technical support in a wide spectrum of areas such as institutional analysis, strategic thinking, guidelines, training and capacity development, monitoring tools, urban futures analysis, and policy simulations all designed to help cities to advance on the prosperity path in a more sustainable manner. 

UN-Habitat&apos;s wheel of prosperity symbolizes the well-balanced development of the five dimensions, the current condition of which is graphically represented in the City Prosperity Index. The outer rim absorbs the cumulative forces transmitted through the spokes the five dimensions of prosperity. At the centre is the hub the local urban power functions, with four interrelated roles: ensuring the prevalence of public over any other kind of interest; controlling the direction, pace and momentum of the wheel; ensuring the balanced development of the five spokes and associated synergies; and in a two-way relationship, absorbing and amortizing any shocks transmitted by the spokes.
The hub brings together the power functions (e.g., laws, regulations and institutions, urban planning, civil society, trade associations, special agencies, etc.) associated with the five spokes. In this role the hub represents human agency in all its embodiments. Clearly therefore, the thematic focus of the project is directly linked to and integrates all of UN-Habitat&apos;s thematic priorities as symbolized by its 7 Branches. The operationalization of the Cities Prosperity Initiative will involve all Branches of UN-Habitat given the direct linkages between the five dimensions of the Wheel of Urban Prosperity (productivity, urban infrastructure, quality of life, equity and environmental sustainability) and ongoing work in UN-Habitat&apos;s thematic Branches. Once the CPI is estimated for cities, UN-Habitat&apos;s Branches will be fully engaged in the roll out of the Technical Advisory Package (see above) especially in the diagnosis of prosperity challenges and opportunities to prepare a general action plan and road map; identification of appropriate innovative solutions, best practices, tools and guides to facilitate operationalization of the general action plan and road map; and technical advisory services to support the establishment of local monitoring mechanisms to track progress on a path of prosperity. 
In addition, UN-Habitat&apos;s regional offices and Habitat Programme Managers will play a critical role in the operationalization of the Cities Prosperity Initiative and related activities. Accordingly, using seed funding obtained from the UN-Habitat Internal Development Fund, the recruitment of three consultants to be located in UN-Habitat offices in Africa, Asia and Latin America is already underway.
A number of external partners will also play a critical role in the realization of the objectives of the City Prosperity Initiative. These include local and metropolitan authorities, urban development authorities, local and regional academic, policy and research institutes, national and regional banks and Habitat Professionals Associations. Furthermore, where available, UN-Habitat will rely on Local Urban Observatories (LOUs) for gathering and processing data for the estimation of CPIs. Moreover, LUOs will be used as a platform for establishing specific prosperity monitoring mechanism for in each city.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zapopan Municipality</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-04-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Capacity Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Halfani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Gora.Mboup@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-04-01">800000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">274065</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">274835</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-2411" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved awareness leads to increased participation by Habitat Agenda partner</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved awareness leads to increased participation by Habitat Agenda partner</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	Improved policies and strategies of cities towards prosperity path are catalyzed through customised action plans;
2.	Cities begin to implement actions and policies to advance on a prosperity path based on a customised action plan; and
3.	Cities have enhanced capacity to measure and monitor present and future progress towards the prosperity path.
4.	Improved  capacity in cities to develop actions and policies to advance on the prosperity path</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	Improved policies and strategies of cities towards prosperity path are catalyzed through customised action plans;
2.	Cities begin to implement actions and policies to advance on a prosperity path based on a customised action plan; and
3.	Cities have enhanced capacity to measure and monitor present and future progress towards the prosperity path.
4.	Improved  capacity in cities to develop actions and policies to advance on the prosperity path</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Urban Observatory (GOU; various members)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Urban Observatory (GOU; various members)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
