<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3400</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eliminating Violence Against Women In West Bank And Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Based on the problem, the purpose of this joint programme is toreduce vulnerability of women and girls in West Bank   Gaza to all forms of violence against women and from the threat of such violence.- Eliminating violence against women requires interventions on both the side of service providers as well as service users. This will be achieved through supporting reforms to the health and social service sectors&apos; capacities to be effective and accountable for preventing, mitigating and responding to violence, but also very importantly through changes to the community&apos;s utilization of services and the behaviors and attitudes related to violence against women on the part of all concerned parties.- The program builds on ongoing work across the UN system in West Bank and Gaza Strip and forms a coordinated, multi-sector, long term strategy designed to produce results in preventing and combating violence against women and girls through experimentation and documentation of &#x2018;what works&apos; and lessons learnt. It also draws on the pending process of harmonizing legislation and regulations with international standards related to preventing and combating violence against women.- The programme focuses on comprehensive and integrated interventions that are designed from a proven evidence base. The interventions are targeted at different levels (the individual, the relationship between partners, the family, the community, including the physical environment (through providing safe and inclusive public spaces), the society, local government, national government, grassroots civil society); across the three pillars of prevention, response and policy development (the intermediate outcome areas as outlined above); and with a longer-term time-frame recognizing that preventing and responding to violence against women requires sustained commitment of financial and human resources.- This is a joint programme led by UN Women and including UNFPA, UN Habitat and UNODC. The joint programme will build coalitions, between and with civil society organizations and establish networks at the local and national levels. The programme will ensure complementarity and synergies with other relevant programmes and projects avoiding duplication and overlapping through coordinating with established networks and coalitions. The key partners for UN Habitat components are: The Ministry of Local Government, five selected municipalities in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, and the Palestinian Universities (Birzeit, Al Najah, and the Polytechnic).- UN Habitat will develop a methodology and training sessions for local authorities and municipalities on the provision of inclusive, safe and free of violence public spaces especially for women and girls, implement this capacity building and advocate with local authorities and the Ministry of Local Government for the development of a national gender responsive public space policy based on the lessons learned and results achieved during the programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWomen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Arab States</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Muhammad Basil Kadhim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Lubna.Shaheen@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian Territory, Occupied</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-01">2827086</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1315368</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decreased harmful practices and attitudes that perpetuate and validate violence against women and girls within targeted households and communities.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decreased harmful practices and attitudes that perpetuate and validate violence against women and girls within targeted households and communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">c)	Proportion of women and girls, men and boys in the targeted communities who agree that harassment and violence in public spaces is not acceptable under any circumstances</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">c)	Proportion of women and girls, men and boys in the targeted communities who agree that harassment and violence in public spaces is not acceptable under any circumstances</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="will be determined through a National Survey on Violence Against Women, which will take place in 2018" year="2018">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number and percentage of women and girls, men and boys participating in the planned survey</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number and percentage of women and girls, men and boys participating in the planned survey</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
