<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3274</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Securing Housing, Land And Property Rights Of Protracted Idps And Returning Refugees: Ensuring Durable Solution</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will promote durable solutions for displaced communities of both internally displaced persons in prolonged states of displacement and regional refugee returnees, that have informally occupied land in major cities in the country. It will demonstrate how the Guiding Principles on Internal Displacement (1998), Inter-Agency Standing Committee (IASC) Framework on Durable Solutions for Internally Displaced Persons (2005), the SDGs as well as the New Urban Agenda can be localized in a coherent and integrated manner. In addition, work on operationalising the National IDP Policy (2015). The experience through the project will benefit Asia-Pacific as well as other regions, therefore making Afghanistan a global leader in Durable Solutions framework implementation.The objective of the project is to support activities that provide tangible durable solutions in informal settlements comprising protracted internal displacement and regional refugee returns, through the sectors of land (UN-Habitat and NRC); livelihoods and economic development (DACAAR); documentation and access to services (NRC, DACAAR, AfghanAid) that support meeting Strategic Development Goals (SDG) outcomes. In particular, the project aims to contribute towards the following SDG targets (in order of descending relevance):1.	SDG 1.4 and 5.7 &#x2013; undertake reforms to give women, as well as the poor and vulnerable, equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance, and natural resources, in accordance with national laws2.	SDG 8.6 &#x2013; substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education or training3.	SDG 16.9 &#x2013; provide legal identity for all, including birth registration, by 20304.	SDG 1.7 &#x2013; create sound policy frameworks at the national, regional, and international levels, based on pro-poor and gender-sensitive development strategies5.	SDG 11.1 &#x2013; ensure access for all to adequate, safe and affordable housing and basic services, and upgrade slums6.	SDG 16.3 &#x2013; promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for allThe project in addition supports the UN Secretary General&apos;s resolve for early warning, preventing conflict and sustaining peace. When displacement related issues are addressed and durable solutions achieved the sometimes cyclical nature of conflict and displacement maybe avoided.The intended Impact of the UN-Habitat component of the project is to &#x2018;Strengthen Housing, Land and Property Task Force (HLP-TF) members and displaced communities&apos; influence on the Government of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan (GoIRA) to recognise and respect the land tenure rights of poor and vulnerable displaced communities in Afghanistan and achieve durable solutions.&apos;The Project aims to work towards the progressive realisation of the human and housing rights of the displaced population through the following activities measured through the related indicators:
 
  
  Impact:
  
  Strengthen
  Housing, Land and Property Task Force (HLP-TF) members and displaced
  communities&apos; influence on the Government of the Islamic Republic of
  Afghanistan (GoIRA) to recognise and respect the land tenure rights of poor
  and vulnerable displaced communities in Afghanistan and achieve durable
  solutions.
  
  
  
  Increase in the # of landless
  and displaced communities secure access to suitable land.
  The increase in the # of
  occupancy certificate and subsequent title deeds issued by the ARAZI and
  ensured benefit to women by 2017.
  The # of laws and regulations
  that respect and recognise the land rights of landless and displaced
  communities in Afghanistan.
  Increased # of displaced
  population included in the GoIRA&apos;s development framework.
  
 
 
  
  Outcome
  1: Awareness Raising and Capacity Building
  HLP-TF members and
  displaced communities have increased knowledge and understanding of HLP
  issues and capacity to effectively advocate for their land and housing rights
  (security of tenure) and achieve durable solutions.
  
  
  At least 75% of HLP-TF members,
  displaced communities and government authorities attending the trainings
  enhanced their knowledge, understanding and skills on Housing, Land and
  Property Rights and Durable Solutions.
  At least 75% of KIS-TF members
  and KIS residents attending the training enhanced their knowledge and
  understanding no how to access to Land Tenure under the proposed Law on
  Registration of Urban Informal Property (Occupancy Certificate 
  At least 75% (7/10) HLP-TF
  members and displaced community representatives increased their knowledge on
  national and regional experiences on land rights advocacy and practice.
  
 
 
  
  Outcome
  2: Coordination and Participation
  Improved
  coordination and participation of HLP-TF members and displaced communities
  with local, regional, national and to some extent international clusters,
  working groups and networks working on HLP and durable solutions issue.
  
  
  Increased
  participation and solidarity among 85% of HLP-TF members and displaced
  communities and development of # of joint advocacy action plans to
  respond to the emerging HLP issues including focus cases of the affected
  communities; and three year HLP-TF Action Plan reflecting the priorities of
  the HLP-TF members and displaced communities.
  Enhanced
  strategic direction of HLP-TF.
  
 
 
  
  Outcome
  3: Evidence-based Advocacy and Policy Influence
  HLP-TF members and
  displaced communities actively monitor HLP related legal and regulatory
  framework/policies at local, regional and national level and influence
  decision makers to respect and recognise the land tenure rights of poor and
  vulnerable displaced communities.
  
  
  # of inputs and policy
  recommendations related to HLP are considered and incorporated by ARAZI,
  MUDH, MoRR, IDLG/DMM etc into the draft law and policies.
  Increased # of displaced
  communities participate in policy consultations and decision-making process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-12" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yoshinobu FUKASAWA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Srinivasa.Popuri@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asia, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Housing policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-03-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-12">917505</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">519970</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">791356</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased awareness and availability of services to promote access to basic sanitation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased awareness and availability of services to promote access to basic sanitation</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The increase in the # of occupancy certificate and subsequent title deeds issued by the ARAZI and ensured benefit to women by 2017.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The increase in the # of occupancy certificate and subsequent title deeds issued by the ARAZI and ensured benefit to women by 2017.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">occupancy certificate</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-03-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">occupancy certificate</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local and national governments and other Habitat Agenda Partners have improved tools and approaches for increased security of tenure for vulnerable groups, women, youth, IDPs and indigenous peoples</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local and national governments and other Habitat Agenda Partners have improved tools and approaches for increased security of tenure for vulnerable groups, women, youth, IDPs and indigenous peoples</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in the # of landless and displaced communities secure access to suitable land.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increase in the # of landless and displaced communities secure access to suitable land.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="n/a" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Landless and displaced communities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-03-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="n/a">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Landless and displaced communities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local and national governments have strengthened institutional and policy frameworks towards inclusive, sustainable and adequate housing for all, within the framework of the Global Housing Strategy (GHS) including the right to adequate housing/protection against forced evictions, housing policies and strategies, housing finance, housing culture and diversity, green housing, post-disaster and housing reconstruction</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local and national governments have strengthened institutional and policy frameworks towards inclusive, sustainable and adequate housing for all, within the framework of the Global Housing Strategy (GHS) including the right to adequate housing/protection against forced evictions, housing policies and strategies, housing finance, housing culture and diversity, green housing, post-disaster and housing reconstruction</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased # of displaced population included in the GoIRA&#x2019;s development framework.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased # of displaced population included in the GoIRA&#x2019;s development framework.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDP Communities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-03-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDP Communities</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The # of laws and regulations that respect and recognise the land rights of landless and displaced communities in Afghanistan.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The # of laws and regulations that respect and recognise the land rights of landless and displaced communities in Afghanistan.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/A" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laws and regulations</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-03-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="TBD">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laws and regulations</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
