<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3380</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Goals, In Particular Goal 11 On Cities, Work Related To Indicators, Tools Capacity Building And Monitoring</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal 11 monitoring and reporting creates major challenges that other SDGs do not necessarily confront. A mixed-bag of approaches will need to be deployed to address the data needs for indicators under Goal 11 and other urban related indicators especially where the city will act as the unit of analysis. For example, out of the above 16 listed indicators, 7 will be collected at local city level and not by routine data collection mechanisms such as census or household surveys: 11.2 public transport; 11.3.1 land consumption; 11.3.2 civil society participation; 11.5.1 budget on cultural heritage; 11.6.1 solid waste; 11.62 Air quality; 11.7.1 public space. In addition, from the 16 indicators, 7 require some form of spatial data collection and analysis at local/urban level with a clear method at the urban agglomeration level: 11.2 public transport; 11.3 efficient land use; 11.5 people affected by disasters; 11.6 urban solid waste and air quality location; 11.7 public space; 11.b climate change and resilience. Also out of the 16 indicators, 6 will require special aggregation techniques to generate the desired data at the national level from city-based data. This will require working with a representative National Sample of Cities for each country selected in such a manner that it reflects the country&#x2019;s territory, geography and history, and any other dimensions that will be agreed upon by experts.Consequently, all national statistical systems need to coordinate with local authorities and service providers to collect information at city level as the unit of analysis, using conventional (i.e. communities) and modern (satellite imagery and ICT) forms of data collection, including the integration of spatial data as part of the necessary and required tools/techniques. The use of innovative geospatial tools in data collection systems, including census and surveys to measure and to track performance of cities towards many Goal 11 targets is new for many national statistical agencies and institutions. The aggregation of the city level information from human settlements data at city level and yet report performance at national/country level is new and of paramount importance to many national statistical agencies. Without a standardized method of measurement and clear techniques of aggregation, countries will face serious problems to create a consistent set of cities that is representative of their territory, geography and history.12 They will also be challenged by the difficulties to report on national (urban) progress in a systematic manner. This national aggregation problem will make it difficult, if not impossible, to report at regional and global levels on locally produced urban/city level data. Through this project, UN-Habitat and other collaborating partners recognize this challenge and are responding to demands from governments to put forth a methodology that will ensure that a system of representative cities is drawn and made available for national level reporting. The national sample of cities will be drawn using sound statistical and scientific methodologies based on, but not limited to national importance, geographic location, size of the city, population in the city, economic and political importance, etc.                              12 Reporting on a handful number of cities that are not necessarily the same does not represent, statistically, the country, and data cannot be aggregated at national urban level without a clear method of aggregation. 11In addition, some cities and countries are recognizing the difficulty to integrate a city-wide approach in policy formulation when monitoring and reporting on Goal 11 indicators that are very sectoral in nature. This is even further complicated by the silo-approach of ministries and government departments found in many governance systems across the world.In light of above, further capacity building work is needed so as to align data collection processes, methodological work, including definitions of concepts to SDGs requirements and integrate aspects of policy formulation applicable to related SDG targets. Enabling political, legal and institutional frameworks as well as financial support is also needed. A formalized coordination mechanism involving all data producers, with clear mandate and specified role and responsibility at all levels is also required. At the city level, urban management and development process involve many actors and at different levels (political bodies, national, subnational and local). Similarly, these different stakeholders are involved in the production of various supporting indicators required for monitoring progress towards the SDG 11. The establishment and use of a centralized national data platform, the clarification of methodologies used for measuring indicators and defining concepts, as well as availability of indicators and metadata in the centralized data platform are among measures that can contribute to the improvement of data availability, accuracy, timely reporting and comparability. All these issues are already providing challenges to national statistical systems, and this project will aim to provide a proof of concept and document lessons learnt in selected countries and selected cities on how goal 11 can be monitored through development of a national sample of cities and working with a diverse set of partners and departments. Tools and knowledge generated through this pilot will be widely shared with other countries for easier reporting and implementation of the Goal 11 and other urban related monitoring frameworks.In addition, the project will ensure that the tools and mechanisms for monitoring goal 11 and other SDGs urban related indicators integrate the international and national gender, youth and human rights monitoring strategies at all levels. Specifically, tools and national sample of cities methodology will be developed to measure and assess inclusion of women&apos;s participation in socioeconomic and environmental activities. Already CPI tools which will form a core set of indicators have good ratings for tracking inclusiveness including gender balance in internal structures and decision-making processes, and incorporating gender perspective into all actions (in national governments and ministries, as well as in local governments), higher education institutions. Indeed CPI indicators such as, access to adequate housing, water and sanitation, access to quality education, as well as access to internet and citizen participation, or any other civic, cultural, economic, political and social right metrics that link directly to many human rights agendas.All steps of the project will emphasize the need for gender mainstreaming and young people inclusion and reaffirm that appropriately designed tools and monitoring frameworks can bring new opportunities for women and young people in urban areas if they have equal access to resources and adequate training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norway</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-10" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Capacity Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Halfani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email></email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Botswana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunisia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle East, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South America, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Botswana</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Botswana</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunisia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunisia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="4" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-10"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-01">154021</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">0</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">131454</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="41120-0" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced technical capacity of the selected 4 countries and 8 cities to adopt and implement a reliable urban local monitoring framework (that produces reliable, timely, and disaggregated natio</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced technical capacity of the selected 4 countries and 8 cities to adopt and implement a reliable urban local monitoring framework (that produces reliable, timely, and disaggregated natio</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2019, 3 out of the 4 target countries design and implement National Sample of Cities methodology (to increase data comparability, measurement standards and national averages for country, regional and global aggregations).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2019, 3 out of the 4 target countries design and implement National Sample of Cities methodology (to increase data comparability, measurement standards and national averages for country, regional and global aggregations).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
