<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3207</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Governments For Sustainable Urban Development (Umbrella Project)  Phase Ii 2016-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The
project objectiveis to contribute to sustainable urban development and
local democracy through capable, resourceful and empowered local governments.
The strategic result is that local governments will have better governance structures,
mechanisms and resources to fulfill responsibilities and
influenceurbandevelopment agendas atall levels of
interventions.

Strong
and capable institutions are critical for sustainable urban development.
Improved governance processes are at the core of sustainable management and
planning of cities and towns. Laws and policies have to be adapted to the local
needs. UN-Habitat is working through this project to develop and reinforce a
conducive and enabling environment, which requires adequate legal frameworks,
political, managerial and administrative process, mechanisms, guidelines and
tools to respond to the needs of the population and its local representatives. While
significant results have been achieved by phase I, more work is required for
gains made to be consolidated and extended.
This project will keep on assisting in a catalytic manner in advancing
UN-Habitat&apos;s urban governance agenda and its norms, namely sustainability,
subsidiarity, equity, efficiency, transparency, accountability, civic
engagement and citizenship.

In
order to keep contributing to the implementation of the Strategic Plan
2014-2019, the LGDU identified the need to broaden its relationships with local
and regional governments and its associations as wells as with other strategic
partners at normative and operational levels to
raise awareness on UN-Habitat mandate in relation to urban governance and
management; to develop, test, evaluate and disseminate tools, methodologies and
knowledge to reinforce local governments&apos; recognition and capacities on urban
governance and management issues and to provide technical assistance to
national, regional and local authorities and other institutions responsible for
urban governance issues in the formulation, development and implementation of
global processes such as the 2030 International Development Agenda. This project will allow the coordination of
on-going efforts in the area of urban governance throughout the Agency and will
leverage resources with other ongoing projects. This project builds on existing
work streams within the area of governance and looks at developing more adapted
approaches and means of operationalization for local and regional governments.
As this is cross-cutting issues, each area will involve cooperation with another
unit of UN-Habitat and/or relevant partners able to relate to and involve local
governments.

In
general terms, the project will address the issues raised by implementing the
following strategies: 


 To
     develop and reinforce a conducive and enabling environment, which requires
     adequate legal frameworks, political, managerial and administrative
     process, mechanisms, guidelines and tools to respond to the needs of the
     population and its local representatives.
 To
     assist in a catalytic manner in advancing UN-Habitat&apos;s urban governance
     agenda and its norms, namely sustainability, subsidiarity, equity,
     efficiency, transparency, accountability, civic engagement and citizenship.
 To
     partner with various stakeholders at normative and operational levels to reinforce
     local governments&apos; recognition and capacities.
 To
     orientate the work at local, territorial, national and global levels.


In a
more detailed way, the project will operate at the same levels of phase one: 1)
municipal, 2) territorial (city-region), 3) community and 4) global, always in
collaboration with the national level. Moreover,
the second phase of the project will address the challenges mentioned above and
will specifically focus on enhancing local governments&apos; adequate
responsibilities and functions (multi-level governance), fostering their
capacity to develop and implement institutional accountability and transparency
strategies for urban management, promoting innovating and SMART solutions to
improve municipal finances and management and the awareness and promotion of
the role of local governments in global processes. The project addresses the
issues in four main working lines:

1. Developing governance multilevel and
multiscale governance arrangements in order to improve policies, institutional and
technical frameworks, and tools to place local governments as kingpin of Sustainable
Urban Development

Local governments are placed in a network of relationships and
jurisdictions. Reinforcing their role, in a decentralized framework, with a
multi-sector vision and at different scales requires a strong multilevel
governance approach. To be able to &#x201C;do their job&#x201D;, local governments need to be
in constant dialogue with all the other local stakeholders. To ensure effective
measures and to achieve positive results for the citizens, tax-payers and
economic agents, a constant coordinated action is required. Challenges such as
urban mobility, employment and environmental sanitation, among others, extend
beyond the realm of local governments and cover various legal-administrative
divisions in the territory, hence the need for multi-level dialogue, both
horizontal and vertical. Soft governance modalities, such as inter-municipal
cooperation, allowing for two or more neighboring municipalities to perform
together municipal administrative tasks and deliver public services or any
other governance arrangements at the territorial scale could be explored. Sound
territorial management is also a way to go beyond the rural-urban divide and to
address metropolitan governance.

There is a need for a common vision on the political and
conceptual approach of multilevel governance and to unpack and translate this
concept into practical tools for the use of local leaders. There is also a need
to communicate successful strategies applied for others, to learn from other
contexts either about the political process as well as its implications for
public services delivery and to establish new horizontal cooperation between
local governments.

Moreover, Phase I has already developed significant work to
improve the understanding of decentralized governance improved trough urban governance
mapping by developing and implementing the Urban Governance Survey and the corresponding
Urban Governance platform involving
more than 100 cities, in collaboration with LSE Cities and the UCLG Committee
on Decentralization and Local Governance. Additionally, the International guidelines
on decentralization and basic services were championed and mainstreamed and technical
assistance and continuous support has been offered through the project to five
countries (Jamaica, Solomon Islands, Cape Verde, Gambia and Uganda) in the
adaptation process. Regarding metropolitan
governance, the first phase of the project specifically addressed coordination
and cooperation between levels of governments, as one of the key issues of
adequate metropolitan arrangements and directly related to decentralized
governance. Publications such as the a comprehensive study &#x201C;Unpacking
metropolitan governance for sustainable development&#x201D; was elaborated and
published, specific technical assistance was given to metropolis for tailored
programs to deal with the complex management issues arising from the common
provision of basic urban services by different political and administrative
bodies (Brazil, Colombia) and three in-depth case studies were initiated (Bandung,
South Africa and Guadalajara) in order to engage further in advisory services
and developing tools for improved coordination and peer-learning services,
based on partnerships with Metropolis and FMDV (Global fund for city
development). 

The second phase of project will keep on analyzing, developing and
reviewing multilevel governance mechanisms as well as developing, consolidating
and disseminating knowledge on territorial and metropolitan institutional
mechanisms, as most of the outputs undertook in phase one still have an open
work line to be further developed. A Global database on current models of urban governance for public dissemination, comparative policy and research analysis. For further information please refer to:http://urbangovernance.net

2. Fostering transparent and accountable local governments to improve
municipal management and service provision

Corruptionis,
perhaps, one of the most damaging consequences of rapid urbanization processes,
especially when this happens within a context of weak institutional and governance
structures.
High population densities in urban areas often leads to an aggravated pressure
on natural resources and on the provision of basic urban services. The supply
of services, such as access to land, adequate and safe housing, clean water and
sanitation, among others, is finite and scarce in some cases. This
factor increases pressure on local governments, sometimes, exceeding their
ability to provide services and to respond to the large and vast established
demand. As a result, some sectors and services are prone to corruption,
misappropriation and, worst of all, inefficiency and mismanagement.
Consequently, there is a tangible effect on the quality of services, eroding
public trust in the accountability and merits of local governments. 

It is often perceived that local decision-makers suffer from a
high risk of being captured by special interests and that, in many cases,
institutions designed to hold local public officials to account are not always
adequate. In this regard, there is a need
to generate alternatives to change this perception. Building trust in the local
public administration is essential for any further action, and that cannot be
possible without improving the communication with citizens on the one hand, and
without eradicating corrupt and ineffective practices, especially those
affecting the provision of basic services that have a direct impact on the
daily lives of citizens.

A common effort to mobilize stakeholders around a local
anti-corruption agenda is critical for sharing experiences and knowledge, both
as a repository for knowledge on transparency and a platform for local
government to engage and dialogue with the citizen. With the pressure of
quality service delivery at an affordable rate, engaging and developing transparency
and accountability strategies is becoming an important tool for local
governments to improve municipal management and improve service provision. This
project responds to the need to enhance knowledge and skills of local
governments in the field of transparency and accountability in municipal management
and service delivery, to allow them fulfill their responsibilities. The
development of new tools to support transparent urban management cannot ignore
the enormous potential of technology. Local governments need to adapt quickly
to this challenge to take the advantages offered by this new window for the
participation and contribution of everyone in the city. In this sense, there is
a great demand by Mayors and other public managers, regarding experiences,
tools and apps developed for the use of SMART technologies in the interests of
greater transparency in urban management and effective fight against
corruption.

Main outputs and activities developed by the phase I of the
project include the development and publication of &#x201C;E-Governance and urban
policy design in developing countries&#x201D; to
enhance and promote ICT as an instrument to increase the levels of
participation of people and the accountability of public policy implementation.
Additionally, the project organized and supported the participation of local
governments and local governments associations in international events and
networks regarding accountability and transparency in municipal management
promoting the awareness and advocacy of the issue of corruption as essential
for good urban governance, and on the need of new tools and innovative
instruments to be created to support local governments in being more
transparent and accountable. 

The current second phase will focus on the need to strengthen the
capacity of local governments to respond to the challenges posed by corruption
in urban management by supporting the development and adoption of transparency and
accountability strategies in municipal management as well as promoting and raising
awareness on the positive relationship between transparency and accountability
and sustainable cities. The LGDU will keep its strategic relationship with
Transparency International to explore possibilities for further collaboration
in fighting corruption in local governments with specific focus on urban
development. Transparency International (TI) defines corruption as: &#x201C;the misuse of entrusted power for private gain&#x201D;. Corruption flourishes when transparency is absent. Obscure, non-transparent decision making processes create favorable conditions for corruption. The absence of transparent and prescribed regulations can give substantial discretionary power to officials as it creates an opaque environment with few &#x2018;checks and balances&apos; (UN-Habitat, 2013).According to TI International surveys, bribery affects more than one-in-five Africans, and disproportionally affects the poor in urban areas. The majority of Africans (58%) say that corruption has increased over 2015. The situation in the Middle East and North Africa is not much different, where the majority of people (61%) across the region think that the level of corruption has gone up over the last 12 months and the fifty million people had to pay bribes to access the basic services that they needed. Which means that nearly 1 in 3 public service users suffered from corrupted practices, according to TI. Furthermore, according to the last corruption perception Index (2016), perceived levels of corruption in the public sector for Latin America are usually high. In the overall ranking, countries like Peru (85), Colombia (94), Bolivia and Mexico (103) and Argentina (107) rank low, with Venezuela being the country in the region with more corruption perceived in the public sector ranking 161 of the 174 countries surveyed. In response, in recent years, many Latin American countries have witnessed a wave of social upheaval attacking corruption cases discovered (Example: Brazil, Guatemala, Mexico).Zinnbauer, D. (2013). Cities of Integrity: Draft Working Paper.http://unhabitat.org/books/e-governance-and-urban-policy-design-in-developing-countries3. Supporting local governments in the
adaptation to the new opportunities offered by SMART technologies to improve
municipal sustainability

Open data strategies, open and accessible information about the
implementation of public services, local governments performance monitoring and
access and follow up to the municipal finances are increasingly demanded by the
citizen today. This makes clear that improving governance systems and
mechanisms of accountability at the local level are essential for the
establishment of strong local governments, efficient and effective municipal
management and local government connected to the real demands of their citizens.

In response to the growing interest of local governments for the
use of technologies to improve the management of the city, there is today an
emerging market of SMART (Sustainable &#x2013; Monitorable &#x2013; All-inclusive &#x2013;
Rights-based - Transparent) urban services. The inclusion of citizens in
decision-making processes and the facilitation of the appropriation of new
technologies by both governments and their own citizens, have enabled the
emergence of innovative and inclusive solutions for improving the different
challenges municipal administration. SMART technologies are changing the
day-to-day lives of people in both industrialized and developing countries,
producing incredible side-effects in the local economy, but also accelerating
social transformation and generating a direct in impact in the lives of the
poorest. 

The project addresses the increasing citizen&apos;s call for pro-poor
approaches, transparency and effectiveness in public service delivery,
municipal finances and management. To be able to deliver their mandate, local governments
need to be sustainable both financially and institutionally. In developing
countries, one of the main causes of local unsustainability is the failure of
local governments to expand access to affordable services for the poor and to
create the conditions for the informal economy to become formal and safe. Many
citizens, especially the poor, obtain basic services (such energy or water)
from informal sources, creating a vicious circle where municipalities are
unable to provide services because the lack of funding, and leaving citizens
with the only option of obtaining unsafe and often more expensive services from
informal providers. Therefore, the informal access to services appears as the
only option, making poverty a permanent situation. Providing municipal services
to the poor and gradually bringing the informal to the mainstream mutually
benefits all, enabling municipalities to expand their revenue base, increase
public expenditure and improve access to basic services, but this is a very
complex and long-term process. In this context, many municipalities are looking
into the application of SMART technologies (such as mobile phones, sensors or
cards) to municipal finances and management, as a tool to support revenue collection
and to shorten the time in service delivery, cheapen energy costs, protect the
environment, increase accountability and reduce corruption. Technologies can
reduce the time-lapse between the payment of the tax and the provision of the
service. Smart technologies appear to be a tool to improve public service
delivery, operational efficiency and ease intergovernmental relations. 

During the first phase of the project and within the Future Policy
Modeling (FUPOL) research consortium, an e-participation tool was developed in
Mtwapa (Kenya) in the field of slum upgrading, which has contributed to gather
lessons learned on the application of ICT and mobile devices with Youth and
urban poor. Furthermore, LDGU, in cooperation with FMDV (Fond Mondial pour le
Development des Villes) established the Ura&#xED;a Platform to
respond to the local governments&apos; needs regarding last trends in municipal
management innovation, seeking innovative solutions to respond to the
challenges of urbanization and build more resilient and inclusive territories.
The Ura&#xED;a platform has creates a space for exchange between local governments
and their partners about the possibilities offered today with the introduction
of SMART technologies in local public management and citizen participation. The
Platform offers now services of knowledge exchange, building of capacities and
development of pilot projects. The work in this area has included advocacy and
learning activities with focus on the development of SMART technologies for
municipal sustainability, the development of guidelines on PPP negotiations and
procurement and the identification and consolidation of best practices in the
area. 

The second phase of this project will build up on the existing
platform and work on improving the network and keep the work on best practice
collection, learning advocacy activities and the development of new sets of
guidelines in response to the requests presented by the partners. The
development of specific tools (apps) is being considered as a next step for the
platform services. Full information in wwwuraia.org

4. Advocating for the role of local and
regional governments in global processes including 2030 Development Agenda. 

The scenario marked by the definition of the 2030 Development
Agenda and the Sustainable Development Goals and the New Urban Agenda has represented
an opportunity to reassess the key role of local government in achieving
sustainable urban development and set as a priority facilitate and strengthen
its voice in the formulation and development of these global processes. Both
processes require a combination of experience collection and technical
expertise displaying how and what local government can provide for the
achievement of sustainable urban development. There is also a need to ensure
the follow-up of these international and political processes: the outcomes of
the 2030 Development Agenda and the New Urban Agendas are likely to call for
stronger implication of local governments, as essential responsible for their
implementation.

In 2014, during the first phase of the project, UN-Habitat, UNDP
and the GTF were appointed to lead the dialogue on the implementation of the
Post-2015 agenda at the local level. Local and national consultations took
place in 13 countries together with a number of regional and global
consultations, resulting in a strategic global coalitions of partners &#x2013; LRGs,
CSO, United Nations agencies, etc. The Dialogues resulted in key messages
underling the importance of LRGs in promoting sustainable development and in
guaranteeing social inclusion, national ownership and institutional
accountability. The results showcased how the new Global Agenda could not be
locally implemented without the leadership of LRGs. A final report, including
recommendations and suggestions to facilitate the road ahead, was developed and
shared in international events and policy discussions and presented to key
decision-makers of the Post-2015 framework.
This process also directly related to the campaign for an urban SDG,
strongly supported by the Global Taskforce and UN-Habitat bringing together
bringing Mayors, Governors and local government associations to raise their
views and concerns at the UN and to create awareness on the needs of local
government regarding the international development agenda. Additional effort
were made for advocating the importance of local governments in global
processes by means contribution to research papers, advocacy and learning
activities as well as participation in several events. 

Furthermore, the relevant actors involved in the previous process
expressed the need to be equipped with strategies, mechanisms and capabilities
to translate the key outputs of the process into substantial development plans.
Therefore, the three partners capitalize on the alliance, results and platforms
matured during the Dialogues on Localizing the Post-2015 Agenda in order to
elaborate and develop a strategy composed by principles, tools, mechanisms and
processes for localizing the SDGs. 

The second phase of this project will focus on this localizing
strategy that will provide support by setting advocacy arguments, enabling
environment and concrete mechanisms to address common global development
challenges related to SDGs implementation at the local level. It will focus on
main conceptual areas (multilevel governance, local strategic planning,
monitoring), that constitute the base for the local implementation of the SDGs.







The
project will target primarily policy-makers at local and regional level who
will be the end-beneficiaries of the project, as well as local governments
associations. Citizens and urbanites will be the indirect beneficiaries of
enhanced capacities (human, financial and institutional) of their local
representatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Capital Development Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-23" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban Legislation, Land and Governance</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joe Hooper</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Diana.Lopez Caramazana@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="WW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral, unspecified</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="15140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government administration</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public sector financial management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="14" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="15" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-02-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-02-23">958235</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">727779</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">941536</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 1
Strengthened multi-level and multi-scale policies, institutional and technical frameworks, and tools to place local governments as kingpin of SUD</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 1
Strengthened multi-level and multi-scale policies, institutional and technical frameworks, and tools to place local governments as kingpin of SUD</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national and local governments, promoting and implementing appropriate policy and tools for functional local governance systems.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of national and local governments, promoting and implementing appropriate policy and tools for functional local governance systems.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Weak articulation between different levels of governments Few governance arrangements at the territorial scale Weak metropolitan governance in targeted developing countries" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">__</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 8 countries with reviewed, analysed and improved governance mechanisms">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">__</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 2
Strengthened capacity of local governments for improved transparency and accountable and participatory municipal management and service provision</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 2
Strengthened capacity of local governments for improved transparency and accountable and participatory municipal management and service provision</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partners, including national and local governments, promoting appropriate tools and approaches for transparent urban management</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partners, including national and local governments, promoting appropriate tools and approaches for transparent urban management</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Weak endogenous resources mobilization Perception of high corrupted local governments" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">_</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 20 partners trained and using appropriate tools and approaches for transparent urban management">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 3
Improved local governments&#x2019; capacities for the adaptation to the new opportunities offered by SMART technologies to improve municipal sustainability and management</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 3
Improved local governments&#x2019; capacities for the adaptation to the new opportunities offered by SMART technologies to improve municipal sustainability and management</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partners using SMART Technologies in public management and for enabled governance //Number of partners promoting renewed approach of informality //Increase in revenue generated from implementing innovative tools</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of partners using SMART Technologies in public management and for enabled governance //Number of partners promoting renewed approach of informality //Increase in revenue generated from implementing innovative tools</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="Few use of ICT potential / Improving practical knowledge on inclusion of innovation of public management" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">_</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="At least 4 partners using new developed innovative tools for improving municipal managment//At least 40 partners promote renewed approach of innovation of public management, proving better opportunities for active citizenship.//Increase in revenues (at least 10%) in 4 of selected local governments as a minimum">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 4
Enhanced recognition of the role of local and regional governments in the implementation of the 2030 International Development Agenda and processes related to the New Urban Agenda to ensure the local dimension of development is taken into consideration internationally.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project EA 4
Enhanced recognition of the role of local and regional governments in the implementation of the 2030 International Development Agenda and processes related to the New Urban Agenda to ensure the local dimension of development is taken into consideration internationally.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Perception of local governments of an effective, democratic and legitimate partner in the implementation of international development strategies and programs.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Perception of local governments of an effective, democratic and legitimate partner in the implementation of international development strategies and programs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="progressive visibility of local governments in the international agendas." year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">_</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-02-23"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20 targets that have local governments as direct implementers">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
