<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>41120-3029</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="41120" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-Habitat</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational Skills Training For Economic Growth In Urban Areas In South Central Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project supports
both the revitalization of critical economic infrastructure and the development
of human capital vis-a-vis quality technical and vocational training necessary
to support stability and economic development. This will be achieved by i)
rehabilitation of key economic infrastructure (communication, transportation,
and distribution networks, financial institutions and markets, and energy
supply systems) ii) women&apos;s empowerment and food security through improving
productive capacities iii) strengthening the institutional capacity of Somalia&apos;s
vocational training system to deliver up-to-date training courses relevant to
the requirements of modern enterprises operating in the country. 

Project Development Goal:

Improve economic growth and
employment opportunities in Somalia



Project Outcome:

Strengthened economic and civic infrastructure and technical
and vocational education training



Project
Objectives:

1.
Strengthen quality of, and access to, vocational
training   improve workforce skills and productivity focusing on critical
urban infrastructure (transportation, light manufacturing, construction sector/
construction related industries) as well as in upcoming sectors of the urban
economy;

2.
Improve livelihoods and food security for urban women
in the (renewable) energy and handicraft sectors;

3.
Create short and long term jobs through the
revitalization of key economic infrastructure such as communication,
transportation, distribution networks, financial institutions, energy supply
systems, and/or markets through physical rehabilitation, capacity building and
on the job skills training.


 
  
  No
  
  
  Expected Accomplishment
  
  
  Outputs
  
 
 
  
  Component 1 &#x2013; Quality
  vocational training delivery   productive workforce
  
 
 
  
  1.
  
  
  
  
  2.
  
  
  Strengthened capacity and
  quality of vocational training delivery. 
  
  Skill level and
  productivity of work force improved
  
  
  Improved learning environment of 1 public training provider.300
       underemployed and under skilled youth trained in marketable skills through both
       institutional learning and practical skills training related to the
       construction sector.150
       successful trainees linked to employment and income generation
       opportunities through
       technical toolkits and engagement of local employment networks.
  
 
 
  
  
  
 
 
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
 
 
  
  Component 2 &#x2013; Livelihood
  opportunities and food security for urban women
  
 
 
  
  3. 
  
  
  Livelihoods of urban women improved.
  
  
  Improved income generation of 150 local female entrepreneurs in
       4 women&apos;s groups through 
  -
  Technical
  skills training (charcoal briquette production)
  -
  Health and
  hygiene
  -
  Marketing
  (labeling, branding, market access)
  150 long-term employment opportunities for
       vulnerable women4,000 work days in temporary employment for
       vulnerable women
  
 
 
  
  Component 3 - Revitalization of urban economic
  infrastructure 
  
 
 
  
  4. 
  
  
  Economic growth and job
  creation.
  
  
  Improved infrastructural and managerial
       capacity of 1 critical economic infrastructure, such as meat
         vegetable market, fish market, slaughterhouse, etc. (location to
       be identified)Improved access to markets and/or
       services for at least 10,000 peopleShort term employment (4,000 work days) related to economic infrastructure rehabilitation and creation of
       economic/trade space mainly in the construction sectorLong term
       sustainable employment (100 permanent jobs) related to the rehabilitated/ newly constructed economic
       infrastructure facilities
  
 






Component 1) Quality vocational training delivery   productive workforce



Vocational training activities will be decided upon following an
assessment of needs and market demands in the construction sector. Such an
assessment will consider existing training courses as well as best practices
and lessons learnt through previous partner projects in the sector. Specific
training courses and training spaces will be developed based upon this
information. 



Training workshops will be established &#x2013; including relevant construction
and/or rehabilitation works &#x2013; in a pre-existing One Stop Youth Centre in
Mogadishu, developed through a UN Joint Programme under the leadership of
UN-Habitat. Inclusion of project training activities in this One Stop Centre
enables closer coordination of activities in the sector as well as the sharing
of resources and development of networking ties for project beneficiaries.





Component 2) Livelihood opportunities for urban women



Charcoal briquette production units will be established and run by four
women&apos;s groups in Mogadishu and Kismayo. Charcoal briquettes are a low-tech,
low cost fuel that can easily be produced. Briquettes are a more efficient fuel
compared to charcoal and firewood and reduce negative health implications on
the user as compared to these fuels. Technology needed for the establishment of
fully functioning briquette production groups is limited. All relevant
materials &#x2013; paper, charcoal dust, water and other organic materials &#x2013; are
available at the local level and are easily accessible in local communities.
Relevant labour (for small scale construction such as drying racks) is also
available at the local level and serves to create networks in the local
community whilst also enabling the impact of the activity to be felt at a wider
level outside of the women&apos;s groups themselves.



Project partners have strong experience in the establishment of briquette
production groups and have existing networks that can be utilized in training
and networking with new women&apos;s groups.





Component 3) Revitalization of urban economic
infrastructure



Rehabilitation works
will be decided based on the most urgent needs of local authorities in South
Central Somalia but will focus on core economic infrastructure that has the
potential to kick-start a chain of economic activities as well as increase
access to services for high numbers of beneficiaries. Local stakeholders will
participate at all levels of the design and implementation process to ensure
that activities are relevant to local needs. Supervisory committees will be
established to ensure that rehabilitation works meet required standards and
that local counterparts are able to receive a level of technical on-the-job
training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="FUNDING">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Italy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned Start Date</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Office for Africa</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Axumite Gebre-Egziabher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+254-20 7623091</telephone>
   <email>Britta.PETERS@un.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN-HABITAT P.O. Box 30030 GPO Nairobi 00100 Kenya</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="8"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa, regional</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </description>
  </location>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urban development and management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="1" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="13" significance="2" vocabulary="RO"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="20"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="CO1" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="CO1"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-01">1109524</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="E"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">695755</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total expenditure to date</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="IF"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-21">1109253</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total income to date</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
