<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10061</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zamcell Zambia Limited II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Zambia - Zamcell II      RegionSub-Saharan Africa   Sector   Project No010061   Projected Board DateFebruary 28, 2000   Company NameZamcell Zambia Ltd.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The projects technical partner and the major shareholder of Zamcell Zambia Ltd. (Zamcell) is Mobile Systems International Cellular Investments Holdings B.V. (MSICIH) (80%), a holding company located in the Netherlands with mobile cellular investments primarily in sub-Saharan Africa. MSICIH is an experienced operator, which owns stakes in mobile phone operations in Zambia, Malawi, Uganda, Egypt and Hong Kong.   The two other shareholders are Mitsui (10%), a Japanese trading house active in the area of telecommunications in Asia and other parts of the world, and the International Finance Corporation (10%).    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The estimated project cost is US$11 million. IFC proposes to provide a US$3.3 million loan and to invest a further US$440,000 in Zamcell&apos;&apos;s share capital.     Location of project and Description of site    	Network coverage and capacity will be expanded in Lusaka, Zambia&apos;&apos;s capital city, as well as in the northern industrial area known as the Copperbelt Region and the southern tourist area centered around Livingston.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project comprises the expansion of Zamcell&apos;&apos;s nationwide digital cellular network. The project would be a follow-on to a previous IFC investment in Zamcell, approved in 1998. Zamcell launched its cellular service in Lusaka, the capital city, and the Copperbelt region, in December 1998 under a 15-year license to operate a nationwide mobile phone network. Since the launch of the network, Zamcell is experiencing much higher demand for its services than originally anticipated. Zamcell is planning to meet this demand by expanding network coverage and increasing capacity.    The huge market demand confirms the urgent need of the Zambian business community for efficient and reliable telephone services. The project would help meet this demand and support the growth of an emerging private African telecom operator.     IFC&apos;&apos;s role would include: (i) providing the company with long-term financing, which is scarce in Zambia; (ii) assisting in mobilizing parallel long-term financing; and (iii) demonstrating continued support for private sector participation in the infrastructure sector.      Environmental Category and Issues    	The proposed transaction is classified a category C project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental and social review procedure. The original project was a category B project and environmental clearance was obtained in June 1998. Operation of the network commenced in December 1998. The company reported its environmental and social compliance in February/March 1999 in conjunction with the IFCs initial equity disbursement, and was found to be in compliance with World Bank Group policies and guidelines at that time. Zamcells first annual environmental monitoring report to IFC is scheduled for early 2000.   Zamcell is also a subsidiary of MSICIH for whom an IFC investment was approved in September 1999 for equity of $10 million. Under the terms of this investment, MSICIH is required to produce an Environmental Management Plan, which should consolidate all elements of the group&apos;&apos;s environmental policy and operational procedures in one central management plan.        Date SPI sent to InfoShop     January 18, 2000      This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIRTEL NETWORKS ZAMBIA PLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10061" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-04-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-06-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="ZM-Zambia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-14.3333300000 28.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Mobile Telephony</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $3.74 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-04-20">3300000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-04-20">440000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-04-20">3300000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIRTEL NETWORKS ZAMBIA PLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-04-20">440000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIRTEL NETWORKS ZAMBIA PLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10061/zamcell-zambia-limited-ii">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
