<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG082</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project  for peace consolidation and  dialogue between young people of Maradi Diocese</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The diocese of Maradi in Niger covers 5  regions (Maradi, Agadez, Tahoua, Diffa and Zinder) with an average population of 8.023.299. It is divided into 07 parishes: 
- Agadez, Tchirozerine  and Arlit parishes in the north sector
-Tahoua, Birni Konni  parishes for the west sector
-Maradi, Zinder and Diffa parishes for the eastern part of the country.
The average distance between parishes  is about 350 km. Islam is the major religion across the country.  Nowadays, we observe  that integrism is rising  among community members, this phenomenon has negative impacts on the population in general and for the survival of church in particular. Even though Niger reflects a good model for cohabitation and religion tolerance,  in 2012 and 2015, the country experienced  interreligious violence that affected Christian minority.  these cause significant loss of property, destruction of infrastructure, school, death and physiological trauma and feeling of insecurity. In addition to that, Muslim youth though being assimilated with violence , this make them to be living with fear of reprisal  and adopt defensive attitudes. On the other hand, Christian youth felt being victims of violence   with loss of properties and destruction of worship places, this make them for living in fear and adopting  attitudes for prevention of the occurrence of this phenomenon.
CADEV Maradi requested support from  CAFOD for funding a project that will enable them to work with the youth from different religious group of  the diocese to foster among them mutual understanding, fraternity and tolerance for better coexistence.  This project contribute in peace building  and interfaith dialogue among the community members in general and the youth in particular  for proper prevention of the occurrence of interreligious conflicts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG082" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Maradi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG082" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG082" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-01">22000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="50512">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-02">22000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="65022">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-02">22000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Maradi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
