<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG093</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENHANCE - Enhancing CADEV&apos;s capacity to respond to emergencies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ENHANCE will support CADEV to effectively prepare and respond to humanitarian crises by:
- Deepening the organisations&#x2019; commitment, vision and understanding of quality humanitarian work so that this is firmly rooted in their values and policies and followed by staff and volunteers throughout the structure.
- Strengthening the core foundation of the organisation so that its systems and procedures are robust, flexible, accountable towards the beneficiaries and widely used by staff in an emergency.
- Promoting a culture of learning and risk taking whereby innovations in humanitarian response and capacity strengthening can flourish.

ENHANCE is funded by Caritas Denmark through the humanitarian innovations funding as part of their FPA with the Danish Ministry of Foreign Affairs. CAFOD signed a memorandum of understanding to enter into a 4 year strategic partnership on 29 January 2018. This partnership underpins the ENHANCE project.

CAFOD supported CADEV with humanitarian capacity development from 2014 to 2016. CADEV developed an Emergency Preparedness and Response plan, a Security Plan and participated in humanitarian leadership training.  However, progress was not made in the areas of humanitarian strategy, MEAL and communications and advocacy strategy. The 2016 evaluation findings highlighted the importance of further accompaniment for achieving change. CAFOD, Caritas Denmark, CRS and Secours Catholique - Caritas France (SCCF) have been exploring opportunities to collaborate on capacity strengthening with CADEV-Niger. A consolidated Capacity Strengthening Plan has been developed and each partner pledges to support a specific field/sector of the plan. In consultation with CADEV, CARITAS Denmark and other CIMOs in Country. CAFOD aims to support CADEV to improve its Humanitarian capacity through four primary themes:
1. Mobilization and Management of Community Volunteers for humanitarian early warning
2. Emergency Preparedness
3. Knowledge Management and Information Sharing
4. Humanitarian Advocacy and Communication</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG093" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG093" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG093" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">26219</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="51165">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-02">26219</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="65707">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-02">26219</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
