<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG078</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting  CADEV Niger to purchase  generator for Saint Augustin Health Center ,  Niamey, Niger</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Located in the Sahel Region of Sub Saharan Africa, Niger is amongst the poorest countries of the world . Amid its preoccupying internal situation (food insecurity crisis, high prevalence of acute malnutrition, rising demographics, poor social services  including health and education).
The health system is facing many challenges such as:- Poor accessibility to health care service  and poor infrastructure and materials
- Insufficient and inadequate referral system for cases with complications from primary health care service (CSI) to the higher level in health system pyramid
- Insufficient qualified Health workers in health facilities, . 
- Frequent disruption (shortage) in stock of essential drugs, medical consumables and supplements that affect the continuity of care services in the health centres, leading to dropouts.
The health system in Niger is guided by  a Health policy known as  Health Development Plan which received  partners supports .   CADEV Niger has been supporting the Government through the creation of health centres  and supporting existing one to deliver quality care to the population. Saint Auguistin Health centre located in Niamey  and serving a population of   15 535 of 6 quarters is among them.  CADEV  Niger requested  CAFOD support  in order  to purchase a generator  for Saint Auguistin Health centre to address untimely electricity cut off which is very frequent. This causes a serious  barrier to the quality  and limitation to care  and comfort of both patients and health centres staffs. It represents a risk for the maintenance of cold chain  which is important for sotage of vaccine and drugs.   The project  will  be provide an impact in providing the accessibility to quality health care service to the population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG078" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG078" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG078" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-05">7950.26</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="50407">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-17">7950.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="64680">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-17">7950.26</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
