<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG119</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Raising public awareness on peaceful elections and participating in election observation in Niger</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niger, like other African countries, experienced repetitive military coups and back-to-back rebellions by ethnic Tuaregs in the northern region of Agadez that undermined the process of accession to true democracy. The democratisation process began in 1992 when several political parties were created and allowed to operate freely on the territory of Niger. This process was interrupted by three repeated military coups d&apos;&#xE9;tat in 1996, 1999 and 2010 with negative consequences on the pace of economic development. 
Since 2011, Niger has returned to democracy with the election of Mr. Mahamadou Issoufou as President of the Republic of Niger. At the end of his first 5-year term in March 2015, new elections were held. He was re-elected for a new and final 5-year term until 2021.
This year, the Nigerien presidential election will be held on 27 December 2020 with a possible second round on 20 February 2021 to elect the president of the Republic of Niger. Legislative elections will be held at the same time as the first round. 
This presidential election coincides with the end of the mandate of the current President of the Republic, His Excellency MAHAMADOU Issoufou who is in his second and last mandate. In order to respect the Constitution and allow democratic alternation, he has decided not to touch the Constitution in order to give himself a third term, leaving his place to his successor, BAZOUM Mohamed.
With the invalidation of the presidential candidacy of the main opponent(Hama AMADOU), the tension around these elections only increases.
This project therefore aims to make the population aware of the need to preserve the gains of democracy, calm and peaceful elections, and a sense of the common good. The project will also train election observers who will actively participate in the observation of the electoral process.
The project is co-funded by Caritas Spain, CRS and CAFOD.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG119" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG119" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG119" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-07">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54584">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-09">10000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="69106">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-09">10000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Niger</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
