<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-NIG088</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve population  access to hygiene and sanitation services in  Tchadoua Commune  Agui&#xE9; Department</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tchadoua commune is located 40 Km from Maradi  city, and 34 km from Aguie, the capital of the Department with an area of about 600 km2.It is limited to the North by the rural municipality of Sherkin Hausa (Mayahi), South by the rural community of Jiratawa and Dan Issa, West by the rural municipality of Sa&#xE9; Saboua, and on the East by the city of Agui&#xE9; commune.
The present project for Hygiene and sanitation will be implemented in Tchadoua city which has a population of about 25 500 inhabitants (source: Tchadoua Hall.) with an area of about 7.5 km2.
The majority of the population in Tchadoua is illiterate and there is poor adherence to good hygiene and sanitation practices as a result of ignorance.  Many habits such as catting animals within household premises, storage of animal feeds are very common  and  the situation is no longer improving as this is not felt as a problem and there was no sensitisations actions conducted  for households  members  to change these behaviours.
Access to potable water is a major concern for the population of Tchadoua; there is a single mini AEP for Tchadoua city and the surrounding villages. This situation poses serious health problems, which predispose to the waterborne diseases, gastrointestinal infections. Data from Health information systems revealed that in 2016 the integrated health Centre (CSI type II) of Tchadoua recorded: 9 854 cases of malaria, 1 468 cases of dysentery, 1 447 cases of digestive  Tchadoua has insufficiency in term of latrines making open defecation more frequent.
CADEV Maradi requested the support of CAFOD to develop a project that will address insalubrity for prevention of illness and improvement of accessibility in potable water.   Awareness raising sessions will be conducted at community level to make community members aware of danger associated of poor hygiene and sanitation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG088" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Maradi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NIG088" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="NIG088" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-02">51958.3133</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="50915">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-27">51958.3133</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="65414">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-27">51958.31</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caritas Developpement Maradi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
