<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CH-FDJP-CHE109668357-300310</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CH-FDJP-CHE109668357" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lemann Foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills for Prosperity Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">English language teachers and public school students from Brazil&apos;s state networks, focusing on socially disadvantaged groups (Afro-Brazilian female teachers and students).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Skills for Prosperity (S4P) programme is implemented with resources from the Department for International Development/Foreign Commonwealth Office&#x2019;s (FCDO) Prosperity Fund, via a consortium led by the Lemann Foundation, with whom the British Council, Associa&#xE7;&#xE3;o Nova Escola and Instituto Re&#xFA;na signed a contract to develop the programme&apos;s activities and receive their respective budget.

The programme encompasses work in five pilot states and aims to help Brazil reach a higher level of prosperity, through the transformation of English language learning and teaching in the country.

Through the programme, the consortium addresses policies and standards for the teaching of English at the national level while carrying out more targeted activities, such as the development of didactic material and teacher training for the last years of Elementary School (6th to 9th grade), High School, Technical and Vocational Education (1st to 3rd grade) and Higher Education (teacher training only).  

The programme&#x2019;s activities are divided into 4 outputs: Policy and regulatory reform (Output 1), Design and delivery of ELT curriculum reform (Output 2), Teacher training (Output 3), and a cross-cutting Equity output (Output 4). 

While the British Council, Associa&#xE7;&#xE3;o Nova Escola and Instituto Re&#xFA;na are responsible for implementing programme&#x2019;s activities, the Lemann Foundation looks after the overall programme management, guaranteeing strategic alignment and ensuring its success. It is the main point of contact with the FCDO&#x2019;s In-country Programme Leader, and is responsible for: Overview, support and assess the Programme&#x2019;s monitoring &amp; evaluation; Coordinate and consolidate the work of the other members of the consortium; Ensure coherence between the work of the different organisations in the consortium; Financial management and distribution among the delivery partners; Recruit and manage experts and consultants to assist in cross cutting deliveries; Communicate and report on Programme development to HMG; Support and collaborate to the activities of the other organisations (e.g. advocacy activities); Assess and manage the Programme&#x2019;s risk; Map and monitor Secondary Benefits opportunities; Validate and support the Programme&#x2019;s institutional communication activities; Organise and plan Tactical and Strategic Committees.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme aims to effectively transform English Language Teaching (ELT) in Brazil through the development of national reference documents, school materials, and teacher training, while aiming to empower and produce transformative change in the lives of disadvantaged groups, with a strong focus on gender and social inclusion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="300310" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Associa&#xE7;&#xE3;o Nova Escola</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="A05853" ref="GB-CHC-209131" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instituto Re&#xFA;na</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="300310" ref="CH-FDJP-CHE109668357" role="3" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lemann Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lemann Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Educational Policies</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>551138979670</telephone>
   <email>luizamaniero@fundacaolemann.org.br</email>
   <website>https://fundacaolemann.org.br/en</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lemann Foundation 
Nobel &amp; Hug Rechtsanw&#xE4;lte, Dufourstrasse 29, CH-8032
Zurich
CHE</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Macap&#xE1; (Amap&#xE1;), Recife (Pernambuco), Campo Grande (Mato Grosso do Sul), S&#xE3;o Paulo (S&#xE3;o Paulo), and Curitiba (Paran&#xE1;)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="63" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="37" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-01">472340</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">2697439</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">2747322</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2022-04-01">2054740</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
