<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34106722-MOZ</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Partnership for Mozambique: a conducive environment for effective policy influencing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - Political parties and their representatives - The Assemblee Nationale and its Members, Committees and staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">System level: A level playing field, for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics. System level: Formulation of, proposing to, and approval of jointly formulated policies in parliament securing civil and political rights. Actor level: Improved capability to attract and relate to political actors. Culture level: Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors. Gender and inclusion: The voice and positioning of female politicians in political debates is improved.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership between NIMD, AWEPA and the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to contribute to a conducive environment in which political and civic actors can effectively lobby and influence political and policy processes to advocate for inclusive and equitable social change. The partners concentrate on a selected number of countries in Africa: Benin, Ethiopia, Kenya, Mali, Mozambique, Uganda and Zimbabwe. In Mozambique, the partners jointly contribute to four specific goals: i. To improve the enabling environment for effective policy influencing, by creating a level playing field for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics. ii. To strengthen the policy influencing capacities and responsiveness of political parties, parliaments, MPs and civil society actors. iii. Increasing general interest in consulting and collaborating among and between political and civic actors. iv. Strengthening the voice and position of women and youth in the consultation processes. The departing point for the Strategic Partnership in Mozambique is a joint NIMD-AWEPA Theory of Change and Baseline. The country programme is embedded in strong local political networks, underpinned by a deep rooted knowledge of the local political economy and a solid institutional infrastructure for programme implementation. To acknowledge the importance of cross-border themes and regional interdependencies that increasingly shape national policy agendas and to stimulate peer learning and exchange, dedicated strategies and instruments for peer learning, knowledge and innovation and PME have been developed as part of the strategic partnership. Furthermore, to maximize opportunities for regional and international lobby and advocacy on issues that emanate from national policy agendas, the programme foresees in the development of dedicated strategies for potential upstream policy influencing at regional and global fora and bodies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-MOZ16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership end on 31st of December 2020</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The inception phase of the Strategic Partnership started on 1st of January 2016, with activity implementation planned for April 2016.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 20 524 5678</telephone>
   <email>amsterdam@awepa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.awepa.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prins Hendrikkade 48-G 1012AC Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">325389</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">383280</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="December 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">99183</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">December 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Second quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">41765.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditures second quarter</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">46139</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">January-March 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="October - November 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-30">116232</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">October - November 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Second quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">85285</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second quarter 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-31">20408</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Third quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">114500</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://www.awepa.org/programmes/mozambique-programme/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique programme</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-07-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-MOZ16" type="5"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2: Formulation of, proposing to, and approval of jointly formulated policies in parliament securing civil and political rights.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both political and civic actors recognize the influence of the multiparty and democratic system in Mozambique in enhancing political and civil rates of the Mozambican citizens. There has been investment towards reforming and building new political institution (legislation) aimed at enhancing political pluralism and citizens&#x2019; rights, as well as an inclusive and sustainable economic and political and governance development. Amongst the legislation that has been referred to by civic actors and the opposition party the national Constitution is often mentioned, which strongly emphasizes and secures the rights of political pluralism and diversity, as well as citizen&#x2019;s rights. Additionally, the Constitution&#x2019;s Law of Party (1991), the Law of Freedom of Association (2009), the Right of Access to Information also emphasizes the importance of political pluralism. Despite this legislation and institutions enhancing pluralism and the possibility to work together as political opponents, working together across parties does not happen a lot in Mozambique. Also there seems to be a trend towards less space for civil and political rights in Mozambique.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.1: # and expected impact from legislation passed by Parliament in the previous five years, increasing political tolerance and protection of citizens&#x2019; rights</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The political actors from the opposition parties and civic actors admit that since 1994, the period in which the country moved to a multiparty democratic system, the country has made significant progress. There has been investment towards reforming and building new political institution (legislation) aimed at enhancing political pluralism and citizens&#x2019; rights, as well as an inclusive and sustainable economic, political and governance development. Amongst the legislation that has been referred to by civic actors and opposition parties, the national constitution is often mentioned, which strongly emphasizes and secures the rights of political pluralism and diversity, as well as citizen&#x2019;s rights. Additionally, the constitution&#x2019;s Law of Party (1991), the Law of Freedom of Association (2009), the Right of Access to Information also emphasizes the importance of political pluralism. However political actors from the opposition and civic actors highlight that legislation does not always necessary respond to the national needs. Despite this fact, 47% of civic and political actors in general believe that the enacted legislation does promote political tolerance and protects citizen&#x2019;s rights; while the remaining 53% of political and civic actors (mainly those from the opposition parties, civic actors and academics) believe that the same legislation has limited impact on promoting political tolerance and protecting the citizen&#x2019;s rights for the following reasons: (i) Mozambican laws do not yet fully reflect/serve the interest of the majority and (ii) there is a significant gap between what is written in laws and the implementation . Despite the existing sound legal framework the legislations passed by parliament to increase political tolerance and protection of citizen&#x2019;s rights still need improvement.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 5: Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors (political parties and MPs) and, Civic actors (civil society organizations) recognized each other as relevant actors for the process of policy development and implementation, but not all stakeholders are willing to collaborate. The collaboration between the political parties, as well as that between civil society and political parties is still fragile. More activities need to be undertaken through a collaborative process in order to build trust based on the understanding that inclusive and sustainable socio-political and economic development of Mozambique is based on their ability to work together.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 5.2: % of civic actors that consider members of the governing party as a constructive partner in policy development and implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="100" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civic actors were critical of the ruling party&#x2019;s MPs and government because of some cases in which laws and policy formulation were approved and adopted by the government based on top-down approach without including the input from the civil society. The interviewed civic actors also revealed that their participation in policy making and implementation has deteriorated post-President Chissano. Since then they perceive that the government and national parliament often do not respect the existing mechanisms of policy dialogue among government and civil society. The room given to civil society for contributing in policy making and implementation is increasingly limited; the time usually allocated to them is not enough to provide sound inputs. For instance, the scholars interviewed in this baseline study feel that in significant cases they were consulted for a practical policy making processes but most of their inputs were not integrated into the final product in the form of implemented policy. The civic actors revealed that their relationship with government became challenging after the civil society national agenda shifted from a simple humanitarian developmental focus to interests in economic and governance agendas. With the discovery of natural resources, civil society have significantly increased their demand for good governance, inclusive and sustainable resources development and management policy which would allow the government and state to be transparent and accountable to its citizens.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 5.1 : # of opposition political actors that consider members of the governing party as a constructive partner in policy development and implementation.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The political actors need to build trust in each other. This is particularly complicated when it comes to establishment of working partnership between RENAMO and FRELIMO. The two parties recognize that their political history has had a major effect on developing an effective working relationship. RENAMO members interviewed stated that FRELIMO was not open and interested in promoting democratic policy dialogue within the country, and was not prepared to accept outside FRELIMO policy inputs, especially when it came from the opposition party such as RENAMO. The information collected reveals that despite the lack of trust between the two parties, during the time of President Joaquim Chissano&#x2019;s administration, the political environment was significantly conducive for the opposition parties&#x2019; collaboration with the ruling party/government in many important policy processes. They understand that during that time the two parties were often able to find common ground and interests in order to work together for the benefit of socio-political and economic development of the country. This environment is considered to have deteriorated since the conclusion of President Chissano&#x2019;s term of office, with the political environment for opposition parties to operate freely collaborate on common development policy being considered to have become structurally and systematically limited. The political actors interviewed from RENAMO believe that between the two main political actors in the country an eventual collaboration in policy making and implementation is critical. But eventually collaboration would be possible after the two parties have reached an agreement on the political and military national conflicts causes, such as the decentralization/provincial autonomy process, and the Joaquim Chissano Conference Center conversations (which was stopped after the outbreak of the military attacks by government forces and opposition parties). Contrary to the perception of RENAMO, the perception of political actors from FRELIMO are that the political environment is conducive for the political actors to collaborate in policy making and implementation processes and, Mozambique has the legal-framework to allow the opposition parties to operate freely since the political actions are based on the national constitution. The FRELIMO political actors also said that they are always open to receive new policy ideas and inputs from all national political and developmental stakeholders. However, they highlighted that the problem is the opposition parties who are not prepared and also do not have the capacity to actively participate in national politics using democratic means. The MDM on the other hand indicated that their relationship with FRELIMO is not healthy. Further their relations with FRELIMO are often complicated, especially at local, provincial, district and municipality levels were the MDM is in power, such as Nampula, Quelimane and Beira. In terms of working relationship between MDM and RENAMO, the MDM members interviewed revealed that their relationship with RENAMO is at lower level but does not necessary have a great impact on political activities of the both parties. Although political parties recognize the gains of collaboration in Mozambique, not all political actors see each other&#x2019;s as partners in the process on development and implementation of legislation. Data revealed political actors from the opposition do not perceive the ruling political party and MPs as their partners (67% RENAMO, 33% MDM). Only FRELIMO (100%) consider other parties and MPs as partners. Political actors (mainly MPs) and civic actors see each other as important partners in the process of policy making and implementation, with 100% of both actors seeing each other as partners in process of policy making and implementation to enhancing an inclusive and sustainable socio-political and economic national development. There has been some successful policy collaboration and partnership between civic political actors. The civic actors were able to strongly influence the processes. Some laws that have been passed in the parliament and enacted by the executive which were proposed by civil society, for Instance, the Law against Domestic Violence (2009) and the new Family Law (2004) were both suggested by the civil society.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: A level playing field, for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors (political parties and members of parliamentary) in Mozambique have a tradition of working individually. Trust between political actors that would ensure an environment where they are able to work collectively and promote policy dialogue and implementation in the interest of the country remains weak. Civic actors interviewed believe that the political environment for their participation is very limited and that there is an increasing level of political intolerance and intimidation of actors with opposing views to government and the ruling party.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.1: % of political actors that experience an enabling environment in which they are involved in inclusive policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="40" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both FRELIMO and RENAMO acknowledge that the working environment between them has deteriorated over the years, more so since the last presidential and legislative elections. In order to restore the positive working relationship between RENAMO and FRELIMO there are many important aspects that would need to be addressed first at a high political level by the two main parties and government. These aspects include the causes of political and military conflicts (such as decentralization/provincial autonomy) and reaching a security and peace agreement on the Joaquim Chissano Conference Center conversations. The MDM also indicated that its relationship with both RENAMO and FRELIMO is challenging. Further the relation with the ruling party has often been complicated, especially at local, provincial, district and municipality levels. Interviews revealed that there is also a lack of trust among the opposition parties (MDM and RENAMO), which have only been able to reach consensus in parliament on few occasions, including the 2012 vote against a government/ruling party law proposal regarding the Public Probity Law.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.2: % civic actors that experience an enabling environment in which they can influence or are involved in policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The collected information reveals that the government of Mozambique recognizes civic actors as key partners in the process of building inclusive and sustainable political and socio-economic development and this is reflected in the national constitution. Furthermore, they recognize that civic actors&#x2019; have the right to participate in democratic policy dialogue with government. However, in spite of an existing national comprehensives legal-framework and formal mechanisms to promote civic actors&#x2019; participation in the policy making and implementation process, the level of trust and collaboration has deteriorated significantly in the past years. The civic actor understanding is that the political environment for their participation is very limited and that there is an increasing level of political intolerance and intimidation of different actors who think differently to government or the ruling party. Civic actors and academics feel that they are consulted in order to legitimize the process. However the government does not always take their input into a consideration within the policy making process. Additionally, the civic actors believe that the government is not focused on communicating and promoting a dialogue about key aspects of the national development policy. Some of the individuals who were interviewed revealed that the reason for this deteriorating relationship is mainly because of the current economic and political governance challenges that are ongoing in the country, specifically the prolonged armed conflict between RENAMO and government military-forces. Other aspects on which civic actors and academics believe that government has become less tolerant in the last few years include the contention regarding the possible decentralization of government, the attempt at prohibiting civic protests related to social discontent such as socio-economic grievances and the exclusion of citizens within a democratic process, and the increasing cases of kidnappings and alleged assassinations of Professor Gilles Cistac, Persecutor Marcelo Vilankulo and scholar and TV political commentator, Prof. Jaime Macuane). This data reveals that despite the achievements of the recognition of civic actors in the political process within the national constitution, the level of political engagement and collaboration between government and civil actors, is still low.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3: Improved capability of political actors to attract and relate</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The capacity of political actors to connect with their bases (such as women and youth league party representatives), is still challenging, despite all parties having women and youth leagues. There is no political document, such as a manifest, election program, position paper or policy proposal approved or adopted by political parties based specifically on the inputs from a defined support base.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.1: # of types of collaborations between MPs and political actors or civil society stakeholders that are perceived as being active</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The political actors that were interviewed identified three mechanisms of collaboration between them, namely: (i) Sharing of information, (ii) Consulted meetings and (iii) joint activities. The civil society organizations that were interviewed identified five mechanisms of collaboration among them and with political actors, namely: (i) Development of laws; (ii) Participation in debates, (iii) Participation in consultation sessions, (iv) Provision of capacity to some parties and through (v) Providing inputs to the electoral manifest for some politic parties. All of the respondents (politics actors, MPs and civil society stakeholders) stated that they collaborate with each other. These actors have a similar perception about the level of collaboration between each other, for instance 70% of political actors view their collaboration with civic actors as being active and 30% of them as being partially active. Likewise, 71% of civil stakeholder&#x2019;s have an active collaboration with political actors, while 29% think that their collaboration is partially active. Although evidence from the field indicate there is active collaboration between civic and political actors, this collaboration does vary between actors. In the current legislative term, most MP&#x2019;s from RENAMO and MDM indicate that they consult civic actors mainly on imminent legislative debates, meaning that frequency of this collaboration varies from occasion to occasion. While there are peak periods such as during the electoral season, when law proposals are under discussion, both political and civic actors tend to collaborate more intensively. However, there are times when collaboration is required but challenges arise which prohibit effective collaboration. Most representatives from the opposition political parties and civil society pointed out several challenges that limit their collaboration with the government. These challenges were traced back to 1994. The main challenge identified includes the claim that the process of peace building, democratization and decentralization was imperfect which mainly benefited the ruling party and excluded other key political actors such as RENAMO. The representatives interviewed believe that this is the reason for the current socio-political and economic inequalities as well as military conflicts in Mozambique. Furthermore, despite the progress made in some areas, limited political space for government, political and civil actors to work together has been established in the country. The Mozambican state and government has not yet consolidated an adequate system of checks and balances in governance processes; within the decentralization process of power and institutions this has also not been completed yet. Participants also regard the judiciary system as not being totally independent from government interests. Furthermore, the lack of a culture of sharing information and the lack of skills of most political and civil actors was considered to be a key barrier to greater engagement between various stakeholders. Although Political actors stated that they have a close collaboration with civic actors, civic actors claim that such collaboration is conditional on the interest coming from the political parties. Whereas collaboration tends to be more difficult when it is requested by civil actors. Civil society organizations indicated that they faced challenges of having their plans or request for information accepted by political parties which shows lack of trust, even though their request may be accepted at a later stage. They also stated that they often used informal channels to access information from political actors. Thus one conclusion that could be made is that civil society organizations may be serving the interests of specific political parties. Despite the above mentioned challenges, civil society organizations have collaborated with political actors in the development of many laws such as the law against domestic violence (2009); Family law (2004); revision of the criminal code (2014) as well as participating in debates, consultation sessions, collaboration through capacity building of party members and have also given inputs to the electoral manifesto of some politic parties. On the basis of the information that was collected, it is concluded that the collaboration between the political parties, as well as that between civil society and political parties, still needs improvement. Further, more space for formal dialogue and for the increased inclusion of civil society stakeholders needs to be established or used effectively in order to allow for better collaboration in the process of policy development and implementation.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 4: Improved capacity of local partners.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the measurement of the capacity of the AWEPA Mozambique office via the organizational 5c assessment, a methodology originally developed by ECDPM, but adjusted by AWEPA for its purposes. It measures five different organizational capabilities. Through the SP, AWEPA will continue to invest in the capacity of this new organization.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 4.1: AWEPA Mozambique office score on 5-Capabilities Scan</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="3.8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commit and act: 3.5 Deliver results: 3.9 Adapt and self-renew: 3.2 Attract and relate to external stakeholders: 4.4 Balance coherence and diversity: 3.8</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 6: Political actors advocating for gender equality and inclusion are part of political consultation processes.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women are fairly well represented in Mozambican parliament. 36% of the 250 total MPs of the National Assemblies in the current legislature are women; the National Assembly itself is led by a woman; two of the three parliamentary benches are also headed by women and the National Assembly has women parliamentary cabinet. Nevertheless, women&#x2019;s participation in politics is still not effective. Women MPs have not yet led any policy initiatives in parliament.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 6.1 : # of legislative and policy initiatives coming from Women MPs</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique has been exemplary in terms of improving the inclusion of women in key executive positions and more particularly in the National Assembly. In 2014, Mozambique was located at 14th place in the world ranking of women representation in parliament, with 39.2% of parliamentarians being women (from 250 parliamentarians, 98 are women). The information collected during the interviews with female Members of Parliament (MP) shows that there is no policy initiative or laws that were led by women MPS in Mozambique. Policy and law initiatives that are submitted in the National Assembly usually come from the executive, parliamentary benches, parliamentary commissions, and sometime also from the civil society. This is despite the fact that: (I) 36% of the 250 total MPs of the National Assemblies in the current legislature are women; (ii) the National Assembly itself is led by a woman; (iii) two of the three parliamentary benches are also headed by women; (iv) the National Assembly has women parliamentary cabinet. The fact that women MPs have not yet led policy initiatives although they are fairly represented in parliament is related to the fact that they are attached to political parties in which a strong patriarchal culture still exists. This leads to the rise of two main perceptions. Firstly, women MPs may not feel comfortable to act effectively in the public sphere and lead law and policy initiatives, a task which legitimacy to perform is still granted to men; and secondly, when women in top executive positions sometimes do not exercise their power effectively, the general perception is that they operate under male dominance. These perceptions become the cornerstone for not only numerical enhancement of women&#x2019;s presence but also their ability to transform outcomes, the content and the ways in which policy actors make public policy. Women MPs, members of Women leagues interviewed (MDM) and members of civil society organization working on issues of women&#x2019;s empowerment, political participation and representation agreed that women&#x2019;s participation and representation in decision-making bodies involves their enhanced presence as well as their empowerment through participation. A balance between women&#x2019;s representation at the parliament and their effective participation still needs to be found. Thus, women in politics should develop political agendas and effectively take part in politics through a range of activities such as discussions, debates, lobbying and activism in formal and informal ways.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 7: Capability of the AWEPA Mozambique office to carry out lobby and advocacy.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 7.1: AWEPA Mozambique local office score on the 5-Capabilities scan.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="2.6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AWEPA Mozambique office scores an average of 2.6/5 across the five measured capabilities. The specific scores are as follows: Commit and act: 2.8 Deliver results: 3.6 Adapt and self-renew: 2.2 Attract and relate: 2.6 Balance coherence and diversity: 1.8</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust and relations amongst political actors and other stakeholders involved in the electoral process is improved.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of meetings of the multi- stakeholders electoral dialogue platform.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1meeting of the multi- stakeholders electoral dialogue platform has been conducted since the start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 thematic policy issue has been discussed and brought to parliament since the start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The capacity of MPs to scrutinize and develop legislation is improved.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of amendments proposed by MPs.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 amendment has been proposed by MPs since the start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trust and collaboration between political and civic actors is improved.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of interactions between citizens and politicians during radio programmes with questions and comments.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 interaction between citizens and politicians during radio programmes with questions and comments since start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of platform meeting.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 platform meetings have been organised.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of diversity and inclusivity of actors participating in the policy platform.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of diversity and inclusivity of actors participating in the political sphere.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s participation in policy and decision making processes is promoted.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of male leaders in political parties that are willing to enhance gender equality in party regulations and practices.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Male MPs who promotes gender equality in party regulations and practices.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Male MP expressed desires to promote gender equality since the start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women involved in politics that feel that they are able to take part in decision making process.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
