<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34106722-UGA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Partnership for Uganda: a conducive environment for effective policy influencing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - Political parties and their representatives - The Parliament and its Members, Committees and staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">System level: A level playing field, for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics. System level: Formulation of, proposing to, and approval of jointly formulated policies in parliament securing civil and political rights. Actor level: MPs understand the legislative process and have increased capacity to develop and formulate policy ideas into legislation. Actor level: Political actors that voice and monitor citizen interests. Culture level: Political actors are more aware of and have internalised democratic values, rule of law and gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics. Gender and inclusion: A more conducive environment for inclusive participation of women and youth in leadership and political processes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership between NIMD, AWEPA and the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to contribute to a conducive environment in which political and civic actors can effectively lobby and influence political and policy processes to advocate for inclusive and equitable social change. The partners concentrate on a selected number of countries in Africa: Benin, Ethiopia, Kenya, Mali, Mozambique, Uganda and Zimbabwe. In Uganda, the partners jointly contribute to four specific goals: i. To improve the enabling environment for effective policy influencing, by creating a level playing field for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics. ii. To strengthen the policy influencing capacities and responsiveness of political parties, parliaments, MPs and civil society actors. iii. Increasing general interest in consulting and collaborating among and between political and civic actors. iv. Strengthening the voice and position of women and youth in the consultation processes. The departing point for the Strategic Partnership in Uganda is a joint NIMD-AWEPA Theory of Change and Baseline. The country programme is embedded in strong local political networks, underpinned by a deep rooted knowledge of the local political economy and a solid institutional infrastructure for programme implementation. To acknowledge the importance of cross-border themes and regional interdependencies that increasingly shape national policy agendas and to stimulate peer learning and exchange, dedicated strategies and instruments for peer learning, knowledge and innovation and PME have been developed as part of the strategic partnership. Furthermore, to maximize opportunities for regional and international lobby and advocacy on issues that emanate from national policy agendas, the programme foresees in the development of dedicated strategies for potential upstream policy influencing at regional and global fora and bodies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-UGA16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership end on 31st of December 2020</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The inception phase of the Strategic Partnership started on 1st of January 2016, with activity implementation planned for April 2016.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 20 524 5678</telephone>
   <email>amsterdam@awepa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.awepa.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prins Hendrikkade 48-G 1012AC Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">355078</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">369805</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="December 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">88588</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">December 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Second quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">43782.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditures second quarter</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">39258</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">January - March 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="October - November 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-30">57231</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">October - November 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Second quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">126171</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second quarter 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-31">22990</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Third quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">92580</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-UGA16" type="5"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3: Improved capacity of local implementing partner</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA has a local office in Kampala based in the National Assembly. It is supported by the AWEPA Regional Office that is also based in Kampala. An assessment was carried out in 2016 to measure the capabilities of the implementing office, in line with the 5-C model.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator i3.1: Kampala local implementing office&#x2019;s average score on 5-Capabilities scan</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="3.6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The organisational score on a scale of 5 for each of the Cs was as follows: commit and act 4; deliver results 3; adapt and self-renew 4; attract and relate 2; balance, coherence and diversity 5.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-27"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 4: A more conducive environment for inclusive participation of women and youth in leadership and political processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently in Uganda all political actors, political parties and civil society organizations are sensitive on gender issues. They include youth and women issues in their programs. This is partly because of the power play in the game changing politics where youth and women present a desire for political actors to address social injustices. Political parties show responsiveness to the call for increased representation of women and youth. However, the numbers are still low and structural change is yet to be achieved. For example, out of every 8 representatives of a political party at an event, there is always, on average one female and one youth. At the IPOD Council table, of the 18 members, only 16 percent are women. However, there are some instances where women and youth are disadvantaged for example towards the 2016 elections, nomination fees for parliament were disproportionately increased to the disadvantage of women and youth who are relatively poor compared to other sections of the population. This calls for more efforts to advocate for a more conducive environment to enhance the participation of women and Youth in both political and policy processes.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 4.1: % of political actors that propose concrete policies/actions in their manifesto/public statements to improve democratic values, the rule of law and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="100" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">None of the political actors that we are aware of pushes for exclusive agendas against women and youth. Evidence from practices of 9th Parliament show that parliamentary staff and MPs are exposed to the democratic and gender sensitive norms and practices. MPs tabled private members Bills in support of gender causes. In the some way, Parliamentary staff helped MPs to table amendments favorable to gender legislations tabled by government. Nonetheless, gaps in awareness and capacity exist among the new MPs in 10th Parliament on the dynamism of gender issues. The gaps are obviously explained by the dynamics high turnover in February 2016 elections There are no legal requirements for the gender and equity certificate as the condition for the passage of bills. As such bills passed in Parliament of Uganda do not possess it. Nonetheless there is notable semblance in some bills and determination in others for MPs to make bills gender sensitive. This notion originates mainly from the knowledge and sensitization of MPs and staff on gender issues. The determination part of it especially is an indicator that Parties and MPs have the capacity to design gender equal legislations that is untapped. The best example for this untapped potential is found in the bill tracking of the Public finance management bill 2012. In a bipartisan decision, the committee recommended to Parliament to compel minister of finance to present a certificate of gender equity accompanying the budget framework paper and national budget. They recommended to Parliament to compel ministers to present their budget statements to Parliamentary committees with certificates of gender equity. Parliament adopted the recommendation. Consequently under section 15(g) of Public finance management Act 2015, the minister for finance in consultation with the equal opportunities commission must issue a certificate of gender equity for all budget statements to Parliament. Under the rules of procedure, the committee of equal opportunities is mandated to examine relevant bills and make recommendations and other matters to ensure compliance with relevant constitutional provisions and favorable responsiveness to gender and marginalized groups (9th Parliament rules, 156(2a). The committee can also initiate bills and motions appropriate for the protection, equalization of opportunities and protection of women, youth, workers and the disabled (156(2b). However, during the entire life of the 9th Parliament, the committee did little to perform any of the two functions. It never sponsored any private members bill. Also, it did not scrutinize any of the bills before committees that scrutinized bills or give suggestion on majority bills (especially the legal and Parliamentary affairs committee). The committee seems to have concentrated more on the budget process.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-27"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Formulation of, proposing to, and approval of jointly formulated policies in Parliament, securing civil and political rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 9th Parliament, there was an attempt under IPOD to present a joint position on a number of issues to Parliament. But the efforts made no impact mainly because of inattention by the ruling party.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.1: Number of inclusive policies (securing civil and political rights) jointly formulated and submitted to parliament by the ruling and opposition parties.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPOD presented to the legal and parliamentary affairs committee joint positions on electoral and constitutional amendment bills. It included 43 proposals for political and electoral reforms. There were also some unsuccessful efforts to present joint position to the committee of defense and internal affairs on the NGO bill. Outside the informal arrangements of political parties, there was yet another attempt in 9th Parliament by a coalition of MPs and CSOs to sponsor Private Member&#x2019;s Bills. The coalition of MPs was composed of NRM, Opposition and independent MPs. Efforts of this coalition were unsuccessful because NRM MPs silently withdrew from the activity due to pressure from the party. The failure by IPOD to present joint positions to Parliament led the passage of clauses in the bills, especially the NGO bill that are unfavorable to operations of CSOs and unleveled the playing field for political parties. The composition of committees in Parliament follows strict gender sensitive criteria of including a mandatory 1/3 (one third) of women committee members. In 9th Parliament the minimum number of women MPs on every committee was 6/20 (six out of twenty) MPs. 1/3 (One third) of the entire committee leadership of session committees was women. The Speaker rejected any proposals for composition of committees that violated this criterion.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-27"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2: MPs understand the legislative process and have increased capacity to develop and formulate policy ideas into legislation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2001, there has been a high rate of turnover in Parliamentary elections. Above 50% of MPs who are voted in do not understand the legislative process. In February 2016, the turnover was 83 %( the highest in Uganda&#x2019;s legislative history since 1986). The majority of MPs are young in the age cohorts below 40 years and are having their first job in public service as legislators.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.1: Number of Private Members bills and Substantive amendments.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="15" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence from the 9th Parliament shows that the composition of the private members bills to the total number of bills passed was approximately 10%. Approximately 42% of the 15 private members bills tabled were passed. Women sponsored slightly more than one half of the bills and opposition MPs sponsored only one fifth of private members bills. Qualitative analysis of the Private member bill data is consistent with the facts stated in the description above. All motions of seeking leave to table PMBs in 9th Parliament, except one, were moved starting with the 3rd session. One half on these motions was tabled by new MPs. This suggests that new MPs pick the issues involved in the legislative process as Parliament gets in the middle of its term. It is also consistent with what is documented in speeches of authorities at Parliament of several occasions. That, &#x201C;It takes up to two years for new MPs to get conversant with legislative processes and procedures&#x201D;. A further indicator, though not spectacular, is embedded in the fact that none of the 15 Private members bills tabled was transformed in a cabinet bill. Conversely, in the three Parliaments before 9th, which had a turnover below 60, government transformed several private members bills into cabinet bills. This trends points to the fact that long serving and experienced MPs table PMBs on issues that are attractive and of great concerns to Government, that if not attended to can have adverse effects on the conduct of business by the executive. Also, in the 9th Parliament, none of the private Members bills was transformed, instead in two cases Government tried to introduce its own version of bills to counter private bills.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-09-27"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organisational capacity scan AWEPA offices: Uganda</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This tool is used to do a quick scan of the capacities of the AWEPA offices. It is based on the 5C-model, which stands for the 5 core Capabilities: the capability to act and commit, to deliver on development objectives, to adapt and self-renew, to relate to external stakeholders and to achieve coherence.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA Uganda local office score on the 5-Capabilities scan.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AWEPA Uganda local office scores an average of 4.4 over 5 across the five measured capabilities. The specific scores are as follows: Commit and act: 4, Deliver results: 3, Adapt and self-renew: 4, Attract and relate: 3 Balance coherence and diversity: 5</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="4.4" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="4.4"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IO5.1: MPs and Committee staff have increased capacities to analyze and develop legislation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">i2: Level of increased capacity of MPs/Staff to analyze and develop legislation.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- &#x2018;Level of increased capacity&#x2019; &#x2013; is defined by AWEPA&#x2019;s capacity strengthening model and is based on four levels of evidence of capacitation, further explained below and in the AWEPA Activity reporting form. - &#x2018;to analyze and develop legislation&#x2019; &#x2013; this is determined by the intermediate outcome statement and by the capacity building activities&#x2019; objectives.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1st training, date, etc. Training workshop in Policy scrutiny and analysis for staff of Parliament took place from the 29th &#x2013; 30th march 2016. Topic covered. &#x2022; Best practices in policy and Law making. &#x2022; An insight into drafting cabinet memorandum. &#x2022; Basic principles of Regulatory Impact Assessment. 2nd training. Induction training workshop for three Parliamentary committees ie Gender Labor and social development, Equal opportunities and Public service and local Government. These induction trainings took place from the 3rd -4th August 2016 for the committee of Public service, 12th -13th August 2016 for committee on Gender labor and social development as well as 29th -30th July 2016 for committee of equal opportunities.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IO7.1: MPs are exposed to the needs and interests of citizens and special interest groups.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">i3: # of civic actors consulted on policy issues.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- &#x2018;civic actors&#x2019; &#x2013; those actors that are not involved in political decision-making: civil society organizations, women&#x2019;s groups, citizens, etc. - # of actors &#x2013; is defined as each separate (representative of) a civic group or civil society organization - &#x2018;consulted&#x2019; &#x2013; relates to any kind of interaction between MPs and civic actors that has as objective to increase mutual understanding and the sharing of information. - &#x2018;policy issues&#x2019; &#x2013; thematic topics that are subject to public policy and lawmaking.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="300">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">- 2 consultation/outreach missions per year (4), 3 regions per mission, 10 civic actors consulted per region. - 1 consultative meeting per year (4), 6 civic actors per meeting. - 2 informal lobby meetings per year (4), 4 civic actors per meeting.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">MPs from the committees on human rights and Equal opportunities conducted consultative meetings with women, local leaders, youth, People with Disabilities (PWDs) and elderly people in Eastern Uganda region.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IO8.1: MPs have increased capacity to use parliamentary tools to promote gender equality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4#Level of increased capacity of MPs/staff to use parliamentary tools for gender equality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender equality: parliamentary tools:</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A scale of 1-4 ranging from exposure to change in practices has been used.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Knowledge and skills on using parliamentary tools for gender equality have increased. The committee of parliament on Equal opportunities was facilitated to conduct consultative meeting with women and other marginalized groups in selected districts of Eastern Uganda (Soroti, Tororo and Mbale). The committee collected views and aspirations of women and other marginalized groups that would inform sector budget appropriation to ensure their needs are taken into consideration.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IO3.1: Joint policy reform agenda developed.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1# of issues discussed and brought to parliament .</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">PWD Bill 2015 : AWEPA contributed to the process of the People with Disabilities bill 2015 by funding the committee of equal opportunities to carry out consultative meetings with the People with disabilities, Civil society organizations and other special interest groups like Women, Youth and workers. MPs were able to get information to use in developing PWDs bill 2015 through interacting with the stake holders in eastern Uganda. The Child amendment act 2016: When the act was passed in early 2016, the issue of the budget for the National children authority established by the act was differed to 2017/2018 financial year. This issue was highlighted in AWEPA sponsored induction of the Gender and social affairs committee. Members of the committee tabled this matter in committee deliberations with Gender ministry official on the budget plans of the said financial year in February 2017. Support for private members bills: The minimum wage bill 2015. Still in AWEPA sponsored committee inductions the committee members leant about the stalled process of Minimum wage bill in 9th Parliament and government&#x2019;s discomfort about it . Because the bill protects workers rights, the Gender committee discussed plans of re-tabling it and pass it into law in 10th Parliament -Capacity to scrutinize legislations: When passed into law, the bill will domesticate the 2nd Optional protocol to the international covenant on civil and political rights that seek to abolish the death penalty, which Uganda is party. Furthermore, it will give effect to the commitments made by government of Uganda to the United Nations following the first universal periodic review of Uganda&#x2019;s human rights record.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusion of marginalized groups (PWD Bill 2015) - Gender mainstreaming of Bills (gender equity certificate) - Implementation of Human Rights charters - Space for Civil society -Sponsorship/ support for private members bills</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 issues have been discussed and brought to parliament since the start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
