<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34106722-ZBW</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Partnership for Zimbabwe: a conducive environment for effective policy influencing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - Political parties and their representatives - The Assemblee Nationale and its Members, Committees and staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">System level: Enhanced credibility and acceptability of the NPRC in promoting healing and peacebuilding in Zimbabwe. Actor level: MPs and parliamentary staff understand the legislative process and have increased capacity to develop and formulate policy ideas into legislation. Gender and inclusion: Enhanced participation of women in parliament and in internal parties&#x2019; democratic decision making.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership between NIMD, AWEPA and the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to contribute to a conducive environment in which political and civic actors can effectively lobby and influence political and policy processes to advocate for inclusive and equitable social change. The partners concentrate on a selected number of countries in Africa: Benin, Ethiopia, Kenya, Mali, Mozambique, Uganda and Zimbabwe. In Zimbabwe, AWEPA and NIMD are partnering with the Zimbabwe Institute, an independent local political think tank. The partners jointly contribute to four specific goals in Zimbabwe: i. To improve the enabling environment for effective policy influencing, by creating a level playing field for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics. ii. To strengthen the policy influencing capacities and responsiveness of political parties, parliaments, MPs and civil society actors. iii. Increasing general interest in consulting and collaborating among and between political and civic actors. iv. Strengthening the voice and position of women and youth in the consultation processes. The departing point for the Strategic Partnership in Zimbabwe is a joint NIMD-AWEPA Theory of Change and Baseline. The country programme is embedded in strong local political networks, underpinned by a deep rooted knowledge of the local political economy and a solid institutional infrastructure for programme implementation. To acknowledge the importance of cross-border themes and regional interdependencies that increasingly shape national policy agendas and to stimulate peer learning and exchange, dedicated strategies and instruments for peer learning, knowledge and innovation and PME have been developed as part of the strategic partnership. Furthermore, to maximize opportunities for regional and international lobby and advocacy on issues that emanate from national policy agendas, the programme foresees in the development of dedicated strategies for potential upstream policy influencing at regional and global fora and bodies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-ZIM16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership end on 31st of December 2020</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The inception phase of the Strategic Partnership started on 1st of January 2016, with activity implementation planned for April 2016.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 20 524 5678</telephone>
   <email>amsterdam@awepa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.awepa.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prins Hendrikkade 48-G 1012AC Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">219900</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">266299</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="First installment">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-27">70000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">First disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-ZBW" ref="NL-KVK-34106722">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-24">70000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contractual commitment with the Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-ZBW" ref="NL-KVK-34106722">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-31">35000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contractual commitment with the Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-ZBW" ref="NL-KVK-34106722">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">11334</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contractual commitment with the Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-ZBW" ref="NL-KVK-34106722">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="December 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">-5467</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">December 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Second quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">43155</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditures</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">24208</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">January - March 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="October - November 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-30">44007</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">October - November 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Second Installment">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-31">34900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second Installment</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Second quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">29082</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second quarter 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Third quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">9323</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://www.awepa.org/news/20400/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Benin programme</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-12-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-ZIM16" type="5"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2: MPs and parliamentary staff understand the legislative process and have increased capacity to develop and formulate policy ideas into legislation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All three political parties represented in parliament were represented in the study and the majority indicated their parties do not provide training on the role of parliament. It therefore happens frequently that individuals are elected without full knowledge of the role of parliament and their roles as MPs. Once elected MPs and committee clerks(not elected) have some knowledge of the roles of parliament and parliamentary committees due to training provided by parliament; however this training is extremely brief and focuses on introductory 1 day awareness raising); etc. However, there are low levels of appreciation of the representative role of parliament which is an important aspect of formulating relevant policy ideas.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.4: Afrobarometer score on &#x201C;Trust parliament/national assembly&#x201D;</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="52" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer carries out regular public opinion surveys. The following question was asked: How much do you trust Parliament? 52% of the respondents answered with &#x201C;Somewhat&#x201D; or &#x201C;A Lot&#x201D;.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.2: Afrobarometer score &#x2018;Performance: MP/National Assembly rep&#x2019;</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="39.1" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative description: Afrobarometer carries out regular public opinion surveys. The following question was asked: Do you approve or disapprove of the way that our Members of Parliament have performed their jobs over the past twelve months? 39.1% of the respondents answered with &#x201C;Approve&#x201D; or &#x201C;Strongly approve&#x201D;.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.3: &quot;Afrobarometer score on &#x201C;MPs listen&#x201D;</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="17.3" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative description: Afrobarometer carries out regular public opinion surveys. The following question was asked: How much of the time do you think Members of Parliament try their best to listen to what people like you have to say? 17.3% of the respondents answered with &#x201C;Often&#x201D; or &#x201C;Always&#x201D;.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.1: # of Private Member Bills/amendments moved and % adopted</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative description: In analysing the Hansard over the last twelve months, there are no recorded Private Member Bills (PMBs) in this period. In corroborating with Veritas, there was also no information listed of PMBs moved in this period. The period was pushed back to January 2015 and there were still no listed PMBs. There were none adopted.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Enhanced credibility and acceptability of the NPRC in promoting healing and peacebuilding in Zimbabwe</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 18 December 2015, the Government of Zimbabwe gazetted the National Peace and Reconciliation Commission (NPRC) Bill which sought to set up the NPRC as per provisions of section 251 to 253 of the Constitution of Zimbabwe. The Portfolio Committee on Justice; Legal and Parliamentary Affairs and Senate Committee on Human Rights conducted public consultations relating to the NPRC Bill. Through the public consultations, strong reservations were raised by the public about the bill. Consequently, the NPRC Bill was withdrawn from parliament in May 2016 to allow for re-consideration and re-drafting of the bill to take into account the adverse report from the Parliamentary Legal Committee and the views from the public consultations. The Commission is therefore currently not operational. The Commission&#x2019;s ability to fully execute its constitutional mandate is therefore currently limited and reconsideration of the bill to align it with constitutional provisions would enhance its credibility in promoting national healing and peacebuilding in Zimbabwe.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.1: # of parliamentary parties that publicly express their support for the NPRC</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative description: From the research undertaken, there was one recorded instance of expression of support for the NPRC by an official party spokesperson or members of parliament in the last twelve months. This was in the form of MP (MDC) for Umzingwane Priscilla Misihairabwi - Mushonga who was reported in online news (ZimbabweSituation.com) reports to have made public statements in support of the NPRC but with negative sentiments regarding the bill and the manner in which it was crafted. The general finding is that parliamentary parties did not make any positive statements on the NPRC.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.2: Parliamentary Legal Committee passes NPRC Bill as constitutional</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">0 = Negative 1 = Positive</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The importance and significance of public consultations in the legislative process was well demonstrated by the withdrawal of the NPRC Bill from parliament on the 10th of May 2016. On 18 December 2015, the National Peace and Reconciliation Commission (NPRC) Bill was gazetted. This bill sought to set up the National Peace and Reconciliation Commission as per the provisions of Sections 251 to Section 253 of the Constitution of Zimbabwe. The Parliamentary Legal Committee (PLC) of the Parliament of Zimbabwe conducted public consultations relating to the NPRC Bill. Through the public consultations, several reservations were raised by members of the public about the bill. The concerns were detailed in the Adverse Report of the Parliamentary Legal Committee on National Peace and Reconciliation Bill [H.B. 13, 2015.]. Among other concerns that were raised was the contravention of sections of the Constitution of Zimbabwe by the provisions of the NPRC Bill. &#x2022; For example, by having the National Peace and Reconciliation Commission report to the Minister for National Peace and Reconciliation, the NPRC Bill(Clause 6(1) (b)), would contravene Section 235 of the Constitution of Zimbabwe which provides for the independence of a commission. &#x2022; The NPRC Bill further sought to limit the functions of the Commission to only producing a report and making recommendations to the Minister which contravenes Section 252(b) of the Constitution which states that the function of the Commission is to &#x201C;develop and implement programmes to promote national healing, unity and cohesion in Zimbabwe and the peaceful resolution of dispute&#x201D;. &#x2022; The Report cites Clause 8 of the NPRC Bill of 2015 as giving the Minister for National Peace and Reconciliation power to issue a &#x201C;Ministerial Certificate&#x201D; that the evidence presented during a hearing is contrary to public or economic interests and that evidence should then be heard in camera. This is problematic because conducting closed hearings would not guarantee that justice was served based on that evidence and therefore impinges on the fundamental rights to administrative justice and right to fair hearing &#x2022; Further detailed concerns raised in the report can be found in the PLC Adverse Report - National Peace and Reconciliation Bill As a result of the feedback, the NPRC Bill was withdrawn from parliament on the 10th of May 2016 to allow for the re-drafting of the bill for alignment with constitutional provisions and mandate of the Commission.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3: Enhanced participation of women in parliament and in internal parties&#x2019; democratic decision making</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">With Amendment No. 20 of the Zimbabwe Constitution of 2013 and the SADC protocol on Gender and Development that took effect on 22 February 2013, efforts have been made towards gender parity in the Parliament of Zimbabwe. The Constitution now provides for 60 proportional representation seats for women in the National Assembly for an effective 10 years from its enactment. Two provisions in the Zimbabwe Constitution encourage the participation of women in the National Assembly and the Senate. Section 120(2)(a) of the Constitution of Zimbabwe provides that Senators be elected on the basis of zebra listing; alternate listing of male and female party candidates in party lists, which are required to be headed by a female candidate. Section 124(1)(b) provides for the 60 proportional representation seats for women in the National Assembly. Women&#x2019;s representation in the National Assembly has increased from 11% in 1990 to 31% in 2013. Zimbabwe currently ranks in the top 5 Southern African countries in women&#x2019;s participation in parliament. The changes in the constitution and the protocol on Gender have had a positive impact on women&#x2019;s participation in internal party processes and efforts to promote women&#x2019;s participation in political leadership. However, only one of the three parties (ZANU PF) has a resolution on parity and levels of participation remain well below the recommended 50% whether or not the internal party policies have rules on this. Internal party policies require updating for compliance and practice.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 3.4: % of women MPs elected in the last elections</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="12" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excluding the 60 seats reserved for women in the National Assembly, the percentage of seats won by women after the 2013 election was 12%, down from 15% prior to 2013. The 60 seat women&#x2019;s quota in the National Assembly brought the women&#x2019;s representation up to 31.48%; with an aggregate representation of women in both the national Assembly and the Senate to 35.1%. The 60 seats women&#x2019;s quota lapses after 2018 as provided for by Section 124(1)(b) of the Constitution.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 3.1: % of women in the national executive council (or equivalent) of political parties represented in parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="25" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">MDC: 30.2% MDC-T: 33.5% ZANU-PF: 16.7% The MDC has the lowest proportion of women to men on its register at about 33% of members being women; while MDC-T and ZANU-PF both stand at over 50% women members on their registers. Having said that, ZANU-PF scores lowest on the percentage of women in decision making positions within its ranks. Despite the one-in-three quota that is meant to apply to all its organs, ZANU-PF has not achieved this across all structures: an all-male Presidium and Central Committee membership of just over 16% being women, has the party falling short of its own policy. However, at its National People&#x2019;s Conference in December 2015, the party adopted a resolution to ensure 50% of all leadership positions in the party&#x2019;s organs are held by women. While women make up the majority of its members, MDC-T has a one-in-three women&#x2019;s quota in its structures. Women in leadership in MDC-T make just over 30%: 33.3% in the Standing Committee, 30% in the National Executive and 33.5% in the highest decision making body of the party &#x2013; the National Council.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 3.2: % of women in senior national leadership positions of political parties represented in parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="26" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Parliament Principal Officers: 40% 5 2 Speaker&#x2019;s Panel: 40% 5 2 Cabinet: 24% 66 16 Qualitative description: Participation in administrative functions of parliament In addition to membership of parliamentary committees, two women Members of Parliament hold positions as principal officers in the Parliament of Zimbabwe. Hon. Edna Madzongwe is the President of Senate and Hon. Mable Chinomona is the Deputy Speaker of Parliament and Chairperson of Committees. The speaker of the National Assembly, Deputy President of Senate, and Deputy Chairperson of Committees are men. Of the five Members of Parliament in &#x2018;Principal Officer&#x2019; roles in the Parliament of Zimbabwe, 40% are women. Of the five members of the Speaker&#x2019;s Panel, two are women. The speaker&#x2019;s panel consists of the Speaker of Parliament and the Deputy Speaker of Parliament, and three Members of Parliament. The representation of women in the Speaker&#x2019;s panel is therefore 40%. MDC The MDC has one Member of Parliament in the Standing Rules and Orders Committee and one member in the SADC Parliamentary Forum. The party&#x2019;s chief whip in parliament is a woman, Hon. Jasmine Toffa. MDC-T The presidium of the MDC-T consists of the president and vice president. The president of the MDC-T is a man, Morgan Tsvangirai, and the deputy president is a woman, Thokozani Khupe. The MDC-T&#x2019;s shadow government consists of 16 members. Of the 16 members of the shadow cabinet, 5 are women. Cabinet Following a cabinet shuffle in September 2015, there were a total of 66 ministers in cabinet. Of the 66 ministers, 16 were women. 9 of the women held the post of minister, while 7 were deputy ministers. Women constituted 24.2% of the cabinet.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 3.3: % of women candidates for constituency seats in the last elections</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="49.5" year="2013">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women candidates in the 2013 totalled only 49.5% of the number of constituency seats that were contested in 2013 elections Female candidature in 2013 elections: - # of Contested Seats: 210 - Total # of Candidates: 846 - Total # of male candidates: 742 - Total # of female candidates: 104 - Female candidates as %: 12.3% - Female candidates as a % of number of contested seats: 49.5% Source: Inter-Parliamentary union A relatively low number of 104 women candidates stood for election in the 2013 elections for the National Assembly on First-Past-The-Post (FPTP) basis. On this basis, if every woman had won a seat in the 2013 election, the highest possible representation of women in the National Assembly would have been 49.5%. Achieving gender parity would therefore require that more women candidates are fielded in elections. Only 25 of the 104 women candidates were elected in the 2013 elections, meaning a 24% probability of a being elected.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced credibility and acceptability of the NPRC in promoting healing and peace-building in Zimbabwe.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of MPs on joint committee that have been trained/oriented on NPRC oversight.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Peace and Reconciliation Commission (NPRC) established for a period of ten years as an independent commission to ensure peace-building, post conflict justice, healing and reconciliation among other things.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="42">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2016, 42 MPs have been rained on NPRC oversight role.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of MPs and parliamentary staff trained on public consultation processes.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public consultation: Consulting citizens on certain issues of public interest to inform policy formulation.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 MPs have been trained on public consultation sine the start of the programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MPs and parliamentary staff understand the legislative process and have increased capacity to develop and formulate policy ideas into legislation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of MPs trained/oriented on oversight role.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oversight: Parliament function to oversee government actions and advise on ways and means to improve.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 MPs have been trained of parliament function of government oversight.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced participation of women in parliament and in internal parties&#x2019; democratic decision making.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women trained in Lobby and Advocacy strategy.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="NL-KVK-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="38">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">38 female MPs have been trained in lobby and advocacy since 2016.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
