<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34106722-MAL</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Partnership for Mali: a conducive environment for effective policy influencing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - Political parties and their representatives - The Assemblee Nationale and its Members, Committees and staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">System level: Formulation, proposition et approbation de politiques formul&#xE9;es de maniere conjointe par le Parlement, assurant la promotion des droits civiques et politiques. System level: Une situation &#xE9;quitable entre tous les acteurs politiques et civiques ayant la volont&#xE9; d&apos;influencer les politiques. Actor level: Les d&#xE9;put&#xE9;s comprennent le processus l&#xE9;gislatif et ont des capacit&#xE9;s am&#xE9;lior&#xE9;es pour d&#xE9;velopper et traduire des id&#xE9;es de politiques en l&#xE9;gislation. Actor level: Les acteurs politiques expriment et suivent les int&#xE9;rets des citoyens. Culture level: Int&#xE9;ret pour la consultation, la collaboration, l&apos;harmonisation, le sens de la r&#xE9;sponsabilit&#xE9; et la compr&#xE9;hension mutuelle parmi les acteurs politiques et civiques. Gender and inclusion: Les partis politiques et le Parlement encouragent la participation politiques des femmes et des jeunes, et cette participation est am&#xE9;lior&#xE9;e.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership between NIMD, AWEPA and the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to contribute to a conducive environment in which political and civic actors can effectively lobby and influence political and policy processes to advocate for inclusive and equitable social change. The partners concentrate on a selected number of countries in Africa: Benin, Ethiopia, Kenya, Mali, Mozambique, Uganda and Zimbabwe. In Mali, the partners jointly contribute to four specific goals: i. To improve the enabling environment for effective policy influencing, by creating a level playing field for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics. ii. To strengthen the policy influencing capacities and responsiveness of political parties, parliaments, MPs and civil society actors. iii. Increasing general interest in consulting and collaborating among and between political and civic actors. iv. Strengthening the voice and position of women and youth in the consultation processes. The departing point for the Strategic Partnership in Mali is a joint NIMD-AWEPA Theory of Change and Baseline. The country programme is embedded in strong local political networks, underpinned by a deep rooted knowledge of the local political economy and a solid institutional infrastructure for programme implementation. To acknowledge the importance of cross-border themes and regional interdependencies that increasingly shape national policy agendas and to stimulate peer learning and exchange, dedicated strategies and instruments for peer learning, knowledge and innovation and PME have been developed as part of the strategic partnership. Furthermore, to maximize opportunities for regional and international lobby and advocacy on issues that emanate from national policy agendas, the programme foresees in the development of dedicated strategies for potential upstream policy influencing at regional and global fora and bodies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-MAL16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Partnership end on 31st of December 2020</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The inception phase of the Strategic Partnership started on 1st of January 2016, with activity implementation planned for April 2016.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 20 524 5678</telephone>
   <email>amsterdam@awepa.org</email>
   <website>http://www.awepa.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prins Hendrikkade 48-G 1012AC Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">340506</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">386108</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="December 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">36041</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">December 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Second quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-30">37923</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditures second quarter</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">55695</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">January - March 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="October - November 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-30">58366</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">October - November 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Second quarter 2017">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">99980</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Second quarter 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="First quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-31">25282</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" ref="NL-KVK-34106722"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="Third quarter 2016">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-30">74015</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-MAL16" type="5"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-34106722-STP" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Formulation of, proposals for, and approval of jointly formulated policies in parliament, securing civil and political rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of the dominance of the executive power on Parliament in the Malian political system, the drafting and proposal of public policy occurs exclusively at the governmental level. The political setup of Parliament, where three out of four parliamentary groups support the presidential majority, is not conducive to involvement in this area as the vast majority of laws are passed unanimously, with little or no amendments being made. The parliamentary opposition accounts for less than 10% of MPs, a figure which means they are not in any position to fulfil their role as counterweight within the institution. Joint initiatives combining majority and opposition proposals are non-existent. Furthermore, even if there was actual dialogue between parliamentarians and civil society, the latter does not actually play a part in the drafting and approval of public policy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.2: The quality of civil society consultations carried out by the National Assembly committees</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scale: 1) Low - civil society is not consulted; 2) Medium - civil society is only superficially consulted; 3) High - civil society fully participates in committee work)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society (associations, organisations, unions and other notable plays) is included within the National Assembly general committee contacts and is regularly consulted when discussing certain draft laws during the committee review stage. Nevertheless, the actual consultation takes place during quite an advanced stage of the legislative process, when laws have already been drafted and tabled by the National Assembly. The CSO inputs considered by commissions may therefore only be taken into account via amendments submitted by MPs during plenary sessions. However, the new initiative brought forward by the Law Committee is worthy of note in that in 2016 it organised sessions with CSOs to discuss institutional reform with a view towards initiating a legislative process in this regard which allowed society the chance to actually get involved in the legislative process.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 1.1: The number of draft laws which have been amended as a result of dialogue between the parliamentary majority and the opposition</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently there have been no draft laws submitted to vote which were the result of a harmonisation of the various points of views held by parliamentarian groups and in support of government actions and the opposition. Additionally, no formal dialogue structure between groups within the National Assembly is in place. As part of the CMDID platform two draft laws have been submitted for debate since 2015 between the majority and the opposition: the electoral law and political party charter. The political parties have duly considered the content of the laws and suggested modifications, with the draft law having been submitted to the National Assembly for due amendment and voting on. The CMDID Foundation and AWEPA have succeeded in implementing a monitoring committee made up of MPs and political leaders, whose mandate involves advocating for due consideration of the proposed changes to the platform by MPs.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 2: A level playing field, for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Favourable conditions are in place so all public actors can interact and participate in public policy: Freedom of political expression is not restrictive and is guaranteed by constitutional prerogatives which are actually respected. The free press (radio and newspapers) has room to openly give its opinion on political actors even if some censorship remains in place for national TV, which is under the influence of the ruling powers. The adoption of the law on the status of the opposition would likewise strengthen freedom of political expression. Nevertheless, it is not possible to confirm a level playing field exists between actors nor are their specific ways for them to influence public policy. In the current political situation in Mali, where the executive branch wields tremendous power, the political parties represented in the National Assembly do not have any real influence over their respective parliamentary groups, who themselves are limited in terms of their legislative function. Civil society, which does not have a strong level of organisation, does not maintain structured dialogue with political actors aside from its involvement with the National Assembly committees, such that it is not able to influence policy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.2: Percentage of political actors who enjoy a conducive environment in terms of policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline description: All of the MPs interviewed said they did see the political environment as conducive in terms of being able to produce laws, pointing to the following factors: - The power held by the executive branch versus that held by the legislative branch, with the former controlling what is on the agenda for parliamentary sessions as well as restricting parliamentary legislative initiatives. - The high rates of MP turnover after each legislative election, preventing the continuity needed to work on producing laws. - Problems tied in to the recruitment of parliamentary staff, which is based more on candidates&apos; political affiliations rather than their actual skillset, resulting in staff who are not qualified to support MPs in their legislative mandate. - Practical problems concerning MPs: outside of members of the parliamentary Leadership and committee Chairs, MPs do not have actual physical offices where they can perform legislative tasks, nor do they have support staff, with parliamentary assistants being solely assigned to standing committees. Regarding parties outside of parliament, recent experience shows they have often played the role of catalyst for reform without actually initiating things in this respect owing to the above-mentioned difficulties in terms of proposing laws.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 2.1: The number of structural changes and new mechanisms introduced to engage political and civil society actors.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The prospect of the Algiers Peace Agreements has provided a new mechanism for co-operation between political actors and civil society to have exchanges and suggest proposals to make improvements to regional policies. Political actors and civil society have been highly consulted with respect to changes to the Agreement. Some points of convergence between certain politicians and civil society have been noted, although the actors from the two sides have been engaged separately. Consultations have also taken place between certain parties and CSOs condemning the institutionalisation of interim authorities, although generally speaking these points of convergence have not been the subject of reconciliation. The explanation for all of this would be how fragile co-operation is in the first place as well as the need for each actor to discuss the matter for visibility&apos;s sake rather than actually proving to be an influential factor on decisions.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-18"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3: MPs understand the legislative process and have increased capacity to develop and formulate policy ideas into legislation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the interviews with National Assembly legislative services and parliamentarians, it became apparent that the majority of MPs participating in the Fifth Parliament have limited capacities to understand the legislative process as well as how to develop legislation. In Mali the initiative to prepare laws rests solely with the executive power who, as stated above, also sets the agenda for draft laws to be voted on by the Assembly. MPs therefore play only a very minor role in the legislative processes, as only two private members bills have been passed by the current Parliament. Furthermore, most laws receive a unanimous vote, with no amendments being made. The same problems involving competency also arise with parliamentary administrative staff, who are not sufficiently equipped to assist MPs in their legislative mandate.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 3.2: The Afrobarometer score on &quot;Performance levels for National Assembly members&quot;</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="53.2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer results are based on public opinion polls. Afrobarometer 2014/2015 participants were asked the following question: &quot;Do you approve of how MPs have performed their roles over the past twelve months?&quot; 53.2% of respondents stated they &quot;Approved&quot; or &quot;Strongly approved&quot; their MPs&apos; performance.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 3.1: The number of Private Members&apos; Bills tabled in Parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">There have been two laws enacted which came about at the initiative of members of the Fifth Parliament: - The proposed law amending the Malian Law of 4 November 1996 on the creation of municipalities by Hon. Moussa Biadaga (16 December 2015) - The proposed law amending the Malian Land and Property Code by Hon. Moussa Coulibaly (24 May 2016) It should be noted here that the two private members&#x2019; bills enacted by the current Parliament are texts amending a pre-existing law and cannot be completely considered as new legislation. Although the number of laws enacted by parliamentary initiative have increased compared to previous Parliaments, the obstacles faced by MPs still remain and are various in nature: the parliamentary administrative staff&apos;s inability to support MPs in their legislative work; the fact the MPs themselves are ill-equipped for their position; the fact the government sets the agenda for parliamentary sessions (laws drafted by parliament are not deemed a priority); the fact a law drafted by parliament cannot affect the State budget, which severely limits areas MPs can act in; and the fact the government is &quot;allergic&quot; to laws drafted by parliament and does everything in its power to limit their effect.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 5: Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 5.3: The Afrobarometer score on &quot;Level of public confidence in the National Assembly&#x201D;</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="62.2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer results are based on public opinion polls. Afrobarometer 2014/2015 participants were asked the following question: &quot;Are you confident in the National Assembly?&quot; 62.2% of respondents stated they were &quot;Partially confident&quot; or &quot;Very confident&quot;.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-10-18"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 5.4: The Afrobarometer score on &quot; Public perception on how well MPs listen to the needs of their constituency&#x201D;</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="55.9" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer results are based on public opinion polls. Afrobarometer 2014/2015 participants were asked the following question: &quot;How would you rate how well you think legislative elections guarantee National Assembly MPs will actually advocate for people&apos;s views?&quot; 55.9% of respondents answered &quot;Well&quot; or &quot;Very well&quot;.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 5.1: The level of co-operation between MPs and other political actors (including governmental actors).</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scale: 1) Low - Co-operation in this regard is almost non-existent; 2) Medium - Some co-operation occurs but is only superficial in nature and/or the amount that goes on is not satisfactory; 3) High - The quality of co-operation is excellent and is carried out in a structured way</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDIUM All of the MPs interviewed stated they regularly work together with governmental actors. Contact in this regard occurs as part of their work as parliamentarians, with government members being present during Parliament plenary sessions and frequently summoned by standing committees. The actual frequency with which this happens is down to the parliamentary schedule, with contact on a daily basis occurring when Parliament is in session. Moreover, this contact happens as a result of MPs&apos; personal initiatives, who frequently meet with political actors from the government or from their own political parties. However, actors from political parties have noted that even though they regularly work alongside MPs, the latter do not always toe party line, with priority being given to their own personal interests.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 5.2: The level of co-operation between political actors and members of civil society</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scale: 1) Low - Co-operation in this regard is almost non-existent; 2) Medium - Some co-operation occurs but is only superficial in nature and/or the amount that goes on is not satisfactory; 3) High - The quality of co-operation is excellent and is carried out in a structured way</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDIUM Exchanges between MPs and civil society are frequent and occur mainly within the framework of the standing committees who invite CSOs to hearings for relevant legislation (e.g. the law on the creation of the National Observatory of Cities was subject to intense consultation between the Law Committee and civil society). Contact likewise also occurs via parliamentary thematic networks such as the Women Parliamentarians&apos; Network (REFEP), who frequently consult with CSOs on gender-related matters and activities. Lastly this contact also occurs at the personal initiative of MPs, who are requested by CSOs on a daily basis to advocate for causes against other parliamentarians. Nevertheless, the quality of these interactions is not optimal as they remain quite formal and restrictive (as they are only for specific legal texts). Outside of Parliament co-operation between political and civic actors is difficult and almost non-existent. Relationships are not institutionalised and mutual suspicion and manipulation is common. It should be noted nevertheless that the CMDID has involved civil society organisations in all of its activities starting from 2013 and takes into account civil actors&apos; contributions when considering political matters. This experience is behind the above statement that no sustained, organised co-operation is in place.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 6: Political parties and Parliament encourage young people and women to participate in politics; additionally, participation from these groups has improved.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Parliament initiatives encouraging women to participate in politics occur mainly via the Women Parliamentarians&apos; Network (REFEP), which is quite active and frequently organises field visits, although it does not have the financial resources it needs. They are supported in their activities by technical and financial partners from the National Assembly such as the NDI-NIRAS consortium and United Nations agencies. Institutional initiatives from Parliament are non-existent, particularly as the number of women MPs remains quite low (14 out of 147). The Malian Law on Gender Equality which was passed in 2015 should help contribute to improving women&apos;s participation in politics as part of the National Assembly. The CMDID has been leading initiatives arising from a gender-based strategy prepared in 2008 with the objective of carrying out in-depth work within parties to make their actions and decisions more gender-sensitive on the one hand and, additionally, contributing to the strengthening of women&apos;s leadership abilities so they can compete on equal footing with men. Within the scope of the implementation of this strategy three CMDID Foundation member parties decided via circular notice they would try to get more women into eligible positions during the (now aborted) upcoming council and regional elections.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 6.1: The Afrobarometer score on &#x201C;How women are perceived as leaders&#x201D;.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="57" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afrobarometer results are based on public opinion polls. Afrobarometer 2014/2015 participants were asked to react to the following statements: Statement 1: &quot;Men make better political leaders than women; in elections priority should be given to men over women.&quot; Statement 2: &quot;Women should have the same chance of being elected to political positions as men.&quot; 57% of respondents stated that they &quot;Agreed with statement 2&quot; or &quot;Strongly agreed with statement 2&quot;.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 4: Capability of the AWEPA Mali office to carry out lobby and advocacy</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AWEPA office in Bamako opened early 2016.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome indicator 4.1: AWEPA Mali local office score on the 5-Capabilities scan</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="3.6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The AWEPA Mali office scores an average of 3.6/5 across the five measured capabilities. The specific scores are shown below: Commit and Act 4,5 Deliver Results 3,5 Adapt and Self-Renew 4,5 Attract and Relate 2,5 Coherence and diversity 5,5</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="3.6"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IO6.1: The relations, interactions and mutual understanding between political actors and citizens are improved.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">I6.1.2: # of civic actors consulted on policy issues.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">- &#x2018;civic actors&#x2019; &#x2013; those actors that are not involved in political decision-making: civil society organizations, women&#x2019;s groups, citizens, etc. - &#x2018;consulted&#x2019; &#x2013; relates to any kind of interaction between MPs and civic actors that has as objective to increase mutual understanding and the sharing of information. - &#x2018;policy issues&#x2019; &#x2013; thematic topics that are subject to public policy and lawmaking.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">MPs have interacted with 17 political actors during the first outreach visit.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">i6.1.1: # of new content brought to the parliamentary radio.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of new shows (debates, interviews, interactions with audience, etc.) added to the parliamentary radio&apos;s broadcast planning.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first parliamentary outreach activity has been entirely broadcasted on the parliamentary radio.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">i6.1.3: # of political actors consulted on policy issues through parliamentary consultation.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors: political party representatives, MPs, local elected authorities (mayors, presidents of regional and district councils, etc,)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="38">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the outreach visit in S&#xE9;gou, civic actors representing civil society, traditional and religious authorities, youth and women were 38.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IO2.2: Parliament strengthens its procedures of public consultation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">i2.2.2: # of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of thematic policies discussed with MPs in the framework of activities implemented by AWEPA.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">An exchange workshop between the parliamentary Law committee and civic &amp; political actors on improving the electoral law has been implemented in August 2016.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">i2.2.1: # of initiatives developed by Parliament to improve public consultation.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Initiatives developed by Parliament: activities, decisions, new mechanism, resolutions, taken by the parliamentary leadership, the clerk, committees or parliamentary groups. Public consultation: inform or involve citizens and civil society organisations in the work of the parliament in Bamako or in the distritcs&quot;.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="Nl-kvk-34106722" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">start of the programme</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The outreach initiative &quot; Le parlement chez vous&quot; (Parliament at your doorstep) brings a framework for consultation between MPs and various actors (Local authorities, citizens, NGOs, political partis, community and religious leaders).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
