<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="ES" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>AR-CENOC-16969-A-4000004373-UniqueActivity</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="AR-CENOC-16969-A" secondary-reporter="0" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundaci&#xF3;n Fondo Mujeres del Sur</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading from the South 2021-2025: the power of LAC activisms for new feminist realities (LFS II).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LFS is a feminist resource alliance that supports feminist activism and lobbying efforts by women, girls, and trans led organisations, movements, and networks at the regional, national, and grassroots levels in the Global South. Recognising that women, girls, and trans people are best placed to determine ways in which to address injustice and unequal power relations in their own communities, LFS resources and supports those who lead change and transform societies towards the full achievement of gender equality and human rights in the Global South. In addition to recognising the critical leadership of the South in guiding resources to address the experience of the Global South, it also values the impact of southern feminism in claiming resources on grounds of equality and non-discrimination to ensure women&#x2019;s access to and enjoyment of human rights. In its first phase, LFS was financed through a special grant of  &#x20AC;42 million from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Netherlands over four years. By renewing their financial commitment and increasing it to &#x20AC;80 million over the next five years, the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs has demonstrated its commitment to leadership from the Global South in addressing women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality. This strengthened relationship between the Dutch Government and the LFS Consortium also makes a vital contribution to the reframing of bilateral relationships with Southern-led feminist funders. 
Based on this, LFS is implemented through 3 main strategies: 
1- REGULAR GRANTMAKING (to Southern Women Rights Organisations -SWROs- and  consortia though Latin America en the Caribbean).
2- SPECIAL GRANTMAKING (to Southern Women Rights Organisations -SWROs- and  consortia though Latin America en the Caribbean).
3- LINKING AND LEARNING ACTIVITIES  (directed to Southern Women Rights Organisations -SWROs- and  consortia though Latin America en the Caribbean).

Additionally, SUPPORT tasks are implemented in order to make the implementation of the previous activities possible.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights, feminist and LBTIQ+ people&#x2019;s organisations and movements play crucial civil society roles that drive transformative social change.  Strengthening their power and leadership will contribute to improve preconditions leading to an enabling environment in which their activism can thrive. As such, LFS-LAC strategic programme&#x2019; objective is to strengthen the ability of SWRO, networks and alliances to lead change and transform societies towards the full achievement of gender equality and human rights in LAC.
LFS-LAC programme will pursue an interconnected approach grounded in human rights, gender equality, empowerment, intersectionality and interculturalism. It incorporates interconnected strategies for strengthening L&amp;A capacity and agency among small, medium, and large SWRO, building on momentum garnered in Phase l to further strengthen cross-movement alliances.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="4000004373-UNIQUEACTIVITY" ref="fms" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondo de Mujeres del Sur</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="4000004373-UNIQUEACTIVITY" ref="AR-CENOC-16969-A" role="2" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundaci&#xF3;n Fondo Mujeres del Sur</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004376" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="498" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">2716300</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2021. Regular grantmaking">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-31">73333</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants to regranters women funds in LAC.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004376" ref="AR-CENOC-AR-CENOC-16969-A" type="60"></provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2021. Support tasks">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-31">20906</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Support tasks includes expenditures on general communication issues; Learning, Monitoring and Evaluation (LM&amp;E) activities; bank costs, human resources (salaries), consultancy costs, among other overhead costs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004376" ref="AR-CENOC-AR-CENOC-16969-A" type="60"></provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2021. Incoming Funds">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-01">15000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004373" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="AR-CENOC-AR-CENOC-16969-A-4000004373" ref="AR-CENOC-AR-CENOC-16969-A" type="60"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Outcome 2. Strengthened ability of SWROs, networks and alliances to lead change and transform societies towards the full achievement of gender equality and human rights in LAC.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ES">WRGE indicator 2.2. # of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO
demands and positions on women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership and
representative participation in decision-making processes in public, private
and civic sphere, through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or
movement building (link SCS3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="ES">Methodological notes
Quantitative measurement: CSO&#x2019;s succeeding in creating space for their demands
and position on Women&#x2019;s Leadership and Participation can include the number of
times: L&amp;A targets include CSOs in the decision making process; targets react upon
the positions of the CSOs by adopting their argumentation and terminology; and
L&amp;A targets react upon the positions of CSOs by putting their issues on the agenda.
Disaggregation for this indicator will be at the (inter)national level or subnational
level as presented in below.
Qualitative measurement: Explain how CSOs have played a transformative role in
decision making processes through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or
creating space to engage. From a learning perspective, please also consider
explaining cases where CSOs were unable to play a transformative, and/or where
other actors (not CSOs) were more important for this.
In answering this question it helps to consider&#x2026;
&#x2026;explaining how CSO involvement changes decision making processes and policy
discussions of targeted government, private sector and societal actors
&#x2026;explaining how and what frames introduced by CSOs are taken up by targeted
actors, for instance by the media, in policy documents and in official speeches
&#x2026;explaining how and what CSO issues reach the agenda of targeted government,
private sector and societal actors
Indicator codes &amp; disaggregation
This indicator has two indicator codes: WRG018 is to be used to report on # of times
that CSOs succeed in creating space at subnational level. Creating space on all other
levels can be reported under WRG017.
WRG017 # of times that CSOs (succeed in creating space for CSO demands
and positions on women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership and
representative participation in decision-making processes in public,
private and civic sphere, through agenda setting, influencing the
debate and/or movement building;
WRG018 # of times that CSOs (succeed in creating space for CSO demands
and positions on women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership and
representative participation in decision-making processes in public,
private and civic sphere, through agenda setting, influencing the
debate and/or movement building at subnational level;
Reporting is only required on the indicator codes relevant for your programme.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1 (ultimate): Improved pre-conditions leading to an enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">WRGE 2.1. # of laws, policies and strategies blocked, adopted or improved to promote women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership, and representative participation in decision-making processes in public, private and civic sphere</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="ES">Methodological notes
Quantitative measurement: Number of concrete and significant changes in laws or policies as a result of CSO engagement.
Qualitative measurement: Explain how, as a result of CSO L&amp;A activities, governments, private sector and societal groups change their laws and policies, to support sustainability and (gender)inclusiveness.
In answering this question it helps to consider&#x2026;
&#x2026;describing the content of law, policy, attitude and norm changes
&#x2026;explaining the advocacy process towards changes, reflecting on successful and
unsuccessful strategies
From a learning perspective, please also consider explaining cases where L&amp;A
activities did not result in the desired change, and/or where other actors (not CSOs)
were more important for bringing about change.
Indicator codes &amp; disaggregation
Data for this indicator will be disaggregated by:
- Laws
- Governmental policies
- Private sector company policies
- By-laws
- International agreements
For which the following indicator codes are to be used:
WRG012 # of laws blocked, adopted or improved to promote women&#x2019;s
voice, agency, leadership, and representative participation in
decision-making processes in public, private and civic sphere
WRG013 # of governmental policies &amp; strategies blocked, adopted or
improved to promote women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership, and
representative participation in decision-making processes in
public, private and civic sphere
WRG014 # of private sector company policies blocked, adopted or
improved to promote women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership, and
representative participation in decision-making processes in
public, private and civic sphere;
WRG015 # of by-laws blocked, adopted or improved to promote women&#x2019;s
voice, agency, leadership, and representative participation in
decision-making processes in public, private and civic sphere;
WRG016 # of international agreements blocked, adopted or improved to
promote women&#x2019;s voice, agency, leadership, and representative participation in decision-making processes in public, private and
civic sphere;
Reporting is only required on the indicator codes relevant for your programme.
By-laws are defined as follows:
- a regulation made by a local authority or corporation or
- a regulation made by society to control the actions of its members.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="ES">Outcome 3. Improved sustainability of SWROs, so their agendas, demands and visions are recognised and sustained by society.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="ES">WRGE indicator 5.2.1 # of organizations with strengthened capacity to
advance women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
