<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="ES" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-IATI-359A08-Activity#0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="AR-CENOC-AR-CENOC-16969-A" secondary-reporter="0" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondo Mujeres del Sur</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading form the South- General Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grassroots, intermediate and large southern women&#xB4;s rights organisations (SWROs).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LFS supports women&#x2019;s rights activism and lobbying efforts by women&#x2019;s organisations, movements and networks at the regional, national, and grassroots levels in the Global South. In order to achieve this objective, LFS: 1) Provide funding in the form of innovative and flexible grants to women&#x2019;s organisations and change agents in the Global South. 2) Invest in capacity building through technical and financial resourcing to strengthen capacities of change agents. 3) Promote advocacy by supporting women&#x2019;s movements and networks in the Global South. 4) Help build partnerships across strategic regional and global alliances, and provide critical spaces for South-South learning, and advancing the human rights of women and girls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading from the South (LFS) is a feminist philanthropic fund and alliance conceptualised and managed by four leading women&#x2019;s funds: African Women&#x2019;s Development Fund (AWDF), Fondo de Mujeres del Sur (FMS), International Indigenous Women&#x2019;s Forum (FIMI) / AYNI Fund (AYNI), and Women&#x2019;s Fund Asia (WFA). LFS supports women&#x2019;s rights activism and lobbying efforts by women&#x2019;s organisations, movements and networks at the regional, national, and grassroots levels in the Global South. It is financed through a &#x20AC;40 million (~US$46 million) fund from the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs over four years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-359A08" role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondo Mujeres del Sur</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29481" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="498" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The FMS covers with the LFS 21 Latinamerican countries.</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">1487246</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">1473217</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">1526329</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">1213198</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="[ref=&quot;XM-DAC-7&quot; provider-activity-id=&quot;NL-1-PPR-29481&quot; ]">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-06">1487246</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-1-PPR-29481" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XI-IATI-359A08" type="60"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15170" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="ref=&quot;XM-DAC-7&quot; provider-activity-id=&quot;NL-1-PPR-29481]">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-04-04">1473142</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15170" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="&quot;XM-DAC-7&quot; provider-activity-id=&quot;NL-1-PPR-29481]">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-02-04">1526264</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15170" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="&quot;XM-DAC-7&quot; provider-activity-id=&quot;NL-1-PPR-29481]">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-24">1213123</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="15170" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="30"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Macro level: Improved pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Macro level: Improved pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Positive changes in preconditions for enabling environment&#xA0; for advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <dimension name="Changes in control, Changes in values and norms, Changes in actions, Changes in association, Changes in resource allocations."></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Changes in control: 18 organizations from 12 different countries reported to have worked to foster positive changes in laws, regulations and public policies (adoption, blocking, improvement, etc.) in 2020, with 28 changes being promoted. 

Changes in values and norms:
6 organisations contributing to produce change.
8 changes promoted.

Changes in actions and practices:
13 organisations contributing to produce change.
13 of changes promoted.

Changes in resource allocation:
70% of organisations accessed to new economic resources from their participation on LFS ( 26).

Changes in the mechanisms to make progress in fulfilling the goals of the 2030 Agenda (2030AG):
7 organisations contributing to produce /sending recommendations for National Voluntary Reports.
17 organisations participating in key international events: 17  (3 grantees supported via the LFS Special Programme to Promote Participation in Key Events). # of events in which LFS grantees have participated during 2019: 39 (most of them on virtual basis. 3 participations in key events supported via the LFS Special Programme to Promote Participation in Key Events).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <dimension name="Changes in control, Changes in values and norms, Changes in ac"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Changes in control: 9 organisations reported to be promoting (contributing to) changes in control. Mainly, the results reported focus on the implementation of L&amp;A strategies aiming to modify or promote specific regulations, both in the national and local level. Concerning the main issues approached, the highlighted ones are: abortion decriminalization, political parity, trade agreements and AIDS regulations with gender perspective. Changes in values and norms: 10 organisations reported to be promoting changes in values and norms. In relation to the &#x201C;field&#x201D; in which the reported changes take place, the grantees mention mainly the local community (with specific references to &#x201C;the school&#x201D; and &#x201C;the house&#x201D;) and the organisation itself, understood as a community of ideas, values and practices. Concerning the issues considered, the ones that stand out are: sexual and reproductive rights, sexual harassment, religious fundamentalisms, violence against women in general and patriarchal oppression. It is important to highlight that the organisations do not understand equally what do they mean by &quot;changes in values and norms&quot;&quot;, being important to bear that in mind at the moment of analyzing results. Changes in actions: 12 organisations reported to be promoting changes in actions. The results related to this change are the creation of new and innovative spaces to promote the debate and reflection among women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality, a strengthened participation in the AG2030 monitoring instances, a more precise understanding of the alliances as political platforms for L&amp;A, the incorporation of inclusive and non-sexist language and the promotion of political parity in different spaces, among others. Changes in association: 21 organisations reported to be: 1) Creating new alliances/undertaking joint actions or campaigns; 2) Strenghtening existing alliances (for example, reactivating old alliances). Specifically, the results linked to changes in the ways of relating with other organisations focus, mainly, in the articulation of new alliances within the framework of LFS. It is possible to identify two kind of new alliances: 1) operational alliances among the LFS grantees &#x2013;orientated mostly to the co-execution of specific activities included in the projects-; 2) strategic alliances with local, national or international organisations; articulated with the objective of strengthening the regional women&#xB4;s movement and or improving the conditions for change. The main stakeholders that integrate these new alliances are women&#xB4;s rights organisations and state institutions. For security reasons, the composition of the alliances is not detailed. Changes in resource allocations: 8 organisations report to have access to new financial resources (state and international cooperation resources) form their participation in LFS. In addition, 9 grantees declare to be implementing collaborative actions with other agents that contribute financially. The results reported to these collaborative actions are, in general terms, a better positioning within the donors community, a stronger L&amp;A ability and a greater capacity of action. For security reasons, the names of the grantees that report changes on resource allocation is not detailed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <dimension name="Changes in control, Changes in values and norms, Changes in actions, Changes in association, Changes in resource allocations."></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Changes in control: 16 organizations reported that they have been working during 2018 to promote positive changes in laws, regulations and public policies (adoption, blocking, improvement, etc.). In this regard, 30 changes are being promoted, 22 of which have a national scope of intervention, 7 with a local scope of intervention and only one critical action with a regional level: the one regarding trade liberalization and its rules in the WTO/G20, prompted by Red de G&#xE9;nero y Comercio. Most of the advocacy strategies putted in place focus on changing laws and regulations, being a minority the strategies that aim to advocate on public policies (two exceptions in this regard are the signature of the Letter-Agreement &quot;Prevention with Education&quot; 2016-2020, to prevent child pregnancy, between Asociaci&#xF3;n AMA and the Health Ministry of the Government of Guatemala and the participation of CLADEM in the &quot;Gender Equality YES&quot; movement, with more than 30 organisations, with the aim of defending the incorporation of the gender perspective in public policies). Changes in values and norms: 3 organisations reported to be promoting changes in values and norms. In relation to the &#x201C;field&#x201D; in which the reported changes take place, the grantees mention modifications in values and norms regarding sexual harassment in private companies, changes regarding political partity (which boosts more political participation on the side of women) and changes at the level of civil society organisations (adopting new values and norms potentially enabling gender equality). Changes in actions: 7 organisations reported to be promoting changes in actions. The results related to this change in 2018 are the greater incorporation -through real facts- of gender perspective in some civil society organisations in the north of Argentina, the greater visibility of LGBTIQ people as public policies subjets, the increase of women participation in politics and the greater access of women to contraceptive methods. Changes in association: 27 organisations reported to be: 1) Creating new alliances/undertaking joint actions or campaigns; 2) Strengthening existing alliances (for example, reactivating old alliances). Specifically, the results linked to changes in the ways of relating with other organisations focus, mainly, in the articulation of new alliances within the framework of LFS. It is possible to identify two kind of new alliances: 1) operational alliances among the LFS grantees &#x2013;orientated mostly to the co-execution of specific activities included in the projects- (this has been strengthened form the implementation of the Exchange Programme, with 15 exchanges in 2018); 2) strategic alliances with local, national or international organisations; articulated with the objective of strengthening the regional women&#xB4;s movement and or improving the conditions for change. The main stakeholders that integrate these new alliances are women&#xB4;s rights organisations and state institutions. For security reasons, the composition of the alliances is not detailed. Changes in resource allocations: 17 organisations report to have access to new financial resources (state and international cooperation resources) form their participation in LFS. Summing up, the achievements described show that the organisations focused, during 2018, mainly in promoting changes in regulations, laws and public policies as a way to improve the pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality (outcome). Clearly, this is a highly relevant area in which to promote changes; however, more efforts need to be directed to promote changes in other areas, as the private sector (for example). Grantee: Cat&#xF3;licas por el Derecho a Decidir: Women&apos;s revolution for legal abortion: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HSYHl7PGrOM&amp;feature=youtu.be</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target>
      <dimension name="Changes in control, Changes in values and norms, Changes in actions, Changes in association, Changes in resource allocations."></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Improved pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality. Changes promoted in 2019, per domain of change 1) Changes in control: Description of the promoted changes 1) Department of Cauca, Colombia: Ethnic chapter of public policy for gender equality: since 2019 the organisation has been promoting the elaboration of the ethnic chapter of public policy for gender equality for the department of Cauca, which aimed for the recognition of the particularities of black / afrodescendant women. Additionally, specific actions were taken to guarantee that the policy would be implemented with an ethnic and gender focus. 2) Jujuy, Argentina: The organisation supported actions to force adherence at the municipal level to the Micaela Garc&#xED;a Law in the town of Tilcara. 3) Jujuy, Argentina: The organisation contributed producing information and data to be shared with the deputy Mariela Ortiz, author of the project of provincial adherence to National Law No. 27499 known as Micaela Law, which in Jujuy that was approved as Provincial Law No. 6140. 4) Panama: Specific actions were conducted by the organisation in order to modify the concept of &quot;embryo&quot; in the New Born Law. 5)Honduras: the organisation participated in the elaboration of the draft Law for the decriminalization of abortion for 3 reasons. 6) Honduras: The organiisation participated on the elaboration of a proposal for a comprehensive Law regarding violence against women. The draft document of the proposal for the comprehensive Law about violence against women was presented to the Minister of the Women&apos;s Institute (INAM) at a public event on November 26, 2019, in Honduras. 7) Bogot&#xE1; (Colombia), City Land Management Plan: the Consortium conducted advocacy actions during its formulation for the incorporation of gender and women&apos;s rights approaches. 8) Argentina, Draft of the National Rental Law: the Consortium conducted advocacy actions during its formulation for the incorporation of gender and women&apos;s rights approaches (half sanction in the Chamber of Deputies in November 2019). 9) Argentina, Comprehensive Care Law: the Consortium prepared and shared proposals to improve the draft. 10) El Savador, Municipal Policy on Substantive Equality and Gender Equity of San Salvador PMISyEG: the Consortium participated in the process of co-building the draft document. 11) San Salvador (El salvador): Plan of care of the City of San Salvador. The Cosortium participated in the process of co-building the draft document. 12) San Salvador (El Salvador): elaboration of the Multidisciplinary guide for municipal design and intervention in equitable, friendly, safe and sustainable public spaces. 13) Chile, Process of constitutional change: the Consortium is actively participating in the process. 14) Guatemala, National Plan for the Prevention and Eradication of Domestic Violence and against Women (PLANOVI): the Consortium is having an active participation in the update process of the Plan. 15) Brazil. Dialogue with parliamentarians from the legislature about creating a front for national and state urban reform. 16) Brazil, Debates on institutional violence due to gender in the Chambers of the municipalities of the legislative branches form: S&#xE3;o Paulo, Santos, S&#xE3;o Vicente, Campinas, Diadema, S&#xE3;o Luis do Maranh&#xE3;o, Recife Pernambuco, Manaus and R&#xED;o de Janeiro. 17) Guatemala: Letter-Agreement to Prevent with Education 2016-2020. The organisation carried out an advocacy process at the local level. 18) Guatemala: National Plan for the Prevention of Teenage Pregnancies &#x2013;PLANEA-. The organisation carried out an advocacy process at the local level. 19) Suriname: After an advocacy campaign of the organisation, the Regional Health Service (RGD) incorporated 15 minutes of information and information sessions on gender awareness, domestic violence and health during their regular school examinations in all five Nickerie resorts (Western Polders, Nieuw Nickerie, Eastern Polders, Henar and Wageningen). 20) Dominican Republic: After an advocacy campaign of the organisation, the local governance system of the Municipal Board has committed to the local organisations that will implement and respect the gender quotaat the municipal level. 2) Changes in values and norms: Description of the promoted changes 1) Colombia: Changes in values and norms were promoted through a campaign to prevent violence against women, as well as through workshops and a communication strategy that uses the local media, commemoration meetings (25N) and training for officials who are rights holders of the women. With this campaign to prevent violence against women, &quot;the fight of women has hope&quot;, through a pedagogical work of the organization, it has been possible to empower women in terms of which actions are classified as violence and which are its typologies. It has been oriented not only to women, but also men, boys and girls in issues related to GBV, laws and norms of detection, prevention and care of GBV such as Law 1257 of 2008. Additionally, information was shared about the institutions that must guarantee the full exercise of women&apos;s rights. These actions have allowed a significant advance, which is evident in the empowerment of women who have initiated some legal processes denouncing violence based on gender and their motivation to get out of these circles of violence and access decent living conditions free from assault. These actions have made possible to create a precedent with women regarding the acquisition of knowledge that allows them to protect themselves, but primarily to demand before the institutions the guarantee of their rights. Greater interest is evident in the officials responsible for implementing policies in favor of women. 2) Argentina: the society is in a process of very positive changes for women and sexual dissent. Through accompaniment in activism, training and the materials produced, the organisation has contributed to changes and proposals in Argentine legislation aimed at expanding women&apos;s rights and sexual dissent. The Consortium permanent work to disseminate women&apos;s rights to cities and territories is contributing to install new perspectives on spatial injustices and violence and rights violations experienced by women and sexual dissent. They are slow modifications, which occur not without setbacks and contradictions, and are due to the confluence of a multiplicity of actions, processes and actors involved. 3) In Colombia, the commitment of the Consultative Council for Women (CCM), the District Secretariat for Women (SDMujer) and the District Secretariat for Planning with the rights of women to the city, expressed in an inclusive POT and Development Plan, were expanded. 4) In Argentina there is a greater role of feminists in the debates regarding the right to cities: we are consulted, we are invited more frequently than before and the gender / feminist perspective is named more frequently, often even without incidence concrete that we seek. 5) In Guatemala, the work of women has resulted in the strengthening of their knowledge about their rights and in particular about their right to enjoy the city. 6) In El Salvador, women leaders present concrete proposals to ensure their rights to OPAMSS and trans women are visible in their demands and the discrimination and violence they face towards the municipality. 7) In Guatemala: through LFS, changes in values and norms related to the free exercise of Sexual and Reproductive Rights and gender equality of girls and women in southern Pet&#xE9;n have been promoted. The Christian churches have been one of the power groups historically opposed to the free exercise of the Sexual and Reproductive Rights of girls and women, which clings with greater intensity in contexts where the macho and patriarchal system strikes with greater severity. This is the case of the indigenous, rural and poor communities in the South of Pet&#xE9;n. This condition further limits girls and women belonging to the Evangelical Christian religion, since established doctrines strengthen the idea that men are the lord and master of all, including the body of women. For this reason, evangelical girls and women in the South of Pet&#xE9;n have few spaces to receive information and guidance on sexual and reproductive rights, gender equality, ways to prevent violence and the exercise of citizenship. This began to change through the inclusion of the Spanish-Q&apos;eqch&#xED; bilingual radio program &quot;The ABC of Sexuality&quot; on a private radio station oriented to the Evangelical or Protestant Christian religion and its continuity throughout the execution of the present project. As progress is made in the dissemination and socialization of the themes, the adolescents and women of the Protestant religion in the South of Pet&#xE9;n, begin to speak openly and value the importance of exercising their rights. During the radio programs carried out in the project, there was more communication, ranging from congratulating for transmitting it, to requesting topics such as &quot;identity and sexual orientation&quot;, a controversial issue for the church. 8) Paraguay: In this first phase of the project, which was mainly a formative stage for young activists, the organisation collaborated to strengthen the knowledge of the participants and thus further strengthen their scheme of values that they have been developing empirically in their organizations. Their testimonies were captured in a video that portrays the process carried out in which they express greater security when talking about feminism, gender equality and confronting hate speech in the spaces in which they interact. With this training the organisation has empowered the participants in their relationship as representatives of their organisations with other civil society organisations, their community and with the authorities with whom they interact. The training space also served for them to share experiences and situations that they lived through throughout their lives as women in a machista and patriarchal Paraguayan society and they were dialoguing about what kind of values and practices they can transmit and practice to reach a country with greater equal rights for all people. 9) Suriname: behavioral changes with respect to VAW, violence against children and gender equality. Also, on breaking the silence because VAW is still taboo in many rural communities. First of all, many key stakeholders were trained in how to deal with Violence Against Women and Children (VAW&amp;C) and issues of gender equality. Then, a brainstorming session was held with them about the content of the various materials to be designed (leaflets, posters, billboards and caps) which revealed that there was a change in attitudes towards the issue and greater empathy. 3) Changes in actions: Description of the promoted changes 1) Argentina (Jujuy): empowerment of the women who participate in the project, who then replicate these changes in their organizations and create spaces for interpellation towards their male and female partners. 2) Honduras: women show greater commitment to the defense of their rights and denounce and demand their rights. There is interest in acquiring more knowledge about their rights and a greater number of women have been integrated into neighborhood groups. The group is organizing two more collectives; one in L&#xF3;pez Arellano and the other in La Jutosa village. 3) Uruguay: the awareness raised about violent practices among health personnel generated changes in their practices. 4) Girls now have access to some health care to better manage their physical and mental bodies. They understand better certain biological reactions of their body. They accept and assert themselves as girls. 4) Changes in association: 35 organisations reported to have articulated new alliances or consolidated previous ones, mentioning 225 alliances (new/consolidated). 5) Changes in resource allocation: 11 Organisation reporting increased resources since their participation in LFS: Other donors supporting the LFS organisations&#xB4;work 1) Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID). 2) USAID. 3) Alianza por la solidaridad. 4) Planned Parenthood International. 5) Global Fund for Women. 6) Ford Foundation. 7) Fundo Luterano de Di&#xE1;conia. 8) Open Society Fundation. 9) ACNUR. 10) Wellspring Foundation. 11) Fondo &#xC1;gil. 12) Colectivo Con y Para las Ni&#xF1;as. 13) Global Fund for Children. 14) Ayuntamiento de Madrid. 15) Universidad Cat&#xF3;lica de Chile. 16) Spark. Improved pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality. Changes promoted in 2019, per domain of change 1) Changes in control: Description of the promoted changes 1) Department of Cauca, Colombia: Ethnic chapter of public policy for gender equality: since 2019 the organisation has been promoting the elaboration of the ethnic chapter of public policy for gender equality for the department of Cauca, which aimed for the recognition of the particularities of black / afrodescendant women. Additionally, specific actions were taken to guarantee that the policy would be implemented with an ethnic and gender focus. 2) Jujuy, Argentina: The organisation supported actions to force adherence at the municipal level to the Micaela Garc&#xED;a Law in the town of Tilcara. 3) Jujuy, Argentina: The organisation contributed producing information and data to be shared with the deputy Mariela Ortiz, author of the project of provincial adherence to National Law No. 27499 known as Micaela Law, which in Jujuy that was approved as Provincial Law No. 6140. 4) Panama: Specific actions were conducted by the organisation in order to modify the concept of &quot;embryo&quot; in the New Born Law. 5)Honduras: the organisation participated in the elaboration of the draft Law for the decriminalization of abortion for 3 reasons. 6) Honduras: The organiisation participated on the elaboration of a proposal for a comprehensive Law regarding violence against women. The draft document of the proposal for the comprehensive Law about violence against women was presented to the Minister of the Women&apos;s Institute (INAM) at a public event on November 26, 2019, in Honduras. 7) Bogot&#xE1; (Colombia), City Land Management Plan: the Consortium conducted advocacy actions during its formulation for the incorporation of gender and women&apos;s rights approaches. 8) Argentina, Draft of the National Rental Law: the Consortium conducted advocacy actions during its formulation for the incorporation of gender and women&apos;s rights approaches (half sanction in the Chamber of Deputies in November 2019). 9) Argentina, Comprehensive Care Law: the Consortium prepared and shared proposals to improve the draft. 10) El Savador, Municipal Policy on Substantive Equality and Gender Equity of San Salvador PMISyEG: the Consortium participated in the process of co-building the draft document. 11) San Salvador (El salvador): Plan of care of the City of San Salvador. The Cosortium participated in the process of co-building the draft document. 12) San Salvador (El Salvador): elaboration of the Multidisciplinary guide for municipal design and intervention in equitable, friendly, safe and sustainable public spaces. 13) Chile, Process of constitutional change: the Consortium is actively participating in the process. 14) Guatemala, National Plan for the Prevention and Eradication of Domestic Violence and against Women (PLANOVI): the Consortium is having an active participation in the update process of the Plan. 15) Brazil. Dialogue with parliamentarians from the legislature about creating a front for national and state urban reform. 16) Brazil, Debates on institutional violence due to gender in the Chambers of the municipalities of the legislative branches form: S&#xE3;o Paulo, Santos, S&#xE3;o Vicente, Campinas, Diadema, S&#xE3;o Luis do Maranh&#xE3;o, Recife Pernambuco, Manaus and R&#xED;o de Janeiro. 17) Guatemala: Letter-Agreement to Prevent with Education 2016-2020. The organisation carried out an advocacy process at the local level. 18) Guatemala: National Plan for the Prevention of Teenage Pregnancies &#x2013;PLANEA-. The organisation carried out an advocacy process at the local level. 19) Suriname: After an advocacy campaign of the organisation, the Regional Health Service (RGD) incorporated 15 minutes of information and information sessions on gender awareness, domestic violence and health during their regular school examinations in all five Nickerie resorts (Western Polders, Nieuw Nickerie, Eastern Polders, Henar and Wageningen). 20) Dominican Republic: After an advocacy campaign of the organisation, the local governance system of the Municipal Board has committed to the local organisations that will implement and respect the gender quotaat the municipal level. 2) Changes in values and norms: Description of the promoted changes 1) Colombia: Changes in values and norms were promoted through a campaign to prevent violence against women, as well as through workshops and a communication strategy that uses the local media, commemoration meetings (25N) and training for officials who are rights holders of the women. With this campaign to prevent violence against women, &quot;the fight of women has hope&quot;, through a pedagogical work of the organization, it has been possible to empower women in terms of which actions are classified as violence and which are its typologies. It has been oriented not only to women, but also men, boys and girls in issues related to GBV, laws and norms of detection, prevention and care of GBV such as Law 1257 of 2008. Additionally, information was shared about the institutions that must guarantee the full exercise of women&apos;s rights. These actions have allowed a significant advance, which is evident in the empowerment of women who have initiated some legal processes denouncing violence based on gender and their motivation to get out of these circles of violence and access decent living conditions free from assault. These actions have made possible to create a precedent with women regarding the acquisition of knowledge that allows them to protect themselves, but primarily to demand before the institutions the guarantee of their rights. Greater interest is evident in the officials responsible for implementing policies in favor of women. 2) Argentina: the society is in a process of very positive changes for women and sexual dissent. Through accompaniment in activism, training and the materials produced, the organisation has contributed to changes and proposals in Argentine legislation aimed at expanding women&apos;s rights and sexual dissent. The Consortium permanent work to disseminate women&apos;s rights to cities and territories is contributing to install new perspectives on spatial injustices and violence and rights violations experienced by women and sexual dissent. They are slow modifications, which occur not without setbacks and contradictions, and are due to the confluence of a multiplicity of actions, processes and actors involved. 3) In Colombia, the commitment of the Consultative Council for Women (CCM), the District Secretariat for Women (SDMujer) and the District Secretariat for Planning with the rights of women to the city, expressed in an inclusive POT and Development Plan, were expanded. 4) In Argentina there is a greater role of feminists in the debates regarding the right to cities: we are consulted, we are invited more frequently than before and the gender / feminist perspective is named more frequently, often even without incidence concrete that we seek. 5) In Guatemala, the work of women has resulted in the strengthening of their knowledge about their rights and in particular about their right to enjoy the city. 6) In El Salvador, women leaders present concrete proposals to ensure their rights to OPAMSS and trans women are visible in their demands and the discrimination and violence they face towards the municipality. 7) In Guatemala: through LFS, changes in values and norms related to the free exercise of Sexual and Reproductive Rights and gender equality of girls and women in southern Pet&#xE9;n have been promoted. The Christian churches have been one of the power groups historically opposed to the free exercise of the Sexual and Reproductive Rights of girls and women, which clings with greater intensity in contexts where the macho and patriarchal system strikes with greater severity. This is the case of the indigenous, rural and poor communities in the South of Pet&#xE9;n. This condition further limits girls and women belonging to the Evangelical Christian religion, since established doctrines strengthen the idea that men are the lord and master of all, including the body of women. For this reason, evangelical girls and women in the South of Pet&#xE9;n have few spaces to receive information and guidance on sexual and reproductive rights, gender equality, ways to prevent violence and the exercise of citizenship. This began to change through the inclusion of the Spanish-Q&apos;eqch&#xED; bilingual radio program &quot;The ABC of Sexuality&quot; on a private radio station oriented to the Evangelical or Protestant Christian religion and its continuity throughout the execution of the present project. As progress is made in the dissemination and socialization of the themes, the adolescents and women of the Protestant religion in the South of Pet&#xE9;n, begin to speak openly and value the importance of exercising their rights. During the radio programs carried out in the project, there was more communication, ranging from congratulating for transmitting it, to requesting topics such as &quot;identity and sexual orientation&quot;, a controversial issue for the church. 8) Paraguay: In this first phase of the project, which was mainly a formative stage for young activists, the organisation collaborated to strengthen the knowledge of the participants and thus further strengthen their scheme of values that they have been developing empirically in their organizations. Their testimonies were captured in a video that portrays the process carried out in which they express greater security when talking about feminism, gender equality and confronting hate speech in the spaces in which they interact. With this training the organisation has empowered the participants in their relationship as representatives of their organisations with other civil society organisations, their community and with the authorities with whom they interact. The training space also served for them to share experiences and situations that they lived through throughout their lives as women in a machista and patriarchal Paraguayan society and they were dialoguing about what kind of values and practices they can transmit and practice to reach a country with greater equal rights for all people. 9) Suriname: behavioral changes with respect to VAW, violence against children and gender equality. Also, on breaking the silence because VAW is still taboo in many rural communities. First of all, many key stakeholders were trained in how to deal with Violence Against Women and Children (VAW&amp;C) and issues of gender equality. Then, a brainstorming session was held with them about the content of the various materials to be designed (leaflets, posters, billboards and caps) which revealed that there was a change in attitudes towards the issue and greater empathy. 3) Changes in actions: Description of the promoted changes 1) Argentina (Jujuy): empowerment of the women who participate in the project, who then replicate these changes in their organizations and create spaces for interpellation towards their male and female partners. 2) Honduras: women show greater commitment to the defense of their rights and denounce and demand their rights. There is interest in acquiring more knowledge about their rights and a greater number of women have been integrated into neighborhood groups. The group is organizing two more collectives; one in L&#xF3;pez Arellano and the other in La Jutosa village. 3) Uruguay: the awareness raised about violent practices among health personnel generated changes in their practices. 4) Girls now have access to some health care to better manage their physical and mental bodies. They understand better certain biological reactions of their body. They accept and assert themselves as girls. 4) Changes in association: 35 organisations reported to have articulated new alliances or consolidated previous ones, mentioning 225 alliances (new/consolidated). 5) Changes in resource allocation: 11 Organisation reporting increased resources since their participation in LFS: Other donors supporting the LFS organisations&#xB4;work 1) Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID). 2) USAID. 3) Alianza por la solidaridad. 4) Planned Parenthood International. 5) Global Fund for Women. 6) Ford Foundation. 7) Fundo Luterano de Di&#xE1;conia. 8) Open Society Fundation. 9) ACNUR. 10) Wellspring Foundation. 11) Fondo &#xC1;gil. 12) Colectivo Con y Para las Ni&#xF1;as. 13) Global Fund for Children. 14) Ayuntamiento de Madrid. 15) Universidad Cat&#xF3;lica de Chile. 16) Spark. Improved pre-conditions / enabling environment for women&#x2019;s rights and gender equality. Changes promoted in 2019, per domain of change 1) Changes in control: Description of the promoted changes 1) Department of Cauca, Colombia: Ethnic chapter of public policy for gender equality: since 2019 the organisation has been promoting the elaboration of the ethnic chapter of public policy for gender equality for the department of Cauca, which aimed for the recognition of the particularities of black / afrodescendant women. Additionally, specific actions were taken to guarantee that the policy would be implemented with an ethnic and gender focus. 2) Jujuy, Argentina: The organisation supported actions to force adherence at the municipal level to the Micaela Garc&#xED;a Law in the town of Tilcara. 3) Jujuy, Argentina: The organisation contributed producing information and data to be shared with the deputy Mariela Ortiz, author of the project of provincial adherence to National Law No. 27499 known as Micaela Law, which in Jujuy that was approved as Provincial Law No. 6140. 4) Panama: Specific actions were conducted by the organisation in order to modify the concept of &quot;embryo&quot; in the New Born Law. 5)Honduras: the organisation participated in the elaboration of the draft Law for the decriminalization of abortion for 3 reasons. 6) Honduras: The organiisation participated on the elaboration of a proposal for a comprehensive Law regarding violence against women. The draft document of the proposal for the comprehensive Law about violence against women was presented to the Minister of the Women&apos;s Institute (INAM) at a public event on November 26, 2019, in Honduras. 7) Bogot&#xE1; (Colombia), City Land Management Plan: the Consortium conducted advocacy actions during its formulation for the incorporation of gender and women&apos;s rights approaches. 8) Argentina, Draft of the National Rental Law: the Consortium conducted advocacy actions during its formulation for the incorporation of gender and women&apos;s rights approaches (half sanction in the Chamber of Deputies in November 2019). 9) Argentina, Comprehensive Care Law: the Consortium prepared and shared proposals to improve the draft. 10) El Savador, Municipal Policy on Substantive Equality and Gender Equity of San Salvador PMISyEG: the Consortium participated in the process of co-building the draft document. 11) San Salvador (El salvador): Plan of care of the City of San Salvador. The Cosortium participated in the process of co-building the draft document. 12) San Salvador (El Salvador): elaboration of the Multidisciplinary guide for municipal design and intervention in equitable, friendly, safe and sustainable public spaces. 13) Chile, Process of constitutional change: the Consortium is actively participating in the process. 14) Guatemala, National Plan for the Prevention and Eradication of Domestic Violence and against Women (PLANOVI): the Consortium is having an active participation in the update process of the Plan. 15) Brazil. Dialogue with parliamentarians from the legislature about creating a front for national and state urban reform. 16) Brazil, Debates on institutional violence due to gender in the Chambers of the municipalities of the legislative branches form: S&#xE3;o Paulo, Santos, S&#xE3;o Vicente, Campinas, Diadema, S&#xE3;o Luis do Maranh&#xE3;o, Recife Pernambuco, Manaus and R&#xED;o de Janeiro. 17) Guatemala: Letter-Agreement to Prevent with Education 2016-2020. The organisation carried out an advocacy process at the local level. 18) Guatemala: National Plan for the Prevention of Teenage Pregnancies &#x2013;PLANEA-. The organisation carried out an advocacy process at the local level. 19) Suriname: After an advocacy campaign of the organisation, the Regional Health Service (RGD) incorporated 15 minutes of information and information sessions on gender awareness, domestic violence and health during their regular school examinations in all five Nickerie resorts (Western Polders, Nieuw Nickerie, Eastern Polders, Henar and Wageningen). 20) Dominican Republic: After an advocacy campaign of the organisation, the local governance system of the Municipal Board has committed to the local organisations that will implement and respect the gender quotaat the municipal level. 2) Changes in values and norms: Description of the promoted changes 1) Colombia: Changes in values and norms were promoted through a campaign to prevent violence against women, as well as through workshops and a communication strategy that uses the local media, commemoration meetings (25N) and training for officials who are rights holders of the women. With this campaign to prevent violence against women, &quot;the fight of women has hope&quot;, through a pedagogical work of the organization, it has been possible to empower women in terms of which actions are classified as violence and which are its typologies. It has been oriented not only to women, but also men, boys and girls in issues related to GBV, laws and norms of detection, prevention and care of GBV such as Law 1257 of 2008. Additionally, information was shared about the institutions that must guarantee the full exercise of women&apos;s rights. These actions have allowed a significant advance, which is evident in the empowerment of women who have initiated some legal processes denouncing violence based on gender and their motivation to get out of these circles of violence and access decent living conditions free from assault. These actions have made possible to create a precedent with women regarding the acquisition of knowledge that allows them to protect themselves, but primarily to demand before the institutions the guarantee of their rights. Greater interest is evident in the officials responsible for implementing policies in favor of women. 2) Argentina: the society is in a process of very positive changes for women and sexual dissent. Through accompaniment in activism, training and the materials produced, the organisation has contributed to changes and proposals in Argentine legislation aimed at expanding women&apos;s rights and sexual dissent. The Consortium permanent work to disseminate women&apos;s rights to cities and territories is contributing to install new perspectives on spatial injustices and violence and rights violations experienced by women and sexual dissent. They are slow modifications, which occur not without setbacks and contradictions, and are due to the confluence of a multiplicity of actions, processes and actors involved. 3) In Colombia, the commitment of the Consultative Council for Women (CCM), the District Secretariat for Women (SDMujer) and the District Secretariat for Planning with the rights of women to the city, expressed in an inclusive POT and Development Plan, were expanded. 4) In Argentina there is a greater role of feminists in the debates regarding the right to cities: we are consulted, we are invited more frequently than before and the gender / feminist perspective is named more frequently, often even without incidence concrete that we seek. 5) In Guatemala, the work of women has resulted in the strengthening of their knowledge about their rights and in particular about their right to enjoy the city. 6) In El Salvador, women leaders present concrete proposals to ensure their rights to OPAMSS and trans women are visible in their demands and the discrimination and violence they face towards the municipality. 7) In Guatemala: through LFS, changes in values and norms related to the free exercise of Sexual and Reproductive Rights and gender equality of girls and women in southern Pet&#xE9;n have been promoted. The Christian churches have been one of the power groups historically opposed to the free exercise of the Sexual and Reproductive Rights of girls and women, which clings with greater intensity in contexts where the macho and patriarchal system strikes with greater severity. This is the case of the indigenous, rural and poor communities in the South of Pet&#xE9;n. This condition further limits girls and women belonging to the Evangelical Christian religion, since established doctrines strengthen the idea that men are the lord and master of all, including the body of women. For this reason, evangelical girls and women in the South of Pet&#xE9;n have few spaces to receive information and guidance on sexual and reproductive rights, gender equality, ways to prevent violence and the exercise of citizenship. This began to change through the inclusion of the Spanish-Q&apos;eqch&#xED; bilingual radio program &quot;The ABC of Sexuality&quot; on a private radio station oriented to the Evangelical or Protestant Christian religion and its continuity throughout the execution of the present project. As progress is made in the dissemination and socialization of the themes, the adolescents and women of the Protestant religion in the South of Pet&#xE9;n, begin to speak openly and value the importance of exercising their rights. During the radio programs carried out in the project, there was more communication, ranging from congratulating for transmitting it, to requesting topics such as &quot;identity and sexual orientation&quot;, a controversial issue for the church. 8) Paraguay: In this first phase of the project, which was mainly a formative stage for young activists, the organisation collaborated to strengthen the knowledge of the participants and thus further strengthen their scheme of values that they have been developing empirically in their organizations. Their testimonies were captured in a video that portrays the process carried out in which they express greater security when talking about feminism, gender equality and confronting hate speech in the spaces in which they interact. With this training the organisation has empowered the participants in their relationship as representatives of their organisations with other civil society organisations, their community and with the authorities with whom they interact. The training space also served for them to share experiences and situations that they lived through throughout their lives as women in a machista and patriarchal Paraguayan society and they were dialoguing about what kind of values and practices they can transmit and practice to reach a country with greater equal rights for all people. 9) Suriname: behavioral changes with respect to VAW, violence against children and gender equality. Also, on breaking the silence because VAW is still taboo in many rural communities. First of all, many key stakeholders were trained in how to deal with Violence Against Women and Children (VAW&amp;C) and issues of gender equality. Then, a brainstorming session was held with them about the content of the various materials to be designed (leaflets, posters, billboards and caps) which revealed that there was a change in attitudes towards the issue and greater empathy. 3) Changes in actions: Description of the promoted changes 1) Argentina (Jujuy): empowerment of the women who participate in the project, who then replicate these changes in their organizations and create spaces for interpellation towards their male and female partners. 2) Honduras: women show greater commitment to the defense of their rights and denounce and demand their rights. There is interest in acquiring more knowledge about their rights and a greater number of women have been integrated into neighborhood groups. The group is organizing two more collectives; one in L&#xF3;pez Arellano and the other in La Jutosa village. 3) Uruguay: the awareness raised about violent practices among health personnel generated changes in their practices. 4) Girls now have access to some health care to better manage their physical and mental bodies. They understand better certain biological reactions of their body. They accept and assert themselves as girls. 4) Changes in association: 35 organisations reported to have articulated new alliances or consolidated previous ones, mentioning 225 alliances (new/consolidated). 5) Changes in resource allocation: 11 Organisation reporting increased resources since their participation in LFS: Other donors supporting the LFS organisations&#xB4;work 1) Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID). 2) USAID. 3) Alianza por la solidaridad. 4) Planned Parenthood International. 5) Global Fund for Women. 6) Ford Foundation. 7) Fundo Luterano de Di&#xE1;conia. 8) Open Society Fundation. 9) ACNUR. 10) Wellspring Foundation. 11) Fondo &#xC1;gil. 12) Colectivo Con y Para las Ni&#xF1;as. 13) Global Fund for Children. 14) Ayuntamiento de Madrid. 15) Universidad Cat&#xF3;lica de Chile. 16) Spark.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Micro level: More women exercise their leadership to promote women rights and gender equality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women and girls actively promoting/advancing womens rights and gender equality with various stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc). Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions in different levels (formal or informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Grantees&#xB4;beneficiaries (girls and women participating on the activities implemented by the grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-01-01" value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="ES">The reported result refers to women who are (from the beggining of LFS): 1) Holding positions in institutions in different levels (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights. 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights. 3) Formally involved in structures of governance with focus on the promotion of gender equality.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="900">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on a target of 45 grantees during the 4 years period, it would be desirable to reach the goal of having at least 20 women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders, on average, per organisation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="614">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategies have been put in place from the grantees in order to promote women political participation, which can be represented in 3 complementary goals: 1) More women holding positions in institutions in different levels (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights; 2) More women actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights, 3) More women formally involved in structures of governance with focus on the promotion of gender equality. Voices from the ground: Grantee: Asociaci&#xF3;n AMA: El ABC de la sexualidad / The ABC of sexuality: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ixvQEQZSu2U&amp;feature=youtu.be</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="900">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on a target of 45 grantees during the 4 years period, it would be desirable to reach the goal of having at least 20 women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders, on average, per organisation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="635">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategies have been put in place from the grantees in order to promote women political participation, which can be represented in 3 complementary goals: 1) More women holding positions in institutions in different levels (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights; 2) More women actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights, 3) More women formally involved in structures of governance with focus on the promotion of gender equality.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="900">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on a target of 45 grantees during the 4 years period, it would be desirable to reach the goal of having at least 20 women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders, on average, per organisation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="832">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Strategies have been put in place from the grantees in order to promote women political participation, which can be represented in 3 complementary goals: 1) More women holding positions in institutions in different levels (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights; 2) More women actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal) to promote gender equality and women&#xB4;s rights, 3) More women formally involved in structures of governance with focus on the promotion of gender equality.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="900">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on a target of 45 grantees during the 4 years period, it would be desirable to reach the goal of having at least 20 women and girls who are actively promoting/advancing women&#xB4;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders, on average, per organisation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="212"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meso level: Strong Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations advancing women&apos;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations engaged in initiatives to advance&#xA0; women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations (Grassroots, Intermediate and Large) who are engagged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc). Categories: 1) Holding positions in institutions in different levels (formal and informal). 2) Actively engaged in dialogues with different stakeholders (formal or informal). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-01-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45"></target>
     <actual value="34">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 34 FMS-LFS grantees reported that they are engagged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45"></target>
     <actual value="34">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 34 FMS-LFS grantees reported that they are engagged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45"></target>
     <actual value="37">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">The 37 FMS-LFS grantees reported that they are engagged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45"></target>
     <actual value="37">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">The 37 FMS-LFS grantees reported that they are engagged in initiatives to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality with various stakeholders (state actors, NGOs and CSOs, traditional leaders, religious institutions, private sector, academia, media, etc).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations establising or consolidating alliances to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Women&apos;s Rights Organizations (Grassroots, Intermediate and Large) who are establising or consolidating alliances to advance women&apos;s rights and gender equality. Categories:1) Creating new alliances/undertaking joint actions or campaigns; 2)Strenghtening existing alliances (for example, reactivating old alliances). Subject: Only direct beneficiaries (grantees).</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://www.minbuza.nl" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2017-01-01" value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="34">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Being the goal to reach 45 grantees at the end of LFS, the objective es that 75% (34) could report -at the final stage of the programme- to have consolidated existing alliances or created new ones.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="27">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The results linked to changes in the ways of relating with other organisations focus, mainly, in the articulation of new alliances within the framework of LFS. It is possible to identify two kind of new alliances: 1) operational alliances among the LFS grantees &#x2013;orientated mostly to the co-execution of specific activities included in the projects-; 2) strategic alliances with local, national or international organisations; articulated with the objective of strengthening the regional women&#xB4;s movement and or improving the conditions for change. The main stakeholders that integrate these new alliances are women&#xB4;s rights organisations and state institutions. For security reasons, the names/composition of the alliances is not detailed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="34">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Being the goal to reach 45 grantees at the end of LFS, the objective es that 75% (34) could report -at the final stage of the programme- to have consolidated existing alliances or created new ones.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="21">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">The results linked to changes in the ways of relating with other organisations focus, mainly, in the articulation of new alliances within the framework of LFS. It is possible to identify two kind of new alliances: 1) operational alliances among the LFS grantees &#x2013;orientated mostly to the co-execution of specific activities included in the projects-; 2) strategic alliances with local, national or international organisations; articulated with the objective of strengthening the regional women&#xB4;s movement and or improving the conditions for change. The main stakeholders that integrate these new alliances are women&#xB4;s rights organisations and state institutions. For security reasons, the names/composition of the alliances is not detailed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Being the goal to reach 45 grantees at the end of LFS, the objective es that 75% (34) could report -at the final stage of the programme- to have consolidated existing alliances or created new ones.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">The results linked to changes in the ways of relating with other organisations focus, mainly, in the articulation of new alliances within the framework of LFS. It is possible to identify two kind of new alliances: 1) operational alliances among the LFS grantees &#x2013;orientated mostly to the co-execution of specific activities included in the projects-; 2) strategic alliances with local, national or international organisations; articulated with the objective of strengthening the regional women&#xB4;s movement and or improving the conditions for change. The main stakeholders that integrate these new alliances are women&#xB4;s rights organisations and state institutions. For security reasons, the names/composition of the alliances is not detailed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">Being the goal to reach 45 grantees at the end of LFS, the objective es that 75% (34) could report -at the final stage of the programme- to have consolidated existing alliances or created new ones.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="36">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="ES">The results linked to changes in the ways of relating with other organisations focus, mainly, in the articulation of new alliances within the framework of LFS. It is possible to identify two kind of new alliances: 1) operational alliances among the LFS grantees &#x2013;orientated mostly to the co-execution of specific activities included in the projects-; 2) strategic alliances with local, national or international organisations; articulated with the objective of strengthening the regional women&#xB4;s movement and or improving the conditions for change. The main stakeholders that integrate these new alliances are women&#xB4;s rights organisations and state institutions. For security reasons, the names/composition of the alliances is not detailed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
