<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>ET-0000165</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-32092131" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edukans</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ET-0000165 STAR-school program in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The general objective of star-school program is to improve students&#x2019; academic achievement in 42 primary schools through school improvement program.
Specific objectives:
1. Infrastructure/school environment: To make 42 primary schools child friendly and conducive for learning in the next three years.
2. Teaching: To capacitate 412 teachers to effectively use active learning methods in their classroom.
3. Learning: To improve the average learning results of 67.658 students from the existing 53% to 76% in the coming three years.
4. School-management: To capacitate 294 members of school management team to enable them provide effective support for the school improvement program.
5. Community involvement: To Mobilize the local community to support schools and contribute for the school development programs.
This project is designed to benefit 67,658 primary school students (34,288 directly and 33,370 indirectly-with 50% female) in 42 rural primary schools located in three National Regional States of the country: Afar, Amhara, Oromia and Addis Ababa City Administration. The project will be implemented in cluster form in which 18 primary schools are directly addressed. These 18 cluster schools will share lessons with the rest 24 Satellite schools in which 2-3 primary schools are clustered under a target school. The selection has been made on the bases of the intensity of their poverty status and level of marginalization for quality education.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Expertise Centre Ethiopia - DEC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
