<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GH-0000267</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-32092131" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edukans</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GH-0000267 NICHE II-Sexual Health TVET trainees</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen post-secondary TVET providers in the field of SRHR education to increase effectiveness of their vocational training courses, especially for girls and women.

NICHE EP Nuffic
154.288 is de grant; total budget is 190.590; Eigen bijdrage Edukans is 29.434 Eigen bijdrage Rutgers is 3.098 en Eigen bijdrage Savsign is 3770 in total zijn de Eigen bijdragen 36.303
99.929 contract savsign dat is inclusief bijdrage in kind van 3.770
overgemaakt naar de partner en dus gereserveerd zal worden 96.159
13610,50 contract Rutgers inclusief eigen bijdrage van 3098 gereserveerd om over te maken wordt 10512,50
Totale eigen bijdrage van Edukans wordt als unbillable gereserveerd. wat met de rest van de grant is dat voor Edukans?


14 Programme officers and curriculum developers within 7 (non-formal) post-secondary TVET training providers in Ghana.
Our innovative initiative is two-folded and will result in 2 major outcomes: 
- Outcome 1: Post-secondary TVET providers are able to identify the SRHR needs of their target group, and respond to this within their own organisations. 
- Outcome 2:  Post-secondary TVET providers offer CSE for their students, with a curriculum that fits the specific needs of their target group and is adapted to the local context. 
To achieve these outcome results, we have carefully planned activities that will lead to the following results at output level: 
- Output 1.1. 14 staff members of 7 post-secondary TVET providers are trained in research methodologies to develop a comprehensive SRHR policy for their organisations.
- Output 2.1. 14 staff members of 7 post-secondary TVET providers are trained in the design and development of a comprehensive sexuality education curriculum for young people in post-secondary TVET programmes.
Output 2.2. Based on the results and lessons learnt of a small-scale pilot in 7 post-secondary TVET institutions, the working group adapted the CSE curriculum for final approval by the advisory board.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Savana Signatures</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
