<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-218186-300530-102</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-218186" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leonard Cheshire</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability Data Global Mapping and Assessment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the project is the creation of a centralised online open source of information relating to disability by country, using data generated by governments and other actors, and preparation of an initial summary / analysis of global disability statistics for DFID&#x2019;s Disability Summit in July 2018. The three main components of the Disability Data Global Mapping and Assessment project are: 1. Research: &#x2022; Identify and review latest key statistics (in consultation with DFID) in a defined number of domains &#x2013; (health, education, employment, etc.) and demographics (age, sex, geography &#x2013; urban/rural) by country; &#x2022; Identify other non-governmental sources of data on disability. 2. Online portal development &#x2022; Create a comprehensive accessible web platform that will bring all relevant data together, with particular emphasis on review of prevalence data and key outcome indicators allowing disaggregation from National Statistics Offices (NSOs) on key disability indicators &#x2013; concentrating on censuses, and nationally representative surveys. 3. Data analysis and dissemination &#x2022; Review online data with particular focus on data relevant to SDG indicators &#x2022; Working &#x2013; in consultation with DFID &#x2013; On developing a plan for the sustainability of the portal that would be established through DFID&#x2019;s funding Jan-June 2018.Develop and publish a report with key findings based on an initial analysis and summary of global disability statistics to share at the DFID Disability Summit. &#x2022; The current project will be run with the objective of compiling a viable website that can be presented as a product at the upcoming DFID Summit in July. In the coming months, LCD will explore opportunities for longer term funding for the project that would allow it to continue beyond the Sept 2018.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will benefit people with disabilities worldwide. More specifically, stakeholders engaged in influencing governments and global actors to develop and implement inclusive policies and practices will also benefit from the project as the portal will allow identifying and analysing gaps in the promotion of the rights of people with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="300530-102" ref="GB-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department for International Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="300530-102" ref="GB-CHC-218186" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leonard Cheshire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="300530-102" ref="GB-CHC-218186" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leonard Cheshire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="498" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-01">105838</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="Q1 expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-06">9244</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="3"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
