<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-P7709</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea Disaster Preparedness and Response</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Guinean Red Cross is a key player in the national system of response to emergencies in Guinea. In the response to the epidemic of Ebola, the CRG provided leadership of the Hygiene and Sanitation Commission in addition to the services usually offered to communities in responding to emergencies. Disaster Preparedness and response is one of the three pillars of its strategic development plan 2015-2020.
This program aims to develop the capacities of the Guinean Red Cross at central and branches levels to better respond to emergencies across Guinea and assist more victims. Objectives are to increase their capacity to prepare for and respond to disasters, increase operational efficiency and accountability to beneficiaries and technical and financial partners, to improve information sharing and coordination both internal and external and their ability to learn from their operations.
The Guinean Red Cross aims through this project, to ensure the relevance, quality, scope and sustainability of services in disaster preparedness and response.
The project started at the end of 2016 and concluded in December 2018, funded with remaining Ebola appeal funds until the end of 2018. In Guinea BRC works though a consortium with the Danish RC and the Swiss RC, with BRC being the lead (full BRC funding + technical advice) on this DM initiative. A final external evaluation took place in March 2019 to assess the progress against indicators and evaluate the quality and efficiency of the programme, learn from this experience and provide recommendation to design a second phase.
A 6 months extension to the phase 1 has been developed in June and July 2019. It intends to take forward some recommendations from the final evaluation report to strengthen the achievement of phase 1</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-20700211" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Red Cross Society of Guinea</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swiss Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uko</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="720" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="740" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
