<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-PN1054</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH in Dhaka - Part of ECHO HIP Consortium</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh is among the countries with the highest exposure to natural disasters. Rapid urbanization, lack of space and basic infrastructure exacerbates Dhaka&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x2122;s vulnerability to natural hazards and health events. Although the country has substantial capacity and experience in Disaster Risk Management (DRM), gaps in institutional preparedness and service provision remain.
&#xC2;&#xA0;
The Action will enhance coordination and effectiveness of disaster preparedness in the highly congested urban areas of Dhaka South City, focusing on connecting and strengthening capacities of the City Corporation and Ward structures. To address health emergencies, systems on Mass Casualty Management and overall preparedness of strategically located hospitals will be brought up to standard. In all these components, the position of people living with disabilities will receive ample attention as well as the mental well-being of the population and first responders. All efforts will align with government policies and mandated organizations. The population in the target areas will furthermore benefit from improved solid waste and faecal sludge management services. This reduces urban flooding and improves health and living conditions. To advance DRM in Bangladesh, the partners will re-energize multi-stakeholder advocacy with a specific focus on promoting Shock Sensitive Social Protection in the urban areas and Forecast based Actions (FbA).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh Red Crescent Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-20700211" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">German Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
