<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-P8629</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lithuania Population Movement 2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since mid-May 2021, the number of people who enter Lithuania irregularly from Belarus has been increasing rapidly. Following the series of recent events at the Lithuanian &#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x201C; Belarusian border, Lithuania declared a state of emergency on 2 July 2021. As of 7 July 2021, the total number of new arrivals is 1,416. The number indicates a 1648% increase in irregular border crossings, compared to year 2020.
Before the crisis, asylum seekers used to stay isolated at the Lithuanian border for 1 to 3 days until receiving COVID-19 testing results and then moving into reception centres. However, the sudden influx of migrants has put enormous pressure to the reception system. In early June, the Foreigners Registration Center in Pabrad&#xC4;&#x2014; ran over its maximum capacity. As COVID-19 prevention measures require lower occupancy and separate accommodation, more places have been opened as mandatory isolation and/ or reception facilities.
Approximately 60% of arrivals consist of men, while the remaining 40% are women, children, unaccompanied minors, and persons with disabilities. The nationality of the arriving migrants has shown a specific change in migration to Lithuania trends with 43.5% of people who arrived in Lithuania during the last 3 months of 2021 being of Iraqi nationality, whereas in 2020 most asylum seekers were from Belarus, followed by Russia and Tajikistan. 90 &#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x201C; 95 % of the arriving migrants seek for asylum in Lithuania. However, there is a significant delay in accepting and examining new asylum applications due to the Migration Department being short of staff that carries out the examination of applications and the lack of interpreters.
The IFRC released a DREF on 12 July for CHF 338,885 to assist 4,000 people across 10 provinces for four months. The IFRC are also deploying a Operations Manager and CEA Coordinator for one month in country. The latter will be deployed from the British Red Cross.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-21018" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFRC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="930" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
