<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-P8720</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon Livelihood &apos;Flagship&apos; 2021-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project is continuation of Lebanon - ICRC-LRC cash and livelihoods programme implemented in 2020-2021.
Project intends to conduct market assessment in Aral followed with a set of livelihood activities set up based on labour market assessment results. Project overall objective is &apos;Vulnerable Lebanese residents, Syrian refugees and people of other nationalities are able to cover their essential needs and unavoidable expenditures as defined by their biology, environment and cultural standards in a sustainable manner&apos;. Under outcome 1 Syrian refugees, resident Lebanese and other vulnerable groups, affected by conflict and not assisted by other organizations, in Arsal and LRC priority area have a sustainable income&apos; project will will capitalise on progress made to date under the programme in Arsal and further boost local production and the wider market to develop SMEs, increase job creation and employment, in turn, improving people&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x2122;s capacity to generate their own income to cover their essential needs. Expected direct outputs of the project include 250 new households to have secured their ability to sustainably generate income, 150 existing MSME previously supported by the project continue to generate income, 20 existing MSME are able to employ more than one person.
As opposed to previous edition this project focuses only on livelihood activities while cash assistance component will be discontinued. Project focuses more on knowledge sharing and capacity building by adding two additional outcomes - outcome 2 &apos;Staff and volunteers from the Lebanese Red Cross have the capacity to assess, design, plan, implement, monitor and evaluate livelihoods programmes&apos; and outcome 3 &apos;LRC, ICRC and BRC have a strong partnership model, capitalising on complementary capacities, encouraging effective knowledge and skill sharing and communication and coordination, with the value add on humanitarian outcomes clearly demonstrated for replication in other Movement contexts&apos;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-21016" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICRC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanese Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arsal</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="998" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="998" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
