<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-220949-P8336</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria Disaster Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRC Managed DM Programme
The programme design currently under consideration is based on the four stage Disaster Management Cycle of response to a shock, recovery, DRR and resilience building, and preparedness. The different components of this programme will address all phases of the DM cycle, and will support vulnerable communities to better prepare for disasters, improve community capacity to respond, and strengthen post disaster coping mechanisms. At the same time, service delivery capacity of the NS across the DM cycle will be improved by delivering the project in three distinct phases, which will gradually build up the capacity of the NS to plan, implement, and report on the project independently.
At the idea stage, the current programme plan is as follows:
Phase 1: BRC led hands-on implementation on community level
Phase 1 of the programme is focused on community level planning and implementation. Working through the NS staff and volunteers, BRC will play a strong role in leading this process. By the end of phase one, the NRCS pilot divisions should be capable to plan, implement and report on the activities carried out. and be able to implement these in other communities without external technical support. 
Phase 2: Building NRCS lead capacity and expanding programme scope
In phase 2, the capacity of NRCS on branch level (and partially on HQ level) to plan and implement such community level activities is strengthened; also, the scope of some of the Phase 1 activities will be expanded, adding programmatic complexity. While in Phase 1 BRC will be working closely on the community level with NRCS, leading the process and training NRCS staff and volunteers &#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x153;on the job&#xE2;&#x20AC;&#x9D;. Phase 2 foresees NRCS taking over the leadership and (a) continuing work in these same communities and adding new components, and (b) repeating in new communities what BRC led in Phase 1. 
Phase 3: Consolidation and development of new finance modalities
Phase 3 is characterized by a consolidation of the progress made in phases 1 and 2, and through supporting NRCS to establish herself as preferential partner of the relevant DM institutions in Nigeria. Phases 2 and 3 also see the development and implementation of projects aimed at enhancing community level resilience, through initiatives identified by the communities themselves. It will also look at setting up financing modalities which will enable the NRCS to react quickly and effectively to community, and state level disasters.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-220949" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigerian Red Cross Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <email>Performance&amp;Accountability@redcross.org.uko</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="740" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <sector code="998" percentage="50" vocabulary="2"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
