<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-22503</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Uganda ICWEA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">20 adolescent girls and young women intensively trained as as champions in advocacy, research methods, data collection and reporting 
At least 180 people through district and national level advocacy activities on the rights and health of AGYW 
125 key stakeholders per district (including policy makers, religious leaders, cultural leaders and local leaders) will be trained on the health and rights of AGYW living with HIV in their diversities
Wider community is reached through major anti-stigma campaigns, awareness raising sessions and policy changes</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of the PITCH project in Uganda, ICWEA will build on previous work related to SRHR violations. ICWEA will train adolescent girls and young women (AGYW) as champions in advocacy, research methods, data collection and reporting and will use mass media campaigns to increase community knowledge on the health and rights of AGYW. ICWEA will hold dialogues with health care providers to improve SRHR service delivery for AGYW and will train key stakeholders (including policy makers, religious leaders, cultural leaders and local leaders) on the health and rights of AGYW living with HIV. AGYW will be supported to actively participate in local and national civil and political spaces to influence law and policy development for the promotion and protection of their health and rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICWEA contributes to the following ToC outcomes:
S1.1 Communities are knowledgeable about health and rights for KPs and embrace efforts to address stigma and discrimination against KPs and AGYW. 
S1.2: Across the Healthcare systems (public, private and CSO-led) there is increased technical competency and improved attitudes to meet the specific SRHR needs of KPs and AGYW  
S3: Evidence is methodically collected for the purpose of evidence-based advocacy and research on health and rights priorities for KPs and AGYW  
S4: There is increased engagement and collaboration between CSOs, key stakeholders and potential champions (including government, judiciary, private sector, media, religious, cultural and community leaders) to promote and protect the health and rights of KPs and AGYW
M1: KP and AGYW-led CSOs country-wide are equipped with sufficient technical, human and financial resources to empower and mobilise their constituencies, both as individual organisations and as strong, united coalitions.  
M2: Evidence-based advocacy, targets the government, policy makers, police, judiciary, cultural and religious leaders, and healthcare professionals for full implementation supportive laws and policies for KPs and AGYW 
L1: Friendly, quality, comprehensive, integrated HIV, SRHR and harm reduction services are available, accessible and acceptable in public, private and NGO facilities country-wide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH seeks to strengthen the capacities of local civil society organisations to advocate for sexual and reproductive health and rights, and uphold the human rights of key populations. Our work centres around key populations, adolescent girls and young women in nine countries in East, West and Southern Africa, South-East Asia, and Central Europe. These communities in many contexts carry the main HIV burden. At the same time, they are often neglected in the HIV response and face many barriers in accessing HIV and SRH services as well as human rights violations. PITCH addresses this urgent gap, and is reactive and responsive to local needs/urgencies that have been identified in its geographical foci.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31(0)206262669</telephone>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mubende, Kampala, Wakiso, Mukono and Busia</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Uganda ICWEA Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Uganda ICWEA Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-01">282000</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41207989-P-8809" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
