<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-22508</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Kenya WOFAK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of the PITCH project in Kenya, WOFAK and AYARHEP will conduct community dialogues on stigma and discrimination and SRHR; train AGYW on SRHR; train community health volunteers on human rights and service provision for AGYW involved in transactional sex; train community leaders on SRHR for AGYW; conduct continous medical education on human rights, stigma reduction, culture, values, communication and service provision in focus facilities; and lobby for improvement of laws and policies for AGYW, including AGWY who are engaged in sex work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Directly, this project will reach at least 500 AGYW and their communities with information and access to services; 100 AGYW and 20 community leaders with intensive training to uphold the rights of AGYW and 15 service providers. It reaches the wider community with information and awareness campaigns and through peer-to-peer training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH seeks to strengthen the capacities of local civil society organisations to advocate for sexual and reproductive health and rights, and uphold the human rights of key populations. Our work centres around key populations, adolescent girls and young women in nine countries in East, West and Southern Africa, South-East Asia, and Central Europe. These communities in many contexts carry the main HIV burden. At the same time, they are often neglected in the HIV response and face many barriers in accessing HIV and SRH services as well as human rights violations. PITCH addresses this urgent gap, and is reactive and responsive to local needs/urgencies that have been identified in its geographical foci.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WOFAK and AYARHEP contribute to the following ToC outcomes:
S1.1: Reduced stigma and discrimination regarding HIV and rights of KPs and AGYW amongst duty bearers, the general community, and within the KP and AGYW groups
S2: Unified, inclusive and collaborative advocacy agenda and strategies formulated and shared by all targeted KP and AGYW-led CSOs and  constituencies 
S3: KPs and AGYW-led CSOs and constituencies have improved capacity to capture and utilise evidence to support achievement of advocacy objectives 
S4: Strong and effective partnerships from national to local levels working collaboratively for the health and rights of KPs and AGYW
M1: Strong and inclusive coalitions, linking national and county levels, advocating with one voice for the Health and rights of KPs and AGYW 
M2: Increased political support  from all levels of government and other actors to drive changes in policies, laws and systems protecting and  promoting health and rights of KPs and AGYW 
M3.1: Functional and inclusive accountability spaces KPs and AGYW to engage with the government and other duty bearers from county to  national levels 
M3.2: Increased demand, with strong monitoring and accountability mechanisms, for high quality, KPs and AGYW competent SRHR services 
L1.1: The full continuum of HIV and SRHR services are accessible, available and acceptable country-wide for KPs and AGYW 
L1.2: Meaningful  engagement of KP and AGYW led CSOs with government and other duty bearers in decision-making processes for protecting and promoting health and rights for KPs and AGYW
L2.1: Full implementation of laws, policies and systems
L2.2: Reduced criminalisation for KPs, and reduced human rights violations for AGYW</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31(0)206262669</telephone>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nairobi, Kisumu, Homa Bay</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Kenya WOFAK Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Kenya WOFAK Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-01">580076</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41207989-P-8803" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
