<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-28301</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Nigeria EVA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">30 Adolescent girls and young women are intensively trained as youth advocates and mystery clients who assess service delivery for young people. Over 5,000 young people are involved in age of consent reduction activities. Many more young people and other stakeholders are reached through commemoration days, informative videos and awareness campaigns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EVA will contribute to the following ToC outcomes:
S2: Advocacy agenda developed &amp; stakeholders and opportunities for advocacy mapped.
M1.1: KP and AGYW communities are mobilised in CSOs and networks, and have the institutional and technical capacity to pursue their advocacy agenda.
M2.1: Increased public support among media, government representatives, traditional and religious leaders for the right and need of KP and AGYW to access health services. 
M3: KP and AGYW are aware and informed about their right to access health services, and how to access them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Nigeria, the policy is that HIV treatment is and must be free in public and private facilities. However, the reality is that most facilities including public facilities demand for payment. Meanwhile, these fees charged have devastating effects on AGYW access to services similar to age of consent. Hence, partners will include campaigns and advocacy in Abuja on ensuring that the Minister&#x2019;s declaration to keep HIV treatment free is marched with action to ensure that the user fees are actually removed. 

In Benue, the state has passed an Anti-HIV Discrimination law but awareness of the existence of the law and effective implementation remains a challenge. Secondly, steps have not been taken to review the language and content of the Act to determine its capacity to adequately cover the peculiar needs and concerns of AGYW. Therefore, in 2018, partners will include advocacy activities that will help address these issues on the Act.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH seeks to strengthen the capacities of local civil society organisations to advocate for sexual and reproductive health and rights, and uphold the human rights of key populations. Our work centres around key populations, adolescent girls and young women in nine countries in East, West and Southern Africa, South-East Asia, and Central Europe. These communities in many contexts carry the main HIV burden. At the same time, they are often neglected in the HIV response and face many barriers in accessing HIV and SRH services as well as human rights violations. PITCH addresses this urgent gap, and is reactive and responsive to local needs/urgencies that have been identified in its geographical foci.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31(0)206262669</telephone>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abuja, Benue</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Nigeria EVA Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Nigeria EVA Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-04-01">345840</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41207989-P-8814" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
