<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-9118-260</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging the Gaps: Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging the Gaps is alliance of nine international organisations and networks and more than 80 local and regional organisations, working towards the end of the AIDS epidemic among key populations. 
 
Supported by global and regional level work, Bridging the Gaps works with over 80 partner organisations in 15 countries in three regions: 
&#x2022; Sub-Sahara Africa: Botswana, Kenya, Mozambique, South Africa, Tanzania, Uganda, and Zimbabwe. 
&#x2022; South East Asia: Indonesia, Myanmar, Nepal, Vietnam. 
&#x2022; Eastern Europe and Central Asia: Georgia, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Ukraine. 
 
We work to realize effective needle and syringe exchange policies; an improved legal context for people who use drugs; and increased access to quality, comprehensive and accessible harm reduction services in Kathmandu Valley.

In Nepal, the programme works with, and for the health and human rights of, people who use drugs, including those living with HIV.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging the Gaps partners in Nepal work towards ending AIDS among key populations through (1) a strengthened civil society that holds government to account; (2) increased fulfilment of human rights of key populations; and (3) increased SRHR and fewer infections.

Through innovation, and by building on previous work in Nepal, we will strengthen civil society organisations&#x2019; ability to:

1. Facilitate community development, by:
&#x2022;  Building of national PWUD network;
&#x2022;  Facilitating community development on advocacy.

2. Advocate for the continuously strengthening of services and upholding human rights, by:
&#x2022;  Using evidence from the Human Rights Count (HRC) report on PWUD living with HIV (BtG 1) to build an advocacy campaign, and push for legislative and programmatic changes to ensure that the health and human rights needs of PLHIV drug users are advanced.

3. Deliver inclusive, rights-based and gender sensitive services, by:
&#x2022;  Implementing an efficient and high-quality Needle and Syringe Programme in Kathmandu Valley;
&#x2022;  Conducting size estimation of IDU&#x2019;s in Kathmandu Valley and conducting effective outreach;
&#x2022;  Training outreach workers on thematic skills and pilot outreach methods in the field.

4. Foster global and in-country processes and partnerships that reinforce results, by:
&#x2022;  Improving partnerships in-country with other NGOs, government, the Health &#x2022; 
&#x2022;  Council, and organisations that can assist in (data) management systems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People who use drugs</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-8828458" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INPUD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41209946" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mainline</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31(0)206262669</telephone>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kathmandu Valley</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="55" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging the Gaps: Nepal Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13040" percentage="39" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging the Gaps: Nepal STD control including HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="6" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging the Gaps: Nepal Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">1427129</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41207989-P-8811-260" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
