<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41207989-P-22501</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Uganda UNYPA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">500 young people directly with intensive training and capacity strengthening. Over 10,000 people at schools and in the community with right information, creating an enabling environment for YPLHIV</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of the PITCH project in Uganda, UNYPA will raise awareness among adolescent girls and young women (AGYW) and young people living with HIV so they can demand services, advocate and inform communities about SRH, GBV and stigma and discrimination. UNYPA will organize exchange learning visits among peer supporters to improve psycho-social support for YPLHIV at ART centers, conduct paralegal training on SRH for YPLHIV, facilitate AGYW and young people living with HIV to participate in key advocacy meetings and national celebrations to increasingly voice their rights, and will conduct in and out of school and community awareness campaigns to end HIV-related stigma and discrimination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH seeks to strengthen the capacities of local civil society organisations to advocate for sexual and reproductive health and rights, and uphold the human rights of key populations. Our work centres around key populations, adolescent girls and young women in nine countries in East, West and Southern Africa, South-East Asia, and Central Europe. These communities in many contexts carry the main HIV burden. At the same time, they are often neglected in the HIV response and face many barriers in accessing HIV and SRH services as well as human rights violations. PITCH addresses this urgent gap, and is reactive and responsive to local needs/urgencies that have been identified in its geographical foci.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNYPA contributes to the following ToC outcomes:    
S1.1 Communities are knowledgeable about health and rights for KPs and embrace efforts to address stigma and discrimination against KPs and AGYW. 
S1.2: Across the Healthcare systems (public, private and CSO-led) there is increased technical competency and improved attitudes to meet the specific SRHR needs of KPs and AGYW     
S2: Coordinated strategies for informed advocacy are developed, including identification of key stakeholders and opportunities for engagement on health and rights priorities for KPs and AGYW    
S3: Evidence is methodically collected for the purpose of evidence-based advocacy and research on health and rights priorities for KPs and AGYW     
S4: There is increased engagement and collaboration between CSOs, key stakeholders and potential champions to promote and protect the health and rights of KPs and AGYW  
M1: KP and AGYW-led CSOs country-wide are equipped with sufficient technical, human and financial resources to empower and mobilise their constituencies, both as individual organisations and as strong, united coalitions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41207989" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs Netherlands</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aidsfonds - Soaaids Nederland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31(0)206262669</telephone>
   <email>IATI@aidsfonds.nl</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pallisa, Nakapiripirit, Mbale, Kampala</narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Uganda UNYPA Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PITCH adolescent girls and young women Uganda UNYPA Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-01">243474</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41207989-P-8809" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
