<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27248</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baobab Resources</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baobab Resources Plc (Baobab or the company) is a London-based, AIM-listed (AIM ticker BAO) junior exploration company focused on exploring and developing mineral deposits in Mozambique. The company has a total of 25 prospecting licenses in Mozambique covering a large area of 4,760 km2. The two main prospects are the Manica Project Area and the Tete Project Area.     Baobabs main focus to date has been at the Manica Project Area, where the company has produced a JORC compliant copper resource with gold and silver credits. At the Tete Project Area, recent rock chip samples and aeromagnetic survey results indicate a high grade iron, titanium and vanadium system that extends over significantly great strike lengths.     Baobab is seeking IFCs engagement to help with general corporate purposes, including financing the companys exploration activities in the Republic of Mozambique in line with industry best practice in environmental and social sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFCs early involvement in Mozambiques growing mining sector will have an important demonstration effect in terms of setting environmental and social standards. IFC will assist Baobab to handle social, environmental, community development and mine closure issues in line with IFC Performance Standards on environmental and social sustainability.    The proposed IFC investment will contribute to continued exploration and associated feasibility studies. The direct development impacts during the pure exploration and feasibility study stage are expected to be limited. Nonetheless, key impacts that will be monitored during the exploration and feasibility study phase will include:    - employment;    - consultation with stakeholders including local communities and Government; and    - development of an appropriate environmental, social and community development plans for a mining exploitation project.     Because the investment predates any feasibility study, it is not yet possible to fully quantify or specify the potential development impacts during production stage. Potential development impacts at the mine production stage could include:     - local employment and sourcing;    - taxes, royalties and other payments to the government;    - technology and management skills transfer; and    - setting new environmental and social benchmarks for mining operations in Mozambique.    IFCs proposed investment is consistent with the World Banks Country Partnership Strategy covering the period FY08  11 that emphasizes the need for Mozambique to pursue a vision based on regional economic integration, promoting foreign direct investment and export enhancement.  Extractive industries are specifically mentioned as some of the sectors that should be developed to make optimal use of the countrys natural resource base to expand export earnings and facilitate rural development, a central theme of the joint IMF-WBG Action Plan for the Reduction of Absolute Poverty.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BAOBAB RESOURCES PLC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27248" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-11-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brett Townsend, Managing Director    49 Phillimore Street Fremantle Western Australia, 6160 Australia    Telephone Number +61 8 9430 7151 Fax Number +61 8 9430 7664 Email:    btownsend@baobabresources.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MZ-Mozambique">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Manica Project Area is in western Mozambique, close to the Zimbabwe border. The main Harare-Beira railway line passes within 10 kilometers, as does the Cabora Bassa power line, while the Chicamba hydro-electric scheme is also nearby. The major paved highway from Beira to Zimbabwe is 5 kilometers to the west, while access to the site is via a dirt road.  The Tete Project Area is located immediately north of the provincial capital of Tete. The railway connecting Tete to the deep water port of Beira is being refurbished, as is the port. Power is readily available from the Cabora Bassa hydroelectric scheme with additional schemes on the Zambezi River in advanced planning stages.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-18.2500000000 35.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BC - Copper</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $5.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-11-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-11-27">5000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-11-27">5000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BAOBAB RESOURCES PLC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27248/baobab-resources">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
