<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lempa Vivo: Sustainable and Participatory Management of the Ecosystems located in the Wetlands of the Lempa River Water Corridor</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il problema centrale che il Progetto intende affrontare &#xE8; il costante deterioramento degli ecosistemi del
Corridoio Idrico del Fiume Lempa, nonch&#xE9; le insufficienti capacit&#xE0; da parte delle istituzioni e della societ&#xE0;
civile locali di promuovere azioni di adattamento e mitigazione al cambiamento climatico. Ci&#xF2; &#xE8; dovuto
principalmente a: a) indebolimento dei servizi ecosistemici dovuto ai cambiamenti climatici e alle variazioni
del ciclo dell&#x2019;acqua (zone di ricarica degli acquiferi gravemente compromesse), incremento dell&#x2019;erosione e
diminuzione della fertilit&#xE0; del suolo che hanno condotto a una progressiva perdita di biodiversit&#xE0;; b) Deficit di
governance ambientale dovuto al malfunzionamento delle strutture di concertazione (Comitati Ramsar) e pi&#xF9;
in generale alla scarsa partecipazione della societ&#xE0; civile; c) Deficit di governabilit&#xE0; ambientale conseguenza di
evidenti disfunzioni nei processi decisionali gestiti dal MARN.
L&#x2019;intervento contribuisce al miglioramento degli ecosistemi del Corridoio Idrico del Fiume Lempa, e con ci&#xF2; le
capacit&#xE0; di adattamento ai cambiamenti climatici nel Salvador. Il fiume Lempa costituisce la risorsa idrica pi&#xF9;
importante del Paese ed il suo bacino rappresenta un territorio altamente strategico a livello nazionale e
internazionale. Non a caso, tale area assume una rilevanza prioritaria all&apos;interno del Programa Nacional de
Restauraci&#xF3;n de Ecosistemas y Paisajes. La proposta &#xE8; coerente con gli orientamenti strategici del MARN in
tema di Sicurezza Idrica, Ecosistemi e Biodiversit&#xE0; e Gestione Territoriale. L&#x2019;intervento una volta finalizzato
generer&#xE1; un significativo miglioramento delle condizioni degli ecosistemi di acqua dolce, e allo stesso tempo
un rafforzamento delle capacit&#xE0; delle istituzioni e della societ&#xE0; civile per una gestione sostenibile e
partecipativa di 4 delle 5 zone umide che conformano il Corridoio Idrico del Lempa (Complesso Guija, Bacino
Cerr&#xF3;n Grande, Bacino 5 Noviembre, Bacino 15 Septiembre): Risultati che si intende conseguire:
1. La popolazione dispone di sistemi resilienti al cambiamento climatico attraverso pratiche di
protezione e ripristino del paesaggio: 3.040 residenti nelle aree d&#x2019;intervento (1.456 donne, 1.584
uomini) si vedranno beneficiati dalla costruzione di opere di protezione del suolo, dall&#x2019;elaborazione di
sistemi di allerta contro gli incendi forestali e dalla creazione di 120 unit&#xE0; produttive agroecologiche a
conduzione familiare;
2. La societ&#xE0; civile aumenta la partecipazione nella promozione di politiche e programmi in materia
ambientale: il consolidamento delle strutture di concertazione (Comitati Ramsar, Piani ROLA e CECoP)
permetter&#xE0; a 4.020 persone (2.135 donne e 1.885 uomini) di rafforzare le loro capacit&#xE0; di
adattamento e resilienza agli effetti del cambiamento climatico;
3. Il MARN rafforza la propria funzione istituzionale nell&#x2019;applicazione del quadro normativo vigente in
materia ambientale con la partecipazione di altre istituzioni e della societ&#xE0; civile: 917 tecnici e
funzionari del MARN (a partire dalla Direzione Ecosistemi e Biodiversit&#xE0; e l&#x2019;Unit&#xE0; delle Guardie
Forestali) e 377 di altre istituzioni (tra cui ANDA e UES in qualit&#xE0; di partner) attualizzeranno i propri
strumenti e meccanismi di gestione sostenibile e partecipativa del territorio. A tal fine, fondamentale
sar&#xE0; l&#x2019;attivit&#xE0; di ricerca sui servizi ecosistemici condotta dall&#x2019;Universit&#xE0; Bicocca di Milano. Il progetto, della durata di 36 mesi, produrr&#xE0; un profondo e duraturo impatto su 3 distinti aspetti:
&#x25CF; Governance: rafforza le capacit&#xE0; dei partner locali (in particolare del MARN) e delle strutture di
concertazione territoriali (Comitati Ramsar);
&#x25CF; Incidenza: aggiorna e perfeziona il quadro giuridico vigente in materiale ambientale;
&#x25CF; Best practices: promuove nuove tecniche e metodologie per l&#x2019;adattamento ai cambiamenti climatici e
la ricerca in tema di servizi ecosistemici.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main problem that the project intends to face is the Lempa River Water Corridor&#x2019;s degradation of
ecosystems, along with the insufficient capacities of public institutions and civil society to promote adaptation
actions to climate change. The main causes of the above issue are: a) Deterioration of ecosystem services due
to climate change and variations in the water cycle (aquifer recharge zones in danger); increasing of erosion
and loss of soil fertility that have led to a progressive loss of biodiversity; b) Deficit of environmental
governance due to malfunction of the structures for consultation (Ramsar Local Committees) and more
generally limited involvement of the civil society; c) Deficits in environmental governability resulting from
evident dysfunctions in the decision-making processes managed by MARN. The project shall contribute to
improve Lempa River Water Corridor&#x2019;s ecosystems and increases levels of adaptation to climate change in El
Salvador. The Lempa River represent the most important water resource in the country: its basin is a highly
strategic territory at both national and international level. Not surprisingly, therefore, the area assumes high
priority within the Programa Nacional de Restauraci&#xF3;n de Ecosistemas y Paisajes. The proposal is consistent
with MARN&apos;s strategic guidelines: Water Safety; Ecosystems and Biodiversity; Territorial management. Once
finalized, the Intervention will generate a significant improvement in the conditions of freshwater ecosystems and at the same time a strengthening of the capacities of institutions and civil society for a sustainable and
participatory management of 4 (of the 5) Wetlands that conform the Trifinio Fraternidad transboundary
Biosphere reserve (Giuja Complex, Cerr&#xF3;n Grande Reservoir, 5 Noviembre Basin, 15 Septiembre Basin): Results to be achieved:
1. The population has systems resilient to climate change through landscape protection and restoration
practices: 3.040 residents in the intervention areas (1.456 women, 1.584 men) will benefit from the
construction of soil protection works, from the development of warning systems against forest fires
and the creation of 120 family-run agroecological production units;
2. Civil society increases participation in the promotion of environmental policies and programs: the
consensus-building spaces&#x2019; enhancement (Ramsar Committees, ROLA and CEPA&#x2019;s Plans) will allow
4.020 (2.135 women, 1.885 men) people to strengthen their adaptability and resilience to the impacts
of climate change;
3. MARN strengthens its institutional function in the application of the current regulatory framework on
environmental matters with the participation of other institutions and civil society: 917 MARN
technicians and officials (starting from the Ecosystem and Biodiversity Directorate and the Forest
Guard Unit) and 377 of other institutions (including ANDA and UES as partners) will update their tools
and mechanisms for sustainable and participatory management of the territory. To this end, the
research activity on ecosystem services conducted by the Bicocca University of Milan will be
fundamental.
The project will operate at 4 territorial levels: The project, over its 36-month duration, will produce a profound and lasting impact on 3 distinct aspects:
&#x25CF; Governance: by strengthening the partners (especially the MARN) and the consensus-building spaces
(Ramsar Local Committees);
&#x25CF; Impact: by updating and perfecting the existing environmental regulatory framework;
&#x25CF; Best practices: by promoting new techniques and methodologies for adaptation to climate change
and for research on ecosystem services</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISTITUTO SINDACALE PER LA COOPERAZIONE ALLO SVILUPPO ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/02/8" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SV" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="35" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biodiversity</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="31161" percentage="15" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food crop production</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="15.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, ensure the conservation, restoration and sustainable use of terrestrial and inland freshwater ecosystems and their services, in particular forests, wetlands, mountains and drylands, in line with obligations under international agreements</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, protect and restore water-related ecosystems, including mountains, forests, wetlands, rivers, aquifers and lakes</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, combat desertification, restore degraded land and soil, including land affected by desertification, drought and floods, and strive to achieve a land degradation-neutral world</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improve education, awareness-raising and human and institutional capacity on climate change mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrate climate change measures into national policies, strategies and planning</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protect, restore and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt biodiversity loss</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Take urgent action to combat climate change and its impacts</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-09">1799250.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISTITUTO SINDACALE PER LA COOPERAZIONE ALLO SVILUPPO ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">1079550.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ISTITUTO SINDACALE PER LA COOPERAZIONE ALLO SVILUPPO ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
