<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="94" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3733" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-IOCC-ET-11-3733</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved Wheelchair Access for People with Disabilities (PWD)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1.	Support and strengthen the provision of wheelchairs: Wheelchair assembly and production activities will be implemented by Cheshire Services Ethiopia (CSE) in partnership with United Cerebral Palsy Wheels for Humanity (UCP WFH) and Whirlwind Wheelchairs International (WWI); 2,900 beneficiaries will receive wheelchairs.

2.	Improve the capabilities, quality and appropriateness of wheelchair production: CSE will receive training facilitated by UCP WFH and deliver workshops to users; 2,923 beneficiaries will receive training.

3.	Promote sport activities for wheelchair users: The Ethiopian Center for Disability and Development (ECDD) will implement sports events, training and capacity-building for wheelchair users; 1,946 beneficiaries and 11 organizations will benefit from these activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to create a sustainable and cost-effective wheelchair development, delivery and participatory program to meet the needs of PWDs affected by mobility impairments. The project&#x2019;s approach is designed to build upon the capacity of local stakeholders and focus on inclusiveness and empowerment training. International Orthodox Christian Charities (IOCC) has assembled a strong team of recognized local and international organizations with expertise and experience working in wheelchair service delivery and with PWDs in Ethiopia in addition to its partnership with the largest faith-based network in Ethiopia, the Ethiopian Orthodox Church Development Inter-Church Aid Commission (EOC-DICAC).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Orthodox Church Development Inter-Church Aid Commission (EOC-DICAC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-25-1679348" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Orthodox Christian Charities (IOCC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="IOCC-ET-11-3733" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-12" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-12" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Orthodox Christian Charities (IOCC)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.iocc.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
