<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41149831-26097-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41149831" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mensen met een Missie</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Freedom of Religion and Belief - Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Strengthening voices of local actors of peace, including women and youth, which will increase their capacity to promote greater mutual respect and understanding among religious communities, and contribute to sustainable, peaceful relations in conflict-prone areas; 2. Sensitizing voices will raise awareness among relevant stakeholders, including high school and university students, media, local authorities and police officers, so they can be more effective in promoting religious freedom within their social, home, and work environments; 3. Connecting voices will establish links and cooperative relationships among relevant actors at the local, national and international levels to build a broad support base for freedom of religion and belief, and a more effectively lobby for legal and policy reform.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For strengthening voices the target groups are: Local leaders, local religious leaders, members from partnerorganisations. Especially women and youth. For sensitizing voices the target groups are: Students, local authorities and police, broader public (awareness raising). For connecting voices the target groups are: like-minded authorities, organisations and institutions; local and national government bodies; European Union, United Nations. Capacity building and Linking &amp; Learning: partnerorganisations of Mensen met een Missie.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities in Indonesia are implemented by four partners: Fahmina, Mosintuwu, Imparsial and Interfidei.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="318.2012" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fahmina - Since its establishment in 2000, Fahmina has focused on issues of pluralism, religious freedom and the protection of minorities. From 2007 to 2009, Fahmina facilitated the establishment of a network of organisations that focused on monitoring of and advocacy for the freedom of religion and belief in West Java. Fahmina is connected to many organisations and institutions both locally and nationally that work on religious freedom. Through its network, Fahmina is sharing experiences to increase its capacities and increase the effectiveness of its activities.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="318.1976" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imparsial - Imparsial is a human rights organisation based in Jakarta (national level organisation) that focuses on the role of security actors (military, police and intelligence) related to human rights, including pluralism and religious tolerance, for example by monitoring whether the security actors protect or attack pluralism and religious tolerance. Imparsial conducts research, lobby and public advocacy to support pluralism and religious tolerance.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="318.2010" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interfidei - Interfidei was established in 1991, and existed during five different Presidential governments. It was the first interfaith NGO in Indonesia, and is working together with many different stakeholders, like other NGOs, universities, school, religious institutions and leaders, journalists and government authorities. Educating and developing the National Interfaith Network is one of Interfidei&#x2019;s main activities. This network has developed very well and has a strong positive influence in society.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mensen met een Missie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="318.1993" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mosintuwu - Since its inception in 2009, the Mosintuwu Institute is working for religious tolerance and women emancipation in in the post-conflict region of Poso. The Women school is one of the core activities of Mosintuwu Institute. The aim is to dismantle prejudice and trauma amongst women from different religious and ethnic background and to build self-trust in women who have been victims of the conflict in Poso. After graduation, many women have become facilitators for next batches or leaders in local communities.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia has long been proud of its diverse ethnicity, cultures and spiritual beliefs. However, recent attacks on minority groups such as the Ahmadiyah community and on Christian churches show that religious tolerance is on the decline. Indonesia is the country with the largest Muslim population (86%) in the world and consequently also the largest democracy in the Islamic world. There has been an increase in religious violence in the last decade. Religious minorities are more often confronted with intimidation, discrimination and violence. This programme partly focuses on the Muslim-Christian conflict in Poso, Sulawesi. During the period 1999-2001, waves of interreligious and interethnic violence took place in this area. These waves of violence were all sparked by smaller incidents between the Muslim and Christian communities in the area. In total, the violence has taken the lives of over 500 people, and over 80,000 persons were internally displaced.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6.249776453227819 106.5673828125</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
  </location>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="40"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">292.074</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">379.622</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">176.722</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">173.394</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="26097" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="26097-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="26097-3" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
