<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IT-CF-00677540288-Q6</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IT-CF-00677540288" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM - Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 6</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this programme is to support the Government of Sierra Leone (GoSL) to reduce maternal, neonatal and under-5 mortality and morbidity by increasing utilisation of quality Reproductive, Maternal, Neonatal, Child and Adolescent Health (RMNCAH) services. This will be achieved through a multifaceted approach to strengthen quality, expand access, and build the demand for RMNCAH services in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21000" ref="IT-CF-00677540288" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM - Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM- DOCTORS WITH AFRICA
UNITE FO SEV LAYF NA SALONE &#x2013; ACTIVITY SUMMARY QUARTERLY REPORT
QUARTER SIX &#x2013; APRIL &#x2013; JUNE, 2020
Output 3
Obstetric and pediatric referrals done from SLiSL facilities this quarter include; 38 &amp; 4 and 68 &amp; 111 referrals respectively for Bonthe and Pujehun. In riverine facilities, obstetric boat referrals completed include: 11 in Pujehun and 48  in Bonthe.   Questionnaire to HCWs on the use of the referral forms was completed this quarter and this activity was led by the CCU. Two facilities in Pujehun reported low level of new referral forms OUT. Since the forms were to be additionally printed  by WHO and it is still not done, CUAMM supported the request of the DMO to print additional copies using DHMT operational fund.

Bonthe and Pujehun had 97% and 34% availability of minimum amount of blood throughout the quarter in Bonthe government and Pujehun Government hospital.   Bonthe had average of 29.3/30.3 days&#x2019; minimum quantity of blood on a daily basis throughout the quarter and Pujehun had on average 10.3/30.3 days&#x2019; minimum blood availability in the bank. 94 (UBC 61 &amp; BGH 33) and 99 units (Pujehun Government Hospital) of 450ml of blood was donated. The breakage of blood bank refrigerator since March has contributed to Pujehun not having enough fridge capacity to maintain required daily minimum blood balance in the hospital. A temporary fridge provided is not big to hold enough blood bags. 

However, a new blood bank fridge with support from SLiSL project was prepositioned to the hospital this quarter and training and installation on the use of the new fridge is planned in July. CUAMM commemorated World Blood Donor day this 14th of June 2020 in observance of COVID 19 measures. The activity was done in collaboration with DHMT, Red cross, district council, SLiSL partners and blood donor volunteers groups piloted in CUAMM districts. The activity was climaxed with role plays on voluntary donation and recognition of regular donors identified in CUAMM district.   Due to COVID, the community sensitisation meetings and blood drives were conducted in small groups, taking into account the COVID precautions.  

Output 4 
This quarter, in collaboration with DHMT, 243 Community Health Workers were trained on selected RMNCAH topics with key focus on referrals and follow up on defaulters for pediatric (EPI) and obstetric cases in four hard to reach chiefdoms in Bonthe: Kwamebaikrim, Benducha, Sogbini and Yawbeko in Bonthe.  This training is done as a result of low immunization and poor referrals outcome observed in these challenging areas in the district.  Amidst the COVID, another 300 CHWs in Bonthe, 103 CHWs and 43 Mother Support Groups (MSG) members in Pujehun were given one day training each on IPC and COVID and how to help to improve on patient confidence, referral and adherence to visiting the health facilities during the corona surge. The training provided had helped to build confidence in health care service delivery to community beneficiaries, improve on clinical attendance and education on COVID 19 essential messaging on spread and prevention. This activity was jointly done in collaboration with DHMT and DICOVERC. (District covid emergency response)
Chiefdom level supportive supervision, head by Community Health Officers was ongoing this month in both districts.  The supervision completed this quarter has helped in divers&#x2019; ways thus: improving on mentorship and coaching to lower cadre staff at lower PHUs (MCHA) within the chiefdom, identify quick fix problems in PHUs and report to DHMT for solution, improve on data management and reporting.   

Improving on RMNCAH through mentorship, no mentee assessment was done.  Waiting till the server error CommCare is solved to be able to upload the data afterwards.  Tihun CHC mentees did reach the score above 85% in the last assessment thus competent in minimum standards for a BEmONC facility.  28 mentees received mentorship in CUAMM district, 12 in Bonthe and 16 in Pujehun. All mentee was reached this quarter with mentorship activity. Although in June there was once again one drop out in Delken (Bonthe).
Staff motivation Award was done to best performing PHUs in the two districts. Pujehun Awarded four best performing PHUs and Bonthe Awarded six.  The criterial used for both awards were deduced from the recent ISSV matrix collated for both districts. Key of the indicators looked at were: IPC, Data, EPI and Staff attendance scores from the integrated ISSV matrix collated.  
 
Output6
Six PHU staff in-charges meeting were done this quarter, 3 in Pujehun and 3 in Bonthe. Data presentation done in all the meetings conducted. Five health partner meetings were held this time. Bonthe did not have one in May as they were overwhelmed with response to COVID-19 positive cases prevalent in their district. Seven action points were developed in both district this quarter 3/3 in Bonthe and 3/4 in Pujehun and were achieved against the due date set. 
The second quarter Bonthe reported 8 Maternal Deaths and Pujehun reported 6 maternal deaths.  A cumulative of 12 and 15 maternal deaths have occurred in Bonthe and Pujehun in the 1st and 2nd quarter of 2020.  Out of these deaths 6 &amp;11 is been investigated and reviewed in Bonthe and Pujehun in 2020.  Most of the deaths occur in June and there are plans to conduct review and investigation early in July of next quarter. 6/10 and 13/14 action points were followed up on 3&amp;5 deaths investigated and reviewed in 1 &amp; 3 meeting in Bonthe and Pujehun.  
This half year of 2020, in a short analysis done by CUAMM, it was realised that Bonthe had registered more deaths this year when compared to 2019 year. By this time last year, Bonthe had 6 deaths against 12 deaths this 2020. A meeting was held with Bonthe DHMT this quarter and they were informed on the observation done. Attributing problems identified include: late referrals done by PHU staff and community, Dema and Imperi  chiefdom accounting for most of the deaths, lack of appropriate equipment in  hospital lab to conduct further diagnosis, low knowledge of PHU staff  observed in patient management,  Boat location at Tombay causing challenge in riverine communities, COVID-19 impact (Pujehun and Bo Districts  refusing referrals from Bonthe),  relocation of NEMS ambulance from a PHU in  Imperi to DHMT with no replacement,  stock out of suture and blood cleansing reagents in theatre and hospital lab, lack of consistent supportive supervision from DHS office, DHMT and EPI among others were listed. Action points were developed on the identified challenges and CUAMM is closely working with DHMT to address the action points.    
There was no ISSV planned this quarter.  Activities implemented this quarter on average according to the AWP for CUAMM districts were 12/21 for Bonthe and 13/22 for Pujehun from the SLiSL funded activities. In both districts 18 activities are conducted at least one time during the quarter.    
Output 8
COVID- 19  index case for Sierra Leone confirmed on the 31st of March 2020, impacted one way or the other in activitied completed this quarter. The novel corona out break at its initial outbreak was new and preparedness and respons was challenge with both finincial and human resource. As the quarter went by, new stratergies were developed to both preparedness  response.
CUAMM is supporting the bloodbank regarding lab test and items. Lately MOHS is late responding to emails from the MS requesting items, which results in delay of the supply chain. In addition, the districts are requesting for Sangofix. However, Sangofix are usually provided together with the bloodbags and are normally not for sale in commercial pharmacies as we do understaand. Due to lack of sangofix, patients are more at risk for blood transfusion reaction.  
Some mentors are reporting that some Medical Doctors are not trained on the EMONC and IMNCI protocol, which makes it challanging for the mentees to adhere to these guidelines</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM-Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
