<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IT-CF-00677540288-Q2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IT-CF-00677540288" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM - Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this programme is to support the Government of Sierra Leone (GoSL) to reduce maternal, neonatal and under-5 mortality and morbidity by increasing utilisation of quality Reproductive, Maternal, Neonatal, Child and Adolescent Health (RMNCAH) services. This will be achieved through a multifaceted approach to strengthen quality, expand access, and build the demand for RMNCAH services in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="Q2" ref="IT-CF-00677540288" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM - Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM- DOCTORS WITH AFRICA UNITE FO SEV LAYF NA SALONE - ACTIVITY QUARTERLY REPORT QUARTER TWO &#x2013; APRIL - JUNE 2019 MAIN ACTIVITY COMPLETED DURING THE QUARTER ACHIEVEMENT &#x2022; Coordination of health partners meeting &#x2022; Six District Health Partners Coordination meeting were also conducted during this quarter. (3 in Bonthe and 3 in Pujehun) This meeting had helped to bring partners together to discuss over aching health challenges observed in the district by DHMT and partners and finding ways to improve on those challenges &#x2022; Support to PUH In charges Meting &#x2022; CUAMM in collaboration with DHMT completed five monthly PHU in-charges meeting with data presentation, training on Patograph and discussion of action points of maternal death that has relevance to the in charges meeting. &#x2022; The in charges meeting strengthen the performance of PHU in charges on information sharing, data reporting and data quality for decision making. Out of the five meetings done this quarter, three were done in Bonthe and two done in Pujehun &#x2022; Maternal death Investigation &#x2022; Five maternal deaths occurred this quarter in Bonthe and Eight in Pujehun. Line listing &amp; Investigation were done to ascertain causes of death. &#x2022; Maternal deaths review Meetings completed with action points &#x2022; Bonthe death was reviewed with clear action points and followed up done. In Pujehun out of the eight deaths, all of them have been investigated and 3 have been reviewed with clear action points developed and closely followed by CUAMM. &#x2022; Support to development of standard operating procedures (SOPs) &#x2022; This quarter, one SoP on fuel management in the hospital generator for provision of adequate lightning in the hospital was done. The document was pretested to the hospital of Bonthe and Pujehun last month and seems to be working fine. The remaining SoP on HR, Equipment&#x2019;s and hospital procedure will be done later. &#x2022; CUAMM regarded as one of the medical organizations in the SLISL consortium and lead on the blood bank, this quarter did a draft SoP on how to conduct a recommended community blood donation drive and the document was shared with the consortium for adaptation to other non-CUAMM district and communities. &#x2022; Integrated Supportive supervision and other supervisions &#x2022; Supportive supervision with ISSV check list was done to in 14 PHUs in Bonthe and 10 supportive supervision on data verification was done in Pujehun without using ISSV check list. &#x2022; Support to Pediatrics and obstetric referrals &#x2022; CUAMM support to hard to reach riverine communities this quarter supported 54 obstetric referral cases to the Comprehensive Emergency Obstetric Care Service (CeMOC) with 34 referrals done to Bonthe Government Hospital and 20 to Pujehun Government hospital. The referrals completed are in conformity with NEMS protocol on referral procedure followed on main land country wide &#x2022; During the reporting period, CUAMM had worked with 12 CHC on availability of referral forms developed at district level to support pediatrics and obstetric referrals. It has been ensured that 5 facility in Bonthe and 7 in Pujehun had been supported with referral documentation. &#x2022; The challenge is that, the referrals forms used are not uniform in both districts. There are plan to make uniformity of the referral&#x2019;s forms in before the end of 2019 by MoHS and its partners. &#x2022; RMNCHA and EmONC trainings conducted &#x2022; CUAMM clinical mentors during the quarter have receive additional training on data for decision making, VCAT for family planning and abortion care for Women and Adolescence and ETAT through the SLiSL II consortium training plan for clinical mentors &#x2022; Mentorship on EmONC and IMNCI &#x2022; CUAMM initiated mentorship activity this quarter. Bilateral meeting on mentorship frame work with DHMT teams of both districts was done. In the meetings done, criteria to select a MOHS staff mentee was discussed. Pre selection at DHMT and final selection at PHU level of 24 mentees were done using a selection criterion. 10 mentees are assigned to support 5 selected facilities in Bonthe and 14 assigned to support 7 facilities with RMNCHA activities in Pujehun. &#x2022; Blood Donation Activities Supported &#x2022; In this quarter CUAMM supported blood bank of Pujehun government hospital with 109 units of 450ml of bloods from its community blood donation drive campaigns. Bonthe Government Hospital blood bank were supported with 47 units of 450 ml of blood and Mattru UBC hospital with 25 units of 450 mls &#x2022; Hospital blood bank assessment was completed by CUAMM blood bank specialist Mauro, made the report of the assessment available this quarter. From the report a lot of information on how viable the hospital blood bank will look like has been provided to IRC who happen to be the CCU lead. &#x2022; To foster sustainability and promote voluntary blood donation drive, CUAMM in collaboration with DHMT, Pujehun Government hospital, Pujehun District Council, have initiated to pilot the formation of blood donor volunteers&#x2019; groups in four communities in Pujehun. The groups will serve as donors and ambassadors on voluntary blood donation drive in their communities and Pujehun district as a whole. &#x2022; DHMT/Hospital Operation support &#x2022; This quarter in order to increase on the functionality of DHMT, CUAMM supported the Installation of internet service at DHMT and supported commencement of minor repairs of two water well and one toilets pit at Bonthe government hospital. &#x2022; Pujehun was supported with rehabilitation of the Maternity ward and one emptying of toilet pit in the government hospital of Pujehun. CUAMM also facilitate the smooth running of DHMT office and hospital operations by ensuring daily supply of fuel for generators to ensure provision of electricity in the Facilities. &#x2022; Flexible fund supports &#x2022; CUAMM collaborated with DHMTs of Bonthe and Pujehun to support one Measles and Rubella (M &amp;R) campaign done from the 10-16 of May 2019. &#x2022; CUAMM collaborated with DHMTs of Bonthe and Pujehun to support the Commemoration of world blood donor day at district level on the 14th of May 2019. &#x2022; Others Activities completed &#x2022;</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM- Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
