<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IT-CF-00677540288-4538</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IT-CF-00677540288" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM - Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saving Lives in Sierra Leone: Phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this programme is to support the Government of Sierra Leone (GoSL) to reduce maternal, neonatal and under-5 mortality and morbidity by increasing utilisation of quality Reproductive, Maternal, Neonatal, Child and Adolescent Health (RMNCAH) services. This will be achieved through a multifaceted approach to strengthen quality, expand access, and build the demand for RMNCAH services in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="IT-CF-00677540288" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM - Doctors with Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-5660870" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee, The</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CUAMM- DOCTORS WITH AFRICA UNITE FO SEV LAYF NA SALONE &#x2013; ACTIVITY SUMMARY QUARTERLY REPORT QUARTER ONE &#x2013; JAN - MARCH, 2019 MAIN ACTIVITY COMPLETED DURING THE QUARTER ACHIEVEMENT &#x2022; Coordination of health partners meeting &#x2022; CUAMM supported 4 District coordination meetings where activities and plans of the district were discussed. Of the 14 actions agreed, only 6 were completed by the end of the quarter for the two supported districts &#x2022; Support to PUH In charges Meting &#x2022; Four PHU staff in-charges meeting was done in Pujehun and Bonthe. Data presentation done in both meeting was captioned on EPI coverage, ANC 1 VS ANC 4 and Infection Prevention and Control (IPC) practice in PHUs. &#x2022; Maternal death Investigation &#x2022; A total of 9 maternal deaths were reported in the two districts (3 Bonthe, 6 Pujehun). &#x2022; Maternal deaths review Meetings completed with action points &#x2022; Two review meetings conducted per district to review 4 maternal deaths. Nine action point was developed in Pujehun and Bonthe had 3 action point developed. In Bonthe all three-action point was achieved. None was reached in Pujehun. &#x2022; MDSR community feedback meeting was conducted in both districts from recommendations and action points made from review meting conducted. &#x2022; Support to development of standard operating procedures (SOPs.) &#x2022; CUAMM started the development of SOPs related to fuel support and they are expected to be discussed and endorsed by the DHMT in the next quarter &#x2022; Integrated Supportive supervision and other supervisions &#x2022; CUAMM also supported the DHMT Integrated Supportive Supervision in Bonthe district where 51 PHUs were visited and of these, 50 PHUs submitted a completed checklist to the DHMT. Action points from this activity were actioned with one pending for the repair of drug cupboards on ANC couches and was later followed and achieved in previous quarter. &#x2022; Apart from the ISSV data cleaning exercise was completed to 15 PHUs in Bonthe district. This exercise helped PHUs on data quality and recording. &#x2022; Support to Pediatrics and obstetric referrals &#x2022; There was no support to this activity as there were no clinical mentors in operation this time &#x2022; RMNCHA and EmONC trainings conducted &#x2022; CUAMM conducted 10 days EmONC training for 37 District Clinical Mentors (DCMs) in March. The training was co-facilitated by MoHS EmONC coordinators. Pre and post test scores were 62% and 86% respectively. CUAMM also co-facilitated together with IRC and MoHS a four days mentorship model training 37 clinical mentors of the consortium this quarter as well. &#x2022; Mentorship on EmONC and IMNCI &#x2022; The recruitment of District Clinical Mentors was completed in this quarter, out of four DCMs for CUAMM, three is on seconded by the MoHS. &#x2022; CUAMM collaborated with other Consortium partners to finalized the Mentorship framework a document that will be used as a guide for the mentorship piece of the saving lives project. &#x2022; Blood Donation Activities Supported &#x2022; A joint blood bank assessment was conducted between CUAMM and the MoHS blood bank manager in 10 supported district hospitals and 1 mission hospital (UBC) as per request by MoHS Laboratory and Blood services director. This activity was supported by CUAMM blood bank specialist for the saving lives project. &#x2022; CUAMM in Pujehun supported two (2) mobile blood drives at Bandajuma and Zimmi where seventy-five (75) units of blood were collected for each drive. Bonthe did one static blood drive and fifteen units of blood were collected and the hospital utilise an average of eleven (11) units per month). &#x2022; DHMT/Hospital Operation support &#x2022; CUAMM supported the two Districts and Hospitals in implementing other activities in the AWPs, including: daily fuel for generators, communication support, stationery, data cleaning exercise. This support was given to both DHMT and hospital operation. &#x2022; Flexible fund supports &#x2022; Others Activities completed &#x2022; In January 2019, CUAMM supported the DHMT of Pujehun in responding to the Measles outbreak in Pujehun where 4 cases had been confirmed positive. Support was offered for active case search, line listing and laboratory investigations for the 17 affected communities; this was followed by 17 community meetings in the affected 4 chiefdoms with CHWs conducting village, house and market awareness. Radio discussions and 2 district coordination meetings were supported</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sierra Leone has one of the highest maternal mortality rates (MMR) in the world, with 1,360 deaths per 100,000 live births (DHS SL 2013). One in 17 women in Sierra Leone will die in pregnancy or childbirth. Nearly half (47%) of maternal deaths are adolescent girls. Although one in four (28%) girls aged 15-19 have begun childbearing, this is often not by their own choice. Four in five (83%) pregnant girls report not having wanted to get pregnant, 55% were not in school or had dropped out, and 50% of sexually-active girls report having been forced into sexual intercourse (UNICEF). Contributing factors include inadequate access to contraception and to safe abortion care, and adolescent girls&#x2019; lack of agency over sexual relationships. In Sierra Leone, infant mortality stands at roughly 35 deaths per 1,000 live births, and 12 in 100 children die before their fifth birthday (DHS SL 2013). Neonatal deaths account for almost half of under-5 deaths in Sub-Saharan Africa (WHO) and are closely associated with the quality of prenatal and delivery care, and the age of the mother, with infant mortality more prevalent among younger mothers (WHO). It is well-understood that improving the quality of services along the RMNCAH continuum of care is vital to reducing maternal, neonatal and under-5 mortality and improving health outcomes. The proposed programme therefore aims to reduce maternal, neonatal and under-5 mortalities and morbidities by improving the quality of RMNCAH services and availability of family planning services, particularly for adolescents. In doing so, it will directly address many of the main obstacles to women&#x2019;s, girls&#x2019; and children&#x2019;s lives and health outcomes in Sierra Leone.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">241858</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">911897</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">1381978</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-31">54844</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 1, October 2018 to December 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-31">184511</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 2, from January 1st, 2019 to March 31st, 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-06-30">175582</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 3, from April 1st 2019 to June 30st 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-30">136701</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 4 from July 1st 2019 to September 30st 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-31">312110</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 5, from October 1st 2019 to December 31st 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-31">237773</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarter 6, from January 1st 2020 to March 31st 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="US-EIN-13-5660870">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-23">189938</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC- International Rescue Committee Inc" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-06">19181</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC- International Rescue Committee Inc"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-17">220819</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC- International Rescue Committee Inc"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-31">124744</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC- International Rescue Committee Inc"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-23">312110</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC- International Rescue Committee Inc"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-10">237772.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC-International Rescue Committee" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="US-EIN-13-5660870">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-03">257323.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="US-EIN-13-5660870-DF194" ref="IRC-International Rescue Committee" type="21"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">2514760</value>
   <provider-org ref="IRC-International Rescue Committee"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CUAMM- Doctors with Africa"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
