<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>JO-MSD-200159274-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="JO-MSD-200159274" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JoWomenomics</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integral Development Center for Policy Research and Innovation Advancement (Think Tank)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Feminist Integrated Center for Research and Innovation (FICRI) is a new independent, nonpartisan think tank based in Amman, Jordan. FICRI aims to establish local talent of thought leaders committed to holistic, evidence-based approaches in research to tackling feminist realities in Jordan.

Using the &#x201C;Ficr Circles&#x201D; approach, FICRI builds the capacity of young researchers, human rights activists, gender specialists, anthropologists, social scientists, and lawyers to conduct high-quality feminist research built on a multi-disciplinary/transdisciplinary, socially accountable, diverse, and holistic knowledge-production approach.

FICRI seeks to improve the dissemination of such research to all stakeholders to inform new perspectives on feminism, diversity, and inclusions, which prevents feminist changes from occurring and being accepted by the broader community.
FICRI links to existing coalitions in the region to disseminate knowledge and to assist them in advocacy-related activities. This is achieved by mobilizing young leaders and paving the way for them to lead such change. FICRI focuses on evidence-based feminist research methodology and facilitates policy reform and community engagement. Eventually, FICRI hopes to see policy changes on the national scale, and such changes are welcomed and accepted by stakeholders and individuals at both the national and community levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="IATI-DAC-7-PPR-4000003163" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Duration: 3 years</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15164" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="JOD" value-date="2020-11-25">219265.85</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
