<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-RA000220-VR3810-ETH1210-21</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-RA000220-VR3810" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency live-saving Multi-Sectoral Response for drought affected communities in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As per the latest census data from Ethiopian Central statistical agency , the average household size is 5.7 to 6 persons and hence 2500 households (15,000 people) will benefit from animal feed and multi-purpose cash grant and and hygiene promotion as well as COVID control and prevention activities.  the targeting will consider the level of vulnerability and drought impact of each household and particularly target women, female headed households, elderly and people with disability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of this intervention is to save the lives of drought affected communities and also to contribute toward resiliency of the affected community to the recurrent drought effect through the provision of multi-sectoral WASH, livestock feed and multi-sectoral cash.

The specific objectives are: Save the lives and livelihood of drought affected pastoralist community through provision of WASH, cash and livelihood support; Enhance the livelihood and self-resilience of drought hit pastoralist communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is a severe drought due to shortage of Hageyya/Bega rain in the area. The expected rain in September and October is delayed resulted critical water shortage for both human and animals, shortage in livestock feed and pasture and animal death, displacement as well as disrupted and affected the socio-economic status of the pastoralist communities. More than half a million-pastoralist people are significantly affected by the drought with their livestock.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1159483" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-11-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-11-18">200000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
