<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DE-CR-RA000220-VR3810-UGA-1066-17</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DE-CR-RA000220-VR3810" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">User centred Sanitation Design</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adaptation and use of rapid community engagement methodologies to understand the sanitation needs and practices of communities affected by emergencies</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Innovation Fund: Rapid Community Engagement Project</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 1t proposed project setting is Imvepi settlement in Arua District where 135,000 South Sudanese refugees were settled and lmvepi thereby reached its full capacity. Even though the location was hence closed for new arrivals by July 31,2017, the sanitation gap at lmvepi settlement is huge. Household latrine coverage in the settlement is at only 3% (August 31, 2017), communal latrine density is at 1:45. Therefore adequate sanitation services are urgently needed. The 2nd project setting 15 Bidibidi settlement in Yumbe district, 40 km away from lmyepi Camp. Bidibidi, Uganda&#x2018;s biggest refugee settlement, reached its full capacity and is currently a home to more than 276,000 South Sudanese refugees with settlements extending over 250 km&#xB2;. With an overall latrine coverage of only 40% and even less coverage in some zones (e.g. 17% in Zone 4), there is a huge need for sanitation interventions. Moreover, some areas at Bidibidi settlement are prone to floods, in May 2017 392 households and in July 2017 200 households were affected by floods and relocated to safer locations within Bidibidi settlement, sanitation facilities are still lacking. This leads to an urgent need of appropriately designed facilities. The direct beneficiaries include 300 HH who benefit from latrine materials in accordance with the user centered design 100 HH of people with special needs (PSN) who will be assisted in construction of their HH latrine. 500 HH who will receive hygiene kits (including hand washing facilities (tippy taps)).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="UGA-1066-17" ref="DE-CR-RA000220-VR3810" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-213890" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deutsche Welthungerhilfe e. V.</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+49 (0) 228-2288 0</telephone>
   <email>info@welthungerhilfe.de</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-11-24"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-24">200000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
