<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30963</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">City Express International</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hoteles City Express, S.A.P.I. de C.V. (City Express or the Company) is engaged in development and operation of business hotels for the middle and middle low income markets in Mexico and Latin America.  City Express International (the Project) consists of the development of new hotels in Latin America and Mexico. This expansion will include up to 5 new hotels in Costa Rica and Colombia via a Joint-Venture with Hospiteum Corporation (Hospiteum) one of the few established Central American hotel owner and operators, (the Central America Expansion). The Project will also include an IFC and AMC/ALAC collaboration to support City Express expansion in Latin America including Chile (the Latin America Expansion). Finally, the proposed project will also include a support to City Express expansion in Mexico (the Mexico project) with the implementation of two new properties in Mexico City and Monterrey (all together, the Project). The Project would help City express to consolidate its leading position in the budget business hotel sector, accelerate existing growth plans and initiate its expansion outside of Mexico.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">i) Increased business and tourism infrastructure: The Projects are expected to add to their region&apos;s business and tourism infrastructure by expanding and improving the existing base of accommodation facilities and business services; In addition, they should encourage increased tourism, business and meetings, incentives, conferences and exhibitions (&quot;MICE&quot;) travel;  (ii) Mid-market hotel development: The Projects will help the development of the domestic midmarket business hotel segment, thereby extending the product range in the targeted cities, where there is currently a shortage of supply;   (iii)  Benefits to the local economy: The Projects will create opportunities for economic links (local and regional) between tourism and other sectors, both in the development phase (construction services and building supplies) and during on-going operations (employment and operating supplies);  in addition, the Projects will create both direct and indirect jobs, as well as provide training opportunities for employees. They will also contribute to maintain and increase foreign exchange and tax revenues;  spending by visitors would keep help support a wide range of local economic activities, restaurants, transportation, tours, entertainment, sports and leisure activity; and   (iv) Climate change: In order to adopt sustainable green building design and construction, Hospiteum and City Express will continue to ensure high levels of energy efficiency and have various hotels achieve possibly compliance with LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HOTELES CITY EXPRESS S.A.P.I. DE C.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30963" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-02-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Robertos Palacios, Chief Financial Officer Abelardo Loscos, Corporate Finance Director Hoteles City express, S.A.P.I. de C.V. Montes Urales 715-2o piso Col. Lomas de Chapultepec Mexico DF 11000  Telephone: 	+52 55 5249 8050   Fax Number	+52 55 5249 8098 Website:        www.hotelescity.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latin America Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Latin America Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the Central America and Colombia expansion the hotels will be located in San Jose, Costa Rica, Bogota, Cali and Cartagena in Colombia. The two properties in Mexico will be located in Santa Fe, Mexico City and Monterrey. The Latin America Expansion will include hotels in Chile, mainly in Santiago, Concepci&#xF3;n, Antofagasta and cities in the north of the country.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.0000000000 -45.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - City and Business Hotel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $44.55 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30963/city-express-international">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
