<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-34426</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grupo ASSA II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grupo ASSA Worldwide S.A. (Grupo ASSA or the Company) is an existing IFC client. The Company is a leading midsized pan-LAC IT service provider, with over 1,400 employees and 10 offices and delivery centers throughout Latin America, which offers: (i) Business Transformation and IT Consulting and Integration services; (ii) implementation and operations of Enterprise Applications, including Enterprise Resource Planning, Customer Relations Management and Business Intelligence; and (iii) Information Technology outsourcing (ITO), including maintenance and operation of software applications (application management services). The Company currently has offices and development centers in Argentina, Brazil, Mexico, Colombia and Chile.   Grupo ASSA plans to double in revenues over the next 4 years, reaching $200 million by the end of 2017. An exit in 1 or 2 years is the ultimate goal of the shareholders. In order to achieve the necessary scale and margins to be an attractive acquisition target, the Company is focused on achieving three objectives: (i) increase operating margins in its high-end consulting business by adding  higher value services and a more efficient consulting pyramid structure; (ii) grow the Application Managed Services business by 3x by a) increasing market share in Brazil and Mexico, and b) acquire new clients in the US; and (iii) expand the Application Development business unit by designing and building specialized industry software solutions, by increasing teams organically, and making an acquisition of a mid-sized software development firm in the region.  Grupo ASSA is also seeking to refinance expensive short-term debt with a blended interest rate of approx. 13% with long term debt. This would allow Grupo Assa to free up operating cash flow in the short term that it could use to fund growth initiatives as described earlier. Debt with longer tenors would also improve the negotiating position vis-a-vis possible acquirers.  The Company is legally incorporated in Spain but founded and with administrative headquarters in Buenos Aires, Argentina.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to generate the following development impact: - Increase economic efficiencies: Help companies across diverse verticals achieve greater efficiencies through broader adoption of technology to help it manage its value chain (eg enterprise resource planning software). - Support the expansion of the IT outsourcing sector in Latin America:  The region has an opportunity to replicate the successful experience of India, where the  sector represents over 5% of GDP and where it is a major source of value added exports.  US and European are increasingly eyeing LAC to achieve efficiency gains from proximity, same time zone advantages, and a well-educated labor force. - High Quality Job creation: Companies like Grupo ASSA benefit local IT professionals by creating high quality job opportunities and developing skills in the value-added IT services sector. - South-South investments:  Besides expanding its operations in Brazil and Mexico, Grupo ASSA plans to continue expanding its operations in other countries in Latin America, such as Colombia, Chile and Uruguay.  Entering these markets enables transfer of technology, improving business practices, foster competition and promote further investment in the Region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GRUPO ASSA CORP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-34426" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-11" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paul Dougall, VP of Corporate Development Lima 241, Ciudad Autonoma de Buenos Aires (C1073AAE) Buenos Aires, Argentina T: 54-11-4510-7200 E:  mailto:pdougall@grupoassa.com  W:  http://www.grupoassa.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latin America Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Latin America Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Various countries in Latin America, primarily Mexico, Brazil and Colombia.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.0000000000 -45.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="5415" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">R-BA - Computer Systems Design and Related Services (System Integration, Custom Computer Programming, IT Services etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $8.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-05-11"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-11">8000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-05-11">8000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GRUPO ASSA CORP</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/34426">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/34426">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
